
   
   
      
         
            Kwanzaa

            "I'm still having trouble
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> executive says on that controversial tape recording.
"Now we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>." Although his expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> may have been
extreme, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> is not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> confused about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>. Each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> we hear more and more about this holiday. What is it, and where did it
come from?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX> is a holiday
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">honoring African-American</ENAMEX> heritage and culture. Celebrated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from Dec. 26</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, the holiday</TIMEX> was created after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> riot by Maulana
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Karenga</ENAMEX> , a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and black nationalist, who observed that
black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> had no holiday of their own. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karenga</ENAMEX> feuded
openly with other black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> were convicted in a
plot to assassinate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Panthers</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, Karenga
himself was imprisoned for ordering and directing the torture of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
Now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54 years old</TIMEX>, he is chair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Studies</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California State University</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, apparently rehabilitated in the eyes of many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karenga</ENAMEX> served on the national executive committee
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Million Man March</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karenga</ENAMEX>'s
early attempts to popularize <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> were directed at a relatively small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>. Beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX> began to
attract coverage in the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> . The attention grew as Karenga
modified his rhetoric to appeal to a broader <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, and as interest in
multiculturalism burgeoned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>. Kwanzaa was taken up by
many in the expanding black middle class , whose buying power has
supported such marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX> as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwanzaa Expos</ENAMEX>," convention-center
gatherings at which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afrocentric</ENAMEX> goods and art are sold.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karenga</ENAMEX> took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX>'s name from the Swahili
phrase matunda yakwanza , meaning "first <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>." Swahili words were
chosen because the language, a hybrid of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bantu</ENAMEX> tongues, is tied to
no particular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>. Although there are no directly analogous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">holidays</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karenga</ENAMEX> drew his inspiration from various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> harvest festivals.
From these he extracted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> principles --unity, self-determination,
collective work, cooperative economics, purpose, creativity, and faith. Each of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> is meant to symbolize one of these principles.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">central Kwanzaa</ENAMEX> ritual is candle lighting . First, the mkeka
(straw <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat</ENAMEX>) is placed on the table, along with the kinara (candleholder)
and the mishumaa saba (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> candles). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> candles on the right in
the kinara are red, symbolizing the blood of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>; the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> on the left are green, symbolizing the hope of new life; and the black
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">candle</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> represents the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Around the candles are
placed the mazeo (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX>), the vibunzi (an ear of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> for each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>), the zawadi (gifts, preferably handmade), and the
kikombe cha umoja (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cup</NUMEX>) for shared <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.

            
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> of the celebration, a child lights
the appropriate candle, and the principle for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> is discussed. The
highlight is the karamu, or feast, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuumba</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31</TIMEX>. It
celebrates creativity, and is "an opportunity for a confetti storm of cultural
expression: dance and music, readings, remembrances," according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Copage</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration of Culture</ENAMEX> and
Cooking . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> can be highly symbolic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Shelf Medearis</ENAMEX>, author of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX> cookbook, recommends the following karamu menu: Jambalaya
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moroccan Honey Chicken</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>-Style <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Collard Greens</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fruits of Africa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pie</ENAMEX>.

            How
widely celebrated is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>? In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karenga</ENAMEX>'s own words, "It's widespread
but not mainstream." Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linn Washington Jr.</ENAMEX>, claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 13 million</NUMEX>
celebrants, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit News</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> estimate the
Kwanzaa-related market at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karenga</ENAMEX>'s original
intention, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX> takes on a more commercial flavor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hallmark</ENAMEX> makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX> cards, and there are Kwanzaa posters, books, CDs, and mass-produced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinaras</ENAMEX> . But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX> was not intended to replace <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, and many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> celebrate both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX>.

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> ? It too, if not invented in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, has taken on a different shape and gained importance here. Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> has been on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> calendar for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two millennia</TIMEX>, it was,
until recently, a relatively minor holiday. The pressures of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>,
however, have elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> for many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> of
celebration and gift-giving. (A new book maintains that even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trumped-up</ENAMEX> holiday. See "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>.")

            Hanukkah
commemorates the victory in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">165</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX> of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judas</ENAMEX>
Maccabaeus, over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> who ruled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> at the time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> reclaimed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>, and rededicated it as their place of worship. But
they had only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>'s supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> to light the flame, which was supposed to
burn constantly. Miraculously, the flame burned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>,
until the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> supply was replenished. Following the rebellion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> was restored for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 years</TIMEX>.

            
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX> rituals, most notably the focus on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">candles</ENAMEX>, seem to have been borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanukkah</ENAMEX>. The center of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-day</TIMEX>
Hanukkah celebration is the nightly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> gathering to light candles in a
candelabra known as the "menorah." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oily</ENAMEX> foods, particularly latkes (potato
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pancakes</ENAMEX>), are served during dinner to symbolize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> miracle. By
tradition, family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> play with the dreidel , a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-sided spinning
top, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Hanukkah gelt</NUMEX> (chocolate coins covered with gold
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foil</ENAMEX>) and other presents.

            Unlike
Kwanzaa, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> enjoys no agreed-upon spelling in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. The most
common variant is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chanukah</ENAMEX>," reflecting the proper pronunciation of the
opening consonant, which is like the "ch" in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX>." The spelling employed in
this article is from The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press Stylebook</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libel Manual</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> in such matters.

            

               References:
            

            If you'd
like to know more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>, you can read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Complete Kwanzaa:</ENAMEX>
Celebrating our <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural Harvest</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Winbush Riley</ENAMEX>; A Kwanzaa
Keepsake: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Celebrating the Holiday With New Traditions and Feasts</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica B. Harris</ENAMEX>; or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merry Christmas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby: A Christmas</ENAMEX> and Kwanzaa
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> , edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix H. Liddell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula L. Woods</ENAMEX>. Karenga, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creator</ENAMEX>, has also written two books on the celebration, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kwanzaa: Origin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concepts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Practice and The African American Celebration of Kwanzaa: A</ENAMEX>
Celebration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family, Community & Culture</ENAMEX> . And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Day Wilde</ENAMEX>
describes how the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> gained popularity in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mainstreaming Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>," in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Interest</ENAMEX> , No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spring 1995</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
