
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bounty Hunters</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> armed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bounty hunters</ENAMEX> forced their way into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> home, shooting and killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">occupants</ENAMEX>. In another recent case, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>, bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> broke into
the wrong home and put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> in an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. These stories portray
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bounty hunters</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> who are beyond the law. What is a bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX>? What
legal powers do bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> have? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whence</ENAMEX> do they derive those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX>?

            
               Bounty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> work for bail-bondsmen . They are dispatched to capture defendants
in criminal cases who have skipped bail posted by bail-bondsmen. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 40</NUMEX>
percent of all criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> are released on bail , a cash deposit
that is forfeited to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> fails to appear before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> as promised. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Defendants</ENAMEX> who can't afford bail often hire the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of
a private bail-bond <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to front the cash. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bondsman</ENAMEX>'s fee is usually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent of the bail, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> putting up collateral for the
remainder.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 33,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> posted bail
and then skipped their court date . Most bail-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumpers</ENAMEX> face charges on
drug-related crimes, violent offenses, or theft. The most popular bail-jumper
destinations are warm-weather spots (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX> and south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>) and
big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skips</ENAMEX> stay within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>--avoiding passport-control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, who are trained to spot them.

            In most
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, a bondsman must return the skip within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of the missed
court date to recover his deposit. Few bail-bondsmen keep bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> on the
payroll for liability reasons, choosing instead to pay the bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> the
standard fee of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the bond. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bounty hunters</ENAMEX> (who prefer to call
themselves "recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>") are paid only after the skip is returned to
custody and the bail-bondsman gets his deposit back from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. In most
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> are unregulated . (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bail</ENAMEX>-bondsmen, on the other
hand, are licensed and regulated by all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and in many jurisdictions must
carry liability and general operating insurance.)

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> of bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> are
immense . When arresting a skip, bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> need not read them their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda</ENAMEX> rights . They do not need a warrant to search the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skip</ENAMEX>, even a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Nor are they required to announce themselves before
entering private property, as police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> must. Evidence obtained illegally
by bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> can be submitted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Like police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, bounty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> are authorized to use "all reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> " to apprehend skips.
This means they can shoot to kill if shot at. Also, they can transport skips
across state lines without enduring extradition proceedings. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bounty hunter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cliché</ENAMEX>: Extradition proceedings take place in the trunk of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Bounty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> derive their powers from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> case 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor</ENAMEX>
vs. Taintor
               . In the eyes of the law, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> voluntarily places
himself in the custody of the bail-bondsman and, by extension, the bounty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hunter</ENAMEX>, when he signs the bail contract. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> decided that bondsmen and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bounty hunters</ENAMEX> are proxies for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and therefore deserve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> powers
when taking "custody" of the accused. However, the usual constitutional
protections enjoyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> don't apply to skips pursued by bounty hunters
because, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> decided, the bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> work for the bondsmen, not the
government. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private</ENAMEX> debt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX>--"repo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>"--face more legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fetters</ENAMEX> than bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX>. They can't use violence or search private property
without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>' consent. And unlike bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX>, they can be arrested
for trespassing on private property.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bounty hunters</ENAMEX>' privileges are a vestige of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
common law . Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">custodians</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> awaiting trial. Usually, the custodian was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 13 th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> commonly required custodians to serve
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>' punishments in their stead when their wards skipped, even if this
meant standing in for a hanging.

            
               Bounty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> are more efficient at returning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association of Bail Enforcement Agents</ENAMEX> says that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88 percent</NUMEX> of all
bail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumpers</ENAMEX> are returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> by bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX>. Law enforcement
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> return <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of skips, but catch most of them at routine traffic
stops and at border crossings. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 2 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skips</ENAMEX> remain at large.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Criminal justice experts</ENAMEX> credit bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX>' success rates to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things:
They face less red tape than do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> have
an economic incentive to get their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX> proclaimed bounty hunting one of the hottest job tracks in its
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Jobs for the Future</ENAMEX>" issue. No persuasive evidence substantiates this
claim. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NABEA</ENAMEX>, there are only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200 to 300</NUMEX> full-time bounty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and they earn an average income of about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36,000</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 1,700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> bounty hunt part time. Most of them are former
or off-duty cops or private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>.

            Few bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> training
programs exist--the most frequently attended programs are <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-hour</TIMEX>
courses that cover only basic legal constraints. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have bills
pending that would require bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> to register with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, take more
extensive training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, and obey procedural constraints that apply to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, such as announcing themselves before entering a private home.

            Instances of bounty
hunters abusing their power abound. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> case, the bounty hunters
claimed that they were pursuing a skip but accidentally raided the wrong
address. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> believe that the bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> used their profession
as a cover for armed robbery. Increasingly, civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> hold bounty hunters
liable for their mistakes . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> awarded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX> to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was mistakenly kidnapped and transported to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bounty hunters</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
