
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> police
massacred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 51</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The
dead, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> says, deserved their fate. They
were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> promoting the secession of this remote southern swath
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Balkan watchers</ENAMEX> say the killings will provoke the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>--into armed revolt, sparking a conflagration
that could involve the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Why the long history of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX>
acrimony? Will <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> redux--another bout of ethnic cleansing and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warfare</ENAMEX>, or worse?

            According
to the conventional wisdom, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s murders were the latest chapter in a
centuries-long feud between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian Muslims</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian Orthodox</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> still sting from their defeat at the hands of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ottoman Turks</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1389</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, which began the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">522</NUMEX>-year
occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. Blame for the defeat is pinned on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian Muslims</ENAMEX>, who,
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, are accused of having collaborated with the invaders.
But this interpretation misrepresents the record: Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> resisted
invasion; they didn't collaborate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> any more than their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> did.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-19 th century</TIMEX>, with the growth of
nationalism across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> became an obsession among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, a symbol of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s past grandeur and current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mistreatment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poets</ENAMEX> wrote epics, with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Muslim</ENAMEX> subtexts, romanticizing the
Battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> morphed into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. The liberation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Serbs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> holy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> tyrants became the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">nationalist</ENAMEX> rallying cry, as did the redemption of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> who had converted
to Islam during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>' rule.

            The
nationalist myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> belies a pluralistic reality.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> coexisted--peacefully--under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> rule. Only when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serbia</ENAMEX> beat back the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX> did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> begin to transform
their nationalist fantasies about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> into policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbs</ENAMEX> exported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and expelled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>. Even so, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> have always vastly
outnumbered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>; there are now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>, compared
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>.

            
When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josip Broz Tito</ENAMEX> took
over in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, he attempted to quash <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> nationalism . He preached
that there was no room for ethnic differences in the class struggle. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>,
suspicious of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slovenian</ENAMEX> background, said he was giving them
short shrift. To allay fears of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> chauvinism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX> prohibited
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX>-language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> and gave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s most desirable jobs to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> staged protests in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX> attempted to pacify them
by strengthening local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> (largely dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>) over local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX> and by restoring jobs. This satisfied no one: It was not enough to dent
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> unemployment and just enough to rile <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. Following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX>'s death in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, malcontents on both sides rioted.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>,
while other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> ignored the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> mess, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>, then
a little-known <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> apparatchik, began accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> of
perpetrating genocide against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> organized mass
rallies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> --one of them attended by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>--where he
charged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> with ignoring the crisis. His attacks won him
popular support, which he ultimately parlayed into control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s demagoguery over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> helped convince the
Croatians, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovenians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnians</ENAMEX> that they could no longer deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, they seceded from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>.

            Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> lost all semblance of
autonomy . They were removed from jobs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Separate
but unequal <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX>-only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and health care systems were established. (It
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">credibly</ENAMEX> alleged that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> poisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>' water supply with the
nerve gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarin</ENAMEX>.) Unemployment among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> reached <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX>, higher than
in war-torn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. Arbitrary arrests and searches increased, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
implemented de facto martial law.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
crackdown spurred the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> organized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibrahim Rugova</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic League of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> , modeling it on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s nonviolent campaigns. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rugova</ENAMEX>
established a shadow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoys</ENAMEX> abroad to make the case for
independence. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> remained intransigent. Smarting from losses in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian</ENAMEX> war and from the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> economy, opposition parties
took to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter of 1996</TIMEX> to demand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s resignation.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> survived the protests, his position remains tenuous. He
believes he cannot afford the loss of prestige that would accompany a
compromise on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. Even opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> agree that it is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s
manifest destiny to control <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX> discontent increases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> feel slighted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1995 Dayton Peace Accord</ENAMEX>, which gave autonomy to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> but stayed silent on their fate. The lesson they have drawn:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation</ENAMEX> comes from armed struggle, not nonviolence. Support grows for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of militants, many of whom fought on
behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> now controls several mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> and has
smuggled a sizable cache of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> across the border from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> rumor has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
funding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> because he needs an excuse to start another nationalist
war to boost his popularity. Another says he ordered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s crackdown only
after he received the implicit green light from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gelbard</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gelbard</ENAMEX> called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> a terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has tried to play it both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. It rejects <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>'s claims for independence but decries the
crackdown. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> agreed they would
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stiffen</ENAMEX> sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> to protest the massacres. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is
afraid that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> stationed in neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX> will
get drawn into battle.

            Various nightmare
scenarios describe how the conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> might escalate . One
has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>, which has said it won't tolerate further attacks on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, entering a bloody war with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. Another has the war spreading to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>, where ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> would come to the support of their fellows in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. This, in turn, would inspire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> to intervene to restore order and
protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, gets
involved, the whole of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, bound by treaty, could follow.

         
      
   
