
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baitgate</ENAMEX> (or the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corruption</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hale</ENAMEX>)

            With the closing of
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>, grand jury <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>,
the commentariat pronounced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> scandal had passed, with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> emerging unindicted and unscathed. But another Whitewater
scandal--which neither implicates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> nor involves shady land
deals--still has legs. On the basis of evidence initially published in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> has called for an investigation of charges
that the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> paid off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s star
Whitewater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hale</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Right-wingers</ENAMEX> bark back that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> is a
mere conduit for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin.

            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hale</ENAMEX>
take money? Is he at the nexus of a right-wing conspiracy ? Or is this
alleged right-wing conspiracy an invention of a left-wing conspiracy?

            First, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> refresher: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
an investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> of pressuring him to make a
fraudulent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> loan to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX>, some of
which flowed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> project. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>'s testimony helped persuade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>--first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fiske</ENAMEX>, then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>--to investigate.

            However, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> article by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> 's investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Broder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray Waas</ENAMEX> implied
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>'s motives were less than pure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> repeatedly received
payments that originated with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Mellon</ENAMEX>
Scaif e--the alleged ringmaster of a right-wing conspiracy aimed at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1993 and 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scaife</ENAMEX> gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> that runs it <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 million</NUMEX> to track down <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
alleged malfeasance. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read about this "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project</ENAMEX>.") A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Boynton</ENAMEX>, in turn paid his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dozhier</ENAMEX>--a onetime TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who now owns a bait shop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Springs</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48,000</NUMEX>
to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> "eyes and ears." For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>
says, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dozhier</ENAMEX> used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> money to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>--an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> also alleges that on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>'s trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dozhier</ENAMEX>'s bait <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, the two
concocted elaborate schemes to sink <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Here's a
flow chart to help you track the alleged money trail.

            
Nobody disputes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> frequently
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visited Dozhier</ENAMEX> or that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> discussed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitewater</ENAMEX>--the investigation did,
after all, consume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>'s life. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dozhier</ENAMEX> concedes he lent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> a pickup
truck for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, paid his auto insurance, and gave him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $300</NUMEX> to pay
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX>. But he denies any intent to influence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>'s testimony.

            The
main 
               source for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> 's article is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dozhier</ENAMEX>'s
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caryn Mann</ENAMEX>, who says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dozhier</ENAMEX> drastically underestimates the
payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>. First, she told <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> that though she didn't have an
accurate fix on the amount paid, it was substantial. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> story touting her testimony.) In an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> that appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days later</TIMEX>, she recovered her memory and fixed the
figure at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the story with this version.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> interviews,
she backed down from this number, admitting that she doesn't recall seeing
Dozhier give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> cash.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>'s credibility has been attacked by the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> , who ridicule her for
using tarot cards and (allegedly) boasting about transporting soldiers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telepathically</ENAMEX>. They also say she's a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> operative and still
seething from an acrimonious breakup with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dozhier</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dozhier</ENAMEX>'s own credibility problems.)

            The
testimony of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Rand</ENAMEX> is far more vivid and detailed. He says he saw
Dozhier give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> money on every occasion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> visited their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX>.
According to accounts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rand</ENAMEX> gave both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , the
amounts ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several hundred dollars</NUMEX>, with an estimated total
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rand</ENAMEX> admits the figure he provides is only an estimate.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waas</ENAMEX> say they have spoken with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ex- Spectator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who anonymously corroborate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rand</ENAMEX>'s assertion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project</ENAMEX> paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>. No other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> working
on the story has been able to track down these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.

            Even if
the payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> were conclusively proved, they don't necessarily undermine
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> testimony. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>, then at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , reported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>'s story on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2, 1993</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> made any of the alleged payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>'s story
hasn't changed at all since he spoke with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'93</TIMEX>. Other reporters
covering the story posit another scenario: Financially ruined --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> was
fined <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>--he hung around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dozhier</ENAMEX>'s bait <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, looking for and
receiving petty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handouts</ENAMEX>.

            In addition to attacking the story's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX>
attack its purveyors--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waas</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> recycles the
story that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> had been fired from his job at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX>
when he plagiarized from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Greenberg</ENAMEX>. Others
point to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waas</ENAMEX>' supposedly shoddy reporting of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize</ENAMEX>-nominated
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on arms sales to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> that he co-wrote for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . There is no evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> repeated any of these
alleged sins in their reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waas</ENAMEX> never
explicitly claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> money swayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>. They let others
tease out the implications of their story for them, connecting the dots
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scaife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> : The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> endowed a position for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepperdine University</ENAMEX> (which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has subsequently declined) and then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bankrolled Hale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>. This is the scenario implied by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Holder</ENAMEX>, who suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>,
rather than a biased independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, should investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baitgate</ENAMEX>. Others
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Conyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, have used the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> case to call for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
resignation.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> counter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> 's posited right-wing conspiracy by charging
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webzine</ENAMEX> is a pawn in a conspiracy by the left. They note
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX>'s friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s now famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmett Tyrrell Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> , goes further. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> ,
he says, is bankrolled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> run by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Warnock</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambrecht & Quist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hambrecht</ENAMEX>, now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retired</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, right-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">winger Larry Klayman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Watch</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subpoenaed Waas</ENAMEX> and ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to produce all their notes
relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> allegation as well as to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>. (To read
about how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> can do this, click .)

            
               If you missed the
sidebar on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project</ENAMEX>," click . And read
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dozhier's</ENAMEX> and .
            

         
      
   
