
   
   
      
         
            Death and Taxes

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> proposed abolishing the estate tax. Many other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>,
and some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, have done the same.

            The estate tax is imposed on
assets passed on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> when someone dies. It is the only federal tax on
wealth --as opposed to income or consumption. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> imposed it in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>, mainly motivated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Era</ENAMEX> concerns about the concentration of
wealth in the coffers of a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.

            The
estate tax is progressive --that is, the tax rate is higher on larger
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">estates</ENAMEX>. The first <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> is exempt. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> can, therefore, pass on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2</NUMEX>
million tax-free to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>. The rate is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent</NUMEX> on amounts between
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000 and $750,000</NUMEX>. The highest rate is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent</NUMEX>, and kicks in at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. But any amount inherited by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> is exempt. Pre-death gifts
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $10,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> are also exempt. Thus, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can pass on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> tax-free. (Lifetime gifts above the
exempted amount are subject to the gift tax , which more or less
parallels the estate tax.)

            

               Creative accounting also reduces the
estate-tax burden. Deductions , which include administrative costs and
charitable gifts, are ample. The tax is based on property's "fair market
value ," which is a malleable concept and notoriously underestimated by
professional estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appraisers</ENAMEX>. Squabbles between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> and estates over fair
market value are routine and often protracted. Trusts and other
complicated devices are also used to reduce the tax on large estates, although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has eliminated many of these opportunities and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has been
scrutinizing others more closely in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.

            The estate
tax affects few . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">69,772 estates</NUMEX> with assets of more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> filed forms with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>. The combined value of these estates was
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$117.7 billion</NUMEX>. However, because of credits and deductions--mostly transfers to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 31,918</NUMEX> estates paid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> any money. That's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.2 percent</NUMEX>
of all estates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17.8 billion</NUMEX>. According to calculations done
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens for Tax Justice</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17.8 billion</NUMEX> came
from estates valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 million</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s numbers are similar to
the data from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Proponents</ENAMEX> offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> reasons for the
tax : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It reduces concentrations of wealth, however slightly. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Because
of the charitable-contribution deduction, it spurs giving. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Estates</ENAMEX> donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> to charity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>--almost as much as the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10.1 billion</NUMEX> they paid to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The tax provides revenue--though this adds up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1</NUMEX>
percent or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> of total federal revenues in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a typical year</TIMEX>.

            Staunch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of the estate tax include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> . Family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> often
possess highly valued land, but little cash. Consequently, they say, inheritors
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> must sell their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> to pay the tax. However, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> leaves a taxable estate. The inheritors of such estates
pay very little. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the median estate tax paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>.
Much of the value of inherited land is offset by the deduction of debt. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmers</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> also enjoy special exemptions. For
instance, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> may pay off the estate tax over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX> at very low
interest--an option not available to others.

            Many political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> argue that the
government taxes an estate's assets several times over--first when the money is
earned, then when it is invested, and finally when it's transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>.
They call the estate tax an exercise in class warfare , and argue that it
drains money from private investment. Some left-of-center <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have made
similar arguments. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice Chair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Blinder</ENAMEX> and
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Council of Economic Advisers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Stiglitz</ENAMEX>
argue that: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the estate tax fails as a redistributive measure because rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have become too good at circumventing it; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the considerable effort put
into circumventing the tax wastes economic resources; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the tax encourages
consumption, instead of savings and investment.

            Death is not all bad news
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">taxwise</ENAMEX>. The capital-gains tax on inherited property is based on
increases in value only since the property was inherited. Thus, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of
dollars of profits on stocks, real estate, etc., escape the capital-gains tax
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> dies. Some have suggested a trade-off: End the estate
tax but tax capital gains at death.

         
      
   
