
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop Music</ENAMEX>

            Gangsta rapper Tupac Shakur
is shot to death in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oasis</ENAMEX> stirs international
speculation about whether or not it is breaking up. When pop music makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headlines</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are forced to admit that they have lost track of it.
Herewith, a guide. Although pop music has grown more complicated, most current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> continue to recombine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'60s</TIMEX>, and
'70s--sometimes literally ( sampling , a technique crucial to many current
pop genres, involves lifting passages from older recordings and using them in
new ones). "Rock 'n' roll is here to stay," proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Juniors</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>, and it turned out they were right.

            In rock 'n' roll's first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">songwriters</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Berry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy Holly</ENAMEX> established
its song forms and subject matter: the lives, loves, and modest rebellions of
newly enfranchised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Performers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Richard</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lee Lewis</ENAMEX> supplied sexual charisma, abandon, and even menace.
Vocal-harmony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> ( do-wop ) from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> prefigured
the style that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motown</ENAMEX> would soon codify as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> ," while
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everly Brothers</ENAMEX> anticipated folk-rock .

            Refracted
through a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> prism, these styles became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merseybeat</ENAMEX> , the sound of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Byrds</ENAMEX> expanded rock's themes to
include the poetic and the political, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> influences and psychedelic
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> changed the music and the culture. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> also saw the invention of
art rock , which ranged from the minimalism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Velvet Underground</ENAMEX> to
the florid romanticism of Yes. Such music was meant for albums, not singles,
which meant the decline of the medium that had previously held youth-culture
music together: Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> radio.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, blues rock (a modern white version of
the blues) transformed itself into heavy metal , typified by Led
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeppelin</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Singer/songwriters</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Taylor</ENAMEX> recorded
easy-listening confessionals, and country-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX>
institutionalized The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byrds</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> experiments (and adumbrated the slick
contemporary country sound of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Funk</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brown</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sly</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Stone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funkedelic</ENAMEX>) made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soul wilder</ENAMEX> and looser, and disco combined the celebration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eros</ENAMEX> and
dancing with beats derived from funk, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> music, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> experimentalists
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kraftwerk</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spacey</ENAMEX> electronic music left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conservatory</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Eno</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discreet Music</ENAMEX> introduced the muted wallpaper music
described as "ambient ."

            At the same time, punk
arose in reaction to art-rock pomposity and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>/songwriter narcissism, and
reintroduced political content, derived from both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">'60s rock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaican</ENAMEX>-born
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reggae</ENAMEX> . By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the decade</TIMEX>, punk and disco were tentatively
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crossbreeding</ENAMEX>.

            

               Alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> , which grew out of punk, refers to any band that was
nurtured by the underground infrastructure (indie labels, college radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX>, new-music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>). Alternative's commercial breakthrough came with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nirvana</ENAMEX> 's album <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nevermind</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s grunge
formula, captured in "," combines woozy psychedelic-metal verses with explosive
punk choruses. The recipe has been adopted by scores of bands; most notable:
chart-topping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Smashing Pumpkins</ENAMEX> ' more grandiose version.

            
To the uninitiated, pop music's most mysterious
form is hip-hop , or rap . That's intentional: Its shifting styles
and private language are designed to exclude. But hip-hop is derivative, too.
Its origins can be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> oral culture. Early hip-hop was
mostly party music, but it developed a political message through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Enemy</ENAMEX> . Tracks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.E.</ENAMEX>'s "" gave hip-hop the urgency of an
air-raid siren. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s black-nationalist stance was followed by forays into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitism</ENAMEX>, misogyny, and anti-white racism.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Enemy</ENAMEX> was eclipsed by
gangsta rap , which glorifies "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thug Life"</ENAMEX> (as it was deemed by Tupac
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakur</ENAMEX> ). Gangsta rap's attitude is disturbing, but it's mostly escapist
entertainment, rooted as much in the blaxploitation movies of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX> as
in reality. Gangsta rap shifted hip-hop's center of gravity from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>, and supplanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Enemy</ENAMEX>'s machine-gun attack with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cooler</ENAMEX>, jazzier style. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coolio</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> hit, "," may celebrate "see[ing] myself in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> smoke," but musically, it's relaxed and sauntering. The big hit of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fugees</ENAMEX> is a remake of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Killing Me Softly</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Flack</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>
easy-listening tune.

            
               Rage
Against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machine</ENAMEX> , a popular political rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, derives its beats from
hip-hop. Songs like "," which endorses the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zapatista</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>, marry hip-hop's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thump</ENAMEX>, punk's wiriness, and heavy metal's roar. Hip-hop also influences the
burgeoning field of electronic pop , which ranges from pounding dance
music that is little more than rhythm to quietly rippling music that's only
slightly removed from New Age sound. Current underground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cibo Matto</ENAMEX>
offers yet another variation on hip-hop with playful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>-accented
commentary on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in "."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, electronic music draws on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germanic</ENAMEX> disco,
hip-hop, and dub , the stripped-down, heavily echoed instrumental variant
of reggae. The array of electronic styles pioneered or embraced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>-- techno , <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> , jungle , ambient <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> ,
trip-hop , and so on--features insistent beats and wide-ranging
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eclecticism</ENAMEX>. Add the shrill vocals of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sex Pistol John Lydon</ENAMEX>, and the
result is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leftfield</ENAMEX>'s hectoring "." Drench a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> in shadowy atmosphere, and
the result is the ominous soundscape of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tricky</ENAMEX>'s "." Combine '50s "space"
music, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">balladeering</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> catch phrases, and the result is
such <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stereolab</ENAMEX> confections as "." Transpose the cyclical rhythms of dance music
(and work by minimalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Reich</ENAMEX>) to guitars, and the result
is the hypnotic disorientation of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Bloody Valentine's "</ENAMEX>." Include reggae
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rhythms</ENAMEX> and quotations from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> music, and the result is the
ethno-techno of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Loop Guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> like "."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graceland</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), which was largely derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African Mbaqanga</ENAMEX> , helped popularize non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> music. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> duo <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Can Dance</ENAMEX> mixes dance music with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">medieval European</ENAMEX> music (played mostly on traditional instruments) on tracks
like "."

            
As it has since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, edgy rock coexists
with more easygoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop</ENAMEX>: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'60s</TIMEX>, the best-selling albums included
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Albert</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tijuana Brass ' Whipped Cream</ENAMEX> and Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delights</ENAMEX>. Recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> have brought hip-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopped</ENAMEX> pop-soul acts such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Sweat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariah Carey</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boyz II Men</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TLC</ENAMEX>, as well as
hits for such big-voiced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neo-soul singers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Baker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bolton</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Céline Dion</ENAMEX>.

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s pop success story was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hootie</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blowfish</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
frat-party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. Equally retro but more stylish is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oasis</ENAMEX> , whose
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What's the Story) Morning Glory</ENAMEX>? led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britpop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> and
may prove the best-selling album in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> history. Songs like their biggest hit,
"," are sense-less but skillful pastiches of classic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> moments.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alanis Morissette</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jagged Little Pill</ENAMEX> has sold more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 million</NUMEX> copies. Her songs of rage, like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Oughta Know"</ENAMEX> (composed
with an experienced collaborator), draw on the styles and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> of folkie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joni Mitchell</ENAMEX> and experimentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoko Ono</ENAMEX> . Morrissette rations
the rough edges to create music that will energize but not alienate her young,
primarily female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX>-rock had
taken pop away from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '50s</TIMEX> commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">songwriters</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carole King</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Spector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Sedaka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>) and given it to the poets;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morissette</ENAMEX>'s following indicates, once again, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX> can make music
that resonates as deeply with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> as any poetry.

            With the dizzying array of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pop hybrids</ENAMEX> now being cultivated, there is, of course, a reaction. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Musicians</ENAMEX>
return to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> and blues roots, and reject studio techniques with a
low-fi movement (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guided by Voices</ENAMEX>) that treasures spontaneity and tape
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hiss</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> make music that's as glossy as any, there's an
upsurge of plain-singing balladeers stressing their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian</ENAMEX> roots
(real or imagined). When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iris DeMent</ENAMEX>, the most striking of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX>,
addresses the death of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in "," the effect is immediate and direct.
But the song also gives notice that pop music, cycling and recycling again and
again, can always go back to basics.

         
      
   
