
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sick Economy</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> stock market
fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">another 10 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, bringing its total drop since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> to more
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>. Although the market has since rebounded, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
suspect that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy is headed for a deep recession. More
pessimistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> predict that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> will take the rest of eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
down with it. To head off this scenario, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> is
considering another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$670 million</NUMEX> in loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. Why hasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
transition from communism to capitalism been nearly as successful as the
transformation of some of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> satellites? What's behind the
current woes?

            When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> collapsed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last days of 1991</TIMEX>, control of the economy
fell to a clique of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> raised on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago School libertarian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> learned from smuggled copies of Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>
persuaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s newly installed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to privatize the
state-run economy en masse and to lift all price controls in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fell swoop.
The rationale behind this "shock therapy ": If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> didn't quickly
destroy the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> spouting populist rhetoric
would retake power.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1991 to 1995</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 18,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>--including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
percent of the manufacturing sector--were transferred from state to private
ownership. Now the state owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a few</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military manufacturers</ENAMEX> and an
oil company, though this will be auctioned off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> generated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s gross domestic
product . Some question the therapeutic value of this policy of rapid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">privatization</ENAMEX>, but none dispute the shock. Since communism, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s GDP and
manufacturing have tumbled <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 3 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> on average (much more in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, inflation peaked at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1,500 percent</NUMEX> and was still as
high as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>,
however, the economy began to look up, benefiting from Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>'
enthusiasm for the so-called emerging markets. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> GDP grew
for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time--a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.4 percent</NUMEX> increase in real terms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> declared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> had turned the corner. But with the recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tumult</ENAMEX>, their predictions for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s future have quickly shifted from swim
to sink . Here are the most prominent rationales for the new
bearishness:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> collapse. With <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>'s
surprising collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies, Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> have grown
skittish about all "emerging markets." Though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economy is not closely
intertwined with those of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> have been shifting to the more stable
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> markets rather than risking getting burned again.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Oil
collapse. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has failed to develop a competitive post-communist
manufacturing sector. Instead, it relies for exports on natural resources,
primarily <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>. With oil prices plummeting, thanks to new technologies for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detecting</ENAMEX> and extracting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is running a trade deficit for the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> since communism's collapse.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> No taxes. Despite exorbitantly tax
high rates that discourage enterprise, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> brings in ridiculously
low revenue. The problem: Nearly everyone bribes tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> or simply
refuses to pay (of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 million</NUMEX> filed income
declarations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>). With little tax revenue, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can't provide
even the rudiments of a social safety net or pay its bills. The shortfall also
traps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in a cycle of debt--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly one-third</NUMEX> of its budget is
spent servicing its high interest bonds.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
Credit crunch. Several of the biggest, most corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> collapsed in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, drying up important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of credit. At the same time, the central bank
has hiked interest rates continuously to check inflation and allay the fears of
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, thus discouraging needed business borrowing. The credit
crunch, along with low faith in the stability of the ruble, has fostered
bartering in goods and financial assets. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 10 percent</NUMEX> of transactions are
currently conducted in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">rubles</NUMEX>--the national currency.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5 Arrears</ENAMEX>. Labor strikes have multiplied
in the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> era, especially over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX>. For the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> coal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> in the east, who haven't received a paycheck for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year</TIMEX>, have stopped working and blocked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX>. According to
estimates, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> owe their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> in back pay.
The threat of further strikes and labor disruptions is another deterrent for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. The
ruble. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> worries that foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, anxious to unload
their rubles, will force a devaluation of the currency. This would drive up the
price of imported goods and reignite the hyperinflation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. To
check this, the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> has tripled interest rates and used hard currency
reserves (now reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> in ready cash) to buy back <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">rubles</NUMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> Privatization gone awry. Some argue
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is still reeling from its misguided plan for privatization. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> implemented a program that in essence worked like
this: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> decided the value of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and were given the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chance to buy a controlling share in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, using government
vouchers. The idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> is appealing but, in practice,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>' old Soviet-style <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> gained control. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are chided
for lacking experience, competence, and the desire to adapt their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to
the market.

            Cronyism
also undermined the transition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Businessmen</ENAMEX> used the patronage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> at fire sale prices. For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> auctioned
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yukos Oil Company</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year later</TIMEX>, it was valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>. The biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of the patronage have been the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
best-connected magnates--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Seven Boyars</ENAMEX>." Facing little competition, these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnates</ENAMEX> possess fantastic wealth--mainly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> on natural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>--and own major media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. These oligopolies have in most cases
proved to be as inefficient and disinclined to innovate as the state-owned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monopolies</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s buffoonery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, in
failing health, has lost the confidence of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. Like an old party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX>--and he is an old party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> purges his administration
regularly. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, he dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> and
replaced him with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> political neophyte, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sergei Kiriyenko</ENAMEX>.
Kiriyenko, however, has drawn praise from Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> for his commitment
to free market economic reform and from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> business sector for being
friendly to their interests.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.
Organized crime. Organized crime remains rampant, though less widespread
than at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'90s</TIMEX> peak. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Businessmen</ENAMEX> are no longer routinely assassinated by
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roundtable</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber of commerce</ENAMEX>, were knocked off.) The power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>
has been undercut by the oligopolies, each of which has a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven Boyars</ENAMEX> employs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10,000</NUMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> chicanery. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> makes its
loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> contingent on the order of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">house.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Sachs</ENAMEX>, say that the
government's efforts to satisfy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>--by reducing the budget deficit and
jacking up interest rates to defend the ruble--have worsened the crisis,
deepening the credit crunch and cooling growth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> argue that left to
itself the market will correct, leaving only a few currency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX> to bear
the brunt of a currency collapse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> responds that the
risks of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> collapse are too high (including the spread of contagion to
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> resorting to black market sales of nuclear weapons)
and failing to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> support would be analogous to canceling insurance
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> is sick.

         
      
   
