
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hispanics</ENAMEX>

            By Karenna
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census Bureau</ENAMEX>
estimates that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> will outnumber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. This will make them
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s largest ethnic minority . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> election, as the general
voter turnout neared a record low, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> turnout soared, providing the
margin of victory in several key elections. Who are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>, where do they
come from, and what is the political impact of this rapidly growing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>?

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> officially adopted the term "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, applying it to
any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ancestors</ENAMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>. (The term
itself is derived from "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hispania</ENAMEX>," which was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Empire</ENAMEX>'s name for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iberian</ENAMEX> peninsula.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>'s geography-based definition , which lumps
together <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, and those of mixed race, has provoked a heated debate.
Some complain that the categorization falsely homogenizes a diverse people
under a label linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> imperialism. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> argue for the term
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latino</ENAMEX> ," because it denotes self-definition, allows for more
subcategorization by nationality, and alludes to distant cultural origins
rather than a painful colonial past. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX>" is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX> was
the official language of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hispania</ENAMEX>, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>" was coined by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18 th century</TIMEX> to describe the New World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> refer
to themselves as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chicanos</ENAMEX> ," a pejorative term from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> for
lower-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> that was embraced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s</TIMEX> and early
1970s by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> seeking a new political identity. The Chicano
movement celebrated the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian</ENAMEX> roots of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> culture. As the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chicano</ENAMEX>" label
fell out of vogue, many of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> joined forces with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Latino</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>,
accusing the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX> of grouping <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> under their
rubric to inflate their numbers.

            Today, the
debate boils down to personal preference, shown by clear regional patterns: In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Latino</ENAMEX>" is generally the preferred term. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>" is more common. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>, it's a tie.

            
The rapidly growing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is
resulting in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">browning of America</ENAMEX> ." Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 16 years</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has grown <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">93 percent</NUMEX>--from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14.6 million to 28.2 million</NUMEX>.
(The total <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has grown <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">226.5 million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">265.8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.) By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2050</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> estimates, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> will
constitute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24.5 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, up from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>.
Meanwhile, the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> will grow from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.2</NUMEX>
percent, and the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> will rise only slightly, from
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13.6 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 53 percent</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white, down from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            The growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> is due to high birth rates and immigration . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
birth rates are significantly higher than average, because of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>' lower
median age, higher poverty levels, and enduring cultural values that place a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">premium</ENAMEX> on large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> estimates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> net
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immigration</ENAMEX>--legal and illegal--of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">820,000</NUMEX>, with the large majority being
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hispanics</ENAMEX>
live in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, but their numbers are greatest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. Of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> living in these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>
percent (concentrated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>) trace their roots to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>
(relatively evenly distributed) to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>
(concentrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> (concentrated in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5 percent</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>, they are significant voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX> in key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and, most
of the time, they vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>. In the recent presidential election, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
voter turnout increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly three</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> votes going
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> percentage points above his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> showing). In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>,
where a heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> turnout was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-to-1</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> won for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have
traditionally voted solidly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. But in the last election, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly half</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, double his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> share. That
helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> carry this traditionally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
votes also delivered the margin of victory to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in several close
congressional races.

            
Why the increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> turnout and
support for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' anti-immigrant agenda , which was
aggressively covered by the growing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish-speaking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, had much to do with
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> angered many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> by endorsing the move to make English the
official language of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> also opposed public funding of
bilingual education and the printing of government materials in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> platform advocated that citizenship be denied to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> born in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>.

            However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hispanics</ENAMEX> tend to
be socially conservative, and these instincts could eventually propel many of
them toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>.

            Despite their growing
influence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>-- salsa now outsells <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ketchup</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> have yet to
realize anything near their political potential. Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> turnout among
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hispanics</ENAMEX> remains below the national average. But as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s
population surges in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>, both political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are likely to
address that shortcoming.

         
      
   
