
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feminism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and Harassment

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foremother Gloria Steinem</ENAMEX> took to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed page to argue
that the sexual harassment laws should not protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX>'s
position was roundly dismissed as a scholastic contortion of logic, performed
to protect her ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> gloated over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feminist</ENAMEX>'s hypocrisy on sexual harassment, the movement's sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>. No less
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> editorial page accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinem</ENAMEX> of selling out
her cause. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> sacrifice their principles to protect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>? What are the different feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of thought on sexual
harassment? How have they changed post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>?

            Here, in
descending order of sternness, are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (for a refresher on
harassment law and its history, click ):

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 MacKinnonites</ENAMEX>. This, the so-called radical feminist
position, is trumpeted primarily by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> who take their cues from law
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catharine MacKinnon</ENAMEX>, who holds appointments at the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacKinnon</ENAMEX> argues that sexual harassment
laws are a necessary corrective to the oppressive patriarchy of the workplace,
and she wants current laws stiffened. For instance, she would prohibit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from
having sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinate female co-workers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MacKinnonites</ENAMEX> believe that the
disparities of power in these relationships render them exploitative by
definition.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacKinnon</ENAMEX>'s position, however, is hardly fringe. While a grad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>,
she formulated the theory behind the current practice of sexual harassment
law--that the employment discrimination protections in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Rights</ENAMEX>
Act could be used to regulate workplace behavior such as dirty jokes and
unwelcome advances. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacKinnon</ENAMEX> argues that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> distort her work, by
caricaturing her as a neopuritan. To prove her reasonableness, she concedes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> shouldn't be prosecuted--at least not for sexually harassing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair, she believes, has sparked a hysterical
backlash against sexual harassment laws.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOWistas</ENAMEX>. Mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s groups
wouldn't go as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacKinnonites</ENAMEX> and prohibit all sexual contact between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX>. But with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Packwood</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>) controversies, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> took the stance that female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX> always deserve the presumption of veracity in sexual harassment cases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>, they claimed, "don't make these things up." And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> have an
obligation to counter the prevailing tendency to dismiss <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX> as "nutty and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slutty</ENAMEX>." But, when it came to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>, only a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>--e.g.,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>--consistently supported her case with
similar arguments. Initially, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>--notably the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization for Women</ENAMEX>--maintained a calculated silence. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only after months</TIMEX> of
the press chiding them for their "double standard" did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> begin to
invoke the presumption on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>.

            Now that
it appears the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case will do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> no harm, feminist groups have become
more vocal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Ireland</ENAMEX> worries publicly that the dismissal
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case will deter other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> from bringing sexual harassment
claims. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' case illustrates how difficult it is for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to get her day
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> and others also worry about a possible tumble down a slippery
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slope</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> making passes at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> now that they have seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> get away
with it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 Strict Constructionists</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law</ENAMEX>
School <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicki Schultz</ENAMEX>, argues that harassment law unhealthily obsesses
over sex in the workplace. Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> argues, have used
sexual harassment law as a pretext for preserving "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s virtue." And in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">precedent-setting</ENAMEX> decisions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> imply that there is no such thing as
harassment if there is no sex involved. This, she argues, has led these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>
to discount the types of employment discrimination--unfair promotion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>,
workplace taunts, etc.--the law was originally intended to check. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> tend
to like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> position because it allows them to continue to defend the
idea of sexual harassment law while attacking cases like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>', which
focuses on an alleged sexual act but makes no convincing showing of damage to
her career.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Passers</ENAMEX>. In her now-notorious op-ed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Steinem</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should not be penalized for his "boorish"
come-ons. Sexual harassment, she claims, was born out of the feminist
proposition that with sexual advances, "no means no; yes means yes." And when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> said "no," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> backed off. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX> and others in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Backlash author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>, argue there is no inconsistency
between their support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and condemnations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Packwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>:
Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, they argue, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Packwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> interpreted "no" as "yes" and
repeated their unwelcome advances (although most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Packwood</ENAMEX>'s alleged passes
were single tries). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX>'s distinction is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of a longstanding legal
debate over whether a one-time unwelcome advance is enough to create a hostile
working environment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> divide on whether a one-time deed is
sufficient, but many feminist legal thinkers take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX>'s side.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian Hedonists</ENAMEX>. The lib-hed
position goes a step beyond the strict constructionist position. Articulated by
self-proclaimed iconoclasts such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camille Paglia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Roiphe</ENAMEX>, it argues
that we've become paranoid about sexual harassment, criminalizing consensual
office sex and flirtation. Lib-heds note the proliferation of sexual harassment
cases referred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>
testified before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>--from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 8,000</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 15,000</NUMEX> per year. While
the critique echoes conservative complaints about multiculturalism (harassment
law makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> helpless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>), it also incorporates a libertarian strain
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should not pry into consensual sexual relations) and an Epicurean
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (we shouldn't penalize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with active libidos; so long as nobody gets
hurt--or helped--who cares?).

             

             

            
               If you
missed the link to the refresher on harassment law and its history, click
.
            

         
      
   
