
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Screws Around</ENAMEX>

            Asking
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would have sex with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> he is alleged to have
had sex with is like asking why a hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> would want to eat. How many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would refuse oral service from attractive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21-year-olds</TIMEX> if they
could get away with it? Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s circumstances are a little different:
Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indiscretion</ENAMEX> puts his presidency at stake. Here's a roundup of the top
theories on why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would sleep around.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> He's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmucko</ENAMEX>." According to this theory, the affair
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exposes Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legendary capacity for empathy as a front for his fundamental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rottenness</ENAMEX>. "He has a bad habit of using <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and discarding them" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria</ENAMEX>
Borger, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> ). Meanwhile, right-wing conspiracy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theorists</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrose Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>, gloat that they
have sounded the alarm about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wickedness</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> murder, etc.) from the start. (See 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>'s latest.)

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> He's psycho. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX> speculated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> suffers from an "anti-social personality
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disorder</ENAMEX>," before concluding that "in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s case a strict diagnosis
does not hold." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has no compunction about his multiple sexual relations
or the lies he tells about them. Like a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>, he's so self-obsessed
that he's lost his sense of shame and can't comprehend his culture's mores.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> He's stupid. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disappointed Clinton</ENAMEX> supporters
embrace this argument. His rampant infidelity is caused by his idiocy. "Anyone
who is that dumb should obviously not be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Baker</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> He's a misogynist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, advances this view, as do several right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as
sex objects, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has no qualms about coercing and bribing them into
servicing him. Thus, goes this theory, he sexually harasses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who work for
him (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>), trades jobs for sex (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>),
and has affairs with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> doesn't classify sex addiction as a medical condition, but that
doesn't prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> from making the diagnosis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Alter</ENAMEX> blames <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged sexcapades on the rush that some
addictive personalities experience from the release of the neurotransmitter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dopamine</ENAMEX> during sex. The New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> boasted of bedding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> over the course
of his marriage. If this is true, he's either a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Juan</ENAMEX> or a sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maniac</ENAMEX>. It
would also explain why he (allegedly) falls back on phone sex when he can't
have the real thing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> tends toward addictive behavior.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia Kelley</ENAMEX> loved gambling, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX> got hooked on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandmother Edith</ENAMEX> had a morphine problem. Corollary theory: The risks of
getting caught with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> added to the thrill and kept him coming back for
more. Alter says that he may even "get off on" the "brush[<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">es</ENAMEX>] with political
death" that his adultery precipitates.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> He's self-deluded. Or, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> put it,
he's "in denial." Some say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> learned to compartmentalize misdeeds in his
Hot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>, childhood. Many of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> were devout Baptists
despite running the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort town</ENAMEX>'s illegal gambling industry--the largest in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> also admitted to habitually blocking out problems by denying
their existence.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> He learned it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>. According to biographer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Maraniss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> picked up his promiscuous ways early from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Springs</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, who "got away with whatever they wanted to." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also picked up lax
attitudes about sex from his mother, who dressed provocatively in short shorts
and tube tops, and his biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, allegedly a bigamist.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> He needs love. Another wounded-child theory. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
craves the affection that his abusive, alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stepfather</ENAMEX> and abused,
fun-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> didn't provide him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. This explains his love of
campaigning and his wishy-washy, please-everyone political agenda, as well as
his many girlfriends. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oedipal</ENAMEX> permutation of this theory blames his affairs
specifically on an early deficit of motherly attention and notes that many of
his alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> bear a resemblance to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> in a suit. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blame Clinton</ENAMEX>'s philandering on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-</ENAMEX>love attitudes he adopted as an
anti-war radical and never jettisoned.

            
               10 He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy-man</ENAMEX>. He remains the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in the candy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">store</ENAMEX>, without control over his appetites for sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morrow</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> constantly pushes the envelope to see what he can get away
with, like a 2-year-old who "tests the limits of his independence by toddling
off."

            
               11 This is a midlife crisis. Instead of buying a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motorcycle</ENAMEX> or taking up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">bungee</NUMEX>-jumping, the graying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> paired off with a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21-year-old</TIMEX> to affirm his youth and virility.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' is a marriage of convenience. There are
several versions of this: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> knows her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a sexaholic but
overlooks his infidelity to advance her own political career. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prude</ENAMEX>, forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to satisfy his sexual needs elsewhere. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> angle: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> may not be "into regular sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>," forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
to sate his sexual appetite elsewhere.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> are egomaniacs. The best estimates are
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> cheated on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> are surrounded
by servile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sycophants</ENAMEX> who convince them they are invincible and forgive their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sins</ENAMEX>, and this paves the way for sexual affairs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> of presidential quality
tend to be arrogant, with a sense of "entitlement and lordly expectation"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). The best example of presidential
bravura ever: When told of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s womanizing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>
responded, "God damn it, I had more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> by accident than he ever had by
design!"

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> are alpha male studs. Evolutionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> explain presidential philandering as an atavistic impulse left
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the early days</TIMEX> of the human race. Natural selection rewarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who
clawed their way to positions of power with many sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> (i.e., gave them
many chances to reproduce their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Proponents</ENAMEX> of this theory recall
ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pharaoh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramses II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aztec</ENAMEX> King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nezahualpilli</ENAMEX>, both
of whom sired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s explication.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">15 Power</ENAMEX> is the ultimate aphrodisiac. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> throw
themselves at powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are too weak to resist. The
star-struck <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> appears to have instigated a relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
According to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, she had long fantasized about sleeping with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">16 Miserable</ENAMEX> childhoods bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> together. This is
the most pleasant spin on the whole affair, which ascribes no deviant
intentions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. They were simply two <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely souls</ENAMEX> who
bonded over their shared experience of abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. This theory initially
emanated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            17 We're his enablers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s capacity for
forgiveness only encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s rogue ways. We don't make him pay the
price for his dalliances, thereby convincing him that the risk is worth it.

         
      
   
