
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> Connection

            The latest twist in the
campaign finance furor is the allegation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> funneled
money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s re-election campaign in an effort to influence
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy. What is the evidence linking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>?
Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> know about such an initiative and was he or his staff
influenced by it?

            No one
(except for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>) disputes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government
planned on contributing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
congressional campaigns. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX>
eavesdropped on multiple conversations between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>, describing its intention to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> on the
upcoming election. Campaign contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>, let alone foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, are forbidden by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> election law.

            According to most analyses, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> worried that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
would follow through on his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> campaign promise to revoke <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s Most
Favored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> (MFN) trading status to punish human-rights abuses. In
addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has grown increasingly concerned over the disparity between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> 's sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> lobbying and public-relations
operation and its own piecemeal setup.

            So far,
there is no hard evidence of whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> followed through on
any of its plans to influence <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has been unable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trace</ENAMEX> back any donations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. But there has been
speculation about different channels the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could have used to
funnel contributions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> stories have focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Trie</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kanchanalak</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> who raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $3 million</NUMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>. Ultimately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> returned the money
because of suspicion that it included laundered foreign cash .

            
Here are the grounds for suspicion:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> : The
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy assistant secretary</ENAMEX> of commerce and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> vice chair is said to be
connected to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> through his long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo Group</ENAMEX> , an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo</ENAMEX> to work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, he
received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$788,750</NUMEX> severance package and continued his relationship with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> logs show that he made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> phone calls from
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government office</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> in donations for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> with ties
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> has multiple investments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> Lippo
even became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> when it sold <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of its holdings in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honk Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. During his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-month</TIMEX> stint
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> met with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> separate occasions.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kanchanalak</ENAMEX> :
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Council</ENAMEX> represents <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">industrialist Dhanin Chearavanont</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> are among the largest
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kanchanalak</ENAMEX> personally donated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> originated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chearavanont</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government partners</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Yah Lin Trie</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> restaurateur raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$639,000</NUMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> legal-defense fund. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trie</ENAMEX>'s links to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clearest</ENAMEX>. On his resume he even boasts about his friendship with senior
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. His major business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is a government
official in the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guangzhou</ENAMEX>. Also, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trie</ENAMEX> arranged for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang Jun</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a state-run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>, to
attend a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> organized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>.

            Though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> were viable conduits for laundered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
government money, there is nothing more than highly circumstantial evidence to
suggest they actually participated in a government scheme. But they also could
have raised such large sums by laundering money from their foreign business
contacts. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> all have dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> that give them an
independent incentive to influence <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. (This second
scenario would also be illegal.)

            The Lippo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> also paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, while he was waiting to begin a jail term for bilking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> of his former law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> is a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. At
the least, he was hired in an attempt to influence administration <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy.
That would not be unusual. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> suggest a darker scenario: that the
Lippo fee was a payoff to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> to keep quiet about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>.

            
There are assertions that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> donations to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> swayed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> vote to renew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFN</ENAMEX>. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reported that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, while at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> consulted with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Berman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, an influential <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Relations Committee</ENAMEX>. Their conversations took place at precisely
the moment the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> reconsidered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> MFN. Lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> was not part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>'s job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> had contributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> campaign.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> who received
contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> spoke with him during this same period. But again,
there's no evidence linking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>'s involvement to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government
intended to illegally contribute money to their campaigns. (The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sens.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dianne Feinstein of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Pelosi</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, plus <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
others not yet identified.) Apparently, none of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> received
donations they could link to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feinstein</ENAMEX> did
return a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,000</NUMEX> check brought in by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>. All known targets, except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pelosi</ENAMEX>,
did vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFN</ENAMEX> and had been strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> all along.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> claims to have known nothing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
plans. In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> says that when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> briefed National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> on the subject, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>
specifically not to pass information to higher-ups. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> denies this.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> probably
misconstrued the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>' instructions to treat the matter delicately.

            Though nobody contests the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s assertion that he was kept in the dark, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> speculate that the
atmosphere at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> might have discouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> from
informing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>. Previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> warnings about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> and other
Asian-American <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> had been ignored, and fund raising was known to be a high
priority.

         
      
   
