
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> Act

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidency</ENAMEX> cannot be
separated from politics, but the political uses of the presidency by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> strike many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as abusive. There are calls for a
special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. What behavior would he or she prosecute? What exactly is
the law about politicking and the presidency?

            The law
most often cited is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hatch Act</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>). The law passed following
several big corruption cases involving the burgeoning post-New Deal
bureaucracy, and was aimed at the civil service. But by its terms, it applies
to almost anyone on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> payroll. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> confirmation (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretaries</ENAMEX>) are exempt. The original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hatch Act</ENAMEX> forbade government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to
raise funds, give partisan public speeches, or volunteer for any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> or
party. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s backing, the act was amended to allow
all these things, so long as they are done outside the workplace and government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> don't exploit their positions for political purposes.

            Enforcement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hatch Act</ENAMEX> was always erratic, and there
was no serious attempt to apply its general ban on politicking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> amendment specifically allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Office</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to engage in "political activity." The law defines political
activity to include anything campaign-related --organizing events,
planning party strategy-- except fund raising , which it completely
prohibits. These same limits apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> and all other
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s campaign or
party must reimburse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the use of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> imposed additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>-like regulations on itself.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> can work on their "political" projects only if they put
in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 hours</TIMEX>' work over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> on "official" business. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> installed separate phone and fax lines for political work. But
these rules are not legally binding. And in practice, such distinctions between
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>" and "political" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> work are almost meaningless.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Herman</ENAMEX> , who was in charge of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> "public liaison," is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
now under investigation for violation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hatch Act</ENAMEX>. Her nomination to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of labor is in trouble. The allegation: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman</ENAMEX> headed a working group
that planned strategies for hyping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to different ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
She did wrong, the argument goes, by using government computers to draw up
campaign strategy.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman</ENAMEX>'s work complied with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign reimbursed the
government for the work <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman</ENAMEX> did on the memos she wrote. Besides, the
activity under investigation is simply part of the job description of public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liaison</ENAMEX>, which is supposed to "outreach" with "different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX>" to
improve their relationships with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Clintonites</ENAMEX> say the public
liaisons under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did much the same things. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liaison Bobbie Kilberg</ENAMEX> spent much of her time wooing the religious right.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> point out that, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Baker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Teeter</ENAMEX>) resigned from the
administration to work on re-election campaigns. But these resignations were
legally required under the rules of the pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'93</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> Act, which no longer
apply.

            Other possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> Act violations: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
reports that Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> solicited campaign
contributions, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>'s prohibition on fund raising. And a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
database may have been used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> without
reimbursement to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as required.

            Legal questions are also
raised by allegations that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> granted access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
to elicit donations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Mayer</ENAMEX> uncovered examples of
big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> being invited to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> who say they
attracted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> with promises of invitations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coffees</ENAMEX> and overnights in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> .

            These
sorts of perks are potentially illegal for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons. First, election laws
bar the solicitation of money (by both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and nonemployees) in all
federal office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> --the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> included. In these cases,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> argue, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> invitations to entice them to
give more money. Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> were never explicitly asked to open
their checkbooks on these visits, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s intention was obvious.
The language of these laws, however, only forbids explicit appeals for
donations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickes</ENAMEX> apparently made calls to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government office</ENAMEX>,
but there is no evidence so far that anyone else solicited funds in a federal
building.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, campaign-finance and anti-bribery laws
prohibit granting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> favors in exchange for political donations. The
law specifically forbids favoritism in awarding government jobs and contracts.
More ambiguously, it proscribes "special access" to government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hatch Act</ENAMEX>, however, these laws have never been enforced
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            Preferential treatment for
big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> is nothing new. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">249 $100,000</NUMEX>-plus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> received ambassadorships from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
administration. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team 100</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> also received special policy briefings
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and invitations to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> dinners. Many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> had matters pending before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s response
to charges of selling "special access"--that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> are also his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
and he has the right to have conversations with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and invite them to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>--is disingenuous, but might be hard to refute in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
