
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sylvia Plath</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, the 30-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">poet Sylvia Plath</ENAMEX> killed herself, placing her head on a folded cloth inside an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oven</ENAMEX> and turning on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>. Posthumously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plath</ENAMEX> became a feminist icon. A slew
of memoirs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographies</ENAMEX> argued that the arrogance of her macho <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX>, precipitated her suicide. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> maintained a calculated silence about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s death. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>,
he finally published his side of their story in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birthday Letters</ENAMEX> --an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">autobiographical</ENAMEX> collection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX> poems, written over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
predicted the book would exculpate him and silence his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. But the debate
remains as shrill as ever. What is the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>? How have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> exploited <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birthday Letters</ENAMEX> ?

            First, the background: After
an acclaimed start as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> and while an undergraduate at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith College</ENAMEX>, Plath
attempted suicide. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 20</TIMEX>, she took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> sleeping pills during a stint
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guest-editing Mademoiselle</ENAMEX> . She was hospitalized, recovered, and went on
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fulbright Scholarship</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>. There, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, she met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>, also
a "promising" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four months</TIMEX> after their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> encounter, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plath</ENAMEX> bit
a chunk out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' cheek, they married. Each pursued careers as poets, and
she bore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1962</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> moved out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to
pursue an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assia Gutmann Wevill</ENAMEX>, a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four months later</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX> killed herself.

            Here are
the major points of contention:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Did he kill her? Only college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and the most
radical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> explicitly accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> of murder. But a set of memoirs
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> appeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX> arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' infidelity
and cruelty drove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plath</ENAMEX> to suicide. This has become the standard . From the
start of their marriage, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> mistreated her. He left her at home to care for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and type his work while he schmoozed at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.
Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plath</ENAMEX> was especially sensitive--the quality they say made her poetry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' gallivanting belittled and destroyed her. Another version of
this argument accuses him of a crime of omission: While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX> suffered from
mental sickness and cried out for help, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> cruelly left her to fend for
herself.

            Aside from anecdotal accounts
of abuse, these arguments rely on testimony from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plath</ENAMEX> herself--in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>
and poems. She calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> her "jailer" and compares him to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man in</ENAMEX>
black with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Meinkampf</ENAMEX> look/ And a love of the rack and the screw." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> also
has a bad track record: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wevill</ENAMEX> killed herself and her 2-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, by sticking their heads in a gas oven.

            Despite
Birthday Letters ' seeming tenderness toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plath</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> argue that
the poems unwittingly show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' true stripes. Some, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Showalter</ENAMEX>, say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> tries to exonerate himself by
arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plath</ENAMEX> was fated to kill herself. And he denies his power to save
her: "I was a fly outside on the window pane/ Of my own domestic drama."
Others, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s psychoanalytic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacqueline Rose</ENAMEX>, argue that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> continues to write condescendingly about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX> by figuring himself her
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, they say, doesn't understand his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resentments</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Was she nuts? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>, especially his
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poets</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fenton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake Morrison</ENAMEX>,
contend that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s craziness caused her death. They cite her unsuccessful
suicide attempt and chalk her problems up to obsession with her dead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>--this is also Birthday Letters ' position. "Though your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>/
Was your God and there was no other ..." (The day her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> died, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plath</ENAMEX> made
her mother sign a contract vowing never to remarry.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, the argument goes,
deserves credit for sticking with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX> for as long as he did. And Birthday
Letters , they argue, once and for all proves "beyond all doubt that he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loved Plath</ENAMEX> with all his heart" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glover</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> ).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> Did he cover up? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Feminists</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' tormenting of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX> continued after her death. They accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> of abusing his authority as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executor</ENAMEX> to obfuscate his misdeeds. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> admits to
destroying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX> wrote during the last, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most tumultuous year</TIMEX> of
their marriage and "misplacing" other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. He also edited her poetry to
exclude sections that supposedly document his abuse. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' sister
Olwyn, the literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s estate, refused to cooperate with
biographers critical of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>--that means all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX> except <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Stevenson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bitter Fame</ENAMEX> )--forbidding them to quote at length from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath's</ENAMEX> works. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Damning</ENAMEX> story: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> only authorized the publication of
The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Jar</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>--it had been published pseudonymously
before--to fund his purchase of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country home</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> responds that he didn't
want the publication of materials that would prejudice his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
impression of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> Were they both to blame? 
               Birthday Letters has
produced a revisionist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>--ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Plath</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hagiographers</ENAMEX> who
now feel they were too hard on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed page,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Wood Middlebrook</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Sexton</ENAMEX>, applauds
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> for accepting at least partial responsibility for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s death--"the
role of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fatal Husband</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Alvarez</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>
whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> memoir, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Savage God</ENAMEX> , provides the basis for most of the
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> attacks, praises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' honesty. The revisionist line comes in two
parts: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) As in most bad marriages, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> were at fault. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX>--her illness and irrational anger--that made her poems
powerful.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Who is the better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>? Because
several poems in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birthday Letters</ENAMEX> are explicit rewrites of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s
poems, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have decided to take up this question. Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' "lax and digressive" verses "serve mostly to remind us of
what a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> she was" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> use the occasion to restate their case against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">greatness: Her poetry</ENAMEX> was humorless and hyperbolic and would not be
remembered had she not committed suicide. Any good poems she did write were
derivative of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' style.

            Critics also divide along
national lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, with such exceptions as 
                  Slate
               's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Benfey</ENAMEX>, say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' poems are not very perceptive and not at
all introspective. They especially take him to task for blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s suicide
on fate and astrology. Britons, however, trumpet their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX> as worthy
of the ranks of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keats, Hardy and Auden</ENAMEX>" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>).
They like that Birthday Letters combines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' trademark
violence--dying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, stormy moors--with his compassion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">introspection</ENAMEX>. Others take more pot shots at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fenton</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> says, " 'Plath <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>' will never forgive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> for having been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plath</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>--a role which in their fantasies they
would much better fill."

         
      
   
