
   
   
      
         
            Campaign Fund <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Raising: Who's Worse</ENAMEX>?

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
Foer

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been making
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hay</ENAMEX> over revelations about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund raising. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> asserts
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have no right to talk. "They raise more money. They raise
more foreign money. They raise more money in big contributions. And we take all
the heat. It's a free ride." Does he have a case?

            The national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party (the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Campaign Committee</ENAMEX>) does out-raise
its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. In every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> campaign cycle since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have brought in more total money . During the last cycle
(through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 25, 1996</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> pulled in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$548.7 million</NUMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$332.3 million</NUMEX>.

            Campaign-finance laws break
these contributions into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Hard money :
donations that can be spent directly on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election</ENAMEX>
Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1974</ENAMEX>, there are strict limits on how much hard money
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and political-action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> can give. Corporate and union
hard-money gifts are banned. Here, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have their biggest
advantage. Last campaign, they out-raised the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$407.5 million to $210</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Soft money : The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> can accept unlimited contributions to pay for activities ambiguously
called "party <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> legislation that authorized soft money, party
building referred literally to the cost of building and maintaining a party
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, as well as general promotional activities for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. But
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> decisions and creative interpretations by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> themselves
have led to a much broader definition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parties</ENAMEX> now spend the soft money on
funding TV ads, voter-registration drives, and get-out-the-vote campaigns. Few
distinctions remain between the application of hard and soft money. The soft
money can't be transferred directly into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' coffers, and the ads can't
explicitly promote or denigrate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, which in practice just means no
use of the words "vote for" or "vote against." In the last campaign, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$122.4 million</NUMEX> in soft dollars and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$141.2 million</NUMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' edge in soft money reflects their greater success in raising
big contributions . Soft money is donated primarily by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, and
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PACs</ENAMEX> already maxed out on hard money. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> soft-money contributions
over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 75</NUMEX>.

            However, good-government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Cause</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Public Integrity</ENAMEX>, emphasize that these figures , based on
reports filed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX>, are deceptive . They
exclude donations to state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> that are transferred to both federal and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonfederal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. These donations can be substantial. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported that the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fund-raiser John Huang</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$482,000</NUMEX> through various state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>; and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Republican Party</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
Money . <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> argue that if you count the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>'s spending on behalf
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' fund-raising total surpasses its own.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unions</ENAMEX> gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.7 million</NUMEX> in soft money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $800,000</NUMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. But that is reflected in the soft-money totals. What isn't
reflected is so-called "independent expenditures" on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. Under a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> forbids any
legal limits on such spending, as long as it is truly independent of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.

            
Independent expenditures are not reported to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> say that organized labor spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million to $500</NUMEX>
million promoting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. They cite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> officials
who claim the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX> on a radio-and-television ad
campaign alone. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> sponsored voter guides and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">get-out-the-vote</ENAMEX> campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> deny spending anything close to
the figures that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> estimate.

            Similar independent
expenditures benefited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Chamber of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX> on advertising in support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> on voter guides promoting conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX> put up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">another $1.5 million</NUMEX> that
mostly helped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            

               Foreign money travels <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> routes into party coffers: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) direct
contributions by foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, which are flatly
illegal; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) soft-money contributions by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX> of foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> announced that it would no longer accept
either type of foreign money. However, there are currently no federal laws
prohibiting the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> category.

            But what does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> mean when he says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
"raise more foreign money"? If the statement refers to illegal foreign money,
then his claim lacks evidence. In the last campaign cycle, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> returned
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> in contributions because they may have come illegally from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have only returned a single check for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX>.

            As for legal donations by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> lead in this category, as in all corporate
receipts. But the data are incomplete. A study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Cause</ENAMEX> of contributions
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18</TIMEX> showed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 million</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX> of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> took in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$532,000</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' new prohibition on such contributions is a definitional nightmare.
Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>, now owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Telecommunications</ENAMEX>, forbidden to give? Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, which has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, allowed?

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> argue that even though they receive more big contributions, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are more egregious about special favors for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has offered big givers tennis matches with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> with a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has admitted that this
one was wrong) and, most notoriously, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> stays in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bedroom</ENAMEX> .

            
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> also "sold" social
engagements with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> when they controlled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and have
made a variety of explicit and implicit promises of access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX>.
For instance, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC</ENAMEX> enticed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> by offering them
rides on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force One</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baseball Hall of Famers Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiMaggio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Williams</ENAMEX>. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> recently reported on
a fund-raising letter sent out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX>, guaranteeing
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000-</NUMEX>level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or the other may
have a niche where it excels or is especially trouble-prone, but neither party
can claim clear moral superiority.

         
      
   
