
   
   
      
         
            Major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League Baseball</ENAMEX>

            Sportswriters perennially
complain that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League Baseball</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy owners</ENAMEX> are corrupting the game.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> gripe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are destroying it from within by demanding too
much money. Recent developments have escalated the doomsaying. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX>'s top
executive proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> that the century-old distinction between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> be erased, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in the
leagues realign. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar pitcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Maddux</ENAMEX>
accepted a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> contract worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$57.5 million</NUMEX>, the biggest ever. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> in
decline or, as some claim, in the midst of a golden era? How are the economics
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> changing? Are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> tuning out the televised game? How is the game
itself changing? And is the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> as good as those who played
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the halcyon days of the '30s</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'50s</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">'60s</ENAMEX>?

            Baseball
hasn't reigned as the "national pastime " for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. It was displaced
long ago by a combination of other leisure activities, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>, computer
games, and the more telegenic games of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball and football</ENAMEX>. Although
attendance was damaged by the strike<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-shortened seasons of 1994 and 1995</TIMEX>,
attendance is now approaching pre-strike levels . Overall attendance is
strong: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> attracted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24.3</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in the golden <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year of 1967</TIMEX>, when there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>.

            The perception of declining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> interest causes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tinker</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> traditions from time to time, mostly in the hopes
of attracting more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> was cleaved into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>,
creating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> ticket-selling pennant races instead of just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. Division
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> were pitted against one another in post-season play, with the victors
advancing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> added the
designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hitter</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> who bats in place of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> but does
not play in the field. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DH</ENAMEX> increased scoring, which pleases <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>,
each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> was further divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>, creating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> pennant
races, and post-season play was expanded to involve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> "wild
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> joined the pennant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> in the playoffs. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, MLB
instituted interleague play , scheduling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> against one another in regular-season contests for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time.
Of course, pandering to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> tradition. Examples: night
games, fireworks displays, giveaways, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>, mascots, etc.

            Soaring
attendance for interleague games prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Selig</ENAMEX>, to
propose the realignment of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX>. Under his plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> would be reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> would be grouped geographically, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> switching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Proponents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">realignment</ENAMEX> argue that it exploits natural regional rivalries and
decreases travel time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> complain that it upends tradition.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Owners</ENAMEX> will likely vote on the plan in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. One negative ballot will be
enough to veto it.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> hasn't promoted itself as successfully as
pro <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and pro basketball (it collects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> as much from the sale
of hats, shirts, and other paraphernalia as does either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>), but
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> has aggressively expanded into new markets. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. With the addition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Diamondbacks</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa Bay</ENAMEX> Devil
Rays <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">count</ENAMEX> will reach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>. The game has also gone global, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> aggressively recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> from reliable talent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> south of the
border ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Alomar</ENAMEX> ) and, more recently, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> ( Hideo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nomo</ENAMEX> ).

            Baseball
has always been about money, but even more so since the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1975</ENAMEX> repeal of the
"reserve clause ." The reserve clause bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> (or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> they were traded to) for life. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> can shop their talents to
the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> after their contract expires. Salaries have
escalated since the repeal of the reserve clause. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, the average
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, he earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$512,000</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the average player
salary is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.37 million</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> blame their red ink (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated</NUMEX> total
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$185 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>) on big payrolls . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX>'s wealthiest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, the
world-champion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Yankees</ENAMEX>, spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$66 million</NUMEX> on payroll in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montreal Expos</ENAMEX> spent the least, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 million</NUMEX>. But high-priced free agent
salaries don't necessarily correlate to competitiveness. Drawing on their
excellent minor-league <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX> for cheap new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expos</ENAMEX> finished
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League East</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.

            Even so,
big-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> stay in contention by
purchasing free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> MLB assuaged complaints about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX>/poor gap with a moderate revenue-sharing scheme. Wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> pay a "tax" on every payroll dollar above <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$51 million</NUMEX>. The tax is
distributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> who spend less, usually <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in smaller markets like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $6 million</NUMEX> in
revenue sharing.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> decreased the disparities
between large- and small-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> with salary caps that limit player
salaries. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> has no salary cap, and attempts to impose one sparked the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994-1995</TIMEX> strike by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players union</ENAMEX>, resulting in the first cancellation
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 years</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> retreated from the
salary-cap issue, eventually signing a contract that expires in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            Like its
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, baseball depends heavily on television money . But MLB
complains that it's not getting enough. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>'s current <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> contract
for national TV broadcasts pays it <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2.5 billion</NUMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX>'s contract
over a similar period earns <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1 billion</NUMEX>. But the comparison isn't relevant
because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> also sell nonnational games to local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> and cable
channels, pocketing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> more. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$486-million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> deal.) Once again, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> playing in small markets that suffer,
because they can't command an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> big enough to attract big TV
contracts.

            Because <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> is an entertainment industry, media
conglomerates have purchased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, potentially complicating future TV-rights
negotiations. Time-Warner obtained the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> when it bought
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner Broadcasting Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney Co.</ENAMEX> holds an interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anaheim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune Corp.</ENAMEX> owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Cubs</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>
( of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox TV</ENAMEX> ) recently bid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated $350 million</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Dodgers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>. Because it is in the interest of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> moguls to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as little</NUMEX> as possible for broadcast rights, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
worry that small-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> will get the shaft when the media-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul owners</ENAMEX>
use their inside-the-clubhouse influence to drive down the size of national-TV
contracts.

            Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> complain about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> losses, there is no shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX> willing to
pay record sums for existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> or new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason for the high
value of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> is the prospect of new, publicly financed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballparks</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Owners</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> have all reaped
major profits from these new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, built at little or no cost to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. (New <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> are scheduled for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>.) The most
lucrative amenity at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> are the sky boxes, luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX> rented to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> at exorbitant prices. Also filling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> coffers are fancy food
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and merchandise concession areas. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> have also boosted ticket
prices at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, charging <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 35 percent</NUMEX> more than they did at the
old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>.

            
While it's true that expansion temporarily
diluted the talent pool, the DH artificially increased offense, and players
have gained the economic upper hand, there is a widespread consensus that the
quality of the game itself is as good as or better than ever .
Improvements in hitting have been matched by craftier pitching (by such hurlers
as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Maddux</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Mussina</ENAMEX>). The rise in the number
of home runs (a record of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,962</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>) has been paralleled by increased
strikeouts in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year of this decade</TIMEX>. The exorbitant salaries have inspired
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to train year-round, building strength and stamina with their
new regimens.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Baseball</ENAMEX> is certainly more
competitive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than it was in the dynasty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>. Many small-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>) and expansion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> have cobbled together <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> to do
battle with the dynastic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> from the big markets. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX>
have had consistent success in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>, making them the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Yankees</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-1964</TIMEX> to appear in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> consecutive
World <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> have gone from world champions to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX>-dwellers
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
