
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Education Standards</ENAMEX>

            Public education is
traditionally a state and local responsibility in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Yet many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel that poor public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are a national problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
proposed national standards for primary and secondary education, and so has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Yet many ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of national standards under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>,
such as former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humanities Endowment</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Cheney</ENAMEX>, are leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. What
changed?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last January</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX> to prepare exams to test fourth-grade
reading and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX>-grade math. These are the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> nationwide tests
designed to compare student performance across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and school districts.
Participation by school districts is voluntary. A bipartisan, independent
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> will supervise the drafting and administration of the tests. By
making reliable comparisons possible, the new national tests are supposed to
create healthy competition among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, giving them an incentive to
improve.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has approved the spending of federal money for this purpose, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> to prohibit it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says he will veto
the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education Department</ENAMEX> appropriation if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House-Senate</ENAMEX> conference
committee sustains the ban.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> oppose the bill . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Ravitch</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester Finn</ENAMEX>,
supports the idea of testing but opposes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s version. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
consider testing a necessary precondition for school vouchers--a favorite
conservative remedy that would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to choose among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Without
reliable testing, they believe, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> cannot be good "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>."

            But this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has politicized the test, caving in to left-wing pressure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> . Although the test is being drafted by independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> such
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Testing Service</ENAMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> see the hand of liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>. Early versions, they say, reward
left-wing pedagogical approaches like "new math," which, they say, wrongly
de-emphasize old-fashioned computation. They complain that the fourth-grade
math test can be taken in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
administration's plan was more comprehensive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> proposed to test <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Designers</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> plan limited testing to reading and math, avoiding sensitive
subjects like history in the hope of avoiding arguments over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">politicization</TIMEX>.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> proposal, which was never prepared as legislation, would also have
created a bipartisan, independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to draft the tests. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
recently modified his proposal to give control to an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, he
allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX> to participate in the early stages
of test preparation. When so charged, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> retort that the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> will have ample opportunity to amend the tests if they are
too easy or ideologically skewed.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asecond</ENAMEX> camp of conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and the religious right, dislikes any
version of national testing . This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> believes that the standards are a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> to establish a national curriculum and usurp local control of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. At the very least, they say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are forced to tailor curricula to
the test. They believe that all attempts at establishing national curricula
will be riddled with ideology and partisan politics, and cite the controversial
history-curricula guidelines drafted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
category of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> comprises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Caucus</ENAMEX>, who argue that low test scores stigmatize
minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> as "inferior," when in fact poor schooling and other
disadvantages are to blame for their performance. The test scores, they say,
will be used as an excuse to pour resources into a few select <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, harming
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> left behind.

            However, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> who opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> testing plan
have thrown their support behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s initiative. For instance, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>--long opposed testing, fearing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> performed
poorly would lose their jobs. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> has now given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan at least
nominal support.

            Only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and
15 big-city school districts have agreed to give the test. The reason
for their reluctance: A national test could be embarrassing and disprove claims
of improvement based on other, less-than-neutral testing regimes. For instance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> like to brag that their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s average <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>
score is the highest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. However, most college-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> take a different college entrance exam, making the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> an unreliable
measure of school quality.

         
      
   
