
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fast Track</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is now debating
whether to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "fast track" authority to negotiate trade
agreements with foreign countries. Most of the opposition comes from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, though some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are also opposed (and others
from both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of not pushing hard enough for it). What is
fast track and why is it so contentious?

            After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> signs a trade agreement with a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--reducing or
eliminating barriers to free trade such as tariffs, import quotas, and
subsidies for domestic products--the agreement must be approved by a majority
of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Fast track is a congressional procedure limiting
debate over these agreements. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> invokes fast track,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> must vote yes or no within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX>, and no amendments are allowed.

            Fast track is intended to thwart filibusters and to prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> from adding special protections for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> in their
districts. The rationale for fast track is that trade agreements are
different from ordinary legislation : They are negotiated with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> makes changes, the whole agreement must be renegotiated.
Furthermore, negotiations involve swapping concessions with the other side.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> will not make the necessary concessions in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place if
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concessions</ENAMEX> can be undone.

            No other
country gives its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> a power similar to fast track. But few other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have a legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> so independent of the executive branch.
Fast track exists only for trade --not for arms-control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treaties</ENAMEX> or other
multilateral agreements. These other agreements, like the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Weapons Convention</ENAMEX>, are often subjected to prolonged debate and can be altered
drastically by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Formal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treaties</ENAMEX> can only be approved by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX>
vote of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            
Before fast track's inception in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had even broader <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> . Regretting the notorious
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Smoot-Hawley Tariff of 1930</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> granted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> the power
to reduce tariffs and implement multilateral trade agreements without its
approval. Up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1960s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> negotiated many bilateral tariff
reductions, attracting little attention. However, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> revoked
a series of popular export subsidies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> resumed its complaints about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s powers. Anticipating further conflicts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> inserted fast track into a relatively obscure section of
an uncontroversial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> trade bill.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> repeatedly voted to renew fast track, and by large margins.
But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, fearing a contentious debate about fast-track renewal so soon
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NAFTA</ENAMEX> battle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> allowed fast track to expire .
Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is keen on negotiating a free-trade agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, he has requested that fast track be granted for
the duration of his term.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> have only invoked fast track on a handful of
occasions, and each time the agreement it covered was approved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>
used fast track to get congressional approval of tariff-reduction agreements
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979 and 1994</TIMEX> it was used for major multilateral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> agreements. And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> it was used to pass <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">NAFTA</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX>
say that with fast track, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is abandoning its responsibilities under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX> and giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> too much power . They also say that
the process of hashing out agreements tends to be secretive --without
public hearings or any opportunity for public input. But despite fast track,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> usually plays a major role in shaping trade agreements. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> is the
classic example. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> refused to support the agreement until
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> negotiated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> side agreements to make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> adhere to stricter
labor and environmental standards. According to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> legislation, if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> doesn't keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> up to speed on negotiations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can
revoke fast track. Other provisions in the original legislation give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
an opportunity to suspend fast track.

            
The current fast-track debate will be
contentious. Labor and environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have announced that they
will use the occasion as a referendum on all free-trade accords. Attempts at
compromise--amendments guaranteeing that future agreements will include
provisions protecting the environment and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' rights--have failed to
placate these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this month</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX> voted in favor of the legislation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, says that he might delay introducing
the bill before the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, rather than risk defeat.

         
      
   
