
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Campaign Finance</ENAMEX>

            Campaign finance has been
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the biggest stories of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. During the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have questioned foreign contributions to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> have spent record sums <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. According to one
campaign-finance watchdog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> presidential contest will cost
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 million</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly three</NUMEX> times as much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1992</ENAMEX> race. What are the rules
of campaign finance? What rules, if any, have the campaigns broken?

            Under the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election</ENAMEX> Campaign Act, foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> cannot make
contributions or expenditures in connection with any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> election--federal,
state, or local. Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> include foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The ban does not apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> who
are legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. A domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of a foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX> may make political contributions, but only if the foreign parent
plays no part.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> is embroiled in controversy
over contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> . Most of this money
was raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> , the now-suspended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice chairman</ENAMEX> of finance for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> was forced to return <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> raised
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> after it came out that the donation came from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>,
rather than its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> has kept a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450,000</NUMEX> contribution from
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soraya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arief Wiriadinata</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soraya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arief</ENAMEX> are
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashim Ning</ENAMEX>, co-founder of the Lippo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> , a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> says that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiriadinatas</ENAMEX>' contribution is valid because they were legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. (Since the donation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiriadinatas</ENAMEX> have returned to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>.) Many have questioned the propriety of the donation, suggesting that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has been unduly influenced by a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Riady, Lippo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mochtar Riady</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Riady</ENAMEX> when he came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX> to learn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> finance.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> once worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo</ENAMEX> and is one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Riady</ENAMEX>'s closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have also benefited from
foreign political contributions. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Riady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aileen</ENAMEX>, gave
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> also has received more than twice as
much money as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX> of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s primary election-finance committee was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonso</ENAMEX>
Fanjul, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>-born sugar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> who carries a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> passport but lives
legally in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flo-Sun Sugar</ENAMEX>, has given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$234,000</NUMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> this campaign, as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> in direct
donations to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            It is
against the law for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> to contribute money to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. However, they may sponsor political action
committees which raise money from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and
contribute the money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> may give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> per
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> to a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> in
the primary and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> in the general election)--up to a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. No one may donate in another's name, or give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $100</NUMEX> in
cash . The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> may have violated this last restriction. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> appeared at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, an event that netted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$140,000</NUMEX> for the
party. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> gave up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> of that money after a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> said someone
gave her <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> cash and asked her to write a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> check to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            Qualified presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and political parties
receive money from the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for primary- and
general-election expenses, and national-party conventions. For the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">general-election</ENAMEX> campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> will each receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$61.82</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> from the fund. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29 million</NUMEX>. In exchange, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cannot accept private contributions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> is permitted to seek
private funds up to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$61.82 million</NUMEX> limit. All presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> may
accept private donations during the primary season.

            If the two major-party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are restricted to spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$61.82 million</NUMEX> each, why the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 million</NUMEX>
price tag for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s election? The cost of primaries is one reason. But
there are also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major loopholes in the spending-limit rules.

            
               Soft money .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>--can contribute
unlimited amounts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> for activities such as get-out-the-vote
efforts that do not directly endorse specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. Without violating the
law, this money can be spent on highly partisan messages. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52 million</NUMEX> in soft money and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, just through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$83.9 million</NUMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70.3 million</NUMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> give
soft money to both parties.

            Under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Amendment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> can also spend unlimited amounts
on political advocacy , so long as a specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is not endorsed.
A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> footnote listed the "magic words" that separate issue
advocacy from campaign advocacy. They include: "vote for" and "vote against."
As long as your ads do not include the magic words, you can spend as much as
you want on them. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> plans to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX> attacking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With America</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Groups</ENAMEX> such as pro-term-limit organizations
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Action Network</ENAMEX> have also raised and spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> on "issue"
ads, as have the political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. It is often difficult to distinguish issue
ads from campaign ads.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has held that the First
Amendment also protects independent expenditures . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> can spend as much as they want on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s behalf as long as
they don't coordinate their spending with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PACs</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $11 million</NUMEX> on independent expenditures for
presidential and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last June</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
ruled that political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> (as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PACs</ENAMEX>, interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>) can make unlimited independent expenditures on behalf of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. This decision produced an explosion of spending by political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, although it is not yet clear what constitutes an "independent"
expenditure. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Cause</ENAMEX>, the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are spending
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of dollars as "independent expenditures" on ads that were designed and
produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign organizations</ENAMEX>.

            
               Who gives?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> and business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PACs</ENAMEX> gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$242.2 million</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and the first half of 1996</TIMEX>. Organized labor gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX>
during the same period (in addition to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX> spent by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> on
issue advocacy). The largest single contributor to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Trial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Association</ENAMEX>, which gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,747,725</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>, which gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,131,955</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
