
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood Stars</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ransom</ENAMEX>, a movie that opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX>, cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$61 million</NUMEX> to make.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly a third</NUMEX> of that, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX>, went to its star, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX>
worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>, earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $0.3 million</NUMEX> a day. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> on
the set of the next <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> has been paid
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$833,333</NUMEX> a day--plus, if the film succeeds, he will get another
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> or so from merchandising revenue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nobuyuki Idei</ENAMEX>, the new president
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>--whose major films <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> featured expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and either
flopped or broke even--has declared that his first priority for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is to
liberate it from the tyranny of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> . Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> get paid so much
money? Are they driving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> out of business?

            The
upward creep of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>' salaries, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>' complaints that
it was wrecking the movies, have both been going on since the film industry
began. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>, aspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Laemmle</ENAMEX> wooed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biograph</ENAMEX> (where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.W. Griffith</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>) with higher
wages and a promise to make her a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. Until then, there were no movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.
Feature films carried no acting credits, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> forbade movie magazines
to print cast lists. The reason was precisely the fear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and
actresses known to the public by name would exploit that recognition to demand
higher wages. They did, especially during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1910s and the 1920s</TIMEX>, when a
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Pickford</ENAMEX> could command the then-astronomical sum of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, plus an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> bonus of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$340,000</NUMEX>.

            During the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> era of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s and '40s</TIMEX>, talent
costs were kept artificially low by a code negotiated between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> at the depth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Recovery</ENAMEX>
Act. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> was later ruled unconstitutional, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood Code</ENAMEX>
survived). The code gave the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> minor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> draconian power
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. These included a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> exclusive right to their services, the
right to cancel their contracts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every six months</TIMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> had no such right
in return), the right to dock them for turning down a role in any movie of the
studio's choice, the right to predetermine salary increases, and so on.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>,
an antitrust suit brought by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>
to give up ownership of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>. Without a guaranteed outlet for their
product, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> no longer could afford to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> on permanent
retainer. At that point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> seized control of their own careers, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent agent</ENAMEX> became a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>' triumph
was not complete, however, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX>, after all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> had been bought by larger, mostly international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, and
colorless corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> replaced the larger-than-life moguls of the
studio era. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX> and a few other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were able to use their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' star power to demand a package deal--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> plus screenplay or some
other element of production--which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> was forced to accept, in toto.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creative Artists Agency</ENAMEX> became the single most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ovitz</ENAMEX> left agentry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to become No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Meyer</ENAMEX>, also has left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAA</ENAMEX>,
leading some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savants</ENAMEX> to declare the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> era over. Meanwhile,
though, the triumph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> and the package deal is, perhaps, the main
reason that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>' salaries are as high as they are. But it is also true that
the demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>' services is also at an all-time high. Even television
programming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX> is dominated by movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Danson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary</ENAMEX>
Steenburgen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Fox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Donnell</ENAMEX>). Several television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> recently that they would not produce any new shows unless
they could sign top film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> to them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> are benefiting from the larger economic trend of growing inequality. Not
only is the gap between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and janitors growing; so is the gap among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, the main reason is marketing : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Studios</ENAMEX>
have found no better way to bring in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> than through the lure of popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stars</ENAMEX>, who often command followings in specific age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and can therefore
help target a film to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>, middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, etc. And securing viewers
is an increasingly difficult task. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Audiences</ENAMEX> are shrinking, partly as a result
of competition from videocassettes, cable and pay TV, the Internet, and other
forms of new technology. Films stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> for less time than ever before;
therefore, more films have to be made; and therefore, more money has to be
spent distinguishing one film from another. The cost of marketing a movie is up
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion Picture Association of America</ENAMEX>,
to an average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18 million</NUMEX>. Advertising movies before they open is
crucial but tricky, since each film is essentially a brand-new product with no
identity in the marketplace other than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>'. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word-of-mouth</ENAMEX> takes too long
to kick in and hurts more films than it helps, and no one knows the names of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> anymore (except, perhaps, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s). As a result, the
value of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>' fame has increased.

            Adding to the demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> with recognizable names is
the foreign market . Sales overseas now account for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> or more of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s gross. Waterworld , for example, was considered a flop in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> because it only grossed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$88 million</NUMEX> on a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175 million</NUMEX> budget.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>, though, it grossed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$260 million</NUMEX>. The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable Guy</ENAMEX>, for
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX> was paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> out of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 million</NUMEX> budget, is also
expected to turn a profit abroad. But selling a blockbuster overseas requires
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of A-list <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>; foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> are even less willing than
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ones to accept second-tier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are attempting to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>' influence . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This spring</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> announced that it would cut its production by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>
followed suit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Studios</ENAMEX> will also try to substitute for expensive star vehicles
more animated films and explosive special-effects movies such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twister</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Independence Day</ENAMEX> --the biggest box-office successes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, with
grosses of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $200 million</NUMEX> apiece.

            
Meanwhile, following the lead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint</ENAMEX>
Eastwood, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Howard</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>, more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
are using their cachet to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, often of smaller,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">artier</ENAMEX> movies that might not otherwise attract either funding or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX> won an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Academy Award</ENAMEX> for directing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braveheart</ENAMEX> , as
did <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Lahti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffin Dunne</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Goldblum</ENAMEX>) for
directing short films. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>) included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Thing You Do</ENAMEX>!) , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Buscemi</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trees Lounge</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Pacino</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Looking for</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> ).

            It is not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> have tried to seize the reins of production--that was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Pickford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Chaplin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Fairbanks</ENAMEX> joined forces with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S. Hart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.W. Griffith</ENAMEX> to form <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Artists</ENAMEX> , a distribution
company meant to compete with the larger film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, which were churning
out formula films and treating most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and actresses as hired hands. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX>, however, was plagued by inept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and a lack of resources, and
never became a power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. This time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and actresses have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
over a barrel, and they may just succeed in becoming the next generation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">auteurs</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
