
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are We Using Chinese Rockets</ENAMEX>?

            The
latest scandal to implicate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> revolves around accusations
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> gave aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral Space</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>--headed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign cycle--special permission to export satellites to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> opposition. Even if there is no actual evidence of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quid</ENAMEX> (donations) pro quo (permission to export), these allegations raise
questions. Why would a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> launch satellites on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>? Why
not use <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ones? And if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> that launch satellites and nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> are fundamentally the same, why would the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> authorize
cooperation with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s national aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, which has clear links to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>?

            

               Background. In anticipation of a booming
market, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> began contracting launches with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'80s</TIMEX>. To punish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> crackdown, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government prohibited the launch of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> commercial satellites on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rockets</ENAMEX>, except with a presidentially granted exemption. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
administration, however, granted waivers to the sanctions that soon put most of
the contracts back on track. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, urged on by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>, authorized the export of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
satellites for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> launch. (In fact, sanctions changed little. The export
of satellites to any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has always required government approval.)

            As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> was the most vociferous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of these waivers . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
to read his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaigned against them. However,
aggressive lobbying by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> persuaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to
reverse their position. They have granted waivers for the launch of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> more
satellites. No application for a waiver has ever been denied--by any
administration. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, before this scandal broke, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Monitor</ENAMEX> that they hoped that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> would
soon eliminate these sanctions altogether. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a rundown of the specific
actions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> that underlie the current controversy.)

            

               Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rockets</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> (of which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> is the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> largest) do not rely on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for most of their launches. In the same
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year period</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> satellites into space, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> launched
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of others on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China</ENAMEX>
currently launches relatively few satellites, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX>, like its competitors
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>, aims to increase its use of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> for
several reasons:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Cut-rate prices.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> charges <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>--its least expensive competitor
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 million</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$140</NUMEX> for a comparable launch). Attribute this in part to
massive government subsidies given to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s national aerospace
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. More important, to restore business that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China</ENAMEX> lost after a spate of
rocket crashes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX> slashed launch prices. In the early
'90s, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> launched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX> satellites <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> they only
managed the successful launch of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">for the Philippines</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Rocket shortage.
The proliferation of cell phones, digital television, etc., has caused the
demand for launches to outstrip the supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>. This shortage forces
satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to exploit all available opportunities. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> export policy
exacerbates the dearth. To protect its aerospace industry, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> quotas for this
decade allow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to arrange <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 20</NUMEX> launches with each of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukrainian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> national aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> policy. Fixated on politically popular manned flights, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> has
devoted most of its resources to highly expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Space Shuttle</ENAMEX> flights. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>
neglected development of the cheap, disposable, reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> that other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> pursued. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> began authorizing commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">space</ENAMEX> launches in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, which typically
collaborated on massive government projects, weren't equipped to build entire
rockets for commercial use. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are still catching up and are not
nearly as well stocked as their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>.

            

               Is it dangerous for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to use
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>? It is indisputable that the technology used to launch
commercial satellites is largely indistinguishable from the technology used to
launch <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> ripped off its
commercial space capabilities from its weapons program. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rocket</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">intercontinental</ENAMEX> ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> use
precisely the same rocket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX> and guidance systems. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Wall</ENAMEX> is partly
owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and its upper management has intimate ties to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military's top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, moreover, inevitably acquire a vested interest in improving the
accuracy and reliability of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>, since failures, such as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
crash that destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> satellites, are very costly. In any case,
in the process of launching U.S. commercial satellites, it is unavoidable that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will transfer some technology to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> . To install a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX>, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> work with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> to
substantially rewire and reprogram the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX>. The law, however, requires that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> supervise these procedures. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> official
remains with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> from the time it leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> until its
liftoff.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> considers the
risks of technology transfers negligible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> have not upgraded their ICBMs since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. And they don't need to--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> they supposedly have aimed at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> have always been judged capable of hitting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> (though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s difficulty in commercial launches casts doubt on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s assessment).

            
               Did
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> harm national security? In the wake of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
rocket crash, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> subsidiary chaired a panel composed of
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> that reviewed the findings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> says the review was meant to reassure the insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that indemnify their launches on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> denies that
its report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> divulged sensitive information about rocket guidance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> report claims. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> page report, the
company says, merely pointed out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> had faulty soldering.
And this conclusion, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> claims, was neither original nor based on first-hand
investigation. Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> impounded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> findings before they ever reached them.

            
               If you
missed the links, click to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> criticisms and for a breakdown of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> controversy.
            

         
      
   
