
   
   
      
         
            Balancing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the budget battle
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> shut down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>--who got blamed for the shutdown--more or less
surrendered to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on budget specifics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, has
embraced the principle of balancing the budget by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2002</TIMEX>. As he pointed
out relentlessly during the campaign, the deficit has shrunk by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past four years</TIMEX>. He suggested in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10</TIMEX> interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brinkley</ENAMEX>
that going the rest of the way will be easy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> also
talks as though it will be easy. Will it?

            In fact,
eliminating the deficit shouldn't be hard--at least on paper. The task is
easier partly because of legislative successes over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> and welfare programs have been reformed in ways that will save
money, and discretionary spending was cut vigorously in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 1996</TIMEX>. There were
reverses after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> surrender of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, but they were minor. The
failure to cut taxes also helps. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are mainly the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of pure dumb luck.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> projected
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 1996</TIMEX> deficit at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$207 billion</NUMEX>. It came in at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$107 billion</NUMEX>. Only a
small part of the improvement is the result of congressional deficit-cutting.
Most of it is the result of estimating errors by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX>. Some might say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">estimators</ENAMEX>," but, believe it or not, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 billion</NUMEX> error is not very large in
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.5 trillion</NUMEX> economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> overestimated outlays by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 4 percent</NUMEX> and
underestimated receipts by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 2.5 percent</NUMEX>. These may not be very accurate
forecasts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two-year</TIMEX> period, but they are far from incompetent.

            The causes
of the errors are not yet well understood. Much of the revenue surge may have
been capital-gains-tax revenues associated with the surging stock market--and
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> besides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> wish they had forecast that. Outlays were down because
of lower-than-expected interest rates and a mysterious reduction in the growth
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> spending. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> spending has begun to surge again in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. The good news was short-lived, as it usually is for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>.

            
How hard it will be to come up with an
agreed-upon path to a balanced budget depends on how the CBO adjusts its
projections for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. The lesson of the huge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> mistake might seem to be that
budget projections are futile--but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> has no choice but to project, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has no choice but to accept that projection as gospel. In any event,
the new CBO projections should make the budget-balancing task easier for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, although we do not know how much easier.

            Given the
intense budget struggles of the past, why does balancing the budget now look
easier? First, as noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, we have been nibbling away at the deficit. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">much-maligned</ENAMEX> budget deal of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, fashioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
helped a lot, as did the equally maligned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> deal constructed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. But more important, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX> should be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Age</ENAMEX> for
the budget.

            With luck, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, we should still be enjoying an enormous
peace dividend from the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. Another long-fuse blessing is the
low birth rate during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX>. Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noninterest</ENAMEX> budget goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> will be growing
slowly at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> will have little choice but to
assume the continuation of full employment. There is no recession in sight, and
it would be foolish to try to forecast the timing of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more than a year in
the future.

            Given all
these favorable factors, it might be possible to devise a credible
balanced-budget plan that involves only minor cuts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, and
discretionary spending--were it not for the tax cuts desired by both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. The tax cuts may force them to put some
implausible spending cuts on paper. If the final plan involves significant,
unspecified cuts in real discretionary spending--and if most of those cuts
occur in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001 and 2002</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> will be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of leisure--we should
all be suspicious. It will be very difficult to cut discretionary spending much
further. Defense spending will soon be flattening out, and domestic
discretionary spending proved highly resilient at the end of the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> facing re-election became much more conservative.

            
Arecession at any time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>
also would add greatly to the difficulty. In fact, an economic downturn of any
significant size would destroy efforts to balance the budget in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, and could
push the deficit back toward <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 billion</NUMEX>.

            However, the much more
serious budget problem involves what happens after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. The good news about
the near future will be bad news for the long run if it leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to put forward a plausible balanced-budget plan without beginning the
dramatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> reforms that are required to
avoid an economic catastrophe soon after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> will retire.
At that time, without reform, the deficit will soar to unimaginable levels. The
private savings necessary to finance the deficit will plummet, because there
will be net withdrawals from private pension funds. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> will cause
us to eat away at our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>, and the economy will head rapidly downward.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
are right: Balancing the budget by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> will be (relatively) easy. It's
afterward that the trouble starts.

         
      
   
