
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> Expansion

            By
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karenna Gore</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is on the verge of
offering membership to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">bloc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech Republic</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of what used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX>). The
offer will probably come at a summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>. But it is
controversial. So is the whole purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> is
over.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Atlantic Treaty Organization</ENAMEX> was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>. Its
purpose , in the words of its first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismay</ENAMEX>, was
"to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> out, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> down." In other
words, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, devastated by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to help defend them against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aggression</ENAMEX>, and wanted German
militarism to be merged into joint security arrangements.

            
The key to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article 5</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Atlantic Treaty</ENAMEX>: "The Parties agree that an armed attack against one or
more of them in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> will be considered an attack against
them all." In exchange for the security blanket of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear and
conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in
both policy and operations. (The treaty specifies that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> must be an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.)

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> favors expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, but has been criticized
for insufficient enthusiasm. During the last presidential campaign, ex-Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was dragging his feet. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> has
said that "ambivalence has produced an inconsistency between the
administration's statements of its objectives and the leisurely way it pursues
them." Others in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> pushing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion include a vocal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central European</ENAMEX> diaspora (symbolized now by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX>-born Secretary
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lugar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Mikulski</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lieberman</ENAMEX>.

            
The main arguments for expansion , from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> point of view, are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) This is an opportunity to consolidate the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War victory by locking in the allegiance of newly democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and
ensuring their stability; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) This is an insurance policy against a potentially
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">resurgent Russia</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) This guarantees a continuing leadership role for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, even as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> creates and strengthens its own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of unity. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has remade itself as a peacekeeping and
crisis-management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>--in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, for example--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of
expansion believe this is a valuable role that expanded membership would
enhance.

            But
others say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is "barreling" toward expansion, in
reckless disregard of the attendant risks and drawbacks . The opposition
is diverse and mounting. It includes an extreme right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Buchanan</ENAMEX> , a moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> like former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Nunn</ENAMEX>, and the
editorial page of the 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
               . "Planning the future of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> with blueprints from the cold war is a mistake," says the
Times .

            

               Anti-expansion arguments break down into
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main categories. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> emphasizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is not a feel-good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>--it is a military commitment. Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> really prepared
to go to war to defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech Republic</ENAMEX>? With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in shambles and
communism no longer a threat, what threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests justifies such a
commitment? At present levels of military spending, can the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
credibly make such a promise? And what would it cost to make the promise
credible? Rash treaty commitments to the feud-prone <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of central <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
led to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>--could it happen again? ("Putting a tripwire for war on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>'s border," is how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> put it in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 5</TIMEX> column.) Why can't <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>,
now prosperous, defend itself?

            The
other category of arguments against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion concerns the impact on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> , the object of bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Kennan</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> policy of "containment" of which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> was an expression, declared
in the Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 5</TIMEX> that "expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> would be the most fateful error
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> policy in the entire post<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-cold-war</ENAMEX> era." It would "inflame the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nationalistic</ENAMEX>, anti-Western and militaristic tendencies in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> opinion";
harm "the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> democracy"; "restore the atmosphere of the
cold war"; and "impel <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> foreign policy in directions decidedly not to our
liking."

            
Alesser, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> category of arguments against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion concerns its effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that are not
admitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say expansion could be another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yalta</ENAMEX> (the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX> meeting at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> agreed on spheres of
influence in postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>)--imposing a line between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>, and
leaving nonmembers subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bullying</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, which historically have been invasion <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
membership as the answer to their greatest fears: internal instability and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> resurgence. They also see it as easing their way toward economic
integration with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>. What they have been offered so far is a sort
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior membership</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFP</ENAMEX> provides for
military cooperation, but no defense guarantee. It has been mocked as a
meaningless gesture to stave off eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> and assuage the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>. But
others praise it as a minor-league farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and
celebrate its civilizing influence (some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have settled long-standing
border disputes).

            To allay <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has offered not to deploy nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>. Its central
offer is a "charter" with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> that assures the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> a voice in alliance
policy, without any of the rights of membership. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> warned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX> that unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> backs off, ultranationalists
will threaten the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> will be rolling out" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
