
   
   
      
         
            Mossad

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s vaunted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mossad</ENAMEX>, botched an assassination attempt on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> leader
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>. Soon after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> had injected a poison into their target,
they were captured by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> demanded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> hand
over the antidote, which they did. Bemused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> wondered how the
legendarily effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> had been foiled so easily. What is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossad</ENAMEX>? Does
its track record live up to its reputation?

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Intelligence and Special Tasks</ENAMEX>, a k a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mossad</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> for
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX>"), is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> equivalent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. It engages in foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">espionage</ENAMEX> and covert action . (Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shin Bet</ENAMEX>, is in charge
of domestic intelligence-gathering and security.) Only rarely does the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
government publicly acknowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is accountable only to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> and has little civilian oversight; even the size of its budget
remains a secret.

            Mossad was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX> when newly independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> reorganized its national defense. It assumed control over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> that had organized illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
immigration to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Mossad</ENAMEX> stationed its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embassies</ENAMEX>, where they cultivated "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> working in foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> who fed them information. Other newly recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were
assigned to infiltrate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. The most famous example: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eli Cohen</ENAMEX> befriended <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amin al-Hafez</ENAMEX> and was nearly
named <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>.

            Mossad
established its international credibility with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important finds . It
obtained a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khruschev</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party Congress</ENAMEX> speech about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">atrocities</ENAMEX>, much sought after by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossad</ENAMEX>
uncovered a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX> plot by right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to assassinate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles de Gaulle</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> traded information about the plot with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> for nuclear-weapons technology.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX>'s covert missions have been more
successful than its intelligence gathering. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> kidnapped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Eichmann</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buenos Aires</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>, spiriting him away
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> planned the famous raid on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entebbe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>,
rescuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air France</ENAMEX> jet hijacked by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> passenger and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commando</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yonathan</ENAMEX>--died during the raid.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> has been largely
unable to procure intelligence that would prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> attacks such
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1972 Munich Olympics</ENAMEX> massacre by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> Black <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>.
Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> has attempted to deter terrorism by assassinating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>.
Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, which tries to keep its covert actions secret, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has meant
for its assassinations to be highly visible . After <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX>, for example,
it killed Black <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>'s most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>, forcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> out of
operation by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the '70s</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mossad</ENAMEX> assassinated the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engineer</ENAMEX>,"
a notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>, by wiring his cell phone with explosives.

            Mossad
has tried to incite conflict within <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to mixed effect.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> foiled a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> plot to discredit <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> ultranationalists by
planting bombs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. Egyptians hanged the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>
behind the campaign. More successful was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossad</ENAMEX>'s arming and training of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1963 and 1975</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>-affiliated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> killed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>.

            The failed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> plot and the bungled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX> mission are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX>'s only embarrassments . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> was widely chided for
assassinating an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they mistakenly believed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black September</ENAMEX>
operative. (It did kill its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years later</TIMEX>.) Also in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossad</ENAMEX> was
criticized for failing to predict the surprise <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> attack that began the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Yom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Kippur War</ENAMEX>. It was similarly criticized for not foreseeing the intifada, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> uprising that began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. These breakdowns are attributed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX>'s failure to penetrate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has no diplomatic
relations with most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, making it difficult for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to gather
foreign intelligence.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> has
weakened significantly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>'s return
from exile in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, it has spent more resources tracking potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>
within the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX>, a responsibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shin Bet rather than Mossad</ENAMEX>.
Interagency competition has eroded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX>'s morale.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> has also been handicapped by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
mistrust . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> caught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
naval-intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, shipping sensitive satellite photos to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakam</ENAMEX>--a
now-defunct arm of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> intelligence largely devoted to stealing nuclear
secrets. Following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollard</ENAMEX> affair, rumors circulated that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> had
penetrated other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The flow of information between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and Mossad
is said to have slowed since.

            And
revelations about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> malfeasance have damaged its prestige.
Recent best-selling memoirs by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> tell of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who ran
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-lanced</ENAMEX> as mercenaries . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> also brokered secret,
dubiously legal, private arms sales to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regimes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">white government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> press, which historically has respected
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s request not to probe its workings, splashed these stories across
the front pages. Perhaps even more demoralizing has been a controversial TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">melodrama</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossad</ENAMEX> , which, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, depicts agents
as buffoonish playboys.

            Mossad, which employs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, now has
difficulty competing with private-sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">recruiters</ENAMEX> . Its early agents
were well-educated, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cosmopolitans</ENAMEX> who ran the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> like an
exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. But most current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are career military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and the
conventional wisdom is that they're less intelligent and creative than their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predecessors</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX> fiasco could cost
both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX>. In exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s return of the captured Mossad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assassins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> released <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas'</ENAMEX> spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheik Ahmed Yessin</ENAMEX> ,
who had been imprisoned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. Some worry he will become a major
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX>, endangering peace
negotiations. Others worry that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX>'s botched mission will occasion a new,
high-profile panel that will dig up more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
