
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Gambling</ENAMEX>

            Gambling as an enterprise
among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> has exploded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. The first operation
started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>. Today, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> are conducted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">186</NUMEX> gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>
across <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>; the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> take is estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> are
now locked in competition: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> have filed a suit claiming
they were denied a casino license in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> because wealthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> beat them to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> campaign coffers. It appears likely that an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> will
be appointed to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX>'s handling of the
affair. What is the legal basis for gambling on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> reservations? What
accounts for the explosion in the number and size of such operations? Who
controls the gambling spigot: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> within whose boundaries
the reservations lie, or the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>?

            
               The
concept of tribal sovereignty. The " cases" of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1830s</NUMEX> framed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tribe</ENAMEX>-state-union relations thus: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> were neither foreign nor subject
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX>; they were "domestic dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>," "wards" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guardian</ENAMEX>." Since the reservations were federal protectorates, state law had no
force on their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>.

            

               Exceptions to the rule. Tribal immunity
from state law is not absolute. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tribes</ENAMEX> have, on occasion, opted for a blurring
of boundaries (asking that state cops patrol reservation land, for example).
And several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> decisions since <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cherokee</ENAMEX> have authorized exceptions to
the state-exclusion principle. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> may, for example, make enforceable laws
governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> authority to that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
has used its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> power to transfer its authority to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> on several
occasions. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Law</ENAMEX> 280 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>) gave several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> on
reservations. Even without the specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> of authority, state law may
still be considered valid if it doesn't flout federal goals. Click for an
example.

            

               Limits on state control. Gambling did
not become an issue until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seminole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> identified
bingo as a means of alleviating poverty on the reservation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>'s
decision put it in direct conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s rather restrictive bingo
statute. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crying PL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">280</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--and the court ruled in favor of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>. Its reasoning: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bingo</ENAMEX> was not universally prohibited in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>;
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> were exempt. Therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> had no right to
regulate bingo on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seminole</ENAMEX> reservation.

            The
Seminole victory was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in a series, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> gambling thrived over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next several years</TIMEX>.

            

               Enter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> Gaming
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Act</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>) sought to set regulatory standards and arbitrate
outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>-state conflicts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGRA</ENAMEX> confirmed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>' "exclusive" right
to regulate reservation gambling as long as the gambling activity in question
did not violate federal or state law.

            The act
also divided <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> gambling into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> classes. Of these, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> were given
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (traditional/ceremonial games, bingo, and some card
games). But Class III <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> and the like--required that the tribe
enter an agreement, or "compact," with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            
IGRA obliged the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to enter negotiations in
good faith, failing which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> could sue in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. But when the
Seminoles, victorious in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, sued <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> after being denied compact
negotiations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, they lost.

            Predictably, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGRA</ENAMEX> has come
under fire from all directions. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Incensed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> have pointed out that the
court's ruling stripped them of their safety net, making their sovereignty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moot</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of the Interior</ENAMEX> is exploring alternative procedures that
would let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> negotiate compacts directly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, cutting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> out of the equation. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This July</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> introduced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gaming Regulatory Act Amendments Act of 1997</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, seeking, among
other things, to establish an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that would set minimum
federal regulatory standards for reservation gambling.

            Meanwhile, a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> keep
the bulk of the gambling prize: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> reports that of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">126</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> operating gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31, 1996</TIMEX>, eight
accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of total revenues. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tribal Allocation</ENAMEX>
Priority funds, as federal payments to tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are known, are
divvied up based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> size and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> density rather than income,
meaning that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> with big gambling incomes often get federal subsidies as
big as those with none.

         
      
   
