
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder of JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX>

            It's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> since the
last revelations about the unsolved murder of beauty-pageant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramsey</ENAMEX>, yet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 6-year-old</TIMEX>'s death continues to provide grist for the tabloids,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">op-ed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>, TV talk shows, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-some Web sites that follow the
case. Because information about the investigation comes in dribs and drabs, it
is all too easy to lose track of where things stand.

            Initial
press reports dwelt on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s career on the beauty-pageant circuit. As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contestant</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> dressed as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> (wearing lipstick and
high heels) and performed suggestive dances. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy) Ramsey</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX>, considered her young
daughter her confidante and "best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX> had undergone chemotherapy,
and various press accounts accuse her of fulfilling her own beauty-pageant
fantasies through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ramsey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
heads a software-distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lived in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX>'s posh historic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX>.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 26, 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX> phoned the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in a panic about a ransom note she says she found on a staircase
leading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>. The note demanded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$118,000</NUMEX> for the return of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> arrived at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramsey</ENAMEX> home to monitor incoming phone calls, left a few
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> later, and returned with a warrant to search the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for evidence of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">break-in</ENAMEX>. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX>'s absence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ramsey</ENAMEX> and a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> searched
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> themselves, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> in a basement storage
room. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coroner</ENAMEX>'s report, the cause of death was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strangulation</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s skull was fractured, and she had been sexually
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assaulted</ENAMEX> (though no semen was found).

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX>, who calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> "the focus " of
his murder investigation, has cleared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ramsey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by a previous
marriage of suspicion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> found no evidence of forced entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>;
nor was the new-fallen snow outside disturbed by footprints. The only people
known to have been inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at the time of the murder were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> call the ransom note a fake,
citing its "intentional" misspellings . Searching the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ramsey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, police
found a legal pad on which they believe the note was written. They also found a
rough draft of the note on the same pad.

            Details
from the note leaked to the press indicate an intimate knowledge of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramsey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The amount demanded matched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ramsey</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> bonus--and the
note ended with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Victory SBTC</ENAMEX>," which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> say refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subic Bay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Training Center</ENAMEX>, the defunct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramsey</ENAMEX> was stationed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramseys</ENAMEX> hired criminal-defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to represent
them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> after the murder, even though they had not been named as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> advised them not to submit to formal, videotaped police
interviews until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> agreed to show the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramseys</ENAMEX> copies of the statement
they had made to police <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the murder. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> agreed to the terms,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> was interviewed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1</TIMEX>. There was an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourlong</TIMEX> break between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX>'s interviews, which may have given them time to coordinate
their stories .

            What
motive would the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramseys</ENAMEX> have to kill their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>? The supermarket
tabloids have run riot with speculation, but family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> call the Ramseys
gentle and devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramseys</ENAMEX> themselves have theorized in interviews
that one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> might have killed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>. In an ad
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramseys</ENAMEX> published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camera</ENAMEX> , they accused a
convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molester of the crime. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> acknowledge that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 15</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (caterers, housekeepers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>) had keys to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.

            
While aggressively spinning the case to the
press, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have also withheld important pieces of evidence from
public view, saying that full disclosure would jeopardize the investigation.
The complete autopsy report remains sealed, and the results of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> tests
performed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s bloodstained nightgown, her hair, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> found
underneath her fingernails also remain confidential. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> have taken <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
handwriting samples from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy Ramsey</ENAMEX> and compared them against the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2½</NUMEX> page
ransom note, the complete contents of which have not been made public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX>
say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX>'s handwriting samples are inconclusive because her manual dexterity
has been hampered by sedatives she has taken since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s death. They say
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ramsey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> did not match the ransom note.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, which says it is moving cautiously and waiting to amass more evidence,
has established a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> that includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX> : law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Scheck</ENAMEX> and forensic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Lee</ENAMEX>. The
district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> predicts that an arrest will be made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two months</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney's office</ENAMEX> has bungled the case because it has
little experience with homicides: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet</ENAMEX> was the college <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s only murder
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. They say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> mishandled the crime scene ,
allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ramsey</ENAMEX> to search the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and point out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> let the
couple leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX> prior to questioning them. (The Ramseys
buried their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, then vacationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ga.</ENAMEX>) This
absence, some speculate, gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ramseys</ENAMEX> time to work out a story to explain
their innocence.

         
      
   
