
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecommunications Reform</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is in the
midst of something called "telecommunications reform." What is it, and how is
it going?

            The
Telecommunications Act , passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1996</TIMEX>, was the first
congressional overhaul of telecommunications policy since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>. The new law
promised to promote 
               competition by repealing government
regulations . A key to this hope is digital technology , which turns
all forms of communication--voice, data, or video--into streams of numbers,
which can be carried by any communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>--telephone lines, coaxial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX>, or the airwaves. Telecommunications reform is supposed to break down
existing barriers between these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> so that, for example, phone companies
will sell television hookups and cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will offer telephone service.
It is also supposed to end the distinction between local and long-distance
phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, allowing each to go after the other's business.

            The early results have been poor to middling. Competition
(particularly in local residential telephone service) has been slow to bloom.
And the promised "convergence " of the various communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> has
not arrived. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say the problem is that deregulation didn't go
far enough. The new law deregulates some aspects of the telecom industry while
maintaining or even adding new regulations in others. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say the
problem is too much deregulation. They point especially to a series of giant
mergers --most notably those reassembling the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> telephone monopoly
that was broken up--that the new law does nothing to discourage.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telecom</ENAMEX> law rewrites the ground rules in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> areas of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> industry: telephone service, cable, and broadcasting.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telephony</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Telecommunications Act</ENAMEX> is
intended to erode the local-phone-service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> enjoyed by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
regional "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX> " (and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> for most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> before
that). It requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bells</ENAMEX> to make their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>--the "local loop "
linking home phones to the telephone network--available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, so that
the latter can compete without running wires to every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. It also requires
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX> to resell their entire bundle of services wholesale to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
that might wish to compete on the retail level. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Customers</ENAMEX> who want to switch
phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> must be able to keep their old phone numbers and can't be
required to dial extra access codes.

            The drafters of the law
expected these provisions to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX> facing a variety of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> : wireless services, small startup local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service providers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> and utility <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> (who own valuable rights of way), other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby</ENAMEX>
Bells--and, perhaps most importantly, long-distance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>.

            The act permits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby</ENAMEX>
Bells to offer long-distance service--something the AT&T breakup decree had
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">forbidden</ENAMEX>--but only after they have taken <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> specific steps to open up their
own local phone markets. The act also explicitly requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, to ensure "universal
service "--guaranteeing that rural and other underserved areas receive
telephone services comparable to those provided in urban areas. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>
rolled out a universal service plan, which included discounted Internet hookups
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>, to be funded by charges on all interstate
telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable</ENAMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed a law deregulating cable prices (even forbidding local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> from setting rates). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> it reregulated cable prices. In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> act it deregulated them again. Starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1999</TIMEX>, cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
will be able to set their own rates, except on "basic tier" service (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">no-frills</ENAMEX> menu of broadcast and public-access programming). Even for basic-tier
service, the statute allows cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to begin charging market rates as
soon as they face competition from another local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>. The act allows local
phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to provide video programming to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> (whether via cable,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wireless</ENAMEX>, or through telephone lines), and it lets phone and cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in
most local markets own <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 10 percent</NUMEX> of one another.

            

               Broadcast . As called for by the new law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> gave each of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,600</NUMEX> television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> a second <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> of spectrum space.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call this a giveaway of a public resource worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> are supposed to use the extra spectrum space for the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital</ENAMEX> signals. They are also supposed to give their current spectrum space
back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>, when non-digital TV broadcasting is supposed to stop. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> are now pushing to hold on to the additional spectrum space.

            The act also ends long-standing rules against
cross-ownership in broadcasting. Anyone may now own an unlimited number of
radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, subject only to caps on local concentration. Likewise for TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX>, as long as one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s signals do not reach <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 35 percent</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. The new law also makes it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> to
renew their licenses, and requires TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to install parent-friendly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V</ENAMEX>-chips. Finally, the statute included the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX>, which
was struck down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. Has deregulation worked? During
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, cable-TV prices shot up at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than twice the</NUMEX> rate of inflation.
Non-discount long-distance rates rose even faster. Local phone rates are going
up, too, though some of this rise may be attributable to a reduction in
subsidies.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Competitors</ENAMEX> have not rushed in. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX> still monopolize the
local-household phone market (although competition for business phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
is more visible). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>--though it is gradually losing market share and
lives in fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX> entering the market--still dominates long distance.
The cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are facing some increased competition from
direct-broadcast satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> , but they have maintained their
grip. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> recently abandoned plans for a major satellite assault on
the cable market.) Ironically, price competition has emerged most robustly
among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> not addressed by the new law, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBS</ENAMEX>, cellular phone, and
Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>.

            
The hoped-for "convergence" of industries and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> has not come to pass. The big cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--balking at the
costs of converting one-way cable to two-way voice lines--have shelved
plans to get into the local phone business. Likewise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX>, who,
facing economic and technical obstacles, have abandoned plans to branch out
into video. And the long-distance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have made only tentative steps
toward invading the local residential-telephone market. Even for a mammoth like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, the economics of going local are close to prohibitive, because the
"local loop" is the most expensive part of the entire system to build and
operate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s plan, announced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, to use wireless systems to
offer local phone service has been widely dismissed as unconvincing. It would
be much cheaper for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX>, with local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and a built-in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer base</ENAMEX>, to break into the long-distance market. But that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-point
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">checklist</ENAMEX> is a formidable obstacle.

            Meanwhile, merger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mania</ENAMEX> has seized the telecom industry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> approved a
merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYNEX</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadcasting</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westinghouse</ENAMEX> purchased both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> and radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadcasting</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Telecom</ENAMEX> purchased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> wants
to merge with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX> (which became the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bell</ENAMEX> by swallowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Telesis</ENAMEX>), a move strongly opposed by outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hundt</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
