
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu Sese Seko</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 30 years</TIMEX>, is
considered the continent's most brutal and corrupt living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>. Since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> have battled his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> they seized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kisangani</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, and may soon topple him. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> watchers
predict that chaos could spread to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. What's it all
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>?

            Attribute
part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>'s current crisis to the boundaries it inherited from its
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> colonizers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX> minus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scandinavia</ENAMEX>--envelops <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> . They frequently conflict.
Bantus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>, constitute the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">majority</NUMEX> west of the rain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forest</ENAMEX> that divides <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX> of the rain forest is a hodgepodge.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX> used to be called the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX> . At
independence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, a Soviet-backed socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> took power. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>-backed military coup brought down this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and installed army chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Using violence, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>colonial rhetoric, and a cult of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">personality</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> consolidated his power and suppressed tribal tensions. As
part of a program called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>-ism," he changed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s name. It all
worked fairly well until recently.

            The most
unsettling development has been the civil war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>'s eastern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>. The war is between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>--the Hutus
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tutsis</ENAMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tutsi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> seized power, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> fled across the border to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> included
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> that had led the murder of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tutsis</ENAMEX>. With the sanction of local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zairian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> used camps
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> for raids into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>. To avenge these attacks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Kagame</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>, arranged for the combat training
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banyamulenge, Tutsis</ENAMEX> indigenous to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Zaire</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Banyamulenge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commandos</ENAMEX> attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> operating
out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>. They routed both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, causing them to flee into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
interior rain forest.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> have joined
with the victorious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tutsi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commandos</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, they launched a joint
offensive and so far have captured <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand-mile</NUMEX> swath of territory in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>. The opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> mainly consists of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaba</ENAMEX> and Kasai
provinces in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Zaire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the original post-colonial
government, who have battled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> sporadically since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ascent</ENAMEX>. The most powerful rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurent Kabila</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1965</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, has renounced his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> past, many in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> worry about his socialist tendencies.

            While
militarily successful, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabila</ENAMEX>'s alliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tutsis</ENAMEX> is a political
handicap for him, because many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bantus</ENAMEX> have their own deep-seated hatred toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tutsis</ENAMEX>. Another obstacle to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabila</ENAMEX>'s revolt is the lack of national
infrastructure . Crossing the roadless rain forest, from recently captured
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kisangani</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinshasa</ENAMEX>, the capital, will be arduous.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>'s economic collapse may make all these tribal
differences irrelevant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Groups</ENAMEX> normally hostile to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tutsis</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bantu</ENAMEX>
student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kinshasa</ENAMEX>, have turned against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>'s
natural resources , including some of the world's richest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamond</ENAMEX> and
copper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has become one of the poorest in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, its
gross national product was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than a third</NUMEX> of what it had been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>.
Zairian industry runs at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 10 percent</NUMEX> of capacity. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>
dried up after the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> diminished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>'s strategic importance.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>'s corruption has siphoned off resources. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is said to
have plundered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> straight from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government treasury</ENAMEX>, making him one
of the richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the world. He pays his civil service virtually no salary,
requiring them to earn their income through bribes.

            In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> to receive treatment for
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>. Except for short visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, he
has been staying at his villas on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Riviera</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monaco</ENAMEX>. His absence
has hastened the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s disintegration. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Zairians</ENAMEX> consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> to be
the stern-but-loving "national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> ." Other more superstitious
Zairians endow him with a supernatural aura, something he has cultivated
through his identification with the leopard, which signifies omnipotence in
Bantu iconography. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> made "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leopard</ENAMEX>" his nickname and always wears a
leopard-skin hat .) In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>'s absence, various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have
jockeyed for power, creating serious harm to the war effort. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> voted to oust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> is in shambles, and large
sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have been running themselves, without oversight from
the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            
Increasingly desperate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> uses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercenaries</ENAMEX> to fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> relies on assistance
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonas Savimbi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITA army</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> from neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX>,
formerly backed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, have sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
to assist the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. Their intentions are unclear: Do they hope to grab land
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>? Are they seeking to avenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>'s long support of rebellions in
their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> predict that their involvement in the war could
escalate the conflict, drawing these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> into battle with one
another.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
has not officially taken a position on the civil war. However, it has tacitly
encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>, in the belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>'s patronage of guerrilla
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in the region is destabilizing. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX> has
been a source of tension with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, which supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hutus</ENAMEX> and resents
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabila</ENAMEX>'s alliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banyamulenge</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
