
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> of sexual harassment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX>
dismissed her as a "liar" and an "erotomaniac." Now the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embraced Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' sexual-harassment case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, who once claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> "don't make these
things up," have rallied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s defense or are silent about the
accusations involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, and others. Each side accuses the
other of hypocrisy. What are the similarities and the differences between the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> The evidence: Similar evidence supports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s accusations. Their credibility depends on corroboration by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
claim they were told of the harassment soon after it occurred. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> affidavits
say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> spoke of her encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> on the same day
it allegedly happened. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> testified under oath that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX> told them
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' harassment during the period it allegedly occurred. Possibly
because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s corroborators didn't testify until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> after she had
stopped working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, their statements contain more contradictions than
those made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' corroborators. (Evidence supporting the contention that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton groped Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>--his other alleged victim of harassment--is much
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shakier</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s disputes key facts about the claim, and Willey
has yet to make her case publicly.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 Ulterior</ENAMEX> motives: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and Jones
have allied with opportunistic ideological zealots. And they are right. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>
testified only after liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> had tracked her down and leaked her
story; feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Legal Defense Fund</ENAMEX> advised her.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Arkansas Clinton</ENAMEX>-hater <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Jackson</ENAMEX> coaxed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> into filing
suit; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX> has coached <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>; and the religious right's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutherford Institute</ENAMEX> now helps fund her case. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wing</ENAMEX> and left-wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have helped trumpet the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s causes, nobody has shown
convincingly that either side trumped up the accusations.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lingering</ENAMEX> doubts: Fundamental logical flaws in the
stories of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> continue to create doubts: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> was such an
intolerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, why did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> leave a secure job to follow him from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</ENAMEX>? Why did
she continue to telephone him after she no longer worked for him? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> is
interested only in clearing her name, why did she decide to make such a public
case against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> What the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> (allegedly) did: The behavior at issue
is very different in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases. Which is worse? Are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged short
episodes of physical assault more reprehensible than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' alleged
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-and-a-half-year</TIMEX> verbal assault? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> may have talked about porn films,
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> out on patently unwelcome dates, bragged about his sexual prowess,
and referred to pubic hairs on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> cans, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> never
flashed his genitals, touched her sexually, or propositioned her
explicitly.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 Just</TIMEX> say no? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> note that he
always flags his lascivious intentions before expressing them. He flirted with
Willey over the phone before putting the moves on her. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trooper Danny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX> invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, he told her, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> says
you make his knees knock." Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> realized these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wanted none of
him, he backed off. He purportedly told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I don't want to make you
do anything that you don't want to do." By contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> failed to pick up
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s lack of interest, her repeated assertions that she didn't want to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">date Thomas</ENAMEX> and her "obvious discomfort" with his "wild talk." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
say she should have emphatically told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> to stop.)

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan</ENAMEX> connection: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> unnoted similarity between
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases is the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Mayer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Abramson</ENAMEX> report
in their book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Justice: The Selling</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> , that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> spent a day prepping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> for his confirmation
hearings.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Did Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> violate the
law? If "the law" is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> against sexual harassment, the answer in both
cases is: Probably not.

            According
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>--the basis for most harassment cases--harassment is actionable when it is
"sufficiently severe and pervasive to ... create an abusive working
environment." Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> failed to file her suit before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Title</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VII</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">180-day</TIMEX>
statute of limitations, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have used an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction-</ENAMEX>era
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX> law to make her case. Assuming she did qualify for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Title VII</ENAMEX>,
her legal case is still weak: a) There is no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> suffered any
retaliation for refusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. She received regular pay increases and
promotions after the alleged incident. b) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Courts</ENAMEX> rarely consider a one-time
instance of harassment "severe and pervasive." c) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Title</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VII</ENAMEX> doesn't prohibit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">propositioning</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> or exposing one's genitals to them.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> might have a better case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
if she wants to make it--and if her story is true. She was visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> in search of a job when he allegedly pawed her.

            Even if completely true, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> tale is one of consensual sex, not harassment. The relationship
it describes may strike many as exploitative or ugly for other reasons, but it
is not illegal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>
never claimed that her unpleasant encounters with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> constituted actionable
sexual harassment. She would have had difficulty proving in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
had created an "abusive working environment," because she never complained
about his harassment and maintained her friendship with him even after she left
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EEOC</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> Volume discount? There is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> public accusation
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>. (Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, though, were prepared to testify against him and
didn't get the chance.) There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> public accusations against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9 Addiction</ENAMEX>: Following the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal, much has
been made of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged "sexaholism," his pathological inability to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> his sexual appetites. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> is accused of having a problem keeping his
hands off pornography. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abramson</ENAMEX>, his viewing pleasures
included films such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Adventures of Bad Mama Jama</ENAMEX> , about the
interracial sexcapades of an obese black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. They also say he papered the
walls of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> with nude centerfolds and meticulously maintained a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> collection. (Right-wing investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>
argues that many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abramson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for these allegations have
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">recanted/</ENAMEX>claim they were misquoted.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 Lying: Defenders</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have
argued that, even if true, the behavior they stand accused of is harmless.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>, especially, have said that making such a big deal over a few
crass remarks reflects the excesses of political correctness. But neither man
has attempted to defend the behavior he is accused of. Rather, both insist it
never happened. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> specifically and emotionally declared that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s tale,
if true, was repugnant and would disqualify him to sit on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> contrast his categorical denials of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s allegations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s evasive legalistic denials. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had done Jones no wrong,
they say, his dissembling bespeaks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> unfit for his job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say he cynically played the race card by accusing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of
conspiring to bring down an uppity black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Even if he had done <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> no
wrong, they say, his response bespeaks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> unfit for his job.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">11 Cover-up</ENAMEX>: If the allegations are true, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> lied
under oath about them--a criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also is accused of suborning
perjury. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> tapes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> allegedly says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> coached her
to deny a relationship. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> has reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX> not to testify about the encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>. No one has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused Thomas</ENAMEX> of trying to silence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>. (As the case arose, he had neither
the time nor the opportunity.)

            
               12 Special circumstances: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' alleged harassment is
deemed especially damning because it occurred while he headed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EEOC</ENAMEX> and was
simultaneously approving regulations for workplace harassment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say he should be reprimanded as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> or university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> facing
similar accusations would--by being removed from his job.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">13 Ideological</ENAMEX> cross-dressing: Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> seek to explain away their Jones-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> flip-flop. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Feminists</ENAMEX> say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> came forward at a time when nobody believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of sexual harassment.
Because they advocated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s cause, they say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of harassment now have
more credibility. Case in point: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> has no shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> and needs
no feminist help. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX> concede that their
attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> were indeed politically motivated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> explain the
table-turning by continuing to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s credibility and accusing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> of class bias against the "big-haired" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">14 Timing</ENAMEX>: The accusations against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> came when he was up for a job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> were about to vote on his
fitness for a lifetime appointment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--and they
would have had to vote even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> had not come forward with her tale.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, by contrast, is in a job. He is in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and
can be removed only by impeachment. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> argue that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> knew about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s alleged proclivities, if they didn't know the
details of any particular case, and implicitly accepted them when they elected
him twice.

            Others argue that a
presidential impeachment would be far more disruptive and costly to the nation
than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s rejection of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>; they say it
isn't worth it. This isn't exactly a defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged behavior, but
it has the same practical effect.

         
      
   
