
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clintons and the Mob</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Union of North America</ENAMEX> represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750,000</NUMEX> construction and
waste-removal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur A. Coia</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> is a
major contributor to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> causes, and also has had extensive social
dealings with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Early last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> allowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> to oversee a massive cleanup of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, rather than filing a
racketeering lawsuit, removing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coia</ENAMEX>, and putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> under government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX>' ties to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> have been studied often, most recently in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>
investigation begun during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1994</TIMEX> report of
that probe charged, among many other specifics, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coia</ENAMEX>, "have been controlled and influenced by organized crime
figures" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. Coia, whose entire career has been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>, is a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> thanks in part to real-estate dealings with his own.
His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was also a top union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who, according to federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, had long-standing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob contacts</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX>'s ties to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1993</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX> loaned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s inaugural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> rose to the union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidency</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> had numerous contacts with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> (which held hearings on this matter in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>) has issued
a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> "transactions" between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> extending
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May of this year</TIMEX>. These include watching an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> game together at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, receptions, bill signings, breakfasts, dinners, gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> (an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">autographed basketball</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, the book of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psalms</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>) and
an invitation (declined) from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> to join him on a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> invitation was relayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
Ickes, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who used to represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> also
aided <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> politically . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX> contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993 and 1994</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> broke
with most of the labor movement to support NAFTA. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coia</ENAMEX> personally contributed
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' legal defense fund, and helped organize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX>. He joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of "Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX>," a group of
prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> dedicated to responding to attacks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>'
integrity.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> was scheduled
to give a satellite address to top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX>' union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s organized-crime section recommended in a memo that she
"avoid direct contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX>, if possible." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1994</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> considered appointing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> to the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> on
competitiveness. It submitted his name to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> for a background check. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> warned that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> "is a criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Patriarca</ENAMEX>
organized crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" and was under confidential investigation. The
appointment was dropped. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks later</TIMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coia</ENAMEX> met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> to "share some thoughts and ideas," according to his thank-you
note. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> attended a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> dinner at which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> played the saxophone.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> received a handwritten note from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> thanking him for a "gorgeous"
custom-made golf club and congratulating him on becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>. The
same day, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> received a copy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s report concluding
that he was "controlled and influenced" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1995</TIMEX>, a week
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> addressed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX>' conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> (see photo),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> signed an agreement that gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
to clean up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> under government supervision rather than placing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX> under direct federal control.

            This agreement is central to the controversy. Did
Coia get special treatment because of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> connection? In more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> other racketeering cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> filed the case in court and
ultimately took over control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX>'
arrangement argue that it will clean up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> just as effectively, and at
less expense. Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">245</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who wrote a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Meese</ENAMEX> specifically
opposing a federal takeover of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX>, and
protesting the use of federal racketeering laws against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>.

            Since the agreement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> has
hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and several former federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to pursue the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> reform. So far, that effort has ousted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, put four
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> under a central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trusteeship</ENAMEX>, and overturned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> tainted local
elections. Federal field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> nevertheless have been quoted
(anonymously) saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> is still mobbed up. They say the government
has made a sweetheart deal that is simply allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> to purge his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>.

            At the subcommittee hearing,
the key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> testified that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> was not
involved in the settlement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX> in any way. No direct evidence to
the contrary was produced. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> has
had plenty of contacts with disreputable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> gladly
took endorsements from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longshoremen</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> that were
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> racketeering probes at the time.

         
      
   
