
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Allergies</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> predict that, thanks
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two years</TIMEX> will be the most allergy-ridden in history, a
fitting end to what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the worst century</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> ever. The
percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> has more than doubled
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 40 years</TIMEX>, according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> study. Meanwhile, as part of a
dizzying parade of allergy remedies, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> has
recently approved the over-the-counter sale of cromolyn sodium, a nasal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX>
trumpeted as the most effective nonprescription allergy combatant.

            
               What
are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX>? Who gets them? Is there any way to conquer them? Are they
really more prevalent than they used to be? Why hasn't natural selection
consigned this miserable condition to the dustbin of evolutionary history?

            Allergies share the same etiology: The immune

               system 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overreacts</ENAMEX> to the presence of harmless proteins normally
not found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first few</TIMEX> encounters with a foreign protein
(or allergen), the immune system catalogs its characteristics and tailors an
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> called immunoglobulin to purge it. Thereafter when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">allergen</ENAMEX> enters
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, the immunoglobulins send signals to trigger the release of a set of
nasty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, most notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">histamines</ENAMEX>, that destroy it. Side effects of
histamines include the tightening of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airways</ENAMEX>, constriction of nasal passages,
release of mucus, and redness of eyes. Nobody knows how much of an allergen it
takes to set off this process.

            Some
typological 
               distinctions : <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Allergies</ENAMEX> are technically different
from adverse reactions to poison ivy, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, and lactose, none of which
involves the immune system. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Allergies</ENAMEX> are also distinguishable from colds,
during which the immune system combats viruses that can actually do harm.

            
The most prevalent allergy is hay

               <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fever</ENAMEX> . (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX>'s estimate: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-six million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> suffer from the condition.) Here the immune system reacts to proteins
contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollen</ENAMEX>, tiny airborne particles released as part of the
reproductive cycle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX>, and grasses. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hay</ENAMEX> fever" comes down from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 19 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> who misplaced blame for their
ragweed <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> reaped during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> harvest.) Other common
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> include reactions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> found in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> , the
excrement 
               of 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mites</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva</ENAMEX> 
               of

               some warm-blooded mammals (<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a sidebar on
the myth of the nonallergenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.) Reactions to food afflict relatively few
and, except for shellfish and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">peanut allergies</ENAMEX>, are most common among small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            The
consequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> are usually no greater than sneezing, a stuffy nose,
and itchy eyes. But if you suffer from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> can cause an attack.
And in rare cases, allergic attacks can turn into anaphylaxis , where
toxic levels of histamines and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> are released, causing
asphyxiation, vomiting, and death. More common are infections triggered by
stuffy noses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Allergies inflame</ENAMEX> and clog a nose, precluding it
from draining mucus and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX> from sinuses and ears. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX> become a
breeding ground for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>. (An estimated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of ear infections stem
from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Allergies</ENAMEX> are genetically 
               linked . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX>
have correlated them with a single mutant gene inherited from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. But
statistics also point to the importance of other genes that come via the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX> percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> allergy-suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are
also allergic. With one afflicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>, there is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> chance of
inheritance; and when neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> is an allergy sufferer, there's still a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
percent chance.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Allergies</ENAMEX>
are spread evenly across ethnicity and gender. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX>, however, tend to
experience their effects in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly 10</NUMEX> year cycles . The worst period
usually occurs from birth through adolescence, and then recurs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-20s</TIMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another decade</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> can start at any time. And nobody has a clue
as to why they wax and wane.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollen</ENAMEX> has its own patterns. In the early part
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> emit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollen</ENAMEX>; from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> is the
main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>; from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> are. There's no escaping
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allergists</ENAMEX> say some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>) are better than
others (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>). But all are bad for at least a chunk of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tucson</ENAMEX>, once famed for their pure
desert air, are now corrupted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and grass imported as part of so-called
"civic improvement" projects. The lowest counts occur in coastal areas and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mountains</ENAMEX>, where wind tends to blow pollen away, although <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollen</ENAMEX> has been
detected <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far as 400 miles</NUMEX> out to sea and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two miles</NUMEX> up. (Other useful pollen
tips: During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollen</ENAMEX> counts tend to be lower before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX>, after
dark, and following <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>.)

            Every allergy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> seems
to be touted by the media as being the worst <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the books. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a
sampling of alarmist headlines from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>. ) And there is
much dispute over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niño</ENAMEX> will cause as much trouble as
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allergists</ENAMEX> predict. The claim is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> and mild temperatures
will cause <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> to be more fecund and produce more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollen</ENAMEX>. Also, lack of
winter freezes means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mites</ENAMEX> normally killed off by the cold will
survive.

            Allergy
treatment is a burgeoning sector of the economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annually</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.4 billion</NUMEX> is
spent on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> visits . There is plenty of room for
growth--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only an estimated 12 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay fever sufferers</ENAMEX> seek medical
treatment. New <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> debut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every year</TIMEX>. (Recently, there has been a rush
to fill the vacuum left by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antihistamine Seldane</ENAMEX>, which was yanked from the
market after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seldane</ENAMEX> reacted adversely with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.) None of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antihistamines</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegra, Claritin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zyrtec</ENAMEX>) seems to be consistently more effective than the others. All relieve
symptoms in a vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>, immunotherapy shots
attack the underlying problem, not just the symptoms. Each week <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are
injected with a small dose of allergens to build their immunity. Studies show
the shots cure <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> of treatment. But
they are a huge hassle and costly--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $1,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            Why hasn't natural 
               selection corrected the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>'s misguided response? Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> afflict an increasing
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> if they serve no useful purpose? A few theories:

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Victorious Immune System</ENAMEX>: Evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> speculate that a
hypersensitive immune system was needed back when parasites were ubiquitous and
deadly. Hay fever was the small cost of survival. And since <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> rarely
shorten life spans or discourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>, it is unlikely natural selection will
ever weed them out.

            
               Theory
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leisure System</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and hygiene have licked most of the
major problems that used to preoccupy our immune system. Now, with nothing to
regularly contend with, this theory argues, the system is set off by the most
harmless foreign particle.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Western-Style Living: Here</ENAMEX> blame goes to the advent of poorly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ventilated</ENAMEX>, densely populated living spaces--allergy traps--and the increased
popularity of domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>. In addition, there is the onset of pollution,
which carries <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mites</ENAMEX>.

            
               Hypochondria: More
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are allergic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> because more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are diagnosed as allergic rather
than as suffering from colds. The cynical spin is that pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
have duped the public into believing that they have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> and need <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to
fix them.

         
      
   
