
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Early this month</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in retaliation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s invasion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish</ENAMEX>
city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irbil</ENAMEX>. Who are the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>, and why do they feature so often in news stories
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>?

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 20</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>--one of the largest ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in the world
without its own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Almost the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> lives in a
mountainous area that covers eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and northwestern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, as well as slivers of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armenia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azerbaijan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> nomads, call this region <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdistan</ENAMEX> , and
have lived there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 2,000 years</TIMEX>.

            Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> consider
themselves a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, they share neither a common language nor a common
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish</ENAMEX> consists of several mutually unintelligible dialects,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linguistic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX>, the language of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. The vast majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sunni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, but there are also <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiites</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zoroastrians</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and others.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>
have spent most of the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millennia</ENAMEX> fighting against, or allying with,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Persians</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>. They joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> crusades
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saladin</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> who recaptured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, was
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurd</ENAMEX>). They have ruled their own mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">kingdoms</ENAMEX> at various points in
history. More recently, they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">empires</ENAMEX>.

            The history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> has been one of almost constant warfare and disappointment, as they
have sought autonomy--with little success--in each of their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> principal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homelands</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> of what is now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> were promised a state after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War I</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kemal Atatürk</ENAMEX> annexed them. With <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">help</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> founded
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mahabad</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shah</ENAMEX> crushed it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a year later</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> have been warring for autonomy since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. Today, separatist
movements continue in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> number
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 4 million</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 15 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The recent
Kurdish unrest is rooted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years</TIMEX> of rebellion, betrayal, and defeat.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between the early 1930s and 1975</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mulla Mustafa Barzani</ENAMEX> repeatedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">warred</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. He and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish Democratic Party</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDP</ENAMEX>) controlled much of northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> points, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
government even granted the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> some autonomy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. That arrangement
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soured</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barzani</ENAMEX> again took up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, this time backed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> signed a peace accord with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> and immediately abandoned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDP</ENAMEX>. So did the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> smashed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> uprising. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barzani</ENAMEX> left for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
where he died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> split into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barzani</ENAMEX>'s son
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moussad</ENAMEX> took over the clannish, conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDP</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jalal Talabani</ENAMEX>
founded the urban, vaguely leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriotic Union of Kurdistan</ENAMEX>

               (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUK</ENAMEX>) .

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> war of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> revived the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDP</ENAMEX> made common cause
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> savaged the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> razed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, massacred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, and
forcibly relocated many more to southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. A poison-gas attack on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Halabja</ENAMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 7,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years later</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> rose again at the urging of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in the
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> stomped them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> intervened only when
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> surged toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
borders. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> delivered humanitarian
aid, established a no-fly zone, and pressured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> to withdraw from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish</ENAMEX>
territory. With Western help, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> elected a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.
Based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irbil</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> split evenly between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUK</ENAMEX>.

            Democracy
didn't last. With no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iraqis</ENAMEX> to fight, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> turned on each other .
Civil war broke out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> were killed before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> brokered a peace in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. That peace collapsed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUK</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> conduct an incursion into northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barzani</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDP</ENAMEX>, in
turn, asked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s help (even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> had slaughtered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barzani</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> accepted the invitation. On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUK</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irbil</ENAMEX>. This raid inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> cruise<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-missile</ENAMEX> strikes on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern Iraq</ENAMEX>. After securing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irbil, Barzani</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> quickly routed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUK</ENAMEX> from
its other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strongholds</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talabani</ENAMEX> fled to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> border, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUK</ENAMEX> is all but
defunct. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barzani</ENAMEX> insists that he's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s puppet, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
have withdrawn to the south. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have settled in; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish Parliament</ENAMEX> has collapsed; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> doubt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDP</ENAMEX> can resist
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bullying</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> constitute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. In his effort to build nationalism across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atatürk</ENAMEX> instituted a campaign to suppress <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> identity that
continues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Teaching and broadcasting in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> are banned. And as
recently as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> jailed for treason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who expressed
mild pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> sentiments. This suppression has helped legitimize the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish Workers' Party</ENAMEX> (PKK) , a quasi-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> guerrilla <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champions Kurdish</ENAMEX> autonomy. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of
between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000 and 10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> have been waging a vicious war against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 18,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
died. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKK</ENAMEX> has murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> who teach <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> who side
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKK</ENAMEX> has also bombed
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> classify the PKK
as a terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> has
responded with equal brutality. It has "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">de-Kurdified</ENAMEX> " much of
southeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, bulldozing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 2,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> and forcing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> to move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>. And since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> have invaded northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times to destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKK</ENAMEX> bases.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> are much quieter than those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> constitute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 10</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>; their culture and language are much closer to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s than they are to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s; and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have
permitted them limited cultural expression, though no political autonomy. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish Democratic Party</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> (KDPI) joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayatollah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khomeini</ENAMEX>'s revolution, but he quickly snuffed any hope for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> autonomy.
His <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter planes</ENAMEX> crushed a budding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance movement</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has assassinated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDPI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX>, the
government and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUK</ENAMEX> raided KDPI hideouts in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. This assault, in
turn, helped reignite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUK</ENAMEX>'s war with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDP</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
