
   
   
      
         
            Did She Know?

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
Foer

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 4</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholicism</ENAMEX> and that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> declared, "This was obviously a major surprise to me. I have never
been told this." Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find that hard to believe. No one criticizes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twice-over</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazism</ENAMEX>, then from
Communism), for how they chose to put their lives back together. But there is
lively debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s insistence that her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> roots are "a major
surprise."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doubters</ENAMEX> point, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, to
circumstantial evidence . How could someone as intelligent and
well-versed in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> history as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> (her Ph.D. work focused on
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central European</ENAMEX> politics) not have deduced her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s ancestry
from what we know she knew?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josef</ENAMEX>
Korbel , was a foreign-service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in the liberal interwar
Czechoslovakian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Just after she was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>, he was posted to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. But he was recalled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years later</TIMEX>,
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> Pact essentially made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. Instead
of going home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Korbel</ENAMEX> moved his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech</ENAMEX>
government-in-exile.

            After the
war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> and learned, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> says, that her three
living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> had died. Korbel was briefly the postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, but when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> ousted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> fled to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> knew all this. What she did not know until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>,
she says, is that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> grew up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> and converted to
Catholicism only sometime around the outbreak of the war. And her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandparents</ENAMEX>, along with almost all her other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, died in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> death
camps.

            Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> have intuited
these omissions? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> say her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' story begs obvious
questions :

            Why did a midlevel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat harbor</ENAMEX> enough fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> persecution to uproot his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>? Korbel was a liberal, but not necessarily prominent or active enough
to worry--for that reason alone--about getting singled out.

            Why did <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandparents</ENAMEX> and most of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> die during the war? It's not clear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>
ever received an explanation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Korbel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> were especially
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incongruous</ENAMEX> because gentiles generally suffered less during <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> occupation in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> than in other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            There's
also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s relationship with her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> , who still
lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dagmar Simova</ENAMEX>, has been the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s main source of
information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s wartime experience. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> during the war,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Simova</ENAMEX> survived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, living with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korbels</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simova</ENAMEX> doesn't strongly
identify as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, but has never been under any misapprehension about her
ethnic identity. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simova</ENAMEX> discovered the truth about the wartime atrocities
almost immediately afterward, including her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' deaths in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auschwitz</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korbels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simova</ENAMEX> continued to correspond
after the war, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simova</ENAMEX> met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> briefly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> just after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvet</ENAMEX>
Revolution in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. For reasons unknown, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> has rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simova</ENAMEX>'s
attempts to set up more meetings, though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simova</ENAMEX> is her only surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech</ENAMEX>
relative. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simova</ENAMEX> never mention that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, when living with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korbels</ENAMEX> or during subsequent sporadic communications? Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> not
wonder why this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> was living with them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, or what had happened to
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> says her parents
expressed vivid recollections of childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter and Christmas</ENAMEX>
celebrations . These recollections may well have been true. The elder
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korbels</ENAMEX> came from a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> border where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were
almost entirely assimilated into secular life, hardly practicing, and lacking
any communal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX>.

            A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> reason some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> could have been blindsided by her own life story
is that since she has risen to prominence , the suggestion that she is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX> has been raised repeatedly. Rumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> background have
been circulated ever since she was appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.
A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1996</TIMEX> article in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Hayat</ENAMEX> , an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> published in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, asserted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, would be a dangerously pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>. But less tendentious media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> have also reported on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s ethnic background. Multiple stories about it have appeared, for
example, in major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letohrad</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josef Korbel</ENAMEX> grew up, says he sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> three
letters in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. The letters included recollections of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
the clippings from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> alleging her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> heritage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> says
that she received several other similar letters as well. But she says they
contained too many factual errors and inconsistencies for her to take them
seriously.

            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have come across the facts
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s background that she says she never knew. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> official
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had been <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> say
they have encountered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who recall reading press reports from the late
'40s about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josef Korbel</ENAMEX> was a minor celebrity
during his stints there, and his conversion to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholicism</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>'
deaths in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> were reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s papers.

            According to the New York
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> preparing for her confirmation
hearings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> that she suspected her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> had been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>. That was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> story ran.

         
      
   
