
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fetal Viability</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Viability</ENAMEX>" has become the
focus of the abortion debate. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>'s bill banning the abortion of "viable fetuses." But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> hailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX>'s bill as the great compromise that
might settle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter century</TIMEX> of arguments about abortion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forty-one</ENAMEX> states
already restrict the abortion of viable fetuses. What is a viable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>? How is
the concept of viability relevant to the moral and legal issues of
abortion?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">vs. Wade</ENAMEX> , the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> case legalizing abortion, made fetal viability an
important legal concept . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled that states cannot put
the interests of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> ahead of the interests of the pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> until the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fetus</ENAMEX> is "viable." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> defined viable to mean capable of prolonged life
outside the mother's womb. It said this included fetuses that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> expected
to be sustained by respirators. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> accepted the conventional medical
wisdom that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> becomes viable at the start of the last <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of a
pregnancy, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> trimester, sometime between the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">24 th</NUMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 th week</TIMEX> (a pregnancy usually lasts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38 weeks</TIMEX>). Because the point of
viability varies, the court ruled, it could only be determined case by case and
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>. Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is viable, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> said, states
could not outlaw an abortion if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s life or health was at stake.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Day O'Connor</ENAMEX> argued in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> decision that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> was on a "collision course with itself." She said that
improvements in technology would continually push the point of fetal
viability closer to the beginning of the pregnancy, allowing states greater
opportunity to regulate the right to an abortion. And this seems to be the
case--up to a point. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> now believe a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> can become viable during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 rd week</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week earlier</TIMEX> than was thought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 years ago</TIMEX>. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> will only perform abortions through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 22 nd week</TIMEX> of
pregnancy.

            But no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> has ever been successfully delivered before the middle of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 nd week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babies</ENAMEX> delivered during the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> nd and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 rd weeks</TIMEX> weigh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just over a pound</NUMEX>. Their lungs have barely
formed and their airways are not developed enough to inhale. Circulation
depends on the use of ventilators and injections of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> born
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 22 nd week</TIMEX> has a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.8 percent</NUMEX> chance of survival. And
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> are brain-damaged, either by lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> (from
poor initial respiration) or too much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> (from the ventilator).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neonatologists</ENAMEX> predict that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> will ever be viable before the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 nd week</TIMEX>, because before then the lungs are not fully formed.

            
Probability of survival increases for babies
born later in pregnancy: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 23 rd week</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 th week</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 th week</TIMEX>. By the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 th week</TIMEX>, when a newborn doesn't require a ventilator to breathe,
it has a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> chance of survival. And only after the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 th</NUMEX> week
do the risks of long-term brain damage begin to substantially subside. Because
premature babies depend on technology, survival rates vary based on access
to that technology . For instance, in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, which commonly lack
expensive infant intensive-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, survival rates in these early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> are
much lower.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Doctors</ENAMEX>
assess a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>'s viability by attempting to guess whether its lungs have
formed. Sonograms allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to estimate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>'s weight, which
correlates with the lungs' development, and to look for signs--such as the
development of functioning eyelids and creases in the skin--that
coincide with the onset of a functioning respiratory system. None of the
methods for predicting viability are very precise.

            Despite important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decisions since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>
modifying the doctrine of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s thinking about fetal
viability has remained fairly constant . The only significant revision
came in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casey</ENAMEX> decision (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>), which made viability even more
important. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> said that state laws could require a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and her doctor
to perform tests to prove that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is not viable before she obtains an
abortion.

            Forty-one
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now have laws restricting post-viability abortions. Some allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
to decide for themselves if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is viable. Some require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to
perform tests to prove a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is pre-viable and require multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to
certify the findings. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have banned the procedure called intact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dilation</ENAMEX> and extraction (IDE)--also known as partial-birth abortion --in
the belief that this procedure is used mainly post-viability.

            
Banning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IDEs</ENAMEX> nationwide is a major goal of the
pro-life movement. Movement adherents claim that the IDE procedure--in which
delivery is induced, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>'s skull is crushed, and its brains are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suctioned</ENAMEX>--amounts to infanticide. Barring this procedure is also the only
regulation of abortion that public-opinion polls say has a majority of
support. Pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choicers</ENAMEX> say the ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDEs</ENAMEX> is inconsistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> ,
because the procedure can be used to abort pre-viable fetuses.

            Some medical ethicists
and constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> was wrong to create
the pre-viability/post-viability distinction in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. Why, they ask,
does the fact that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> can survive outside the womb with the help of vast
medical technology change either of the interests at war in the abortion
debate: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>'s own claim to "human-ness" and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s right to control
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>? Even if viability is an important moral line, is it drawn in the
right place? Keeping alive a baby born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 22 nd week</TIMEX> costs
several <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> and usually fails, regardless of the
effort.

            The fuss over post-viability
abortions ultimately concerns only a very small number of procedures .
Less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> percent of all abortions performed take place after the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st week</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1,070</NUMEX> abortions were performed after the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 th week</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
