
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> has asked all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> to observe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 16</TIMEX>, as a
"day of atonement," and to stay home from work or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to fast and repent.
His appeal was largely ignored, in contrast to his call to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Million Man</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March two years ago</TIMEX>, which drew <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 400,000</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> to the
National <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> Many predicted the sect's political power and
membership would burgeon after the march. Has this happened? What sort of
cultural and political influence does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> currently wield?

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '20s</TIMEX> by traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace D. Fard</ENAMEX>,
whose preachings combined Islam with an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afrocentric</ENAMEX> cosmology. He taught that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> are descended from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shabbaz</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> that came from the moon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trillion</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> , and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> were the laboratory concoction of
Yakub, an evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elijah Muhammad</ENAMEX> assumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the sect
after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fard</ENAMEX>'s death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>, proclaiming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fard</ENAMEX> an incarnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allah</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">himself Fard</ENAMEX>'s prophet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, headquartered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, grew rapidly
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '50s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '60s</TIMEX> thanks largely to proselytizing by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X. Temples</ENAMEX> appeared in major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, drawing mainly the young and the
poor. Heavyweight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassius Clay</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> and changed
his name to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX> .

            After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elijah Muhammad</ENAMEX>'s death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>
Deen was named his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>. The very next year, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Deen</ENAMEX> disbanded
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>; rescinded most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s teachings; became an observant Sunni
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muslim</ENAMEX>; and set up a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, which he still leads, the World
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Islam</ENAMEX> . Soon after, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stalwart</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">calypso singer</ENAMEX>, re-established the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in line with its
original tenets. With his provocative speeches, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> receives more
attention than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Deen</ENAMEX>--most notably his reference to Judaism as "a gutter
religion" and his declaration that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was "a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> remain loyal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Deen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> groups
squabble over the legitimacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>'s claim to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muhammad</ENAMEX>'s true
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>.

            The nation
closely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> the scale of its operations. Estimates fix membership between
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000 and 200,000</NUMEX>. Close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> agree that the sect's membership has not
grown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX>. And according to the best guesses, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> runs
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 50</NUMEX> mosques and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> on college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>. Nobody is
sure how much real estate or how many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> it owns. Court papers
confirm that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> runs a newspaper (the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Call</ENAMEX> ), a toiletry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> produce <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, and a private securities
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX> lawsuits were filed against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1986 and 1996</TIMEX> demanding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.9 million</NUMEX> in back payments.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> received unprecedented attention in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994 and 1995</TIMEX> following a publicized speech by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nation spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid</ENAMEX>
Muhammad about a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nation speakers</ENAMEX> soon appeared on major
college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>, grabbing headlines and sparking confrontations between black
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The strident defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> by middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bespoke Farrakhan</ENAMEX>'s growing popularity with the black bourgeoisie.

            Interest
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> seems to correlate with the negative media it generates.
Following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Wallace</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> television documentary on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hate</ENAMEX>
That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hate Produced</ENAMEX> , and denunciations of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> presidential candidate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> for failing to repudiate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>, membership in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> rose.

            Upon re-creating the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> repealed Elijah
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muhammad</ENAMEX>'s prohibition on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s participation in electoral politics.
Aside from maintaining relationships with black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">perennial New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX> , he has announced grander
designs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> says he is interested in becoming a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> and
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> will begin fielding its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            A paucity of charismatic
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> has helped focus attention on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s brand
of black nationalism, which emphasizes self-help, jibed with growing black
frustration with the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. Yet the nation
failed to parlay its biggest public-relations success--the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1995</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Million Man</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> --into greater influence and membership. The march is
credited with having boosted black self-esteem, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-hour</TIMEX>,
meandering speech at the march alienated potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. Especially
disconcerting was said to be his lengthy disquisition on numerology. Many
accounts of the march downplayed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s presence. For evidence, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX> 's docudrama about the march, Get on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bus</ENAMEX> , which
contains few references to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>.

            A
recurring battle with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> has debilitated the 64-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>. (He markets his own remedies, which include a controversial,
developed-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>, through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX> grocers.) Though
he continues to tour regularly, his speeches are said to have become less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">charismatic</ENAMEX> and less appealing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rally</ENAMEX> attendance is much scantier today
than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994 and 1995</TIMEX>, and he wins far fewer headlines than he did then.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>'s foreign-policy adventures in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> following the march also discredited him. Especially damning is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>'s close relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar al-Qaddafi</ENAMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qaddafi</ENAMEX> promised the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1-billion</NUMEX> gift, which has not been
received because of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>. Black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">editorialized</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>'s visits with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> has recently considered leaning toward the mainstream right to
expand its influence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> , supply-side evangelist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jude Wanniski</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> have all praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>'s
self-help program, noting the similarities to their own conservative urban
policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanniski</ENAMEX>, who invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> to a conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>, argues
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">-nation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> could guarantee an unbeatable electoral
majority for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanniski</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> have been drubbed by the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.M. Rosenthal</ENAMEX>, and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> for their flirtations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>.

            Taking an ecumenical tack, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nation officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>
recently issued edicts commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preachers</ENAMEX> to back off their anti-Semitic
rhetoric. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last spring</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> also recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Muhammad</ENAMEX> (a k a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Chavis</ENAMEX> ), an ordained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Church of Christ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> and
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX>. Chavis was ousted after revelations that he used
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> funds to settle sexual-harassment suits filed against him by former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chavis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> both argue that Christianity and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incompatible</ENAMEX>, and many predict that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chavis</ENAMEX> will ultimately
succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s promotion of
black capitalism has not translated into financial success. Many of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are deep in debt and owe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> products--its purported <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> cure, for instance--have
undermined their claim that black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are less exploitative than white
ones. Meanwhile, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> gripe that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> and his closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> live in opulence, owning multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and
driving luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
