
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> has replaced the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild West</ENAMEX> as the movie industry's great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> myth. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>-released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> to commemorate its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> anniversary, The 
               Godfather
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">depicts Mafiosi</ENAMEX> ruling a sprawling business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>. More recent
films present images of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> in decline: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacino</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster character</ENAMEX> loots parking <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meters</NUMEX> to earn his keep. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next month</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> will air <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Don</ENAMEX> , an adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Puzo</ENAMEX>'s latest novel.
What is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>'s role in real life, and how has it changed over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> for "refuge"), also called <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">la cosa nostra</ENAMEX> ("our thing"), began
as a clandestine partisan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sicily</ENAMEX> ,
combating a series of foreign invasions. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18 th century</TIMEX>, it had
evolved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s unofficial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It retained its paramilitary
tactics and insularity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mafiosi</ENAMEX> called their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>," and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> took a blood oath). During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX>, the group
turned criminal. It terrorized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landowners</ENAMEX> who didn't regularly
pay protection.

            At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> attempted to
replicate its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sicilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. It
initially succeeded only in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> had
established "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>) in most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian-American</ENAMEX> enclaves, even in
midsized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX> Extorting protection
payments continued to be its primary function. Only during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX>
did it branch out of ethnic neighborhoods and into bootlegging, gambling, and
prostitution. However, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>--the largest bastions of
organized crime--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> (not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sicilian Mafiosi</ENAMEX>) dominated. In
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1930s</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer Lansky</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lucky</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano</ENAMEX> set up a national
crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicate</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the most powerful organized-crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> to mediate
disputes and plan schemes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> played only a minor role.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> 's depiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> strength in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '40s</TIMEX> is largely
accurate. Because of its committed, disciplined rank and file and economic base
in extortion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> emerged as the dominant organized-crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to
survive <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX>'s repeal. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> took control of the
Lansky-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicate</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s and '50s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> also firmed up
relationships with urban political machines (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> openly
sought their support), police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover</ENAMEX> denied
the existence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> and refused to investigate it). City <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
helped <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> government contracts and turned a blind eye to other rackets. Many
of the scams depended on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>'s increasing control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, especially
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longshoremen's</ENAMEX> .

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>'s power has steadily declined
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '50s</TIMEX> . In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the number of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>" or
"wise-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> "--the ones who take the blood oath--has dwindled. According
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Police Department</ENAMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 750</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> is
said to rely increasingly on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobsters</ENAMEX> who have not taken an oath.
Often this consists of alliances with other ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
ones.

            In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 10 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> have been devastated by arrests . For
instance, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> busted the bulk of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--one of
the most powerful and impenetrable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> describes once-thriving operations
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, and other major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> as virtually
defunct. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s organized-crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are now locked up.

            Only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> have substantial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Mafia</ENAMEX> consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gambino</ENAMEX>,
Genovese, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucchese, Bonanno</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombo</ENAMEX>) that have sometimes cooperated,
sometimes competed with one another. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1992</TIMEX> arrest of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Gotti , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gambino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most powerful. However,
it has been replaced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genovese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, which has recently suffered fewer
arrests. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genoveses</ENAMEX>, too, are in trouble. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent "Chin" Gigante</ENAMEX> , was recently indicted and has been said to be
mentally unstable--he used to wander <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Greenwich Village</ENAMEX> in his pajamas, mumbling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incoherently</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucchese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bonanno</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> merged gambling activities last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> to compensate for thinning ranks.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> estimate that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicate</ENAMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outfit</ENAMEX>" has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> strength. After a series of convictions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'80s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outfit</ENAMEX> lost
its control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>-gambling revenue to legitimate business.

            In spite
of declining numbers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> remains profitable . According to the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York City Police Department</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> pocketed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> from
gambling alone. Loan-sharking also continues to be lucrative. However, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>'s other activities have radically changed. For instance, its biggest
extortion schemes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> area have been broken up: It no longer
controls wholesale <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> broke its hold on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fulton Fish Market</ENAMEX>)
or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>'s garbage-removal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cartel</ENAMEX>. According to the New York
Times , it has adapted to the losses by shifting to white-collar
crime . Major new scams include collaboration with small brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in
stock-tampering schemes, and the manufacturing of faulty prepaid telephone
calling cards sold at convenience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> propose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> explanations for the
decline:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Increased federal
enforcement . Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoover</ENAMEX>'s death, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> did not aggressively
investigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>. In addition, starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX> federal
(<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">RICO</ENAMEX>), passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, to charge top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob bosses</ENAMEX> with extortion.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> cleaned
up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">As late as 1986</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>
controlled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Longshoremen's Association</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant Employees</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Teamsters union</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Union</ENAMEX>. However, subsequent government supervision of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unions</ENAMEX>
has reduced mob involvement.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The rise of black
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> politics destroyed the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> machines the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> once depended upon
to carry out its rackets.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Assimilation :
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>- and third-generation <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sicilians</ENAMEX>, who now control the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>, place less
emphasis on the omertà --the code of silence that precludes snitching.
Turncoats have provided the decisive evidence in recent cases against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gotti</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> failed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> the drug trade . <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Asian</ENAMEX> mobsters more
efficiently import cheaper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and eschew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>. In
addition, many predict the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>, operating out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, will soon
replace the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s largest organized-crime outfit.

         
      
   
