
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Biggest Tax Increase in History</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> imposed the biggest tax increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
disagree, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> himself is responsible for the biggest tax increase in
history: a massive tax bill he engineered as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. Who's right? The answer turns on so many metaphysical questions as to
be nearly meaningless. Nevertheless, the issue will be central to the fall
campaign.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax</ENAMEX> Equity and
Fiscal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Responsibility Act of 1982</ENAMEX> (TEFRA) fashioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and the
Omnibus <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993</ENAMEX> (OBRA-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>) pushed through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> were projected, at the time of passage, to raise almost
exactly the same amounts of revenue. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> measure was estimated by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Committee on Taxation</ENAMEX> to increase the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>'s take over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$235 billion</NUMEX>. The revenue parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s bill were projected to
produce <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$241 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. But these numbers need to be
adjusted.

            

               Inflation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1982 and 1993</TIMEX>, as measured by the GDP deflator, eroded
the value of the dollar by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a third</NUMEX>. Measured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> dollars, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
tax increase would be worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only about $165 billion</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 billion</NUMEX> less than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s.

            On the other hand, most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s tax increase was actually
the partial repeal of future tax cuts that had been enacted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> but
had not yet taken place. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s bill, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $375</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in tax cuts over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following three years</TIMEX>. (This did not deter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s supply-side <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>, from characterizing his bill as a
record-setting tax boost.) Whether repeal of a future tax cut counts as a tax
increase is a metaphysical question. If the answer is "no," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tax
increase is larger.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> promised a middle-class tax cut and
delivered a tax increase instead. That is not quite right. A promise to
increase taxes on the affluent was, in fact, a central feature of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> campaign. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost two-thirds</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63 percent</NUMEX>) of the projected
revenues in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tax increase hit high-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $140,000</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $115,000</NUMEX>). Most of this came from an increase in
the top income-tax rate. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Another 15 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s revenue came from
tax increases on business , primarily a rise in the corporate income-tax
rate and new limits on the deduction for entertainment expenses. These also
were campaign promises made and kept, not broken. (By interesting contrast, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s increased revenues came from business, primarily in
the form of closing loopholes and ending special favors included in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">tax-cut bill.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s bill, while raising business taxes somewhat overall,
introduced a variety of special business preferences.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also reduced the income-tax exclusion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> with incomes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">above $44,000</NUMEX> per couple
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34,000</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>). Whether increasing the portion of a government
benefit check that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> reclaims in taxes amounts to a payment
reduction or a tax increase is another metaphysical question. So is the issue
of whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$44,000</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-and-a-half</NUMEX> times the median
family income--in retirement counts as "affluent."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> bill
increased the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Clintonites</ENAMEX> wish to count this as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> tax cut . The EITC
is supposed to help relieve the burden of payroll taxes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>), and is "refundable" (paid in cash) to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who owe less in income
tax than the tax credit is worth. Whether a government check intended to
mitigate a tax burden amounts to a tax cut or a spending increase is yet
another metaphysical question.

            The
only part of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> tax bill that directly affected middle-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.3-cent</NUMEX>-per<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-gallon</NUMEX> boost in the gasoline tax . This cost the
average family <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 10 percent</NUMEX> of the total
revenue raised. Nevertheless, it was a middle-class tax increase, not a
middle-class tax cut. (Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> act didn't raise gas taxes, only a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacted a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5-cent</NUMEX>-a-gallon increase in the gas tax
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s approval.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> last metaphysical question. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Almost $50 billion</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> projected revenue was supposed to come from cracking down on tax
cheats , by adding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">financial institutions</ENAMEX> to
withhold interest and dividends the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> withhold wages. (This
provision was repealed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>, before it could take effect.) Is getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to pay taxes they already owe but would otherwise escape a "tax
increase"? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> probably would have said "of course not." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> has called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> an "intrusive, oppressive presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
life," and has pledged to cut its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, meanwhile,
has already announced that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> jobs will be eliminated, with more layoffs
to come.

            Campaign assertions about
how much the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s taxes have increased under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should
be regarded with suspicion. (a) Averages obscure the fact that most of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tax increase did fall on the affluent. The typical middle-class
family paid only the new gas tax. (b) Most of the increased tax revenue from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> reflects higher income, not higher tax rates. (c) As a share of
GDP, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> now takes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 cents</NUMEX> on the dollar. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Molinari</ENAMEX> used this
figure in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican Convention</ENAMEX> keynote address to illustrate the burden of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tax increase. But the increase in this figure is due entirely to the
rise in state and local taxes. As a share of GDP, federal taxes have been
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> stable under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Previous Gist columns

         
      
   
