
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lying Lawyers</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lawyer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bennett</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> heatedly declared that the allegations concerning the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>, and others were
"scurrilous" products of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> haters." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> in particular "has no case.
... She was never harassed."

            It is
possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> actually believes his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s story on all these
matters. But suppose, like almost everyone else, he believes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
lying to some degree. Is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> free to tell, with as much passion as he
cares to muster, something he believes to be a lie?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, has made a
"proffer ": In exchange for immunity from prosecution, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> will
testify under oath that she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had sex. So far, Special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosecutor Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has not accepted the proffer. Without a deal, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> free to revert to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s earlier sworn testimony that she and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did not have sex? Having offered to tell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> version of events,
may a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> really choose to tell a contradictory version--as if the offer had
never existed?

            
Officially, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>'s model code of professional
responsibility forbids a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> to "knowingly make a false statement of law or
fact." The code forbids <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> from making any statement, true or
false, outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> that has a "substantial likelihood" of "materially
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prejudicing</ENAMEX>" a trial. In practice, however, these restrictions melt
away .

            
Alawyer may not knowingly lie, but he or she is
under no obligation to know the truth or to draw logical inferences from what
he or she does know. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> was rarely at the scene of the crime, she
can plausibly maintain that she doesn't know for sure what happened--and is
therefore free to argue whatever version of events best suits her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> . Indeed, in the absence of that very rare absolute certainty, the
ethical obligation of "zealous advocacy" virtually requires a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> to
argue his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s version of events--however implausible. To guard against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">certainty</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> take the precaution of not asking their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to say
exactly what happened--or even of asking them not to say what happened.

            Lying
really only arises as an issue in the absurd warhorse of law school ethics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exams</ENAMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> who simultaneously confesses to a crime and insists on
testifying that he is innocent. The ethical issue, even here, is not whether
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is allowed to participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s lie but
whether he is actually required to do so. The answer is: not quite. If a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> knows with ontological certitude that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is planning to lie on the
stand, she is not allowed to report this to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. She is allowed to quit
the case. Or--to avoid being guilty of suborning perjury--she may put her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stand</ENAMEX> and let him testify without asking him specific questions
beyond "Tell your story."

            If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> finds that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> has "perpetrated a fraud
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>"--i.e., told a lie in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--the rules say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> should
inform the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, unless the information was told to him in confidence or
secret. But, of course, just about everything that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> ever tells a lawyer
is a secret or a confidence . Similarly, there appear to be specific and
severe rules forbidding "extrajudicial" remarks, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' statements to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> about a pending case. But the reality is better characterized by the
conduct of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>. It is almost unheard of for anyone to get into
trouble for giving interviews when a case is pretrial. The rule requires a
"substantial" chance of "material" impact on the case, both of which are nearly
impossible to prove.

            Just to
make sure they are not violating the rules against lying, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> can choose
their words carefully . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> clearly intended to communicate that his
position is the same as his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> stories
are all false. But his words can be interpreted--if necessary--to mean
something else. For example, he could be saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> was not harassed
because her description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior, even if true, doesn't fit the
technical definition of harassment. To say that allegations are "scurrilous" is
not necessarily to say that they are false. And so on.

            
In a proffer session, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>, or
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> provides the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX> with a preview of the
evidence he or she could provide or the testimony they would give. The
prosecution is invited to buy this information with leniency.

            Proffers
are increasingly common in the criminal justice system, especially since the
enactment of federal sentencing guidelines in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, which substantially
restricted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s discretion in sentencing. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the few remaining ways to
obtain a coveted "downward departure"--a sentence below the official range--is
through cooperation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> . In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s case, lawyer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, rather than turning state's evidence after indictment, is asking for
immunity--a guarantee that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> will never face charges at all.
Unfortunately, this leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> trying to explain that if granted immunity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> will testify one way, and if indicted she'll stand by her deposition.
This does not do well for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s credibility.

            Normally, these discussions are kept secret. Not because
discussing them in public might violate the rules but because making proffers
public seldom makes tactical 
               sense . In discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
proffer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> either has already lied or will do so
in the future for the right deal. This doesn't look good.

            But these contradictions
cannot be used against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> at trial. The federal rules of criminal
procedure prohibit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> from using any statements made in furtherance
of a plea bargain, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s attempt to gain immunity is essentially a
form of plea bargaining. Additionally, most proffer sessions involve what is
known as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> for a day" agreement, under which both sides agree that
information discussed at such a session will not be admissible against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> at a trial. These protections, enacted to encourage truth before
trial, have the paradoxical effect , when publicized, of making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
appear crazy, mendacious, guilty, or some combination thereof.

         
      
   
