
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>

            When <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> suicide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombers</ENAMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> market <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> as irresponsibly soft on terrorism, withheld
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of dollars <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> owed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and ordered the
blockading of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> border. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> sanctions came the
same week that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> tendered their resignations. What is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>? Why does everybody agree that it is in crisis? What is the future of
the peace talks that established the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>
was born out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1993 Oslo Declaration of Principles</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Israel</ENAMEX> promised
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestine Liberation Organization</ENAMEX>--the self-styled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
government-in-exile--that it would withdraw from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX>,
territories captured from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> respectively in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1967 Six Day</ENAMEX>
War. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> accord also established a timetable for negotiations that would
lead to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s departure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">territories</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> on that timetable was a
plan for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jericho</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> with the largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>), then other major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> centers, then the
remainder of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territories</ENAMEX>. Under the plan, an interim government
organized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> was established to assume control of internal security and
civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>--education, garbage collection, etc. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> accord
predicated progress on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> holding democratic elections . May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> is
the deadline for an agreement over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that both parties claim as
their capital and which neither wants to share. May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> is also the deadline
for negotiations over full <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> withdrawal from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX> and West
Bank, as well as for what is ambiguously called the "final status" of security
and border arrangements.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stages of the withdrawal were completed
before negotiations stalled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> broke ground for a
housing project in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> controls the security and civil
government of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, in which <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 90 percent</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX> live. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> has no jurisdiction over the more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> living throughout the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territories</ENAMEX>. Their
future will probably be decided by the "final status" negotiations.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of personality guaranteed that nobody would challenge his
initial un-elected rule of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PA.</ENAMEX> Following the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> defeat in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> war, a
coalition of disparate guerrilla <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, and political parties
gradually coalesced into a single opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX>. A trained
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and longtime guerrilla, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> came to fame when he led a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> to victory over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> in a minor battle at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Karamah</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. He rose to the helm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> later that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> renounced its support of terrorism, causing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab League</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, to deem it the official
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>.

            
In his self-imposed exile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tunisia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>
was joined by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. When he returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza</ENAMEX> and the West
Bank in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, these "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tunisians</ENAMEX>" received the most important appointments
within the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>. Wealthy enough to have had the means to flee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, they began building villas and buying fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> upon their return,
provoking resentment among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> who have lived for
decades in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>-run refugee <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>.

            Recent
studies corroborate widespread suspicions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> corruption . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comptroller</ENAMEX> concluded that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> dollars had been siphoned
off for private use by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> have been blamed for
egregious abuses, leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> to call for the
resignation of the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> all but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> agreed to
step down, though many say it is unlikely they will ever actually do so.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>, notorious for his scruffiness, has a reputation for eschewing wealth,
and he has not been accused of personal wrongdoing. However, his undemocratic
attitude and predilection for political patronage are seen by many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>
as the ultimate root of the malfeasance.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oslo</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> dependent on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.
He has much to gain from the peace process: more power and land for his
government, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Also, under the accords, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>
nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> in taxes collected from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> who work and buy goods
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. This is the money that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> withheld <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, and it accounts
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>'s budget. The balance of the budget comes in
the form of donations from foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> also is
supporting several major public-works projects in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> territory, including the
construction of an airport and seaport in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza</ENAMEX>. These projects are crucial to
an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> economy. Currently, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 37,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>
commute <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> to jobs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> intend to withhold funds in the hopes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> will crack down on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> militant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. Specifically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> to
shut down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s most powerful domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, which is
purportedly responsible for the suicide bombing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> has a strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>. It controls mosques, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and a political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, all of which
predate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of its terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '80s</TIMEX>. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> reject <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> fundamentalism. According to polls, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 25</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> "support" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>, but they and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> alike avoid
criticizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, as doing so would be considered
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kowtowing</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

            
Conditions are ripe for discontent. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> economy has deteriorated during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>'s reign. Unemployment in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza</ENAMEX> is at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> took
over. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> per capita income has fallen to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,400</NUMEX> per year, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-tenth</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s. These economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s most vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. They
support the argument that the peace process is a failed experiment that should
be scrapped.

            
               Yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> remains popular --he won <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88 percent</NUMEX> of the vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s
presidential elections, and recent polls estimate his public-approval ratings
at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 65 percent</NUMEX>. He quashes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> with brutal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, arresting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militants</ENAMEX> and left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secularists</ENAMEX> who oppose him and shuttering newspapers
and television stations when they criticize him. Human-rights organizations
roundly criticize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, citing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> who have been tortured to
death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX> while in police custody.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>'s massive security
apparatus --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 80,000</NUMEX> strong--appears to be somewhat out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> security has resisted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> demands that it take action against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> and refused, on occasion, to cooperate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Forces</ENAMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> began constructing apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> security stopped relaying intelligence about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>'
terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>. This breakdown of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> cooperation is the basis for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> complaint that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> is culpable for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> bombing.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Israel</ENAMEX> also ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> to arrest one of its high-ranking police
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> for planning an attack on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">settlement</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> cracked
down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> after a string of bombings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, arresting
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,200</NUMEX> suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>, destroying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> safe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, and
confiscating its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> caches. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> is reluctant to reprise that police
action, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> say, because he believes that the threat of terrorism
is the only way to force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> to restart the peace talks. Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> closure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>'s borders further punishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> economy.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has threatened to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and crack
down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> say this would be akin to an act of
war.

         
      
   
