
   
   
      
         
            Book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishing</ENAMEX>

            Among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> it has become a cliché that book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> obsess over bottom lines at
the expense of serious literature. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publishers</ENAMEX> carp back that they can't turn a
profit, no matter what they do. The latest industry tumult is over the
resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Evans</ENAMEX>, who doled out mammoth
advances to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlon Brando</ENAMEX>, only to see
their books bomb. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s troubled book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>,
HarperCollins, canceled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106</NUMEX> book contracts to avoid big losses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Highbrow</ENAMEX> book
imprints have either been scaled back or sold off. Is publishing really in
crisis? Is the serious book dead? How has the industry changed? What are the
issues behind the publishing malaise?

            

               Conglomeratization: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX> publishing is
dominated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schuster</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bertelsmann AG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bantam Doubleday Dell</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advance Publications</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little, Brown</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearson PLC</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking Penguin</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holtzbrinck</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holt</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.W. Norton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> are among the few surviving big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">independents</ENAMEX>.

            Critics
say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> have damaged book publishing with their obsessive pursuit
of "blockbusters ." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">212</NUMEX> hardcovers sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100,000</NUMEX>
copies, establishing a new record. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> pay huge advances and
spend outrageous sums marketing these titles in the hope that they will top the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">best-seller</ENAMEX> lists. Critics also say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, who once patiently developed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, now spend more time marketing books than editing them, which results
in the production of longer, sloppier, less interesting books that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> spurn. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> are accused of having dumbed down books,
publishing titles that may be more easily adapted by their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX> opened an office in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Declining Sales and Profits: Most
conglomerates don't break out figures on their book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX>,
which does release <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>' figures, reports that the book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>'s
operating profit fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66 percent</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first six months</TIMEX> of fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 1997</TIMEX>. Industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> guess that most of the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bantam Doubleday Dell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>, turn <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 4 percent and 8 percent</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> profits--approximately the same percentage they have earned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX> and well below their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-percent to 15</TIMEX>-percent projections.

            Book
sales are stagnating . Sales grew by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 6 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The textbook and computer-book markets continue to boom, but hardcover
sales sag. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, they are off <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> . Some theorize a change in
leisure habits is behind the drop-off, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> shift their attention to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable TV</ENAMEX> and new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> like the Internet and computer games. But census data
reveal that time devoted to reading books continues to expand, with the average
person spending more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">100 hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> with the printed word. Also, the
book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> has boomed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">710 million</NUMEX> books were sold.
Those numbers grew to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">897 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.06 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. These
figures indicate that publishing isn't so much in crisis as it is in flux, and
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX>' financial expectations are unrealistic.

            

               Mega-Advances: The success of hit books
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatherhood</ENAMEX> , which set sales records, induced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX> to compete for blockbuster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>. In frenzied bidding wars ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX> award record advances. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to see a list of big ones.) Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of lesser-selling books now receive larger advances. Where a new book
would have received an advance of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $5,000 and $10,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, it now
gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $40,000 and $50,000</NUMEX>.

            Publishing
houses complain that big advances hurt profits. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> reported
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> in unearned advances on its books,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX>. Book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>
exaggerate the impact of advances, hoping thereby to drive the demand
for big advances down.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noblefication</ENAMEX>: The imagined
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX> age of publishing was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s and '40s</TIMEX>, when gentleman
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alfred A. Knopf</ENAMEX> published only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> they admired.
Book retailing was a genteel and polite profession, too, with few booksellers
owning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. All that changed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the postwar era</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paperback</ENAMEX> book emerged to tap the popular market, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>-based
chains such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldenbooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Dalton</ENAMEX> arrived to make the book market a
true mass market.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'90s</ENAMEX> brought the
superstore, typified by the still-expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> and Borders
chains. Thanks to the superstore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>, retail space devoted to books
expanded by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry</ENAMEX> giant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">455</NUMEX> superstores and does <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.45 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> sales.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> sell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
percent of all books; nonbookstores (department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>,
discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>, etc.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 percent</NUMEX>; small independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> sell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18.5</NUMEX>
percent; and book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> account for most of the remainder.

            Critics
complain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> exploit the industry's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> "returns "
policy, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> pay for only the books they sell. (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 40 percent</NUMEX> of
all hardcovers ordered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> are returned.) Chains overorder to fill
their expanding floor space, but sell a lower percentage of the books ordered
than independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> do. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX> must then absorb the high costs of huge
returns from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>. The conspiracy-minded allege that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> also
leverage their influence to persuade the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> to produce more
blockbusters at the expense of moderate-selling books. Although the book
business has grown more dependent on new blockbusters, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Noble</ENAMEX>'s sales, for example, come from "backlist" books, i.e., books
published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 12 months ago</TIMEX>.

            
               Overproduction: Fueled by conglomerate investment,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX> released <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 60,000</NUMEX> new titles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 10,000</NUMEX> more
than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>. This growing number of titles leaves publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> with
less time and attention to edit and market books. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>--big and
small--have trimmed their lists, consulting closely with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> to
determine what is commercial, and have seen their profits and sales rise.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midlist Crisis</ENAMEX>: Some charge that the
conglomerates are starting to ignore the "midlist " book, serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nonfiction</ENAMEX> and literary fiction that sells <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 30,000</NUMEX> copies, preferring
to gamble on potentially lucrative blockbusters. Imprints that concentrate on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midlist</ENAMEX> books--like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Free Press</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Books</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantheon</ENAMEX>--have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downsized</ENAMEX>, sold, or repositioned by their conglomerate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> say that the
proliferation of midlist books, not blockbusters, have injured the bottom line.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incoming Random House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Godoff</ENAMEX> argues against this notion: She
plans to publish more literature and fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> memoirs, because the
big-market books ultimately earn lower returns.

         
      
   
