
   
   
      
         
            Adultery

            Suddenly, adultery is big
news. But what exactly is adultery? Is it illegal?

            In case you have lost track
of all the adultery stories in the news, here is the list:

            Former football star
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX> was photographed cuddling with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was not his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Lee Gifford</ENAMEX>). He later admitted to having an affair
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Special angle: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> paid her to seduce him.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX> , son
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>, admitted to having an affair with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> baby
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sitter</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> gubernatorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bowers</ENAMEX> admitted to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> extramarital affair. Special
angle: When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowers</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>, he prosecuted a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in what became
a famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> case ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowers</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hardwick</ENAMEX> ) upholding anti-sodomy
laws.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> found comedian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX> , a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, with a transvestite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.

            The newly appointed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Westin</ENAMEX> , acknowledged his affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
public-relations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherrie Rollins</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of political consultant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Rollins</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-support suit was
filed against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Clinton</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, because he
conceived a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> discharged
pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Flinn</ENAMEX> because she disobeyed orders to end her relationship
with a married soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>.

            Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Maj.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s top enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>, was charged with adultery, as
well as with sexually harassing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> servicewomen.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralston</ENAMEX> 's candidacy for the chairmanship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX> was
derailed because he had had a relationship with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> while separated
from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.

            Army Maj.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Longhouser</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aberdeen Proving Ground</ENAMEX>, retired after
an affair he had had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> became public knowledge.

            Most societies prohibit adultery--sex between a married
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and someone other than his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>--at least, formally. A
handful--the most researched is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan Inuit</ENAMEX>--have condoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX>. Tolerance of the practice varies. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">François Mitterrand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> stood next to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> at his funeral. In some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>, adulterers are still stoned to death. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> falls
somewhere between these extremes.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> theories explain
the prohibition's genesis. One is evolutionary: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> must determine which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they sire, something only strict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monogamy</ENAMEX> can ensure. Another is
economic: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prohibiting</ENAMEX> adultery preserves monogamous relationships and thence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, whose labor was needed for agriculture. Finally, it is said that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
enshrined the adultery prohibition in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX>--of which it is the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>--to make their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> more cohesive and to distinguish themselves from
surrounding polygamous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> inherited <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> common law, which made adultery, as well as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fornication</ENAMEX> (sex between unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>) and sodomy (oral and anal sex),
punishable crimes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX> and late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th centuries</TIMEX>, when states
wrote their criminal codes, they incorporated these sex laws. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>
continue to have anti-adultery laws 
               on 
               the 
               books .
These laws vary considerably. Some define adultery as any intercourse outside
marriage. According to others, it occurs when a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> lives with
someone other than his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>,
simply "to lewdly and lasciviously associate" with anyone other than one's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> is to be adulterous.

            
Is a single 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adulterous</ENAMEX> relationship guilty of adultery? All but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> punish both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> only
punish the married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, when a
married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> sleeps with an unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is guilty, but when a
married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> sleeps with an unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, they're both guilty. Most laws make
no exceptions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> who are separated or in the process of obtaining a
divorce. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punishments</ENAMEX> also vary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX> is a felony in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>, and a misdemeanor everywhere else.

            In
practice, adultery laws matter 
               little : Only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case--against an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--has been prosecuted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have not
enforced their adultery laws since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.

            Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, when every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> passed a "no fault
divorce " law, adultery was usually the only reason <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> would grant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">divorces</ENAMEX>. (Under no-fault divorce, no specific reason is required.) Charges of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adultery</ENAMEX> also can be used to get a more favorable divorce settlement.

            Adultery
also matters in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Uniform Code</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military Justice</ENAMEX>, the
military criminal code, bars married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> from having extramarital sex
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unmarried servicemen</ENAMEX> from sleeping with married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. However, the rules
come with qualifications. They say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> will only prosecute when a
case harms "good order and discipline" and when the adultery is "of a nature to
bring discredit upon the armed forces." The ambiguity is intentional: Visits to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> are not reasons for a court-martial, but long-term affairs and
affairs between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are considered dangerous and deserving of
punishment.

            
Unlike civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-adultery</ENAMEX> laws, the
military rules are sometimes enforced. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> alone prosecuted
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> for adultery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> applies these laws
hypocritically, allowing high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male officers</ENAMEX> to get away with affairs
but not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or rank-and-file <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> has
ordered a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> to clarify the guidelines in an effort to
eliminate perceived 
               inconsistencies .

            Adultery
still plays a role in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">annulments</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX>
still does not consider divorces legitimate: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marriage</ENAMEX>, it says, is a sacrament
and insoluble. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> considers a divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who remarries to be living
in a state of sin--i.e., committing adultery--unless a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church tribunal</ENAMEX> annuls
the previous marriage(s). An annulment is a declaration that a marriage was not
legitimate to begin with. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX> is grounds for annulment, on the theory that
if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> knew that his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> had a predilection toward infidelity,
the marriage would not have occurred in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. Until recently the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> was stingy with annulments. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> it granted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 60,000</NUMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> of them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Rauch Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Kennedy II</ENAMEX>, has garnered much attention for her recent book,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shattered Faith</ENAMEX> , which criticizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>'s annulment policies. She
claims that the church hurts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of annulled marriages when it claims that
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were never legitimately wed.

            How widespread is adultery? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s famous
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> sexual behavior found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had
cheated on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. More accurate, more recent research shows that the
prevalence of adultery is not as high. A survey taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Opinion Research Center</ENAMEX> shows that slightly
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 11 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> admitted to having an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adulterous</ENAMEX> affair during their lives.

         
      
   
