
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Drug War</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> charge that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has forsaken the war on illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. They plan to make this
an issue in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> campaign. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) How has <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use changed
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) How has government drug policy
changed? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Is there any connection?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drug</ENAMEX> use among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen-agers</ENAMEX> has risen steadily in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. According to the best study:
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1995</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX> of high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> reported having used an
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">illicit drug</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1993</TIMEX>. But
this rise began before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> took office. Reported teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use
started climbing during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> presidency, after a dozen
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of decline. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1992</TIMEX>, the figure was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27 percent</NUMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marijuana</ENAMEX> is
driving these numbers. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1995</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> reported having
smoked pot or taken hash during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX> in early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> also report using more LSD (up from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.6</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.4 percent</NUMEX>),
more inhalants (up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.2 percent to 8 percent</NUMEX>) and more crystal
methamphetamine , or "ice" (up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.3 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.4 percent</NUMEX>). All these
increases began during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third or fourth year</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.
Many drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> believe that teen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> portends a higher rate of
adult drug addiction in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Adult drug</ENAMEX> use has
barely changed during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
reported having used an illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>, up a tick from
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11.4 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. But a previous rapid decline has stopped: Reported adult
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use fell by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, from a high of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 25 million</NUMEX> users
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hard-core cocaine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>,
between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.5 million and 3 million</NUMEX>, has been stable during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
But methamphetamine (speed) deaths more than doubled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1991</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is gaining popularity.

            The
best available <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> numbers--none of which are much good--suggest that drug
crime has neither surged nor receded during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>,
state, and local arrests for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">offenses</ENAMEX> rose slightly, to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.35 million</NUMEX>, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The number of drug-related murders fell a tiny bit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>.

            
               Drug policy: The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will spend
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $13.8 billion</NUMEX> on drug programs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 1996</TIMEX>, divided among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, officially known as
spending. State and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> disburse another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>-odd <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> to fight
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, most of it on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> drug policy has
barely differed from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> drug policy in either scope or action. Total federal
drug spending has increased <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency, though more
slowly than it did under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. Drug spending rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83 percent</NUMEX> during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.7 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.2 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. Total federal
spending, by contrast, rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 23 percent</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX>. (Most of the
drug-spending increase occurred during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first two years</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
administration. During <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, drug spending rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 2.2 percent</NUMEX>.)
Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, drug spending has risen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13.2 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, compared
with an increase of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.6 percent</NUMEX> in the federal budget as a whole. (But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
has asked for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> increase, to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15.1 billion</NUMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 1997</TIMEX>.)

            Under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> spends <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two-thirds</NUMEX> of federal drug money on
supply reduction and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> on demand reduction, the same ratio as under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. Prevention programs receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.5 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, roughly the
same as they did under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. Criminal-justice costs eat <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>, about the same percentage as they did under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
administration opposed federal funding of needle-exchange programs: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has continued that policy.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> policy shifts have occurred under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. First, the
administration cut spending for interdiction and international supply
reduction from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration has had the same success (or lack of it) interdicting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> as
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cocaine seizures</ENAMEX> averaged <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">113.8 tons</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993 through 1995</TIMEX>, exactly the same as during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s presidency. And the feds
are seizing more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> and marijuana than they did under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drug</ENAMEX> prices have
fallen slightly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX>. But given the global supply glut--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> seized about a ton of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, compared with worldwide
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> production of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400 tons</NUMEX>--many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> question whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interdiction</ENAMEX> has
any effect on street prices. In any event, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is now reversing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interdiction</ENAMEX> cuts. He has asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to increase interdiction funding by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
percent and international program funding by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hasn't used the bully pulpit to speak out against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use
nearly as often as his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> did. The drug issue hasn't figured high
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s domestic agenda until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.

            Drug-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> seem to agree
that social and cultural factors are driving up teen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were bombarded by anti-drug messages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> and filmmakers
relentlessly publicized the horrors of crack addiction and drug violence; the
death of college basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">star Len Bias</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> drove home the dangers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Say No</ENAMEX>" campaign and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free America</ENAMEX> propagandized ceaselessly about the perils of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, the big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> TV
network newscasts aired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">518</NUMEX> stories about the issue. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, that figure had
plummeted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> drove <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> off the newscasts, and the story
never returned. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> kept spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> on
drug prevention, but the frenzy of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> dissipated, and the culture
changed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX> and hip-hop music increasingly celebrate marijuana and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Television, radio, and print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> are donating less time and space to
anti-drug advertising. Surveys suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>, many of them former
marijuana <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> themselves, may be reluctant to warn their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

            To the extent that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can and should keep the drug issue at a roiling boil in society at
large, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has not done so.

            A summary of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
Monitoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future Studyon</ENAMEX> teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use is on the Web, as is the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household Survey on Drug Abuse</ENAMEX>.You also can download the text of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Drug Control Strategy</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
