
   
   
      
         
            Apologies

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
considering a formal, national apology for slavery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> have registered dissatisfaction with the idea. Yet an apology
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> has already been introduced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. When have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> apologized
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>? Which wrongs do or do not warrant apologies? Must apologies be
linked to material reparations?

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX> offered a public apology for biting off a chunk of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evander Holyfield</ENAMEX>'s ear. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sportswriters</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>'s pay-per-chew
regrets disingenuous, saying that his groveling was more about avoiding a
lifetime ban from the sport than about being sorry. Such self-serving apologies
are more transparent when the stakes are higher. The first national apology of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 80 years ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> was forced
to sign the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty of Versailles</ENAMEX> following <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I. The</ENAMEX> treaty stated that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> "accepts responsibility " for "causing all the loss and
damage to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Governments</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> have
been subjected." Reparations of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">132 billion</NUMEX> gold marks were commanded by the
agreement, but the apology that came with the money was even less heartfelt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Iron Mike</ENAMEX>'s.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> world war later, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> asked for forgiveness again,
but this time the expression was genuine. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, who repeatedly
describe their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s past aggressions as "the worst crimes against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">humanity</ENAMEX> ," are still apologizing for starting <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX> dropped to his knees in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warsaw</ENAMEX> ghetto in symbolic atonement. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has made payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $70 billion</NUMEX>, not
including personal pensions for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> amounting to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $15</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> continues to make amends to new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>
it began reparations to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> it paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.35</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lithuania</ENAMEX>, and it is negotiating like
agreements with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estonia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latvia</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> has
also formally apologized for the slaughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> have
paid reparations, but other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have been less forthcoming . François
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitterand</ENAMEX> consistently claimed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> owed no apologies, though in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chirac</ENAMEX> recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> responsibility in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">deporting</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Switzerland</ENAMEX> has
recently offered words of conciliation and established a reparations fund, but
many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> feel it has yet to make full amends for its role as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> penitence is
suspect. Although it has made monetary reparations--a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.9 billion</NUMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burma</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> has been largely
unwilling to admit wrongdoing. It has made no official payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> despite its brutal invasions of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and has never apologized
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied POWs</ENAMEX>, who now demand money and official recognition.

            Also
seeking acknowledgment are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> "comfort <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> ," mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX>,
who were forced to serve as sex slaves for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> denied
their very existence until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> it established a private "consolation
fund" for restitution, but most surviving comfort <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have refused the money,
demanding a public apology and public compensation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' reluctance to apologize stems
from their fear of blaming ancestors and dishonoring war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>. The government
has always used the word hansei , regret, instead of owabi ,
apologize. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomiichi Murayama</ENAMEX> issued an official owabi
after qualified his statement, stressing that it was a personal apology, not a
national <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. At the moment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murayama</ENAMEX>'s remarks, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conspicuously</ENAMEX> visiting a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s military dead--some of whom had been
executed for war crimes.

            The last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decade</ENAMEX> has witnessed a spate of public atonement. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>
apologized to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese-Americans</ENAMEX> placed in internment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> II. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> awarded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> to each internee. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> returned
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">850,000 square miles</NUMEX> of stolen ancestral lands to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Inuit</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maoris of New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zealand</ENAMEX> were ceded <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">39,000 acres</NUMEX> of land and paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$112 million</NUMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, as part of a bill personally signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> of
taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> marked the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">150 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX> famine by acknowledging his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>' failure to aid an
ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>.

            
Of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is
the most contrite. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> apologized to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of unethical
radiation experiments conducted during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> offered
a formal apology to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tuskegee</ENAMEX> medical study that denied
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syphilis</ENAMEX> treatment to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">399</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of both projects have
received compensation. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is pondering an apology to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of
slaves, he says he opposes material reparations. Almost no slaves were
compensated after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>.

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> still demand
apologies. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin Americans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> descent were extradited from their
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and interned just as their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX>
were, yet received no reparations. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are fighting for
official recognition of their holocaust, arguing that any apology to slaves
must be paired with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to their own ancestors. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> aborigines
have long sought acknowledgment of the atrocities inflicted upon them. (This
issuing a national apology.)

            On the other hand, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> struggle for official notice, they are not yet requesting
official apologies. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX> have refused to admit the
Armenian genocide occurred.

         
      
   
