
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is poised
to launch its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> strike against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>.
This latest tussle is over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s refusal to admit <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> into its military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has scoffed at new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
sanctions that punish its intransigence and has threatened to shoot down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
surveillance <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> calls this a "nightmare scenario." What has
happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> since the war? How strong is its economy? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>? Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>?

            In the
final <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> anticipated that a
decisive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> defeat would lead to a coup against a weakened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>.
These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> overestimated the damage--both physical and
psychological--inflicted by the war. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> remains powerful, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
repaired major infrastructural damage --to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, industry, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX>--within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of the war.

            Economic sanctions imposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> have been
more injurious to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> than the war was. The sanctions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> from
accessing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> held in foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) embargo all trade. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s gross domestic product has shrunk an average of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>.
Inflation is rampant: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar fetched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dinar</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, it
buys <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 2,500</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> standard of living has suffered :
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> live in poverty, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> at the
beginning of the war. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> die
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each month</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malnutrition</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. The middle class has been hit
especially hard. Crime, prostitution, and black-market trading are also said to
have become endemic.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
resolutions require that sanctions remain in place until <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> destroys its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> eased up on the sanctions, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to sell
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2-billion</NUMEX> worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every six months</TIMEX> on the condition that the profits go
toward <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and war reparations to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>.

            
The economic decline has not destabilized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. This is due largely to its repressive state security
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apparatus</ENAMEX> , which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> modeled on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stasi</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> major domestic intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> report directly to him,
and each reports on the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> as well as on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. Assassination,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">torture</ENAMEX>, and a network of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">informers</ENAMEX> keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> in line. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> left
behind by defectors are routinely shot.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s perpetual war with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> plays well domestically as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> continue to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stew</ENAMEX> over the damage left behind by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> defeat.
Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> has bolstered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> nationalism by linking his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ancient Babylonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, constructing massive monuments that celebrate the
parallels.

            

               How does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> fund these projects?
Speculation: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) through the covert shipment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) from the
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300-million</NUMEX> worth of oil the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> lets him sell to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) by skimming funds from the sanctioned sale of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> that is supposed to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) from a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> bank
account; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) by playing the oil futures market, which he manipulates by creating
the impression that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> is about to lift the sanctions in reward
for his changed conduct.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
has no viable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is dominated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sunni Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX>,
which crushed a spontaneous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> rebellion by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>. Since then,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiites</ENAMEX> have been passive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>, who hold significant
power, could also challenge him. There are rumors that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> attempted to
kill him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> has kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in line. Following a recent
spat with his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uday</ENAMEX>--who heads the state-run TV station and
newspaper--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> burned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uday</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16-million</NUMEX> antique <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> collection. When a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">son-in-law</ENAMEX> defected to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> enticed him back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> with
promises of forgiveness, but then had him assassinated.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s other potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversary</ENAMEX> --the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> in the north--has been hobbled by infighting and direct
repression. This non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> makes up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> are too busy fighting one another to threaten <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> allied with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish Democratic Party</ENAMEX>--which he bombarded
with cyanide and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mustard gas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>--to seize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irbil</ENAMEX>, the most important
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. This campaign dislodged Western aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several thousand</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> stationed there, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outpost</ENAMEX> . It also provided an
opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to infiltrate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranks</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s attack violated the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> cease-fire limitations, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
punished it by bombing military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in the south.

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX>-man <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam's Commandos</ENAMEX> , led by one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, also
snuffs out unrest. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, which watches for signs of a military
coup, executed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> suspected of planning a rebellion.

            Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1991</TIMEX> cease-fire, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> have largely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disarmed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s nuclear, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX>, and biological <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>, using random
inspections and surveillance cameras to do their work. During the recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">standoff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> tampered with monitoring equipment, and the fear is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> will use this window to create a cache of chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. This is not
the first prolonged interruption of inspections. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of occasions, Iraqis
have refused to admit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
administration launched cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> to force compliance.

            
               What
has inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s most recent flexing? Having fractured the
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> no longer fears the prospect of invasion from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> have sworn to veto any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> military action because they want to protect the post-sanctions oil
deals they've penned with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> only reluctantly agreed to this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> sanctions that bar international travel by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
linked to the inspection dispute. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> is taking advantage of the
current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> backlash against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> , sparked by the latter's
failure to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> a peace settlement with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Even moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> has
expressed sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is ready for war ,
having amassed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. There are
currently <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">warships</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> carrying cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>
capable of hitting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has backed down before on its demands that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> leave. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has never backed down.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is weak, but it could
still wage a fierce ground war. Its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX>-strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> the size
of the one that went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, but it is better trained. Since the
cease-fire, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> has continued to build conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> for these forces
under the watchful eye of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
has a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCUDS</ENAMEX>, capable of traveling <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">370 miles</NUMEX>; and
at least a small stockpile of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VX gas</ENAMEX> , one of the deadliest chemical
weapons. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VX gas</ENAMEX> is banned under the terms of the cease-fire.

         
      
   
