
   
   
      
         
            Stock-Market Circuit Breakers

            In the heat of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Monday</TIMEX>'s
stock-market dive, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> debuted circuit breakers.
Reviews of the procedure, which halts trading when the Dow Jones industrial
average drops dramatically, are mixed. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> say that the pauses
exacerbated the panic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> and others credit the
pauses with calming jittery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. What are circuit breakers? Why were they
created? What is the evidence that they work?

            Following
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1987</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Black Monday</ENAMEX> stock-market crash , a presidential task
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> was convened to investigate the crash's causes and suggest remedies that
would prevent a repeat performance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> blamed "faulty market
mechanisms ." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>, it argued, lacked the infrastructure to
accommodate the trading volume that the drop occasioned: Phone lines clogged,
computers crashed, and printers jammed. Many orders simply weren't received.
Deluged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> couldn't match the buy and sell orders they had. The task force
recommended--and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> implemented-- circuit
breakers , a pause in trading that would give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> time to
assimilate incoming information and arrange transactions. Circuit breakers
afford <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> the time to sell stock calmly, rather than dump it
in a panic.

            The main circuit breaker is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> rule that
automatically stops trading for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> whenever the Dow Jones
industrial average tumbles <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX> points from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its previous day</TIMEX>'s close. Another
circuit breaker halts trading for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> if the market drops <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 200</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercantile Exchange</ENAMEX> now stop trading whenever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> stops. Also after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> agreed to curtail computer trading of futures when the Dow Jones
industrial average either gains or loses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> points. This procedure is invoked
regularly.

            Although circuit breakers
were <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> imposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> does stop trading
when circumstances warrant it. Following the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> market crash, for instance,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> shortened its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to curtail panic trading. During the "paperwork
crisis " of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> cut back <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three months</TIMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> could handle a massive backlog of unfilled orders. In
addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> who handle the transactions of an individual
stock--are granted permission regularly by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> to stop trading stock to
restore temporary imbalances between supply and demand. Bad weather,
presidential assassinations, and power outages all have resulted in the closing
of the market.

            Most
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> require local 
               exchanges to halt the trading
of stocks that have dropped drastically. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, markets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, and
elsewhere prohibited the trading of specific stocks. No other country
automatically closes volatile markets for a breather.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of the new rules say that circuit
breakers flopped in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> debut. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> circuit breaker was thrown
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:35 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Oct. 27</TIMEX>. After the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-minute</TIMEX> pause, trading resumed and
the market dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 204</NUMEX> points in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25 minutes</TIMEX>, triggering the second
circuit breaker . The current Wall Street consensus is that the break made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> even more inclined to sell, instead of cooling them off.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> blame the cable networks , which dwelt on the first circuit
breaker and reported it as a sign of an impending crash. During the first lull,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> who had orders to sell by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> were already anticipating
a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> circuit breaker. Fearing that a second circuit breaker would close the
market for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and prevent them from executing their orders on advantageous
terms, they sold their stocks as soon as possible instead of waiting to find
the best price.

            

               Circuit-breaker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> also argue that the mechanism prevents the
market from working itself out of a crash. Extreme volatility, they say, is a
natural part of the market's quest for equilibrium between supply and demand.
Interrupting this process causes additional drops such as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>'s,
rather than upswings such as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>'s.

            

               Technology has made moot much of the
original justification for circuit breakers. Following the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> crash, both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> invested <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> in expanding and automating the
transaction infrastructure to accommodate the enormous swells in trading. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX>'s computers now can handle the sale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.7 billion</NUMEX> shares <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>, vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">685 million</NUMEX> shares were traded--not much more than the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> average volume of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">528 million</NUMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> handled a record <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> shares, with its central computer processing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 274</NUMEX>
transactions a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">both days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> had no difficulty matching buyers
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> and speedily filling orders.

Commission and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> originally devised the circuit breakers to kick in
after a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>-point drop. At the time, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> points represented <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> of the
market's value. Adjusting for the quadrupling of the market over the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> raised the circuit-breaker trigger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year to 350</TIMEX>
points. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX>-point trigger is far too low , allowing the
circuit breakers to flip at levels that don't warrant a stoppage of trade. They
appear to be right. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, when the first circuit breakers were imposed, the
market had dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Levitt Jr.</ENAMEX> has said
that the circuit breakers should be reformed so that they are triggered by a
drop in percentages, not points.

         
      
   
