
   
   
      
         
            TV Ratings and Sweeps

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spring</ENAMEX> brings the debut of
epically expensive made-for-TV movies. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last May</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> gave us The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX>). On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> will air <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlin</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX>). These television events are part of the hype that is sweeps. During
the sweep <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late April-early May</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>), network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX>
pack their prime time lineups with the shows they are convinced will reap the
highest ratings of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. Inflated sweep <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> ratings are, in turn, used
to set advertising rates for the rest of the rerun-riddled year. Are sweeps as
big a scam as they seem? And what exactly are ratings?

            To track
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">viewership</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> (both broadcast and cable) regularly keep tabs on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
statistics: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Ratings , the percentage of the total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> with TV
sets tuned in to a show. (Because there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 98 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> with
sets, reports dutifully note that each "ratings point" is equal to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">980,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> receive another set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> based on the number of
households wired to receive them.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Shares , the percentage of sets
turned on that are tuned in to a show. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demos</ENAMEX> (short for
demographics), numbers breaking out the age and sex of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> cable networks pay
substantial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fees to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.C. Nielsen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to have these numbers
tracked. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Every morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX> compiles the "overnights "--the ratings,
shares, and demos for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s programs, extrapolated from results
sent in by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">People Meters wired</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> TV sets. (These households
are randomly selected but supposedly represent a cross-section of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>.)
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Every 15 minutes</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">People Meters</ENAMEX>, small black boxes containing a tiny
computer linked to a modem, register whether a set is turned on and, if so, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> to which it is tuned. Attached to the box is a remote-controllike
device with buttons that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> push to register their age and sex each time
they watch television.

            There is a
reason <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> consent to take part in this program--it's a pain. It
requires that your home get wired-- another ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> in your living room,
holes drilled in walls--and that you constantly push buttons. But as a reward,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> get to pick a prize from a catalogue or receive a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> a month
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stipend</ENAMEX>. The incentives apparently work. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX> estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,500</NUMEX> of the
selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> provide data <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each night</TIMEX>. Worried about viewer fatigue,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX> has ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> participate for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two years</TIMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">People Meters</ENAMEX> don't provide statistically
valid data on most (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">173</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">211</NUMEX>) TV markets. Thus, the need for sweeps.
During sweep <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX> sends out "diaries " to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX> households
across all these markets. In these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> log entries every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> for what they watch. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX> use these numbers to set ad rates.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> sell ads based on averages of the overnight numbers.)

            Through
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> tied ad prices strictly to ratings. But with the rise of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> and the proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> lost their leverage to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> prices. Ratings now only provide networks a jumping-off point in their
negotiations with ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. In addition, advertising has grown more
sophisticated, targeting specific demographic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. This can create
unexpected results. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, for example, frequently wins the highest ratings. But
because it has more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> who are senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>--supposedly the stingiest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">demo</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> brings in lower advertising revenue and frequently runs in the red.
On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, with abysmal ratings, are
considered comers because of their success with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>--a prized demo.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> grouch that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsens</ENAMEX> aren't
reliable . Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> have flirted with funding a service to compete with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX>. The biggest beefs are that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX> numbers: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) depend on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
honesty and initiative--filling out diaries, punching buttons, etc. (read

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Life as a Nielsen Family</ENAMEX>" for the confessions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> anonymous
fudger of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX> diary); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) don't cover a truly representative sample
(college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dorms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> are all said to be either
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underrepresented</ENAMEX> or excluded from the survey); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) fluctuate wildly--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, for instance, gripe that ratings for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> 90210
yo-yo <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 86 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week to week</TIMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) measure <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-minute</TIMEX> intervals,
which is detrimental to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> usually watch for
even smaller chunks of time.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>' sweeps tactics, however, take even more heat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say that sweeps
cause <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> to expend the bulk of their resources pulling out all the
stops for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these three months</TIMEX> rather than spreading them around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.
The result: The cash-strapped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are forced to air too many blooper shows
and reruns in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nonsweep months</TIMEX>, turning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off network TV. Others complain
that during sweeps, local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX> compete by injecting even more
carnivalesque antics into local news. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stunts</ENAMEX> pulled include: cash giveaways,
profiles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and tabloid lead stories. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>, of
course, complain that sweep <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> artificially inflate the amounts they pay
for spots.

            
So, if everyone's unhappy with the system, why
does it persist? Some TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> say their industry is reactionary. Even if the
Nielsens are inaccurate--the stated margin of error hovers <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 2 percent</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX>, but some say it's larger--the industry will never muster the
will to replace them. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX>, which now enjoys a monopoly on the TV
ratings business --its major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arbitron and ARB</ENAMEX>, having been
beaten out of the ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>--has little incentive to innovate. Its
technology is supposedly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> behind devices used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
