
   
   
      
         
            Racial Integration

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> and white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of
the integrationist ideal now abound. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advancement of Colored People</ENAMEX>, once integration's most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwart advocate</ENAMEX>, is
reconsidering its goal of racial integration. Who are integration's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>?
What is their position? Who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> separatism for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>? Why are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of
integration gaining momentum?

            The
integrationist ideal holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> should live, work, and
study together. Government policies designed to accomplish these goals include
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">busing</ENAMEX>, affirmative action in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and in the workplace,
forced integration of public housing, and laws barring discrimination in
housing and employment.

            The most surprising new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of integration are
found in traditional civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leadership Conference</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> still support
integration, their dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are dissatisfied with the outcomes
produced by government policies. They note that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> is expanding, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 26 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> still
live below the poverty line.

            
               Black
separatism dates back to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> , when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Delaney</ENAMEX>
and others promoted the "Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> " movement. The literal return to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> was seen as the only option for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> because, they argued, white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supremacy</ENAMEX> could never be displaced. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garvey</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divine</ENAMEX> led the movement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '20s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Separatism</ENAMEX> fades in
and out of media attention: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Separatists</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s and '40s</TIMEX> received little
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX>.

            
Still, segregationists and integrationists have
always coexisted within the civil-rights movement. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'60s</TIMEX>, when
the integrationist ideal reached its peak, the black-power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">civil-rights</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> grew by advocating black self-determination--the
establishment of exclusively black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and a self-sustaining black economy.
More radical elements called for a black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">American South</ENAMEX>.
Even ultra-integrationist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> cast the civil-rights movement
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>colonial liberation struggle late in his career. Also, some black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> sought control over their local public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, which
prefigures the current enthusiasm many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> have for running their
own charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> within the public-school system.

            Recent
markers of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatism</ENAMEX> include the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX>-sponsored Million
Man <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March of 1995</TIMEX>, to which only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were invited; the
debate over the teaching in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebonics</ENAMEX> , the so-called
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dialect</ENAMEX>; the establishment of exclusively <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
dorms on college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>; and single-race <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> , which are even
supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>, because he believes they
will promote the self-esteem of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.

            The best-known separatist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> , although his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> probably number fewer than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
to read a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist" on the Nation</ENAMEX>.) Many consider it portentous that former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Chavis</ENAMEX> is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX> have new academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, the critical race
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theorists</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Derrick Bell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Delgado</ENAMEX>. They argue that despite its guise of neutrality,
the American legal system is riddled with mechanisms for oppressing black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Some critical race <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> argue that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> should acquit
guilty black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> in protest of the unjust system.

            

               What accounts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">separatism</TIMEX>'s current
vogue? Some attribute the new separatism to black demagogues in politics
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> who deliberately exploit black <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX> to further their
careers. Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelby Steele</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>
embrace separatism to cover for their embarrassing lack of skills. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> also
says that separatism appeals to unqualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> admitted to college under
the protection of affirmative action. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> compensate for their
shortcomings by clinging to one another and striking the defensive pose of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">separatism</ENAMEX>.

            Another
explanation holds that integration is out of favor because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Party has retreated from the goal. In hopes of attracting more white votes,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> has distanced itself from civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> like Jesse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, and from issues like welfare reform and affirmative action. Cut off
from the political mainstream, some civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and grassroots
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> have embraced separatist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and positions.

            In the past, the most obstinate white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of
integration (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> and
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Democrats</ENAMEX> ) argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should have the
right to associate--or not to associate--with whomever they wish. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Goldwater</ENAMEX>
later recanted this view, and even the most conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
now laud the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act of 1964</ENAMEX>, which removed barriers that legally
prevented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> from living and working where they wished. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>
still endorse the segregationist line that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> shouldn't
interfere with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s preferences.

            White
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of integration include the neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> , former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>
who supported the civil-rights mainstream until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>. Theirs is now
the dominant right-wing critique of integrationist programs. While continuing
to endorse the ideal of integration, they say affirmative action, busing, and
the rest do more harm than good. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX> wrote, in
Losing Ground , that government programs sap the initiative of the black
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, creating feelings of dependency and entitlement. Black
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Sowell</ENAMEX> concur, adding that government
programs allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to blame racism for their self-inflicted wounds.

            
Also attacking integration is social democrat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Kennedy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law School</ENAMEX>. Government-mandated integration
is wrong, he writes, because any endorsement of racial preferences is
immoral.

            Keeping the integrationist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX> are black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Professors Henry Louis Gates</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX> . Joining them is black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Loury</ENAMEX> , a
conservative who broke ranks to endorse affirmative action as a necessary
policy.

            
               Has integration
succeeded? Not really, say neo-cons <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephan Thernstrom</ENAMEX>. Their
new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> , says that the playing field has
been leveled in spite of government programs. The black middle class benefited
from the postwar economic boom, not affirmative action, they say. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Orlando</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patterson</ENAMEX> writes in his new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ordeal of Integration</ENAMEX> , that
government programs have helped many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> to join the economic and
cultural mainstream, but the programs can't be expected to further expand the
black middle class.

         
      
   
