
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical-Weapons Treaty</ENAMEX>

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 29</TIMEX>, an
international treaty banning chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> will take effect. So far, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> isn't committed to taking part. Thanks mainly to the efforts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Relations Committee</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has delayed ratification of the treaty and may ultimately vote it down.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> claims that despite the ban's best intentions, it will actually encourage
chemical-weapons attacks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Proponents</ENAMEX> of the treaty, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration, worry that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' delaying tactics will shut the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
out of critical decisions about chemical arms control. What's really at
stake?

            Images from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> donning gas masks spurred the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
administration to complete negotiations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chemical Weapons Convention</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">treaty</ENAMEX> requires the member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to destroy all
stockpiles of chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>. It also bans production,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">possession</ENAMEX>, and use of all nerve and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mustard gases</ENAMEX>. Production of other
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorine</ENAMEX> and certain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>, which have commercial as
well as military applications, will continue, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> will monitor
production to prevent their military use.

            This distinction between military and commercial production
is itself controversial. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> exempted from the ban have only
esoteric civilian applications, but obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> uses. For instance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosgene</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydrogen cyanide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases ubiquitously</ENAMEX> used in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, will
continue to be readily accessible to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX>.

            In large part, the CWC
simply reiterates previous international agreements . After <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">145</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Geneva Protocol</ENAMEX> , prohibiting the use of
chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in battle. And under a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> bilateral agreement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are estimated to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the world's chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> between them) committed
themselves to the destruction of most of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arsenals</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2004</TIMEX>. This
will occur regardless of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX>'s fate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$78 million</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> get rid of their <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40,000-ton</NUMEX> stockpile, and plans
to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 10 years</TIMEX> destroying its own <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30,000 tons</NUMEX>.
However, neither of these agreements goes as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX>, which bans all
future production of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.

            
Despite the enormous number of chemical
weapons, most do not pose an imminent threat. The majority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> stockpiles date back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> and are contained in rusty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shells</ENAMEX>, no
longer useable in battle. Nor has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> ever shown much
interest in modernizing them. But curbing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> is not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX>'s principal aim. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> hopes the treaty will
ultimately force potential ground-war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> to abandon their chemical
weapons, and prevent the recurrence of chemical attacks against civilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> assaults against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>.

            However, many of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would like to check have yet to sign up. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hundred</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have agreed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX>, but this includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 15</NUMEX>
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> believed to possess chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. The list of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonparticipants</ENAMEX> is ominous, including most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adversaries</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. Of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX> that have actually
ratified the treaty so far, only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX> are suspected of owning
chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> has signed but not ratified the treaty.) Both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
(the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest stockpiler) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> (the largest) appear to be waiting
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to ratify the treaty before doing so themselves. Even then, some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, which is currently reluctant to participate in
further arms-control efforts, will move to ratification.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX> say that chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> are an
essential deterrent against such attacks by these nonparticipating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> have been reluctant to use their chemical
weapons, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> argue, because they have feared the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would
retaliate with its own chemical attack. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Proponents</ENAMEX> of this argument point to
the chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> race during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s and 1930s</TIMEX>, which they say prevented a
repeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>-style gas attacks in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">treaty</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX>
respond that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> would be unlikely to retaliate with chemical
weapons in any case and is already moving to destroy its stockpiles. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> considers these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> too unreliable for use in battle--the wind
could blow the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> back on your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. And with the exception of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">napalm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Agent Orange</ENAMEX> used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is not known to have
used chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in battle since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. To</ENAMEX> allay concerns about any
loss in deterrence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
will respond to any use of chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> with an "overwhelming and
devastating" attack. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> say this is a coded way of threatening a nuclear response .

            
Because a ban can be easily circumvented
(chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> can be produced from everyday products without elaborate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>), the treaty installs a sweeping verification program ,
originally proposed during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> say it's a further intrusion on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> sovereignty. The
CWC allows any member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to inspect any site--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> or private--it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> of producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">illicit chemicals</ENAMEX> in another member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. This means
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> could legally search <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.
Snooping foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> fear, will exploit their visits for industrial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">espionage</ENAMEX>, stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> secrets for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in their homelands.

            Some legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>, claim these search powers are unconstitutionally broad.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random CWC</ENAMEX> inspections, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> says, violate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourth Amendment</ENAMEX>, which requires
a warrant to search private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">treaty</ENAMEX> requires all
inspections to accord with the constitution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where the inspection
takes place. Thus, if a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> rules a search is unconstitutional, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> will be forced to obtain warrants. Also, the routine random
inspections used by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occupational Safety</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Administration</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX> are almost
exactly like those planned under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWC</ENAMEX>, and these have been found
constitutional.

            Domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> are pushing hard
for the treaty. Though the CWC limits the chemicals they can legally produce,
it also imposes stiff penalties against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that fail to ratify the ban,
to encourage nonparticipants to sign up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signatory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> will be prohibited
from buying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>--those with only residual military use that are not
banned--from nonsignatory <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical Manufacturers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, failure to ratify the ban will cost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600 million</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> in lost sales to such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Proponents</ENAMEX> say the treaty
will suffer a fatal loss of credibility if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> opts not to join.
Aside from the large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> budgetary commitment to the treaty's
enforcement--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $25 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have played a key role in
concocting the treaty and stewarding it to its conclusion. Failure to ratify
the treaty by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 29</TIMEX> squanders <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> influence . Only representatives
from the member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> can sit on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that finalizes the treaty's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">logistics</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> won't hire verification <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonmember</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            These
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> concede that in the short run, the agreement will do little to
reduce the threat of a chemical attack. But the analogy, they say, is the
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Non-Proliferation Treaty</ENAMEX> that took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> to obtain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">178</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>--and
only after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> used sanctions to force the hand of reluctant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
