
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War Syndrome</ENAMEX>

            Since shortly after the end
of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-'91</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Persian Gulf War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> have complained of medical symptoms
they say were caused by exposure to toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> during that conflict. And
they charge that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has not taken their complaints seriously, or is
even covering up evidence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War Syndrome</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
admitted that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were exposed to nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> detected toxins "wafting over unprotected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>." Where does the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War Syndrome</ENAMEX> controversy stand?

            The
revelation that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were, in fact, exposed to toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX> does not
settle the case. The controversy rests on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> remaining issues: finding a
plausible description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> and finding evidence that the low-level
toxic exposures could cause it.

            After <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1990</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> led
deployment of the coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">697,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>, not only were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> casualties far lower than feared, but overall rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> were low
as well. Despite fears that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> would use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> or biological
weapons , no such <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attack</ENAMEX> came and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> became ill or died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
because of toxic-weapon exposure. (After entering an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> bunker, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>
experienced unexplained blistering, which could have been caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mustard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>.)

            After returning home,
however, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> began reporting a variety
of chronic symptoms that came to be called the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Persian Gulf War</ENAMEX> syndrome.
Common complaints are fatigue, joint pain, headache, difficulty sleeping,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diarrhea</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nausea</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX> registered and
examined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who were concerned that they might have
the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 67,000</NUMEX> filed disability claims for environmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sickness</ENAMEX>, unexplained <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, and other ailments.

            No one has
clearly defined what the syndrome really is. No characteristic symptoms or
laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">abnormalities</ENAMEX> have been found. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans</ENAMEX> quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times articles, for example, each cited different complaints--from loss of
teeth to tumors to memory loss to joint pain--and yet all were said to have the
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>. The most frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> complaint (joint pain) was cited by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 11</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> registry. A majority of those registered did not
share any of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozen</NUMEX> symptoms. Other studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> vets show no
higher rates of hospitalization, birth defects, or death than among control
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that did not serve. Thus far, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> have
evaluated the known evidence. None could find any new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> or define a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">unique syndrome</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> point to
evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> encountered many different chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agents</ENAMEX> which,
they believe, made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> ill after coming home. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Troops</ENAMEX> received multiple
immunizations , including uncommon <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anthrax</ENAMEX> and botulinum
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX>. They took pyridostigmine pills as an antidote against nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> used over a dozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>, including
organophosphates, which can cause nerve damage above certain levels. Oil
fires in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> billowed smoke over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> throughout the area. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scud</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> exploded over the 24th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Battalion</ENAMEX>, exposing its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> to
rocket propellant and, some claim, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mustard gas</ENAMEX> --a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> used to rapidly
induce blindness and severe skin burns.

            Last
spring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> reversed its long-standing denial that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> had been
exposed to toxins while destroying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> now admit
that, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1991</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were exposed to low levels of the nerve gas
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sarin</ENAMEX> when an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">battalion</ENAMEX> destroyed an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> ammunitions <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">depot</ENAMEX>. Initial
estimates of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> exposed were increased to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX>, based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
computer model of the gas cloud's drift. The number could be increased yet more
as further data are generated. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> confirmed detection of sarin even
earlier, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1991</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. Sarin
quickly triggers paralysis; death by asphyxiation or cardiac rhythm
disturbances soon follows. It was used, for example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>
subway attacks. But exposure levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> were not high enough to cause
such reactions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has already authorized disability payments
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $21,876</NUMEX> per year for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> with chronic maladies that appeared
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> after the war. The newest revelations about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>' exposure
will add to pressure for more generous compensation.

            
               Inconsistencies remain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unresolved</ENAMEX>, however. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert panelists</ENAMEX>--including a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX>, a
medical school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>, and epidemiology and environmental health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>--did not
find it plausible that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> could have failed to produce major ill
effects at the time of exposure, yet could still cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chronic illness</ENAMEX> later.
No known toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> has ever followed such a pattern. In medical circles,
the argument over <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War Syndrome</ENAMEX> is actually part of a larger debate over
the existence of other nebulous syndromes --including chronic fatigue and
various environmental illnesses.

            A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> problem is that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War Syndrome</ENAMEX> with consistent symptoms has yet to be defined. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX> is a constellation of symptoms; which ones a
particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> gets will vary with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX> may even be
several illnesses, they say, but the common thread is exposure to toxins in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>.

            The independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX>,
however, say none of the proposed chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agents</ENAMEX> are known to cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> at
the low levels which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> faced. Moreover, they have not found any increase
in illness among <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> as a whole or among those exposed to the
proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">battalion</ENAMEX> exposed to sarin
showed no higher <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> rates than others. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vets</ENAMEX> believe, however, that
there is countervailing evidence which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is covering
up .

         
      
   
