
   
   
      
         
            Cryptography

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>,
civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX>, and the computer industry are enmeshed in a controversy
over cryptography policy. What is cryptography? How and why does the government
want to restrict it, and why are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> opposed?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cryptography</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts: encryption and decryption. Encryption
uses complicated mathematical formulas to make information indecipherable.
Decryption decodes the information. The strength of a computer
encryption algorithm depends largely on "key length," essentially the number of
possible combinations in the code. A key that is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 bits</NUMEX> long, for example, has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> raised to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 th</NUMEX> power (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 40</NUMEX> ) possible combinations.
The longer the key, the harder the code is to crack.

            Because of the rise of online commerce, there is a
burgeoning market for cryptography to protect electronic transactions and
sensitive data from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is concerned that foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">powers</ENAMEX> (as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and criminal cartels) might obtain cryptography
that is uncrackable. Advanced cryptography could be used to make phone
conversations impregnable to wiretap and financial records invulnerable to
subpoena. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> permits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to sell any cryptography
domestically, it has imposed export restrictions on technology stronger
than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 bits</NUMEX>.

            These
restrictions have angered the computer industry. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX> have broken
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-bit</NUMEX> technology, and because foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> already sell superstrong
encryption programs of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">128 bits</NUMEX> and more, there is little demand for legal
(<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-bit</NUMEX> and under) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cryptography</ENAMEX>. The industry claims that export
restrictions could cost <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $60 billion</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> revenues by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> from lost cryptography sales, the
rest from lost sales of associated hardware and software.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s cryptography stand
reflects the strong law-and-order views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> argue that unbreakable encryption already is marketed by foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, so the export restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cryptography</ENAMEX> do no good.
Currently, there is no international encryption standard in place; but the
law-enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> hope that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> export policy will lead to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            Since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has been using export restrictions as leverage to
encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to adopt a standard with a "backdoor "--a
route of entry for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, to recover
encrypted data. (The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">128-bit</NUMEX> encryption currently sold by foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
contains no such backdoor.)

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s efforts to establish a standard
have failed. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> came the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clipper Chip</ENAMEX> ," an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80-bit</NUMEX> encryption
algorithm designed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1993</TIMEX>, the
administration said it would lift export restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that use the
Clipper Chip. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would keep a "key," which it could use to
tap a phone or decrypt data. Current rules requiring court orders for such
invasions of privacy would, presumably, continue to apply. Nevertheless, civil
libertarians denounced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clipper Chip</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Brother</ENAMEX> intrusion, and the
computer industry refused to market encryption that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could
crack at will.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> substituted "key escrow " for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clipper Chip</ENAMEX>. Under
key escrow (dubbed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clipper II</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> could export strong
encryption algorithms, but would have to file a key with a government-approved
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, such as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. But key escrow flopped, too. The computer industry said
it could not sell a program with a floating key accessible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government.

            
In a case of role reversal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
administration's law-and-order stance has been matched by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>'
rediscovery of civil liberties . Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> and the computer
industry recruited pro-business <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and anti-government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> (as well as some liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>
introduced a bill to all but eliminate export restrictions. The legislation did
not go to a vote, but it has an excellent chance of passing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>
endorsed the bill; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has promised to veto it.

            This political pressure
forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to propose a compromise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> offered an executive order that would ease export restrictions
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) raising the export limit from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 bits to 56 bits</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least the next</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> (allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to meet the current minimum commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standard</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) transferring export-license authority from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>
military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, which almost always refuses applications, to the more friendly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) permitting export of encryption of unlimited strength,
provided the technology incorporates "key recovery ." This is similar to
key escrow, except there is no single key and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> holds nothing. In
key recovery, a key is broken into several separate pieces of information and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> are stored separately, perhaps by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> themselves, perhaps by
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Reconstructing the key requires the cooperation of each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>.

            If key recovery is adopted,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> are likely to eschew it in favor of unbreakable technology. But if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, and communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> accept key recovery, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> will risk potential exposure every time they do business with those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. Key recovery has barely been tested, much less perfected. And
while a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--notably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>--have embraced the technology, others--like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>--strongly object to it. The rest of the industry is waiting to see how
much control the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> demands over recovered keys. In fact, many experts
believe that the key recovery scheme is so vague and tentative as to be
irrelevant. They say the encryption issue will only be resolved when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
debates the issue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
