
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> put the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> in orbit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sputnik</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in space, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuri Gagarin</ENAMEX>.
The space race was once regarded as a metaphor for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Communists</ENAMEX> seemed to be winning. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> space program is a joke,
symbolized by the space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mir</ENAMEX>. What happened?

            
               Sputnik was launched
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4, 1957</TIMEX>--the first man-made object to orbit <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. Its eerie beep,
broadcast over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">radio</ENAMEX>, signaled the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>'s commanding lead in the
space race. Masterminded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Korolev</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wernher von Braun</ENAMEX> (and, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">von Braun</ENAMEX>, a native product),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sputnik</ENAMEX> seemed to represent a system superior to capitalism, and proved useful
in wooing developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that had yet to choose sides in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> declared, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> of space means control of the world."

            One month
later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sputnik 2</ENAMEX> carried Laika 
               the 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in orbit for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laika</ENAMEX> suffered the first death in space. With no means yet of safe
re-entry, she was put to sleep inside the floating <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">capsule</ENAMEX>.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 6, 1957</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> attempt to put a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX> in orbit exploded on the launch pad. It was instantly dubbed
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flopnik</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaputnik</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stayputnik</ENAMEX>." The first successful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> launch
came on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31, 1958</TIMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>, with their Luna 
               program (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>), achieved the first solar
orbit; the first impact on the moon; and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> photographs of the moon from
a lunar orbit, which allowed them to map and triumphantly name geological
features of the moon's far side. Their next program, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vostok</ENAMEX> ("east")
series, shocked the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> even more. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12, 1961</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vostok</ENAMEX> 1
launched the first human into space. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuri</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gagarin</ENAMEX> 's module was
controlled from the ground--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> were unsure if he would function
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">competently</ENAMEX> in weightlessness. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">76 minutes</TIMEX> of orbital flight, the capsule
began its descent. Gagarin ejected as planned at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23,000 feet</NUMEX>, and parachuted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> did not reveal that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gagarin</ENAMEX> landed separately from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gagarin</ENAMEX>'s post-flight press conference the pioneering cosmonaut
claimed, "While in outer space, I was thinking about our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">homeland</ENAMEX>."

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> met with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX> and asked, "Is there any place we can catch them?" Consensus held the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> were so far ahead that only a manned lunar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landing</ENAMEX> could win the space
race. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25, 1961</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> addressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and called for a moon

               landing by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the decade</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three weeks</TIMEX> before this
announcement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had launched its first manned flight: a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-minute</TIMEX> journey by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Shepard</ENAMEX> that didn't even reach orbit. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX> orbited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hours</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> was
launching daylong flights and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>-orbit mission. Valentina

               Tereshkova , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in space, orbited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 16, 1963--20</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Ride</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tereshkova</ENAMEX> announced, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warm</ENAMEX> greetings from space to
the glorious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leninist Young Communist League</ENAMEX> that reared me.")

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cosmonaut</ENAMEX> took the first 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spacewalk</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spacewalk</ENAMEX> came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that summer</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> racked up a series of unmanned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firsts</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1965 and 1968</TIMEX>: the first 
               impact 
               on

               another 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">planet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX>), the first soft landing on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moon</ENAMEX> , and the first orbit of the moon with 
               a safe return .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soyuz</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>") program, beset by vastly
inferior funding, marked the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> space domination. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
walked on the moon as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soyuz</ENAMEX> suffered from malfunctioning launchers. With
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soyuz</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> announced a shift in its goals. Introducing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salyut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> (a "salute" to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gagarin</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> began a
focus on long-term, orbital space living that endures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soyuz</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> blew a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hatch</ENAMEX> on re-entry, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cosmonauts, but after this early catastrophe
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> program boasted constant space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">habitation</ENAMEX> and scientific
experimentation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two decades</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soyuz</ENAMEX> craft ferried cosmonauts
to a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salyut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, and once to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> docking with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>, the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> international space rendezvous. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> put the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> heritage in space in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> flew in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Salyut 7</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>) set a duration record of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">211 days</TIMEX> in
space--a record since repeatedly broken by various cosmonauts.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>,
the core <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> ("peace" or "world") was launched. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> reeled
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX> disaster, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> briefly enjoyed a return to its
dominant reputation. But as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> floated in orbit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> fell apart.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> took over the space program--with massive expenditure cuts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX>'s life
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">span</ENAMEX> has been extended well past what it was designed for, as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> cannot
afford a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX>.

            
Financial desperation has led <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to
endeavors shunned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s program places advertisements on its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rockets</ENAMEX>, and allows its cosmonauts to film

               commercials (one for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, another for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX>) in space, for a
fee. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> television network paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX> to send a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> as a ratings booster.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25 this year</TIMEX>, a
supply ship slammed into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX>. Since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX>'s main oxygen system has
failed repeatedly (forcing its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> to burn chemical candles to
survive), its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> has developed heartbeat irregularities (caused by
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>), and a cosmonaut has accidentally unplugged its main computer (which is
less powerful than the chip in some cellular phones). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> was docked pay
for its incompetence. The main computer failed again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8</TIMEX>, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement crew</ENAMEX> reported that the situation was "normal."

         
      
   
