
   
   
      
         
            Welfare as We Know It

            All leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, say they want to end
something called "welfare as we know it." What is welfare as we know it?

            
               Aid
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dependent Children</ENAMEX> is the safety net for the poorest
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> provided cash assistance to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 4.2 million</NUMEX> single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 335,000</NUMEX>
two-parent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AFDC-Unemployed Parent</ENAMEX> program. AFDC costs the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $14 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and states another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 billion</NUMEX>. Add
other federal expenditure for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>--food stamps (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 billion</NUMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 billion</NUMEX>, with another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 billion</NUMEX> in state spending), and
harder-to-calculate expenditure for housing, child care, social services, and
so forth--and total federal expenditure for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> exceeds <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 4 percent</NUMEX> of federal outlays.

            A bout one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is now on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX>.
Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.4 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 38 percent</NUMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-American</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white. This
means that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX>, as were about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 7 percent</NUMEX> of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            

               Never-married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> now head <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on welfare were there
because of the death or incapacitation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of
divorced or separated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> accounted for the majority of cases (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 56</NUMEX>
percent), while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of never-married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> made up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another third</NUMEX>. By
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of never-married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost two-thirds</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caseload</ENAMEX>, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 30 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of divorced or separated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX>.

            L ong-term welfare dependency is a serious problem.
According to estimates by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Institute</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladonna Pavetti</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> at any given time are in the midst of welfare spells that eventually
will <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last nine or more years</TIMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, mainly divorced ones, spend a
relatively short period of time on welfare--leaving as soon as they can get a
job. But many others, especially unwed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who had their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> and either dropped out of high school or have little work experience,
find it much more difficult to work their way off welfare. Thus, the increasing
percentage of never-married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> on welfare probably has increased the
length of time the average welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> stays on the rolls. (See chart.)

            More
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> are receiving welfare benefits. Illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> are not
eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX>, although their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are. Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> are
eligible, but during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their first three years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> they are presumed
to receive some assistance from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> if they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX> has
not had a big effect on the AFDC caseloads of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, although it has
a substantial impact in places like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, where non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> account for
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 15 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> on the program. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX> also has increased
federal spending for the indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Income Program</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1982 and 1993</TIMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> getting
SSI benefits jumped from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">128,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">786,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>), at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $3 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Eighty-five
percent of these non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen recipients</ENAMEX> come from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> areas--<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent</NUMEX>), and the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Republics</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent).

            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have begun
reforming their welfare programs using "waivers" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration. The most common provisions allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> who go to work or
get married to keep more of their earnings or stay on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> longer. Other
common reforms reduce benefits if welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> don't send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to
school, don't keep their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s immunizations up-to-date, and so forth. In
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, however, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have received waivers that go to the very
heart of the program : They end the absolute and unconditional
entitlement to long-term benefits. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have similar waivers
pending. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About half</NUMEX> completely terminate cash benefits and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> trigger a
work requirement after a specific period on the rolls, usually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 months</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> others terminate benefits after a period of mandatory work.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> making these fundamental changes include some with the largest welfare
caseloads in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> will
probably join the list soon. In fact, time limits already cover <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 60 percent</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s welfare caseload.

            Many waiver requests
submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> initially proposed an absolute termination of
benefits after the time limit. So far, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
has insisted that there be some sort of protection for long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>.
The most common safety-net provisions exempt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> from the time limit for
personal hardship (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>), inability to find a job (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caretaker</ENAMEX>'s age (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s age (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>).

            After rising <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX>
under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1989 to 1993</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> caseloads are now declining.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between January 1994 and February 1996</TIMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> on welfare
nationwide fell by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.5 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> already is claiming credit
for this decline. He may be right, but the bite of these new rules will not be
felt for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>. Have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> really changed their behavior in
anticipation of future penalties? Another explanation is the stronger labor
market for low-skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> rolls started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>,
when, for example, the poverty rate among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> declined from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33.1</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30.6 percent</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
