
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attorney-Client Privilege</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> a federal appeals
court ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> must hand over notes of their
conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater Independent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> assert these conversations were
confidential, protected by the attorney-client privilege. They will take their
claim to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. What is the attorney-client privilege? Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> in the right?

            Like
conversations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and patient or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> and penitent,
confidential communications between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> are legally
protected . A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> can refuse to disclose the substance of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX>, and only in rare exceptions will the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> be forced to
divulge the information in question. The communication should, however: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
always have been confidential and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) relate to legal advice (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> cannot
deliver documents to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> simply to elude a legal obligation to turn them
over). An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s "work product"--his memoranda, interview notes, and other
trial preparations--are similarly protected. Federal and state statutes codify
this privilege. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> who betray it risk disbarment and can be sued for
malpractice.

            According to legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, a version of the
attorney-client privilege <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. It was revived by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16 th century</TIMEX> and then absorbed into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> common
law. The rationale is that it is in society's interest for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to seek
advice from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in order to make sense of complicated regulations and
laws. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Clients</ENAMEX> will only receive useful advice if they speak candidly with their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> without having to fear that their conversations could later incriminate
them.

            The scope of the
attorney-client privilege remains broad. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 30 years</TIMEX> have
extended the privilege to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and even affirmed its
applicability to dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> .

            There are exceptions:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Clients</ENAMEX> can waive the
privilege.

            It does not apply when legal
advice is used to plan crimes. Conversations between a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> and his
lawyer arranging the murder of a disloyal underboss, for instance, are not
protected. But the distinction is not always so clear. There is a fine line
between abetting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s fraudulent testimony, which is not protected, and
planning a legitimate defense.

            When a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>, the privilege evaporates. This applies to
malpractice suits filed against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and in cases where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is
implicated in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s crime (this was the exemption under which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dean</ENAMEX> testified against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>).

            
The notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> wants to
protect were taken by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> at meetings on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11, 1995</TIMEX>, and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26, 1996</TIMEX>, also attended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> and her private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendall</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> meeting concerned the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s activities immediately
following associate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Foster</ENAMEX>'s suicide ; the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> had to do with her testimony before a grand jury investigating the
billing records from her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> . The records had been missing
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> before inexplicably reappearing in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> family's private
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarters</TIMEX>.

            These
notes were subpoenaed by special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. In response, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> immediately invoked the attorney-client
privilege, a claim upheld by a trial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, however, a federal appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>
reversed the trial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s decision . It held that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>-client
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> during the course of a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s investigation.
Government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are obliged to enforce laws, not to protect an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. If
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> desires a confidential discussion about a potentially criminal act,
he should hire a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>.

            White
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> argues that: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Courts</ENAMEX> have consistently recognized that the
attorney-client privilege applies to conversations between government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> concedes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should be treated as a government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s
decision has nasty ramifications for the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. From now on,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> will be reluctant to discuss tricky legal issues with government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, fearing that their conversations will come back to haunt them, and
will instead secure private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> .

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> need not turn over any
documents until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> adjudicates the case. The ruling, which is
expected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, will turn on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counsel</ENAMEX>'s mandate . No legal precedent presages the decision. Some experts
on the attorney-client privilege predict that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> will uphold it
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has an official interest (the meeting related to the
Foster suicide) and reject it in private matters (the billing records).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say
their rigorous assertion of the attorney-client privilege is driven by a desire
to prevent future incursions on the privacy of conversations between the first
family and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. They say it does not amount to an admission that the
notes contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">damning</ENAMEX> content.

         
      
   
