
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service</ENAMEX>

            Complaining about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> is a national pastime. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> gripe about rotten service and
the recently approved <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one-cent</NUMEX> hike in the cost of first-class postage, which
follows news of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.7 billion</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> profits over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX>.
Shipping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Parcel Service</ENAMEX> grouse that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> uses its
lucrative first-class mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> to subsidize overnight delivery and
international shipments. Stamp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> moan that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> issues
too many stamps, often commemorating frivolous subjects such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bugs Bunny</ENAMEX>,
hoping that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> will buy and hold these stamps rather than use them.
Others warn that digital delivery will destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>. Why
the rate increase, when profits are high? Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> compete
unfairly?

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> was not conceived with profit, or even efficiency, in mind. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental Congress</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1775</TIMEX> established its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> because it
didn't trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, who controlled the mail at that time. Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s mandate is not to make money but rather "to bind the nation
together." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> has been a self-supporting, government-owned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> since the passage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Postal Reorganization Act</ENAMEX>. Direct
public subsidies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> were phased out by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> , and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s USPS
covers all its costs from postage and fees.

            USPS justified its latest rate request by projecting
future losses based on an old debt of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $1.5 billion</NUMEX> and the need to
invest in new equipment and further automation. By law, the rates for each
class of mail must cover direct and indirect costs attributable to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>,
plus a proportion of institutional costs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">presidentially</ENAMEX> appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Rate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, which adjudicates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s applications for rate
changes, cast doubt on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>'s figures, claiming that it had "seriously
misestimated its need for a rate hike." However, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> isn't empowered
to collect data, it reluctantly consented, though it granted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 million</NUMEX> less
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> asked for.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> plans
to increase revenues by boosting its share of the parcel market . But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Express</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>--complain that the
laws give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> unfair advantages. It doesn't have to pay local, state, or
laws, zoning regulations, and antitrust accountability; and it enjoys cheap
credit from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Also vexing to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> are the
postal laws, dating back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1845</TIMEX> , which prohibit private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from
transporting and delivering letters or packets in competition with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service. There are some exemptions, such as those for delivering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>,
magazines, and urgent letters, but where competition is allowed, as in the case
of urgent delivery, private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> must charge <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $3</NUMEX> more or twice as
much as the first-class postage rate. Despite the higher rates, in competitive
areas private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>'s share of business--for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>
currently delivers <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 80 percent</NUMEX> of all the packages shipped in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>, which alleges that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> uses its
first-class mail monopoly profits to subsidize competitive services, has asked
that the firewall between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> and competitive
services be strengthened. Legislation requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> to place its nonmonopoly
products under the control of a separate, profit-making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is pending
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> subcommittee chaired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McHugh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> It also asks that the
requirement to charge twice as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> for urgent delivery be changed to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>'s rate. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> and the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> are generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to
political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, but since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every</TIMEX> congressional district contains
numerous post <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and politically active postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, it is
extremely unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will enact radical reforms any time soon.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> dreams of
cashing in on its enormous cache of detailed demographic data on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> by selling it to direct mailers. This rankles the newspaper industry,
which wants to protect the income it receives for delivering advertising
inserts. The industry has taken its complaints about USPS competition to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and seems particularly aggrieved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s plans to
spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> to promote direct mail. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspaper Association of America</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sturm</ENAMEX> observed, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stamp</ENAMEX>-buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> are given no choice other
than underwriting advertising mail most of them never asked for and don't
want."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s advertising campaigns have drawn fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>--in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, it spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 million</NUMEX> advertising in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albertville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>; and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, developing a new logo cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX>.

            The increasing popularity of fax services, e-mail, and
e-commerce is sure to hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bills</ENAMEX>, payments, and financial statements
currently account for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of first-class mail volume and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>'s
revenue. Beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, all payments from the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must be
made electronically, removing benefit checks, tax refunds, etc., from the mail
stream. (The move will save the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>--it
costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just two cents</NUMEX> to process an electronic payment, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">43 cents</NUMEX>
to cut, mail, and handle paper checks, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
Administration.) To combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cyberpayments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> will soon sell return-mail
envelopes with a reduced postage rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 cents</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, utilities, and
credit-card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> are skeptical that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will use
them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> hopes
to gain some of the e-mail market by offering electronic postmarking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>--a virtual version of certified mail that will provide "official"
confirmation of mailing and/or receipt. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> also recently
announced that, in collaboration with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> company <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-Stamp</ENAMEX>, it will test a program
that will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to purchase postage over the Internet. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-Stamp</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> is also optimistic that some form of "hybrid
mail ," combining Internet transmission and conventional mail delivery, will
gain acceptance. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mail</ENAMEX> is conducting a similar experiment in conjunction with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.)

            
With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 765,000</NUMEX> career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">127,000</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest civilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>. Labor costs constitute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 80 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
expenditures--a figure that has remained steady since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, despite the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> spent on automation. Negotiations with the powerful postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> begin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, with contracts due to expire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. The
appointment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Henderson</ENAMEX>--a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26-year</TIMEX>, second-generation USPS
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> who once served as head of employee relations--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">postmaster general</ENAMEX> is
seen as an indication of the importance of labor relations to the long-term
health of the service. As federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are not allowed to
strike and, if a negotiated settlement cannot be reached, contractual disputes
are resolved by binding arbitration.

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> have
endorsed giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, there don't
appear to be any commercial calls for privatization (no doubt the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27 billion</NUMEX>
in government-guaranteed pension liabilities is a factor) or challenges to the
USPS monopoly on first-class delivery. The size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> is
immense-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> handles <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41 percent</NUMEX> of the world's mail volume , more than
the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> combined. While service standards differ (many countries
offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mail deliveries <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each weekday</TIMEX>, for example), even at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33 cents</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
prices compare favorably with first-class rates overseas--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> charges <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">59 cents</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">48 cents</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Britain</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">37 cents</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
