
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas El Paso</ENAMEX> uh they were undefeated until uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> when they played the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Utah</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh really hum
 	
 	
 		they were beaten by uh a last minute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> point shot
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		and uh so it kind of opened things up a little bit they play uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young University</ENAMEX> tonight
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i i'm pretty sure uh they really got a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and i think
 	
 	
 		do do they do they traditionally have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> or is this sort of an unusually thing
 	
 	
 		uh yes they do uh they usually uh they're usually the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WAC</ENAMEX> conference and they're the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		huh
 		huh yeah see we're it's they're actually in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> system and i don't i don't even know anything about them i'm here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> we have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University UT Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right which is  which i mean i just generally go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> right
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the Longhorns</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah who's doing the who's leading the conference
 	
 	
 		actually actually i don't know right now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longhorns</ENAMEX> aren't having quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that they had hoped um they they had a a star forward that that was disqualified because of
 	
 	
 		uh i see
 		oh
 	
 	
 		of something i guess as he was leaving his junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> they uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> gave him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or something and uh
 	
 	
 		oh  oh i see
 		that kind of fouled things up plus maybe
 	
 	
 		yeah it sure did because they were they had a real good start and then and then and then ended up you know they they're they're holding on but it's not it's not gonna be a  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX> like they had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when they went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Utah</ENAMEX> went and uh they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		got hurt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the season</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and that's why uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas El Paso</ENAMEX> is uh is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Utah</ENAMEX> went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC Double A's</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and they got into the final sixteen i guess but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh UTEP</ENAMEX> like i say is doing real well and it's it's too bad that they have something like that did they restrict the
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longhorns</ENAMEX> as far as uh being able to play in any of the
 	
 	
 		no it it it something had happened outside of that you know and and it happened as as part of his junior college career
 	
 	
 		junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> so it didn't affect their program other than loosing him yeah right that's too bad
 	
 	
 		but no but they pulled him out of the out of the lineup
 		you know and it was something he he reported himself or i mean they  it wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">and</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> uh immediately suspended him and then
 		and then actually UT on his behalf filed a an injunction in the court system to allow him to continue to play which worked for a few games and then they then they pulled him in so
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		oh that's too bad
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		they've been having uh i mean last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last last year</TIMEX> they had a real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> they had every they had a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Penders</ENAMEX> come in um about i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> had been in a long a long decline you know for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they i guess back when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Lemons</ENAMEX> was here they built quite a quite a tradition
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then it it kind of went downhill for about for a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penders</ENAMEX> has done a good job of getting it back on its feet and doing some you know playing some good <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		good i know uh i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last week</TIMEX> and i saw the uh
 		huh the women's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> was playing uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX> was ranked number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> i believe in the women's <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and i i got to watch the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and then i had to leave on a flight uh back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and i uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> was leading
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		i don't know how they came out i don't know if you heard or not but uh
 	
 	
 		i don't know yeah uh the women's program is quite interesting down here the the women's program here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> um
 		actually for a while it was was drawing bigger crowds than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s program if you could imagine that they but they you know they just have have traditionally been a dominant a dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i mean they've they've always been in the top
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country um</ENAMEX> and actually had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> that they haven't been quite as strong but but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern Conference</ENAMEX> uh they've been undefeated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern</ENAMEX> they were no they aren't now but they had been undefeated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern Conference</ENAMEX> for something like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX> streak or something
 	
 	
 		i wish them well
 	
 	
 		and had won the conference title for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		and so that is they've they've that's that's quite a tradition here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		i'll say
 		yeah uh that's uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Utah</ENAMEX> that was the best season they'd had and uh the well the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> had come in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Majerus</ENAMEX> he'd come in uh he'd only been there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really built the program and they were supposed to well they were rated up in the the first uh uh top <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten this year</TIMEX> until they lost their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of their their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star players</ENAMEX> and uh through injuries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and now they are uh they they did beat uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas El Paso</ENAMEX> and uh  that was kind of strange i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas El Paso</ENAMEX> was just weren't weren't uh
 	
 	
 		up to speed yeah
 	
 	
 		hitting and uh
 		
 		
 	