
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		never did worked for a lot of computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in my life but not that not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um okay
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		subject is credit cards and how we use them
 	
 	
 		credit cards
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		sounds like a good you ready to get started
 	
 	
 		i guess so
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 	
 	
 		now what's been your experience with credit cards
 	
 	
 		i stay away from them  no
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i keep <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i keep uh i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> and it keeps a little balance on it not much and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> is the one i use predominantly so i know i have to pay it every month
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i know when i was younger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> or so i i got into quite a bit of hassle with them charging to the limit like to never caught them up
 	
 	
 		well i i uh i belonged to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX>
 		and uh they had a reputation or at least they touted that uh don't go don't leave home without it type attitude that it was good in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and everywhere
 		and i went on traveled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and i was just absolutely appalled at uh
 		the they it was useless
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i think uh
 		being overseas for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five weeks</TIMEX> there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> occasions i got to use the card
 		uh one little hotel out in the middle of nowhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> one little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh later i uh well i get in a scrap with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> because they made some mistakes in my account and it just took too many letters to get it straightened out
 	
 	
 		i've had oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i had an erroneous charge show up on it from some
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> card protection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or something and that took me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> to get that reimbursed and uh find out what was going on there they had authorized they had paid somebody without my authorization
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		i think the final letter was they were sorry that happened
 	
 	
 		well i
 		yeah
 		well it was something i don't remember the exact details so long ago uh they tried to sell me some kind of a special card
 		you know gold card or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super card</ENAMEX> or diamond card and so to do that they had to change my account
 		and so
 		some bills came in under the old account after they transferred all the money out
 		and rather than credit you know move the bills to the new account and pay them off as they should they sent me this statement showing this huge interest charge on uh
 	
 	
 		boy
 	
 	
 		on the account
 	
 	
 		yeah i've never gotten into an interest
 	
 	
 		and it took took me a while to get that straightened out
 	
 	
 		never gotten into an interest charge with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> i know they have it but i just
 		you know if you get it paid within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next thirty days</TIMEX> or something you don't have one so
 	
 	
 		yeah well i tried writing letters to get it straightened out but it uh it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight months</TIMEX> and i finally said cancel the account and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four months</TIMEX> they quit sending me letters
 		uh
 		and now i only carry one really uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> insisted that i get another credit card and uh so i do have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> card
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of hard to get by without one you know it's
 		i rent a lot of videos you got to have one there and different places and so you just about got to have a major credit card my favorites though are department store credit cards
 		uh you can just stop in and shop when you want and don't have to worry about your check book or having cash
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		i found out with at least the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> we've done business with for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they treat you much nicer
 		uh when you have a balance you pay it and
 		there's never a problem with anything you want or anything uh and our give give the cards to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> say here go get what you want
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that sort of thing
 		so those kind of particular credit cards i've always liked
 	
 	
 		yeah well i have another credit card our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> when you travel uh because of the tax regulations they don't like to make cash advances
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because there's uh they're concerned with the tax liability there so uh rather than make a uh cash advance they issue a credit card and you just charge as you go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		send your paper work in and by the time the credit card bill comes in presumably you have your check from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> the
 	
 	
 		when i work that's the way we uh i had a
 		corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and
 		everything was put on that they didn't care what was put on there just
 		and i i usually
 		i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time in all those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i had a situation where my refund check you know my reimbursement checks hadn't gotten here in time to make you know a payment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six thousand</NUMEX> i had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> too and
 		i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> time
 		
 		
 	