
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> yourself or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh yes uh uh not as much as i used to we used to have quite a few credit cards and over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> we've tried to cut them back a little bit and and uh down to mainly mainly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> each uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it's it's easy to let them get out of control
 	
 	
 		yeah it's i work at a at a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> and seen quite a bit used to be a loan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and
 		seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with you know they've had well i've seen a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand dollars</NUMEX> in limits and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> of it used and i and we we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but it's just for absolute emergencies we hardly ever use it
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah yeah that's uh that's what we try to to go to uh and eliminate all the uh uh department store uh credit cards uh got rid of all those
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		for sure
 		yeah they uh they can like you say you can once you start using them they they're always real real willing to raise those limits for you  that's for sure
 	
 	
 		yes they they uh they used to be uh uh more credit conscious i think the credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> now with with interest rates as high as they are they don't have to be as credit conscious they can
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no they can afford to write off a lot more
 	
 	
 		yeah they can write off a lot more losses now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh which which i kind of disagree uh with i'd rather them going back to being a little bit more credit conscious and and lower the rates
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's  excuse me yeah that's true i uh
 		well i can't see why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if they shop around you can find uh you know thirteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> percent rates without any problem i can't imagine why anyone would even think about paying nineteen you know because there's
 	
 	
 		yeah i i've heard though that the ones who are offering the lower rates uh do have tougher credit checks and than the ones with the higher rates have
 	
 	
 		yeah well that make you you know that makes sense i guess if they're they're not willing to write off as much but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know i that uh you know you receive all those ones in the mail and it just seems like well we sent we'll take it just because they sent it to me and then they get charged fifty dollars cost or a year for the just the fee and everything it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i just i have a hard time i like i say i
 		working in a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> i just i'm really rate conscious i guess and can't see paying you know hardly or near that much twenty one percent gets pretty crazy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well yeah
 		well well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> shop real heavily for when they for savings accounts and everything else to get that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">extra percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and then they don't look at at spending uh eighteen percent  on on credit it's uh for some reason they don't look at it that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yep there's i imagine there's there's quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who just pay it off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> so they don't have to charge you know get get charged any but it seems like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can least afford it are the ones of course that can't pay it off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> and get
 	
 	
 		that
 		that's that's true we we have tried uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple years</TIMEX> to to do just that and use them for convenience and pay them off but there's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and times like that we sometimes charge up a bit and takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple months</TIMEX> to pay them off but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who can't afford it uh they really get caught up in in the minimum payment and the interest rate it it's sort of like the federal government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah exactly that's true but
 		yeah i uh i i think that would do the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> a lot of good is a lot of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> paying down some of that debt they've got it just seems like they're
 		they right now they can't afford to buy anymore because they're up to the limits in debt and and everything and so you know that's part of the reason i think everything's kind of stalled out but
 	
 	
 		yes that's right
 		well the credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> i know are arguing against uh being forced to lower their rates but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think it would only mean that they'd they'd have to go back and and toughen their requirements a a bit and they'd probably make just as much money they just wouldn't write off as many losses
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that exactly you know when that thing was they were trying to pass through through that through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> they the thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> didn't realize is that yeah they would just shut off all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were marginal and you know it would slow you know they were trying to
 		pick things up but it would just it do wouldn't do any good because you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> aren't stupid they're going to realize that they can't you know they can't keep affording to write off <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> if they're only charging you know thirteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's right
 		yes uh
 		well like in like in any business they uh the same thing happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> you know they didn't look at uh the credit worthiness of making a lot of loans either and that's in uh in real estate and other things and it's the same with credit cards
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true
 		that's true
 		i don't know what will happen like i say we're sure trying we we just got the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and we just don't want to get any more
 	
 	
 		yeah we i i use a company one somewhat uh uh to to uh
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		do air travel and all but uh i make sure that one's always uh paid off because i'm responsible for the interest on that one if  if i don't pay it off uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		if it's not huh huh where do you work at
 	
 	
 		i work for uh an oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and they they issue a an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> card so that you don't have to ask for uh expense advances when you have to travel and buy air tickets so
 	
 	
 		oh do you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		uh yeah
 	
 	
 		so you just use your card but it's but it's in your name so it's up to you to pay it off and and because it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> you can't run up a a credit on it so that
 	
 	
 		turn in the voucher
 		um
 		
 		
 	