
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Gene</ENAMEX> so it's nice to talk with you and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um food</ENAMEX> is a very intriguing thing our lives are are built around <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> that we like and and nutritionally good for us what kind of dining out do you like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes sir
 		well there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds one i guess i'd say is with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> where we enjoy uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		oh i guess we usually enjoy a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood restaurant</ENAMEX> uh you know something nice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the other is with my whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> whom we uh go somewhere that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will enjoy
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> recently we've been hitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pancho</ENAMEX>'s up it's a local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> pretty heavily because they've got a good rate on the you know good prices and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		Pancho that's a new one um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's it's a chain down here uh it goes up into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and down here i don't know where else it is what about you
 	
 	
 		we had one called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi-Chi</ENAMEX>'s in this in our area
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Bamba</ENAMEX> but it's just it closed recently but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chi-Chi's</ENAMEX> is a national restaurant i think isn't it <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> do you have it there
 	
 	
 		i think think it might be i've seen i think i've seen it around yes sir yeah
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i love <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food myself
 	
 	
 		oh do you yeah
 	
 	
 		but you go ahead now
 	
 	
 		oh we we do too we uh we enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food i'm just not impressed with the quality of it it's just primarily the price that's uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		satisfying at this point but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> seem to enjoy it
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh let's see we've uh just recently discovered a super <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> down here but it's uh
 		not part of a chain it's just an individually owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood restaurant</ENAMEX> but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one we've been to that
 		uh i don't think there was anything on the menu that that any of us had that was uh not just really super it's nice to find a place like that
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that is wonderful well i i agree with you on that and i was was really a seafood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX> myself i i love crab <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> in particular
 	
 	
 		you know yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		i uh i can almost live on on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> and almost live on the crab <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> if  had to
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> have you ever been to uh what is it <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Original Book Binders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know the name but i haven't been there
 	
 	
 		uh that's an old established uh restaurant i used to go there when i was in college
 	
 	
 		uh-huh where did you go to college
 	
 	
 		i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Academy</ENAMEX> and we used to we used to go up there on uh for football games sometimes
 	
 	
 		oh  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Academy</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and have some liberty and yeah we'd go over there to uh  pretty sure it was original <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Original Book Binders i</ENAMEX> think it was yes
 	
 	
 		i'll be darn
 	
 	
 		i haven't been back there in years
 	
 	
 		well we're we're supposed to be talking about dining out but i'll just make one comment that uh i just retired from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>
 		and uh all my work has been in research for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay what area
 	
 	
 		
 
 		underwater acoustics
 	
 	
 		is that right did you have any dealings with the uh underwater sound reference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have dealt with nearly all of the all of the research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has
 	
 	
 		yes sir my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> worked there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that's where that's uh that's where i grew up was down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh you grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that's uh that's interesting well i was in submarines uh
 	
 	
 		well that's what i worked on
 	
 	
 		okay yeah must have had some interesting uh assignments for you there when when did you retire
 	
 	
 		uh end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well great i'm sure you've seen some interesting developments in acoustics
 	
 	
 		i certainly have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so what i hate to uh i wish i could talk to you about that uh but uh i guess we should continue on uh
 	
 	
 		okay right first
 	
 	
 		okay how do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		oh we we do enjoy that yes sir uh i don't know if we're particularly adventurous we find something we like uh like cashew shrimp or something that's got a good uh
 		at a particular restaurant and then we usually stick by it but do you what about you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i uh enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Szechuan</ENAMEX> type of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		hot um-hum
 	
 	
 		yes yep um it's it's i i do a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> cooking myself i have in the past i haven't done it recently but uh it's in the sweet and sour <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porks</ENAMEX> and things like are just really delicious meals
 	
 	
 		um where did you learn how to do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> cooking
 	
 	
 		um just at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i enjoyed the food and i bought a lot of uh
 		good cookbooks and i've been following through on that when you find the right cookbook why it works out
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what's a good reference cookbook for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		okay well that one's a good question here it's right under my nose if i can find it
 		
 
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		i guess one of the things we've uh started avoiding is the uh run of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> chop suey and things like that but we enjoy trying uh different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> or uh seafood you know even uh shrimp uh
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		dishes that are fixed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> restaurant
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the the this book i have is called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chinese Cooking Made Easy</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		it's a paperback and i think it's by someone named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chang yeah Isabelle Chang</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> thanks for that uh reference
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think'll enjoy that
 	
 	
 		okay good yeah
 	
 	
 		well it certainly is nice talking with you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX> and uh what is your phone number at home
 		
 		
 	