
 
     		
 	
 		declined that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> has more crime than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX> yeah i sure am
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's a it's a difficult question i don't know that i uh can easily come up with an answer to what can be done
 	
 	
 		i don't think there is an answer of what would make crime go away there's no such thing
 	
 	
 		i think probably <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> have a lot to do with crime in our society <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you're right
 		have you ever had your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> broken into
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		i haven't either
 	
 	
 		it's it's hard to know actually whether the
 		crime um impact would
 		be better or would would decrease or would increase if there were some changes in the way <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are legislated i don't know if
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i have uh an opinion yet about uh legalization of certain kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> there's certainly a lot connected with that you know
 	
 	
 		that's for sure
 	
 	
 		organized crime as well as
 	
 	
 		that's for sure
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i've never really been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of a crime and i've never had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> stolen or my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> broken into or
 		any of that so
 	
 	
 		well i guess
 	
 	
 		i've always lived in suburbs i don't know if that has anything to do with it or not but
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i grew up in a pretty small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and i'm not sure that um
 		the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> or the general appearances safety really has as much to do with it because because you're seen as an enclave You might get hit by somebody from the outside anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i guess on a on a local level uh i i was thinking when i heard the question about major changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> but it's probably a little easier now that i think about it if i look at what an individual could do and obviously
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if you have lights on and you have uh uh a timing system for your lights in your own home you're going to reduce the risk of being broken into
 	
 	
 		right there's so many things that you can do in that way and you know going into parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> with
 		with your keys out being prepared you know being on the defensive
 	
 	
 		right right looking less like a victim
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		neighborhoods watching each other
 	
 	
 		yeah we have a neighborhood crime watch where i am where did you grow up
 	
 	
 		yes
 		in a southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> suburb It was outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX> kind of near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington Beach</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and i were just just down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Christmas</TIMEX> they play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> and so we were down in that same area
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about thirteen years</TIMEX> now and um probably have learned by
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		uh indirect and direct experiences about things to do to you know avoid those kind of situations but i think part of it's just as you grow
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as you mature you you recognize um how to present yourself in a public situation so that you don't look like you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> a potential victim
 	
 	
 		that's right yep
 	
 	
 		it's a hard thing to communicate to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		it sure is do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		yeah they're not afraid of much at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no but you know as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> we were able to uh ride our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> around the neighborhood and go to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and those are things that i'm not sure i'd be comfortable with when she gets to bike riding age you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yep i can understand that you know as we were traveling back from that same toc soccer tournament i was telling you about we stopped in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mesa Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was just amazed at the freedom that those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> felt they just don't have i mean even here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX> i worry when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		walk you know a block
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we talked to some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> there and they said you know we just don't worry about that there aren't kidnappings and there aren't
 		there isn't that element here yet
 	
 	
 		that's interesting how large a community is that
 	
 	
 		um i don't really know  it's not real big it's right outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh and</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> what would you say is the population
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know that either
 		it's
 	
 	
 		because sometimes it's hard to you know i i look at small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> that have had problems with kidnappings and i think
 		well the you know they're not on the edge of some large metropolis Um you know it's hard to even
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		look at the factors that influence that happening why why in that particular you know
 	
 	
 		why it would happen here and not there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 		i guess you just have to kind of look for a family environment and and neighborhood and hope for the best you know and just
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you find yourself teaching your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> things that uh you you know that they need to do but you didn't have perhaps in the way of level of awareness at an early age
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure it and it's so frightening because you have to teach them to be scared all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh-huh how how do they respond to that when you tell them about kidnappings at what age were they ready for that
 	
 	
 		and to really be cautious
 		
 
 		well they don't know any other way they don't know any other way i mean they weren't raised when i was when you didn't worry about that everyone worries about that now so they just assume that you'll always have to be on your guard
 	
 	
 		uh-huh how old were were they when you introduced that subject
 	
 	
 		and this
 		oh real young i mean i can remember when my my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is thirteen today
 		and when she was just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> i took her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Mall</ENAMEX> do you know where that is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i grew up there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anyway and um she had gotten lost
 		and it started right then
 		you know and every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i would see that had a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> you know tucked under their arm i'd run you know
 	
 	
 		oh gosh a scary experience
 	
 	
 		to see if that was her
 		oh yeah
 		
 		
 	