
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well if you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> you must be very artsy-craftsy everyone i've ever known from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> can do everything with their hands
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh well  actually i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and before then i was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		i didn't know anyone ever moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and then i went to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and i got married there and we stayed there for a while and then now we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm teasing only because i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> i really liked i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but i married a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> and they have a way of dragging you back home
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anyway we're supposed to be talking about crafts do you um do you have any hobbies that that you do things with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX> like knitting or
 	
 	
 		um
 		well i crochet and i do water color and i um sew and i do fabric painting
 	
 	
 		oh you do a lot then do you do needlepoint also and cross stitching
 	
 	
 		um i've done some cross stitching
 		i haven't tried any needlepoint yet how about you
 	
 	
 		um actually i i'm pretty untalented  i used to do a lot of knitting and crocheting um
 	
 	
 		oh right
 	
 	
 		but i i don't know somehow i i don't have the time anymore
 		but i have all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that wherever you go they they sit down and the next thing you know they pull out of their um bags some their most recent uh needle craft
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> everyone was doing stockings you know these gorgeous detailed minute tiny stitch stockings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh God
 		oh yeah well those take a lot of time i only can do things that are pretty fast because
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		we just um got our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and i just
 		don't have the patience to just you know be some  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		is this your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first baby</ENAMEX> have you crocheted or knitted any baby clothes or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> blankets
 	
 	
 		um
 		i crocheted an afghan for our bed that's the only thing and and i did a quilt let's see i've done a quilt for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and i've done a quilt for our bed but i mean
 	
 	
 		did you embroidery the pattern and then quilt it yourself or
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		how how did you make a quilt
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s quilt it was a pre
 		like the design i just went around the design in the quilt i didn't piece it or anything like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		but you actually hand quilted it yourself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and  just
 	
 	
 		did did you need a loom or were you able was it small enough that you could just hold it
 	
 	
 		um
 		i put it on the frame the quilting frame
 		have you are you familiar with that yeah okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but um
 		my again my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> we had a quilting frame in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> and she would she would quilt whole quilts by herself
 	
 	
 		oh my God
 	
 	
 		um yes which i was always amazed i have one of them um but uh you know to have the quilting frame and then to actually do that it's a tremendous amount of work
 	
 	
 		well i haven't done tons of them
 		but um i used to do more before um
 		before i had  before we got our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		have you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you can um use crafts to make wonderful things for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> i think afghans and and the crocheted little sweaters and
 		are are wonderful and and they'll wear them  once they get old enough to talk then they no longer will wear your
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 		well one thing that i like about this fabric painting thing is i can just
 		make a T-shirt and put a little ruffle around it and then um cut out a little pattern from the material from some material like <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> or something and make
 		um a design or you know a little arrangement or something on the shirt and you know fuse it on with
 		Heat and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX> or whatever and then paint around it and i usually sew sew around the flower whatever first
 		and then i paint around it so you can't see the stitching as much
 		does does that make sense to you
 	
 	
 		oh yes i think it's very clever it's uh funny that you said for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and i received matching sweat shirts that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> had made for ours a beautiful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> design and they were matching and they were lovely
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but when i washed them although i took the precaution of turning them inside out i really didn't do anything else and truly everything fell off or most of it so i had i went and bought just some
 	
 	
 		oh sure uh-huh
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cloth glue</ENAMEX> and glued it all back and i bought the paint and redid most of the edges and and it was salvageable and i
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but it's so i'm familiar with that but i think you're very clever to um sew around the edges i think gluing alone
 		certainly if you wash it any amount of time it tends to kind of come loose at the edges
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah someone told me that that it that they had done it both ways and i've always after hearing that i always sewed it on even
 		even with the uh a loose zigzag even helps
 		and um
 		
 		
 	