
 
     		
 	
 		that's that's a timely kind of a question isn't it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it was yes what do you think about the uh former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really don't think that i would consider them a threat any longer and i suppose that's primarily because
 		their economy really won't allow them to uh expend a lot of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> on on war um if that were their primary concern
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it'll be a while before they're an economic threat for sure
 	
 	
 		it seems that way sometimes you wonder if um an economic threat isn't gonna drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do things that would be more drastic than if uh they were a little bit more peaceful you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think it would probably not be a a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> if that was the case but probably to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> other other areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		do you think that if their economy were in a better condition that they would be a threat uh that given their political changes they would still be a threat or
 	
 	
 		well that's what it seemed like even before they uh dissolved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> was that it was becoming less and less of a of a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> uh more and more of an attempted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know relating on more or less normal bases
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		are you involved in
 	
 	
 		there there've been such drastic changes in their political orientation that it's
 		hard to predict what it will look like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX> but certainly so far what we've seen is a turn around from where things were fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's right
 		that's for sure are you involved in any kind of uh political analysis or anything
 	
 	
 		no no and yourself
 	
 	
 		no not really we're involved in some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> in different places but not in
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh any area of uh endeavor that would be of any interest to you know militarily or anything like that
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  personal interests or business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> linguistics primarily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it's interesting to see uh how things are going there and and their the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are there are facing the same kind of
 		uh economic deprivation that uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> are but not it doesn't relate to much to the military uh situation
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes yeah their problems are definitely at this point economic it it seems that the whole infrastructure is focused on you know organizational um
 		skimming off the top you know especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> but um it's gonna be awhile before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> adopt the philosophy that
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		if you work harder you can also benefit personally and that
 	
 	
 		yeah i read an interesting an article in a recent uh
 		Wall Street Journal uh interview with a family there and
 		you know we think of uh how great it is to go to a you know free market uh sort of thing and and they're saying facing uh something that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not even aware you know familiar with they wouldn't they don't know how to deal with it and uh how do you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do you compete when you you're whole you know life has been built on uh working for the state and everything you know things like that
 	
 	
 		and and almost um the philosophy has been put in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as little</TIMEX> as you can because you know that the same results will will be there at the end so why spend the extra energy
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		you face the same uh uh bureaucratic uh headaches whether you work or don't work so and so now they've you know so really it must be uh really traumatic time for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as well as the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		lack of supplies or anything like that adjusting to the new way of thinking about things
 	
 	
 		i wonder too if their thinking hasn't been so influenced over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that the Western way is bad that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it would it's hard for them to look at some of the Western market place strategies as being good because they've been
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		taught to understand that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		propagandized the other direction for so long
 	
 	
 		well perhaps the uh if we give aid of some sort you know maybe it'll turn them around if it's done done correctly you know economically
 	
 	
 		i think that they're one economy that i feel that that's worth the investment you know there are some
 		um places in the world where i'm not sure that the money that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is putting in is really getting the kind of return that that's gonna benefit both parties but
 		um it seems that there's such an effort to make it work there that what they really do need is is the loans and the
 		uh strategic assistance from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i'll i'll be curious to see what happens in this elections because it doesn't seem as though that's forth coming right now um
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		you mean in in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or in
 	
 	
 		yeah i think well i was watching something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> a news program that that indicated um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s part is that if he puts
 		great interest in that area now he's gonna be accused of not spending enough time on the domestic issues you know certainly foreign issues are his strength  so it's a catch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah you can't that's right and well i hope you know just hope we don't wait too long and and uh you know
 		
 		
 	