
 
     		
 	
 		our topic today
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh yeah something about the school system here
 	
 	
 		right and now i'm sort of  don't know if this an advantage or disadvantage my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well then i'll uh i'll walk softly
 	
 	
 		no you go right ahead because i have a lot of strong opinions on it too my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> teaches <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade
 		and you know
 		there is a lot of serious things wrong with the school system <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and the teaching system i think the i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> get enough support quite honestly but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for example my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> she has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and course like everyone she has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that get pregnant even  even in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade
 	
 	
 		what school system does she teach in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano School System</ENAMEX> but but to give you an example uh
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		you know one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will come in and he's
 		you could tell he's just bombed out on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and uh she sends him to the principal<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">'s office</ENAMEX> and the principal sends him right back or her right back and says hey your problem you take care of it
 		you're not allowed to send them home you know if you do that then
 		your allocation's cut from the state or the feds or whatever your you you have to have a certain amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in your class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and just it's it's a numbers game i don't think that's right if they're especially if they're interrupting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and
 		preventing other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from learning
 	
 	
 		well i think it's more of a there's a bigger problem here than uh
 		than discipline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i think it gets back to the uh parental uh participation into the program
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um to give you an example both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy system</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garland School District</ENAMEX> and it's a public system however you'd think that it was a private school
 		because they've taken it the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> they've taking top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">three percent</NUMEX> that have tested out you know in the district
 		and uh put them in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy system</ENAMEX> and to get into the system's very difficult but once you're in uh they have they have self-paced programs
 		and so you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that wanna learn and uh you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that wanna teach and you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that are really interested in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and basically uh
 		there's probably some discrimination if you wanna say that uh because  most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> system
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caucasian</ENAMEX> and because you have to test into the system
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and most of that's not all true but i'm saying a large percentage of them are and also the other large percentage is is that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> just about of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh have college degrees <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> does
 		and so there's i think that uh that's my justification for saying that
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that are that are pushing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at home even if they don't know what their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are learning they're they're saying do your homework let me see it
 		don't get in trouble at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or we're going to be all over you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> had such a tough time in uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> he went to but there was through it wasn't all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s fault it was his fault also but we put him in a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> and that that cost more that was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three semesters</TIMEX> that was more than his college tuition was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh had to be done at least it
 		took care of him and uh threw him in a good learning situation where he did participate and uh want to learn something
 		
 
 		but i'll tell you what there's a there there are a few faults to say the least in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		yeah i think what we've done is um um especially looking at um the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dallas</ENAMEX> area is that we're trying to bring the education
 		level down to the lowest level so that the lowest level can succeed
 	
 	
 		yeah i think we have that problem dealing in most areas which is unfortunate
 	
 	
 		and um that also probably crosses over into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> because now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> also say that if you're not don't have the proper education
 		uh including uh
 		exposure to high tech fields such as computer technology if you can't use a computer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and do word processing and do
 	
 	
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		database management and do i forget all the other stuff financial management and all this other kind of stuff in your regular job uh you can't function
 	
 	
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		you know so i think that the school system proliferates over to the business world and the business world then says we're not going to pay you
 	
 	
 		well it's different
 	
 	
 		unless you have the education and then education and then then we what we've done is caused a big problem that proliferates itself
 	
 	
 		sure well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> you know they have a a tough row to hoe so to speak they just
 		are always fighting the system i don't know if it's better than any you know we came down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> from the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> area we were only there for a short time but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and she was born and raised there and educated there college and everything and
 		i think you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the east are really a lot better than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the south i don't care where you're from and they they i don't know if they learn more but they certainly uh
 		they have a tendency to learn more and in that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> there is all nationalities
 		
 		
 	