
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well do you go camping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes uh we live uh right to the base of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasatch Front</ENAMEX> so uh uh as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were growing up we spent a lot of time camping up in the mountains different taking our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with us or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> hunting or whatever
 	
 	
 		by camping
 		you you mean really roughing it
 	
 	
 		well well uh sometimes we did most of the time we'd  we'd put up tents and we'd go up and stay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> or go up into uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yellowstone Park</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in the campgrounds up there
 	
 	
 		oh but that was
 	
 	
 		but we really had some enjoyable times as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and uh some real good memories how about your experiences on camping uh what have you
 	
 	
 		uh well i've our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were growing up also uh we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and we'd
 		go camping on the long weekends uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day Fourth</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July Labor Day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we went with some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and we'd get as many you know involved as we could and
 		so our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> really grew up all through uh you might say junior high and high school camping and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that sounds uh
 	
 	
 		we've really had a good time doing it um we went to a lake called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake Tawakoni</ENAMEX> uh it's just kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> and south of here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		we camped outside <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we had a tornado come through our campgrounds it was kind of interesting we had snakes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">armadillos</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		all those fun things huh
 	
 	
 		all the fun things that that make memories
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i'll say well we uh when we were up in uh  by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yellowstone Park</ENAMEX> we had uh moose that went through our campground and we had a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX> once that went through uh-huh black <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX> and then we
 	
 	
 		a bear oh oh
 	
 	
 		uh we've seen a lot of rattle snakes uh in our camping trips
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and all of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creatures</ENAMEX> of the wild and like you say those really make memories of things the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> never forget but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think the one that really excited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were quite young and that's when this moose great big antlers come walking right through our campground we had a fire going and and uh it just kind of sauntered through and went over to a stream and was eating and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		didn't didn't mind you being there a bit huh
 	
 	
 		no no no he we uh didn't bother it and uh everything was fine but uh
 		it's uh camping has really uh been a a great part of our life and now we're we're older all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are gone and we don't uh
 		uh fact <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> i didn't go out camping on the deer hunt now we have quite a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> hunting season here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and i didn't first time in uh fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> that i hadn't gone out in the mountains for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> hunting so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time huh well
 	
 	
 		but anyway it uh
 	
 	
 		maybe you'll get a chance to go again
 	
 	
 		yeah when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> uh get a little bit older then we'll we'll we'll do that again
 	
 	
 		take them well we kind of gave up camping <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three four years ago</TIMEX> to and we built a lake house
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and so now all our outdoor activities are centered around the lake house
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i would uh it's not like camping in a way but yet it is you're still uh on the
 	
 	
 		well
 		we're we're still outside but we we we figured we're getting a little too old to rough it as much as we used to
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		
 
 		yes uh we got uh where we had a a camper then we got us a fifteen foot trailer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that we we took up and
 		uh when we were going camping so we when we our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were young we did uh pretty well rough it we were in some good snowstorms and uh
 		speaking about tornados up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> went through there usually they don't have such things here but
 	
 	
 		i didn't know they did yeah
 	
 	
 		it took down pine <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> quite a swath and uh we were there right after that happened but uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh those tornados i guess are uh pretty scary things
 	
 	
 		i guess most you know there's probably not any part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that doesn't experience them every once in a while
 	
 	
 		um-hum that was amazing because that was like i say right up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> and it's uh maybe once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years</TIMEX> or something we have something like that but uh and it happened and uh that was
 	
 	
 		i bet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> was a neat place to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in we we went up we pulled a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> out there from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when uh probably about nineteen seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> i'm trying no no no no it was before that it was must have been nineteen seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> before we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we had like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> foot trailer that uh we pulled behind the car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and everything and actually i i think i liked the camping with the tent better than pulling the trailer
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we made it out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> and it was gorgeous never forget that
 	
 	
 		oh it is it's it's beautiful we've spent a lot of time up there and that but that's a long ways to pull a trailer
 	
 	
 		yeah it was and uh we needless to say we haven't we haven't done it again  pulling the trailer is not the our favorite thing to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah
 		no
 		
 		
 	