
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right uh yeah not as much as i used to be i i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		you say you a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steeler</ENAMEX> fan
 		so did i no kidding
 	
 	
 		did you yeah i left there i went to school out that way that <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about forty miles</NUMEX> east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> and then uh
 		i left in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid sixties</TIMEX> and right after i left well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years later</TIMEX> they started having some good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Knoll</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact uh did the coin flip in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah he's looking good he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> i think and he just you know
 	
 	
 		he looks real good he certainly had a an unfortunate uh end to a brilliant career
 	
 	
 		yeah for considering
 		yeah they just uh i don't know what happened they just weren't getting any draft picks and weren't i guess they just weren't picking the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> weren't right people
 	
 	
 		well that's what i think i think the the the sad thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steelers</ENAMEX> is that they stuck with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> a little too long and i think that's the the biggest problem for dynasties is that you just really have to cycle people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		yeah they uh he was loyal to a lot of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that
 		helped uh helped him win those <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowls</ENAMEX> in the seventies and uh stuck with him too long and then i think the
 		the draft uh picks did fall on hard times and they just never were able to get back to where they were
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh uh we've lived here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about nineteen years</TIMEX> and i've never become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> in fact i don't i just don't like them at all but
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		how about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oilers</ENAMEX> any more appealing to you
 	
 	
 		oh i like them better than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> i don't i just uh
 		other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steelers i</ENAMEX> don't have a real a real favorite uh like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redskins</ENAMEX> but uh usually like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> are playing for the most part you're a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niner</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i had you know i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steeler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> um they've certainly built themselves a you know a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact if they hadn't lost so many games early in the season i think they might have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> might have given <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> a game
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 		yeah yeah they had
 	
 	
 		but uh they lost uh so many games early that they that their comeback made little difference at the end
 	
 	
 		yeah they weren't the same without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montana</ENAMEX> made a difference but as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts analysts</ENAMEX> have said over and over again the game is won and lost at the line of scrimmage a smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> makes a big difference and i really think for example yesterday
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo</ENAMEX> might very well have been in it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> been uh a smarter quarterback i i frankly am surprised that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Marv Levy</ENAMEX> would allow him to call all those plays
 	
 	
 		oh was he calling the plays i didn't even
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think that's just too tough in a on a uh uh you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i mean you got to be real real savvy to do that and i don't see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> as being that savvy i don't i think that's one of the weaknesses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> offense myself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah he had a
 	
 	
 		because they certainly have a heck of a defense although it was picked apart a little bit i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> just looked phenomenal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah well couple of those passes a couple of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">receivers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo</ENAMEX> dropped some important uh passes too they it would have made might have made a little bit of a difference not much but uh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't i i just looked in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this this evening</TIMEX> and trying to figure out when the last time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFC</ENAMEX> won a game guess it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it's it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> beat uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redskins i</ENAMEX> think as a matter of fact but boy it's
 	
 	
 		yeah it's been been a while
 	
 	
 		i was thinking maybe they uh ought to just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFC</ENAMEX> ought to just give it up and uh when uh it comes time for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX> plays an all star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">AFC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that might be a little more interesting because i'm getting a little tired of watching the blowouts in the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it is it is a little disappointing and there's some it it's very interesting to see you know what's what's behind this is it is it the uh i mean you would think theoretically that the draft picks would uh
 		you know random and then free agency also makes a big difference
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i don't understand it i mean they just uh they they <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> you know went a few times and they didn't do anything uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> they didn't do anything now uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well
 		Buffalo twice well they did get close <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> they could have won last <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> could have won <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>
 		but uh just seems like there's a big gap in talent between the or maybe in coaching between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFC</ENAMEX> because it's like i said it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years or eight years</TIMEX> since they uh since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFCs</ENAMEX> won a game
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i guess they're gonna somebody was saying uh somebody i was watching the game with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they were saying that instant replay may be on its way out i guess they have enough votes to uh or not enough votes to keep it going
 	
 	
 		well you know i think that's sad in a way because i think if you look for example there were a couple of calls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that were appallingly bad
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i just it's it's it's shameful and and i think that that once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pandora</ENAMEX>'s out of the box you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know i i i i think it can complicate things i recognize that but i sure think it's it's reversed some some calls that were bad calls although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> it didn't reverse one that was a very bad call what
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 		um yeah i just don't like it it it delays the game it delays uh i don't know it it just kind of interrupts interrupts the flow of things and uh i
 	
 	
 		well there yeah there is that problem and and but uh i guess that  that the real the real interesting thing is in the age of television you're going to get so much analysis of it that a that a game really for example <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> when when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Reid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	