
 
     		
 	
 		planned a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion recently
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion i did not plan i only participated and enjoyed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX>
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		you know i really haven't and i know of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who've done it recently and have really enjoyed um
 		the the planning process but uh most of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> see each other fairly frequently so it's it's uh you know not a a major event to to try and plan it because we're all fairly close um
 	
 	
 		it often depends how far you want to go back on on our particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion they went back to my great-great-grandfather
 		so that it was quite um spread out and there were many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> um and there were many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we didn't know i think the total participation i don't know how many were invited but there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two hundred and fifty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> one of the cutest things that some of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families families</ENAMEX> did was to get T-shirts that identified themselves as that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the family
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		it was fun
 	
 	
 		so your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> was still living and everyone up to that point was invited
 	
 	
 		actually he was not he has gone  but they decided to go ahead and take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion back that far so that it wouldn't just be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> meeting <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> meeting i guess
 		whatever <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> cousins
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh wow</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the other thing that i thought was particularly fun was uh the huge they had a huge family tree uh that was posted so you could sort of everybody could sort of see who married whom and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that was fun
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who organized it who was the one that instigated the the planning process
 	
 	
 		you know in every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there's usually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that is gifted to do these things  i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> who never marries who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> sounds like a bad novel
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and she did she was she's always been interested in genealogy and she's kind of kept track  and so
 	
 	
 		i was gonna ask next how she was familiar with where everyone was
 	
 	
 		um i think she just started out writing to
 		key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and asking them to contact everyone and i really  on the family tree there really was everyone except there was just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that had sort of gotten lost
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> but this is was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>  and it was a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had kind of stayed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it wasn't like they were necessarily from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		now given the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> fairly large is that what contributed to that
 	
 	
 		we're a good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic German</ENAMEX> stock and so yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that i eluded to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> had twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they had some pictures of that that was another thing they did that i thought was fun
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		sounds like the trelve twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful i'm sure that was a wonderful experience for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> too and even if they didn't appreciate it at the moment they'll  probably really appreciate it later
 	
 	
 		that's always true they remember most the games they had lots of games and competitions which were fun well are you planning a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion
 	
 	
 		no uh  uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		do you how your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX> you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> uh moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> and that's where they raised the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and myself
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		sometimes when you've moved perhaps your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion if there ever one would would be back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> i mean that would be where your roots would be
 	
 	
 		i would expect yeah yeah
 		and i know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> were fairly large but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has just one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
 		so we've kept in touch those first cousins very pretty closely um i'm not quite sure how i'd even pursue finding the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		this is a little office
 	
 	
 		i think i think each of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> siblings
 	
 	
 		that sounds
 	
 	
 		so
 		there's got to be a few of those <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> does that make <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		typical
 		i never knew that i i always i thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of your first cousins i always called those second <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i called <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> cousins
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh okay okay
 	
 	
 		that's how i've always named it some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have this once removed stuff and i don't know what that means
 	
 	
 		so perhaps my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents siblings</ENAMEX> would be my great great
 	
 	
 		they'd just be your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-aunts great-aunt</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> would be your great aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aunts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and
 		so but it it is interesting sometimes a little sad when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> branch out quite so much but i don't know that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way
 	
 	
 		did you find that you had a lot in common did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find out things about each other that they hadn't been aware
 	
 	
 		i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> who lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Fort Worth</ENAMEX> area  that that i never had met and didn't know they were here and we we all laughed how it was funny to go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who lived
 	
 	
 		really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles from you so that was sort of funny in fact one of them it's like my father
 		i don't remember how this was i guess it was actually just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> so it's not all that far away turns out he even goes to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	