
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		let's see um
 		have you heard anything in particular about the universal health care system uh health insurance program that they're talking about
 	
 	
 		well i haven't heard any of the specific details of uh what they have planned but uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		basically the noise around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is that uh they're concerned that uh there's not enough health care insurance provided that uh very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have uh health care insurance or
 		any kind of uh coverage where they're employed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i'm not sure that there's any real plan afoot
 		to uh bring a health care plan on line that requires everybody to kick in like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh one of the plan that's been circulated about is a requirement
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> provide uh health care insurance for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and kick in something like eighty percent of the cost of that insurance
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh if they don't do that then they have to pay into a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> that provides the uh health care insurance
 	
 	
 		and it'd probably be cheaper to go ahead and pay a percentage of the local plan
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah especially for major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i tell you one thing that uh we were discussing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this evening</TIMEX> here that discourages me a little bit and worries me about the health care system
 		uh i know that certainly in this region uh that the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> graduating from dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> has been quite large
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and a lot of the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that uh came and stayed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> didn't go back home
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so there's been a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> are kind of glut on the market and they're having a lot of trouble competing and making ends meet
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> i think may be facing the same situation except they apparently have a very strong
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> and they are actually preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from entering medical college
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they keep uh the AMA you've got to go through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> to get accepted into medical school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they keep a tight rein on how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh now dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that's yeah if they've got a glut on the market of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> um
 		i i i don't mean to be ugly about it but uh costs of dental work are pretty high
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and if there's something i don't necessarily think it needs to be driven down again but to keep it from shooting up of course dentistry i don't think has near the problem with like malpractice insurance and such
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's probably the worst thing about health care right now is the unlimited capacity for suing for malpractice and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it seems to be the burden of proof that on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that he didn't do something wrong rather than proving that he did
 		and if he doesn't prove beyond a shadow of a doubt that he did everything just right
 		then suddenly he's got you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> wages down the toilet but uh
 	
 	
 		well i think that's sort of happened universally to all our industries i think our light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> industry went out of business because the uh cost of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>' product liability was too high
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but i think on the other side of the coin that uh maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> is being a little bit too protective of some of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> getting away with murder
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've got my own set of war stories uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> uh turns out she's allergic to gnats
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i went in to have it treated it cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand five hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time i went to a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> said oh she's allergic to gnats give her some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benadryl</ENAMEX> that was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dollar and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five cent</NUMEX> treatment for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so uh you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> in the hospital the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s ward on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> penicillin uh was a lot less effective than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of</TIMEX> teaspoons full of Benadryl
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i have other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that uh have really been misdiagnosed
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i think it's probably a shame that there isn't more competition among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and there isn't a little more policing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh of the results
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		from what i've seen the better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> are quick to ask you to go ahead and get a second opinion
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they're not feeling you know insulted they're it's like that's a little you know sweat off my brow simply because
 		i mean you know they're they're covering their own tail legally and you know a second opinion
 		
 		
 	