
 
     		
 	
 		how do you get your news coverage
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um most of what i do is um listen to the news in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> when i'm heading to work um
 		we get uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> here that run uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> and i really enjoy the format in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> when i'm driving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from work so that's where i get most of my stuff uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's pretty nice
 	
 	
 		yeah we we also subscribe to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of course so we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> here and it's a pretty interesting newspaper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh so it's you know it's it's uh between the two i generally do okay every great once in a while i manage to uh listen to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news but not very often how about
 	
 	
 		yeah that's just about all i get is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news and the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> sometimes i wish <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news was like an hour long instead of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't blame you it's it's uh it's
 	
 	
 		but that would be nice to have uh um you know all is it an all news uh radio station
 	
 	
 		yeah and it actually
 		well no i it's i guess what is it it's um it's kind of a talk radio station it's run by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> here called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American University</ENAMEX> or at least that the the general program that i listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> itself is um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a uh uh a syndicated thing that's run by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that operates here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> uh but if you have any public radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in your area chances are pretty good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> come to think of it uh that you're going to be able to get it down there uh
 	
 	
 		i i guess i never i never really tried that it probably is on the AM i know it's not on FM
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i don't know whatever your you know it it the normally the public radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> are gonna be down at the low end of the dial you know around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX> and uh and so forth and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		this uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> that run here one is a classical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and the other i guess if you had to categorize it's kind of a bluegrass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> or something
 		um but uh yeah that that's i'm i'm dead certain some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in your area carries it because every once in a while they'll do little special features on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> it's a real interesting radio program because they they don't just cover
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it's probably picking up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um KLBJ</ENAMEX> that's a real famous
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Bird</ENAMEX> used to own it
 		radio <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> here but um they're not so much news as they are um uh as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> and and things going on around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um well that's very interesting well this comes on right in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> as i'm driving home
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um what they do is they they give you uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about a five to ten minute</TIMEX> news uh broadcast and then for the rest of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> they usually divide it up into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> where they they cover
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um topics either of current interest or every once in a while they'll just do kind of an indepth reporting on on some uh particular thing like yeah like perhaps for instance how a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is doing or something along those lines yeah it's uh
 	
 	
 		some subject yeah
 		well not bad that sounds pretty interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah it's real good and it  it it uh the other thing is is is my politics are kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> and and um so they have a tendency being public radio to
 		sort of take a look at things from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> point of view as opposed to being terribly sympathetic to the government although the you you've got to give them credit they do a great job of showing both sides of the story
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh they aren't afraid to poke fun at themselves either
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		which is something i really admire so if you watch the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> news which of the news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> do you tend to like the most
 	
 	
 		oh i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> i'll switch around i'm not really partial you know one like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> i might have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> i might have another one you know just to get a different view
 		you know or just someone different  but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i'm the same way but the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news on TV it's it's really it's so short that you just uh i don't feel like you wind up getting enough and yet have you ever watched the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> report on public TV
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		i sort of feel like that news program drags on too long
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's a little draggy
 	
 	
 		and uh with you know with their little round table discussions and all that sort of stuff and i must admit i i used to try to watch it used used to make me feel like oh well this is uh something i should be watching
 	
 	
 		yeah until it gets a little boring though i know there is something better on
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah exactly and
 	
 	
 		so it it's pretty nice in that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> here it's it's it's only you only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and um it's it's kind of biased
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um it it's all right
 	
 	
 		which way which which way does it lean is it conservative or
 	
 	
 		yeah it's very conservative i would say it's very conservative but you know being it's only you you don't have one in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> and you don't have a choice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know i don't i don't like that but other i have uh uh small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> community um that's oh it's it's um
 		uh just in this general area it serves maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh it's free and it's real nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		yeah i really like it you yeah it it's like the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> newspaper you know you can put your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s picture in there if they had a birthday or or something like that you know or some
 	
 	
 		that's good yeah
 		well that's interesting
 		
 		
 	