
 
     		
 	
 		do you use credit cards
 	
 	
 		
 
 		convenience uh
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		i i use them for just uh everything mostly i confine my credit card to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		but um i i carry it with me and clutch it tightly to my bosom at all times fortunately um
 		uh i have a credit card well i have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCards</ENAMEX> one
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> has a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> dollar it's a gold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> and it uh have to pay a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> dollar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fee but as long as i i pay off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's no interest charge
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		but and we never carry over we pay off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		what is the advantage then of a gold card because um you don't pay any interest if you have a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well one thing is whenever we rent a car we don't have to pay um any extra insurance
 		so that we uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s uh family lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 		and uh
 		it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ninety</NUMEX> miles from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hartford</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> miles to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 		so uh as a general rule when he goes up there he rents a car
 		so the times of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that he rents a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> more than pays the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> dollar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fee for having a gold card
 	
 	
 		i see
 		i see we used to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> card and
 		stuff like that and then we just kind of got back to plain old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> uh because we never really had any um
 		benefit that we thought was worth the the price of the special card so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it may change you know if we do a lot of car rental which we don't do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or other types of services i'm sure there're some things that come along with the gold cards that are appealing and and uh i've just wondered what they were they haven't been appealing to us so far
 	
 	
 		no uh unless there's some no i there's no uh unless there's some advantage there's not any point there's there's no prestige factor involved
 	
 	
 		yeah that you know i think that was my original appeal uh i was i was in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenties</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> card really appeals to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on that basis of of you know you've arrived you've got this card
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know it got to what fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or something like that and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> said well this is ridiculous why are we doing this and uh
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we stopped doing it and we refused to pay i don't know whether you know this but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> discovered this we started to refuse to pay our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> uh an annual fee for the that for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa Visa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX>  and they said fine we'll give it to you anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we said you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we're uh we're not interested in your card anymore and they said well wait a minute is is it the price and we said yeah so well we won't charge anymore  you know and they used to charge what eighteen dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or something like that twelve dollars something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		they're wonderful i mean i think credit cards are great we use it to get cash uh you know you can use it now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway</ENAMEX> out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		it's wonderful in that respect and we're glad to have them we we
 	
 	
 		can can you buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> with it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's great you know and it eventually what we're gonna go to is nothing but these kinds of cards and it'll be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard Visa</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> card's gonna make it in the long term
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you know we don't need too many cards and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> will probably survive but it'll have to become more like these other ones and become cheaper i think because the price will come down
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so too
 	
 	
 		i don't think it's worth fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks a year
 	
 	
 		no it's not
 	
 	
 		when you can use the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> everywhere in the world and they're pitching that in all their commercials i notice
 	
 	
 		yeah you really can and uh also um
 		we travel abroad
 		some
 		and um it um you get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX>'s accepted everywhere and and you get the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a a good rate you get a better rate than you do uh cashing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>'s checks of course there are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well now now that's interesting i can see why because then they get some sort of advantage in terms of the  conversion fee probably
 	
 	
 		yeah and and even uh converting your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>'s checks at a bank they still charge you a fee
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		well it it's gonna come that way and the reason it's nice is because basically what it does is put you electronically in touch with your financial resources
 		anywhere in the world and that's where we're headed  the technology supports that nicely
 		and uh it makes more sense than than that because you have a card and if you have insurance which we have had on the card you uh can have you can lose it stolen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you don't get uh anything charged to you and that's great it's just insurance we're very responsible with our cards but nonetheless if we lost them
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum um-hum
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it'd be great to know we didn't have to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um on the cards we look for the low rate we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAA</ENAMEX> cards uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah we do too
 	
 	
 		yeah but but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAA</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> based and uh  that's a great thing for
 		
 		
 	