
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well got any problems on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mockingbird</ENAMEX> with crime or is that a crime free zone there
 	
 	
 		no i don't think there is any such thing as a crime free zone any longer
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i'm afraid you're right
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one evening</TIMEX> i decided to retire early and heard sirens and noises and thought oh well something's happens on Mockingbird
 		and then heard yells and screams and the next thing i know there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> all around my house
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		and they had stopped a uh  a stolen car
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		and caught one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hedge</ENAMEX> and then the other one was on the roof in the back
 	
 	
 		by your house
 	
 	
 		by on my house
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness ah aye aye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so i'm very much aware of uh crime in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and the and the concern about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh my that's that's got to be a frightening way to spend spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was
 		i uh i kept hearing noises and so i i knew that i was not going to sleep until i got up and went out and checked the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> so i got a gun my gun
 		and walked to the you know through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> there was no one there but i wanted to be sure
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> beginning to experience the the kinds of things that are more common in the metropolitan you know in the urban area
 	
 	
 		unfortunately yes yes
 	
 	
 		that's too bad
 	
 	
 		i think uh you know as any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> grows up uh you get
 		the hoods and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ruf riffraff</ENAMEX> and everybody else in there and i think u
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know fortunately the sirens and everything we hear are over on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> but uh we've been we've lived here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now you you know you can tell the change for sure
 	
 	
 		well i was thinking if you've been there that long you've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Plano</ENAMEX> grow from what was really a a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to a city
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well with all the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Expressway</ENAMEX> uh with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and the
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh convenience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and all that kind of stuff it's just prime pickings for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> driving by you know and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i was appalled to read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> about the uh uh shooting on the tollway
 	
 	
 		that's that couldn't be too far from you neither uh
 	
 	
 		uh well it's further west of me
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i live over near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">White Rock Lake</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes okay
 	
 	
 		but uh uh it was really frightening to think that uh it's not even safe to drive onto the tollway or for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the tollbooth uh i never thought about someone robbing those
 		but apparently they do
 	
 	
 		i don't know uh how a few bucks can be worth shooting somebody but
 	
 	
 		yeah it just doesn't seem possible does it
 	
 	
 		it's kind of
 		kind of stupid isn't it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i guess when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do those things they don't really give a thought of the consequences at the time it's looks like easy pickings and away you go right
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah
 		and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> play a tremendous part in um the theft and the the violence that we see
 	
 	
 		i think you're right uh although i think that may be an excuse for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		it it is convenient isn't it i didn't know what i was doing
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right just like the old alcohol idea and
 	
 	
 		that kind of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh
 		i think when you have haves and have nots you're always going to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are
 		too lazy to figure a way to earn money and find it's easier if you can get a gun to go out and hold something up than it is to figure out a way to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legitimately</ENAMEX> earn the money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well yes and i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dallas</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas School System</ENAMEX> and uh uh uh do you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatcher</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> where do you work
 		uh yes i think i do that uh
 		is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amelia Earhout Earhart School</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		uh no this is over near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln High School</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh just not far off <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Central</ENAMEX> Expressway
 	
 	
 		that's a pretty rough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> there isn't it
 	
 	
 		it is a pretty rough area we're over by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um my goodness
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know you watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are marvelous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillacs</ENAMEX> and everything parked all up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> outside these awful taverns
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> see that and uh they know that they can earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several hundred dollars</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> where uh you know running for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> if
 	
 	
 		definitely that area that that's big time big time there sure is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it surely is
 	
 	
 		i don't think i'd go to work without a bulletproof vest on myself in that area
 	
 	
 		well i'm careful
 	
 	
 		gee that's the worst neighborhood in the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh a little scary sometimes and uh i manage the
 		
 		
 	