
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well this is an unusual topic what do you think about it
 	
 	
 		yeah i at first i it took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> times to find you you  so i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> um you know what should i say and then he reminded me but um
 		um  his in his family uh what they usually do on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> or um the aunts will send out little postcards
 		like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks</TIMEX> before reminding everyone where the
 		where to meet and you know just to bring anything and so they just notify everyone by mail and then they just meet at like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> or something to have like a a short um
 		or a small um dinner type thing
 	
 	
 		well that sounds great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> how far away do they come from right
 	
 	
 		um they come from
 		well they all meet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> and they come as far as oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> and and sometimes we've gone and we were from we were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> at the time
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and um but his his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is all around the area and
 		his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s side of the family they all uh have their family reunions in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> to there and um
 		let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> and in that area <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> to southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and they would
 		um assign a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> each time they had a reunion they'd assign a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to be in charge of notifying everybody
 	
 	
 		oh okay that makes sense nobody's out of a lot of trouble more than once
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are down there like they'll assign <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> area one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can call
 		you know beforehand and just make sure everyone knows too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then they just sort of do like a little program or you know something like that so that everyone's sort of involved
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's interesting you sound like you've had a lot of experience with this then
 	
 	
 		oh well  that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s side and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> family uh we we all live in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> so we just have to either call or
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		give a formal invite and we're all there so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern California</ENAMEX>'s still pretty large
 	
 	
 		yeah well i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LA Orange County</ENAMEX> area i mean everyone's you know mostly not farther than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> away
 	
 	
 		i see
 		and
 		yeah
 		well my experience um
 		has been limited pretty much lately to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side of the family uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> there was a big dispute on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side and uh
 		they haven't had a reunion since then they just show up at funerals and weddings
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it was pretty serious and lot of yelling and all that but anyway my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		we had our our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real reunion that i've ever gone to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> and they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in from out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and they took some some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> down at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn</ENAMEX> and
 		uh they had some activity they had a nice dinner planned and all of that stuff and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got up and talked about various parts of the family tree and you know a lot of that sort of thing since it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one that we'd had
 		the you you could do that once now next time we have one we'll have to think of something more creative to do
 	
 	
 		well you know that's interesting because one thing that always brings to my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>'s side together is um they talk about the genealogy of the family tree every time and everyone inevitably everyone is just
 		very interested and and they always have you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> new ones to add to the list you know someone's been born or someone passed away or you know something like that and so everyone has to update their little
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well have have you do you have an interest in genealogy
 	
 	
 		books or whatever
 		um  uh i do but not to very much compared to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not a passion huh

 		um
 		i suspect we'll do quite a bit more genealogy and i i suspect we will do more of it
 		um i found out some about some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> i didn't you know i i didn't even know their names some of the
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> back and some of the aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> and
 		uh there's a lot of things there you have to stop they're really kind of fascinating i found out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was one of a twin and we don't even know where the twin
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we have virtually no
 		no background on on her on the twin
 	
 	
 		really is that your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandma</ENAMEX>'s own sibling and she
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>
 		who would be somewhere in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> i'm sure she's you know dead now because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see oh so
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm quite a bit i'm probably a lot older than you are
 		um
 	
 	
 		well maybe um they just moved away and then just sort of lost contact and
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		
 		
 	