
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		why don't you tell me about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well we uh are a group of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> that just kind of have you know formed out of a desire to sing
 		and many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> are very professional in the sense that they or just real talented i should say lot of them are former music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> or currently teaching uh others have there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gal that's in the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Community Orchestra</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh  just you know different backgrounds it's been really kind of interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		um i play the piano
 		and uh i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> who who has started to play the piano
 		he does that uh musically listens and then he can play which is kind of interesting i think it's because he's always heard music in our home all the since he was a baby
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>  just got through singing in a musical here in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music Man</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh they did
 	
 	
 		yeah and it was lots of fun
 	
 	
 		how did
 		how did they get involved in that
 	
 	
 		um
 		basically they read in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that there were open auditions it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Repertory Theatre</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so they went and tried out and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Hill</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music Man</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> played <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in a band
 	
 	
 		oh how fun
 	
 	
 		so yeah it was really fun and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> plays the clarinet in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>  and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> takes piano lessons too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh we just really like music it's a i i especially like it as an outlet when the TV goes off we  get the TV off and and just have some nice quiet music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah that's nice you say have your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> taking lessons already
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh who do you have her or him take it from
 	
 	
 		um i have him take from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who teaches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suzuki</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is an auditory type learning experience you listen to the music and then learn to play it by learning by hearing the intervals and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i teach uh
 		like what is traditionally taught you know you look at the note on the page and you play what's on the piano
 		but he can't learn like that he's a delayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> he's only about
 		i guess he's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two and a half</TIMEX> in his real understanding of things
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh so when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> played something on the piano and he played it
 		uh with his right hand we went wow we better have him do something do something you know educationally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that was really fun my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i love to go to the musicals downtown though
 	
 	
 		well because my
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i love to go to the musicals when they come into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i have an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight and a half year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who's taken piano lessons since the started out at the age of
 		just turning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> because she wanted you know she just seemed to enjoy it so much and now my my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old four and a half year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		is trying to imitate her older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and wanting to play and she actually does some very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chording</ENAMEX> just naturally she just
 	
 	
 		oh i think that's great
 	
 	
 		so i wasn't sure when to start her i didn't want to push her too early either but uh kind of had a mixed feelings about that scene
 	
 	
 		that's really hard i think because especially if you start them and then they get pretty good and then they get close <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> or something and they go i don't want to do this anymore and you're like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		God i really want you to do it  you know so sometimes it's hard to to know exactly when but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know if she acts like she wants to or says she wants to maybe you could have her take some for a while and see how she likes it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think she'd like to i just don't know if it's really
 		knowing from what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has gone through she's she learned a lot and it course it was something she had to keep relearning if she ever got away from it it was something easily forgotten so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't know if she's any farther ahead than those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who started when they were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>  or or should i say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> i mean she's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted pianist</ENAMEX> in the sense that she's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gonna</ENAMEX> excel just naturally she does have to really work at it but
 		um so  yeah  uh so i'm kind of you know just playing with it but at this point we're going to kind of wait i think just more for the financial reasons of it anyway but
 	
 	
 		that's like me
 		well it can get expensive that's for sure
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> is is very generous in in letting us have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suzuki</ENAMEX> method without paying a lot out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah so it's been good for our family
 	
 	
 		well as a piano <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> do you have any feelings from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who come from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suzuki</ENAMEX> method have you had any former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suzuki</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suzuki</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> um
 		something happening to me at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas time</TIMEX> that that verified to me that i will always
 	
 	
 		i was wondering how they
 		
 		
 	