
 
		
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				
 				so the question is how do we keep up with current events
 			
 			
 				current events you take a newspaper
 			
 			
 				as a matter of fact as you called i was uh taking a look at uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Examiner</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				is that right is that how you usually keep up on the news
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				uh i watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> news hour fairly regularly and uh the network news less often
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				and will watch some of the talking heads programs on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and that's pretty much about it we don't get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> um
 				and uh as a matter of fact i don't get any of those sort of of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> anymore
 			
 			
 				yeah i don't either it's mostly by the news but mine is mostly mostly mostly just like the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> news or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock</TIMEX> is usually about the time i'm ready to look at TV
 			
 			
 				yeah do you watch the network news
 			
 			
 				uh yeah some
 			
 			
 				yeah out here they're moving it to a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock</TIMEX> uh well they're moving the prime time schedule up from
 				uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> which used to be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock at night till eleven o'clock at night</TIMEX> now to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 			
 			
 				oh
 			
 			
 				and i guess the network news which has moved up in time out here
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> will move up on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network affiliates</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				huh
 			
 			
 				i was just reading as a matter of fact about the news coverage of the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">JFK</ENAMEX> have you have you seen
 			
 			
 				yeah that's had a lot of publicity hasn't it
 			
 			
 				yeah it's really interesting to listen to how different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  uh approach different topics um
 				it the i didn't realize this but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to view this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zapruder</ENAMEX> film that was actually made of the assassination
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				and he had viewed it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after and uh got it completely backwards in terms of what had happened that was significant because of the obvious contention that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> at least and not one
 				and uh it's really interesting and he Rather wrote later admitted that he'd gotten the key piece of uh uh evidence backwards that he'd argued like a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> had lurched forward
 				after the shot and he'd in fact been uh forced backward which lends credence to the two
 			
 			
 				right
 			
 			
 				uh to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> conspiracy theory have you seen the movie
 			
 			
 				i haven't seen it
 			
 			
 				i haven't either
 			
 			
 				but it sure will be interesting to see how see it once i do figure out what all the controversy's about
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				it is uh you know i uh are you one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who believes that it was uh not a lone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> that that we just never really got the full story
 			
 			
 				yeah i don't think we got the full story but i don't you know i haven't seen the movie so i don't really have an opinion about what he had to say yet
 			
 			
 				yeah i i haven't seen the movie either but i i think most of us in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> believe that it just doesn't make sense that it was one guy
 			
 			
 				right
 			
 			
 				and uh
 			
 			
 				but who was involved that's i guess that's the story to tell huh
 			
 			
 				well that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>'s seeking to do and i i think it's really interesting to look at this because i think it kind of gets at the question of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get their news sometimes
 				uh really important news comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> through movies
 			
 			
 				yeah just like this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> maybe
 			
 			
 				through television
 				yeah and and i think that's really interesting i know that um uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i were talking about
 				how uh much uh attitudes toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> uh and and the relationships between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women husband</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> uh are changing and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get more of that information
 				through television sitcoms than they do through reading the newspaper
 			
 			
 				that's probably exactly right
 			
 			
 				uh that was the topic of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s T I conversation and and uh i think it's really interesting because i think all of those things wind up carrying the message and i think uh um
 				it's gonna be real interesting to see where we go with all of the selective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to be able to get via cable television and computer services
 			
 			
 				right
 			
 			
 				so much uh so much more than we can possibly consume in the way of news
 			
 			
 				that's right
 				that's right so what brought you to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> have you
 			
 			
 				um i came up here i was uh working for uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and was promoted i came out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to go to graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and and was hired out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> program um in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 				and went to work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and they promoted me and moved me up here and we liked it my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				did
 				did are you living right in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> then
 			
 			
 				live uh right out by the park right uh right off uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lindley Meadow</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate Park</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				oh well you're right in the middle of things then aren't you
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				yeah what took you to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				a job
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> lived out here and he and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> owned a little trucking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and they asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to come and run it
 			
 			
 				oh yeah
 			
 			
 				but we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> before that
 				and he grew up over there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Mateo</ENAMEX> so we know that
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and you grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Walnut Creek</ENAMEX> yeah how long have you been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				right
 				so we
 				um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about nine years</TIMEX> now
 			
 			
 				that's do you like it
 			
 			
 				i do i really like it
 			
 			
 				that's a i i hear a lot of good things about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				yeah i really like it
 			
 			
 				it's big it's probably more affordable housing it's
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's for sure  you can't even uh i mean it's not even fathomable that
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				i well i the the we live yeah living here it's just it's
 			
 		
 	