
 
     		
 	
 		how do you get most of your news
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's a a good question um
 		i read the newspaper obviously and and watch TV
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		what are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> on TV for for news programs
 	
 	
 		uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at at six o'clock in the evening</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> where we have local news  followed by uh
 		and i i i can't name the  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> i guess it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who is who is the gentleman that uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MC</ENAMEX>'s that program
 	
 	
 		uh  that's terrible i know i should know these but is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX>
 		C B S
 	
 	
 		yeah i think in fact i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> yeah i i i have uh been just retired recently so i have had very little time really to watch
 		TV and uh to get the news so all of my time that was available was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between about six</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> uh obviously i scan the newspaper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i think
 	
 	
 		are you one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that tends to like to go through the paper first thing in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> or breakfast or something or do you tend to like to read at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 		i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes that's the way i am
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i at least i used to and now i'm beginning to read it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about noon</TIMEX>  since i just retired i i retired from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX> and i just uh now i have some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> time available
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		and it used to be that we got our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> which i liked because that's when i could read it and i felt like it was fresh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two or three years our</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have been coming <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> and it's been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock at night</TIMEX> before i got to read it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i had already heard all kinds of conflicting things during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before i read a newspaper
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 		sometimes it feels as though what i'm reading in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> is the old news it's as if i heard it just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX> on the television and i wonder where they get a lot of their stories but i think that
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that i'm i feel like i get the most information from is is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> and sometimes it's on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the afternoon</TIMEX> if i'm if i'm home but i work most the time so um
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> is on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from six to seven</TIMEX> which is ideal because
 	
 	
 		well that's my normal time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> for here
 	
 	
 		yes you're preparing dinner but you still have an opportunity to to look at it occasionally we have a little <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> so there's not a lot of time to for me i feel to spend as much time with the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		updates as i'd like to i think i probably get more of it from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> because he works out of our home and um
 		can give me information about what might've happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> if he watched the afternoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeill Lehrer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about the authenticity of these various uh methods of presenting of representing the news
 	
 	
 		it it seems to me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> spends more time with each issue therefore i can count on it being more accurate uh because they've really spent more
 		development of the story as well as research and
 		and i get a better picture of what it is that i'm hearing about i i wonder about the authenticity of the others um i i have a feeling they get a lot from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> and maybe they count on what they get from those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and
 		just give little spots to it and
 	
 	
 		yes  i always wonder about the accuracy of their source of information that's what bothers me particularly you know when we're had this business of the of the war over there in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> i mean i always wondered about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it that they based what they said on whoever told them well whoever told them might not necessarily have the accurate news and know of the overall know the overall
 	
 	
 		right and certainly in that situation there was an effort to exclude the press from some activities because they didn't want to have a lot of political fall out i think but there was probably
 	
 	
 		story
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some repetition of of stories that didn't have complete um confirmation i wondered that about the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> thing recently um you know something coming out in the tabloids and being picked up by a major media
 		uh one of the accusations obviously is that they didn't go down there and research it and and get enough information i don't have a preference or an opinion really on that story one way or the other but it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's clear that there's a lot of controversy about it
 	
 	
 		well then the the only thing that you can be sure of the uh has gotten it straight from the horse so to speak is did you hear uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s speech <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well at least we know what he said
 	
 	
 		
 
 		this is true
 	
 	
 		and we we don't have to to uh read in the newspaper what they think he said or what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> think he said we know what we heard him say
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh  but it is always interesting to hear the follow ups you know on any kind of major presentation you always get the analysis
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's when you find out of all the disturbances that are in the background that know one else knows about that's the problem when you're in a politics
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's always somebody working behind your back and who just doesn't want you to get your way simply because you're on the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> well that's ridiculous really
 	
 	
 		well they all have their perceptions too you know they may have heard the exact same thing and that's just their
 	
 	
 		yeah yep
 		
 		
 	