
 
     		
 	
 		okay you're probably uh more up on this subject than i am but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the roles that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have played <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple couple of year</TIMEX> in our are couple of generations
 	
 	
 		that
 		right well they've entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> more uh you know since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War Two</ENAMEX> is when they started
 	
 	
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		and uh i think that that is you know very significant that the percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> consists of such a high percent of women
 	
 	
 		you bet you know where i've noticed it more i think is i'm a traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesperson</ENAMEX> and i have traveled most of my life and i know just especially in the last
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and really since the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the last half</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i see more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> traveling
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know as far as boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and calling on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> i sell sporting goods and even in our industry uh
 		there was virtually really and truly no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as far as selling the type of things i sell and even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five five or six years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you see more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> being involved and
 		you know it's a it's a credit to them as far as how they're doing things
 	
 	
 		yeah the you see more of that you see more of them uh leaving their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the care of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> while they do travel too
 	
 	
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		you know i i go to a i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> that i belong to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altrusa</ENAMEX> that you know one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> travels quite extensively and she said well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> you know why not
 	
 	
 		you bet that's sort of neat
 	
 	
 		so that that's a i think that's a change and i think that's a change you're going to be seeing more of in the in the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> having that kind of attitude that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s going to take more active role in child rearing
 	
 	
 		sure i think uh it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age age old</TIMEX> thing every once in a while you read in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or you'll see it on TV or something where the discussion comes out that
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are paid less than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and they're and they're doing the same uh
 		or carrying the same job responsibility and you know i that's a very true statement and it shouldn't uh it shouldn't be that way
 	
 	
 		right
 		no that that i think should change will change in the near future also it's been changing it's been evolving but there's still a an
 	
 	
 		and
 		i think so hope so and
 	
 	
 		an unequality in the work force in certain jobs it's you know and you hear some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say you know well he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> he he he needs that salary
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		you know i've
 		right yeah they forget also i think uh a good argument for that is in the area of politics you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if if a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman Congressman</ENAMEX> i'm sure makes as much as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man Congressman</ENAMEX> as and the same as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so they certainly uh they certainly deserve it all the way
 		but i guess just the most significant thing change for me again as i mentioned it was just in traveling you see uh more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> all ages with briefcases and uh and in their business suits and and going
 	
 	
 		and going yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		and i expect you're right in regards to having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> now that's a good a good statement
 		and i think if in the future it's even gonna be uh more noticeable and more significant
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i i think it will be i think i well another another thing i read too <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> this is not just for working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but how much they're out there i guess is that car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers um</ENAMEX> are starting to design <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in mind
 		um because in the past the male bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> but now they're showing that fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are actually making the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> purchases
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and that they are looking for um
 		different things in the car the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is looking for the engine in the engine and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is looking to how easy can she slide in under the steering wheel
 	
 	
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> can her makeup come off the upholstery  and if they're out there buying that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> then there's that many out that are self sufficient and you know mobile and working
 	
 	
 		good point
 		right now i'm self employed and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s always worked she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX> but for she started working and then when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started my bidness uh she was selling real estate at the time and hers was the only income we had for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four months</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know she certainly did her part in help getting me established in my business she still works everyday so
 	
 	
 		yeah we all do
 	
 	
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		i'm just happen to be off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> so  i work too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-oh</ENAMEX> enjoying enjoying it  what kind of work do you do
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well good
 	
 	
 		and i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Treatment Center</ENAMEX> um which is at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX> and Arapaho
 	
 	
 		right married
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well well
 		trying to think what else i can say in regards to this subject
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		i'm kind of out of out of things
 	
 	
 		you see the old uh
 		cigarette ads you know about you've come a long way
 	
 	
 		you've come a long way baby
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> right and uh you think about this when you coming to a when it comes to a subject like that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's really true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have come a long way and you know
 		
 		
 	