
 
     		
 	
 		why don't you start because i'm sure you've seen more movies than i have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't know um let's see have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F Kennedy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no have you
 	
 	
 		no i wanted to go see that one i was hoping my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> went and saw it and she liked it what about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Hand That Rocks the Cradle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no and i like i heard some bad reviews on that
 	
 	
 		it's supposed to be kind of scary well let's
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah have you seen any lately  what about videos
 	
 	
 		no well i mean
 		um let's see
 		well actually i have seen one i'm trying to think of the name of it um
 		it's got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> in it and um
 	
 	
 		is it a new one with him
 	
 	
 		yeah but i can't think of who's in it but it was real good
 	
 	
 		it wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson Hawk</ENAMEX> was it
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh that was horrible
 	
 	
 		oh i haven't see that one
 	
 	
 		um it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that's from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Living Color</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh even i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keenan Winey</ENAMEX>  yeah i guess so <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX> is his last name
 	
 	
 		i yeah well you you know who i'm talking about i'm trying to
 		well i can't think of it but that was it was really i thought i liked it because it was funny and they had so many it was i mean it was really action packed and it was bloody but they had a lot of um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like one liners and stuff but i cannot think of the name i'm so bad with names of movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i had a little more time to think while they were trying to find somebody and you know i haven't seen i haven't seen um any current releases my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i just don't get out to the movies that much
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no but we we're lazy  we like to rent and watch them and be able to rewind them and say what he say
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i hear you well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie</ENAMEX> there's um a ton
 	
 	
 		we saw well we saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flatliners</ENAMEX> i like that a lot
 	
 	
 		gosh that's been out a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah and um let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Awakenings</ENAMEX> did you see that
 	
 	
 		now what was that like
 	
 	
 		oh it was great it was real good it was kind of and it's a true story or so they say yeah about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that uh like
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		near comatose i guess you'd say and they uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> they're able to wake them up after after like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty years</TIMEX> and i mean it's not a real action packed movie but it was pretty neat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i remember the name of  it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Boy Scout</ENAMEX> it was with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> and i can't think of the other name the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s name but yeah it was good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ooh</ENAMEX> and did you like that one you did okay and
 	
 	
 		i'm trying to think well uh what about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Slickers</ENAMEX> since you watch  um
 	
 	
 		you know i've been wanting to i every time i go to the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> to rent that it's all rented
 	
 	
 		that's the same with same with me
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i've been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three or four</NUMEX> times just to get that movie and every time i go i guess i must be going at the wrong times
 	
 	
 		okay well um let's see
 	
 	
 		i did see Beauty and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beast</ENAMEX>  it's beautiful
 	
 	
 		well i want to go see that one but i'll probably wait for it till it comes out on video because i don't think i can get any my date to take me
 	
 	
 		yeah  just go to a matinee there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> there nobody will notice notice that you're not you know with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i said there's there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you won't notice you're not they won't notice you're not with anybody
 	
 	
 		well  that's why i'm
 		doing it well
 		yeah that's true well um what about did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances with Wolves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i saw that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times and then what's the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> was in
 	
 	
 		hm yeah i saw that one too did you like that one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>
 		okay yeah i've i've probably seen it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> times um-hum
 	
 	
 		did you that was pretty long one
 	
 	
 		yeah but i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how many times did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances with Wolves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i only watched that once
 	
 	
 		you did
 	
 	
 		yeah and i cried
 	
 	
 		uh i did too it was so sweet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i could probably tell you more that i wanna see than i have seen what about um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fried Green Tomatoes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i wanna see that one too my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> kind of went hm
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		so he wasn't real excited about going to see that one have may have to go with my mom
 	
 	
 		well a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine went to see is it what's the name of it <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bride</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX> and she said that was real cute um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah i'll probably wait for that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to came up on video it has to be real good for me to spend the money
 	
 	
 		what about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> whatever
 	
 	
 		which one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Terminator 2</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i haven't seen that one either
 	
 	
 		well that's good i cried at that one too
 	
 	
 		you cried in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Terminator</ENAMEX> 2
 	
 	
 		yeah at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end</TIMEX> i won't tell you but  i'll miss that
 	
 	
 		okay  let's see have uh  did you say you'd seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flatliners</ENAMEX> yeah okay what about let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Scissorhands</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that i saw for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time uh uh probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just loved that movie that was so sweet
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's cute then there're some what are some other ones i wonder
 		i haven't really seen that many new ones because
 	
 	
 		oh no i haven't either my in in fact we're supposed to get out to movies <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> but i don't know what we're gonna go see
 	
 	
 		now it's too late now
 	
 	
 		yeah well we might be going to a late one yeah
 	
 	
 		no well um trying to think what else i've seen
 		that's even i guess if i see them it's because they come on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah see we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> and you they have to be pretty old to get on there
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		well i think so i think they have a lot of the same ones run over and over again
 	
 	
 		well see now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Scissorhands</ENAMEX> been on there like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what i hate is they overdo it when you know when they get a major release
 	
 	
 		i'm trying
 		and then well what about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> in it that's an old one <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Days of Thunder</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't even bothered watching that one
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah is it good
 	
 	
 		it it  it's okay probably have to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		is it
 		yeah well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is if you can believe that but i'm not a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		nah he's okay but i don't think i don't see uh what i guess all the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> see in him
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	