
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so okay so what is the subject now
 	
 	
 		
  
 		it's on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the time</TIMEX> that we spend with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well let me tell you about our our situation um  we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> girls uh one is twelve one is uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and i've got uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> that are um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six</TIMEX> and three
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 		uh my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> play a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> and we travel a lot with them
 		and they're either practicing or playing and and it is really tough to fit everything in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i'm not real sure what your situation is if you you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are still at home but
 	
 	
 		uh we just uh well we have the one that uh has left
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he was here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> and uh he was involved in wrestling wrestling and along with my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is uh
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and he was uh All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> in wrestling
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then uh my last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that just left home is All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> in wrestling so we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but we had a lot of participation with them and i know what you're talking about where you it's difficult to find time but i
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i i feel it's very important that you support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> as much as you can you and uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> because uh when uh well both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> uh when they were wrestling uh they would kind of look up
 	
 	
 		you bet
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to see if we were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> and the that's the last they pay any attention to us until after the game is over right and the wrestling match
 	
 	
 		it sure makes a big difference doesn't it
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh we really enjoyed it uh to be involved with our our uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i think it's very important that's something that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> today and and and there is so much involvement that it gets pretty difficult but i think with with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and everything else that you're doing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh that's where a family relationship is really built and uh it's uh then they have
 	
 	
 		it sure is
 		we have uh in fact we this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past um Christmas</TIMEX>
 		we went out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> we uh both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> were involved in in tournaments out there so went out there we spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> with uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> out there in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and then um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we drove out to or down to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX> and had the tournament we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and just kind of you know spent time together that way
 	
 	
 		well super
 		well those are things that they'll they'll never forget and uh they know they're loved when when that takes place
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that you're supporting them there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that i know about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that they just don't take uh time to do anything with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you bet my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> just said to tell you that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> is beautiful
 	
 	
 		oh good good well we're gonna try to get down to uh hopefully for his uh uh the oldest one's uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">baptism</ENAMEX> and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>'s uh our youngest to get his uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessing</ENAMEX> but i don't know whether we can make it or not we're gonna give it a shot but that's coming up
 	
 	
 		
 
 		to be blessed
 		yeah i know that means a you'd mean a lot to uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> he's a he's a heck of a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy boy</ENAMEX> i really enjoy uh being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with him he's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i appreciate that he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super son</ENAMEX> and when he was wrestling uh we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> wrestling and we <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> we went to twelve wrestling matches in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the oldest his older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was in college and he was in high school and we could uh get to all of those but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		when did he find time to learn how to do brakes he just helped me do my brakes
 	
 	
 		oh he he's very talented in all kinds of things uh he's not like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> he can do about anything and uh we really miss him being in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah he is
 		
 
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so anyway
 	
 	
 		well that's great yeah um  my work uh uh fortunately my work doesn't take me away from  from this area so
 		i have uh i have some time i own my own business out here so i have some time just just spent with them you know whenever the time uh whenever they need me but um
 	
 	
 		um-hum well that's super
 	
 	
 		i i know that there's quite a few  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that uh or in our  you know in our area that um
 		that work  outside and and they have a even tougher  time trying to  uh schedule time with  their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum  yep well be sure and tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian hello</ENAMEX> and it's been a pleasure talking to you sounds like our time's up and uh give him the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the best</TIMEX> from him his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i'm i'm not sure if our time's up or  my phone just  went out of out of whack  i think that was just my phone
 	
 	
 		oh oh i see okay
 		i've i've this the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> call so i don't know what happens when the time's up
 	
 	
 		well they'll come back on and tell us when the time is up yeah it they should be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another couple of minutes</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh i see okay fine
 		and course church involvement i think is very important too uh that with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> uh supporting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in in taking them to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> and going with them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh-huh oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's that's another activity that uh time is spent and
 	
 	
 		well i think that's it that's probably more important than anything else and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	