
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what are your feelings on the topic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as far as crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		well i'm
 		think some of the blame can be placed on plea bargaining and people
 		getting less time and not serving any of the or a lot less of the time than they're
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		given by the court system but  i don't know with the economy the way it is i think crime can't do much but go up
 	
 	
 		no i have to i have to agree with you i had an occasion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> to hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Police</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson Texas</ENAMEX> speak and you know it's a shame
 		a a criminal today not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that breaks in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and steals things and you know he does this and he does this for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> hides all the stash and works off of it and then when he gets caught he'll be sentenced
 		something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five to seven years</TIMEX> but he gets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> credit for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> he serves i mean it's like a bonus to go to jail so subsequently a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX> sentence means he's going be out in uh a year
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		on probation i mean what he does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> said is he just merely goes back to a stash stash where he has it hidden and continues to operate and uh when he uses spends
 		uses up all that and spends all that money then he uh starts robbing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> again or whatever and gets caught again and goes through the same thing
 	
 	
 		well there was an article in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> sentenced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> the average serves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		now see that's a you talk about that's a crime right there
 	
 	
 		well we see we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well we don't either in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they shuttle they shuttle them in and shuttle them out and they get them get them early parole in order to make <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> who stay there for their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> and then they're they're paroled uh to make room for the newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>
 		and it just it it's just really absurd
 	
 	
 		well it it certainly is and uh that would be a huge concern you know i don't think the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> really realizes this
 		as far what goes on with our
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> system our judiciary
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX> system and everything else it's just uh it's terrible the way it is right now
 	
 	
 		i think the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is so overwhelmed by things right now so many different things coming in so many different directions
 		that they've just decided to become apathetic towards it all because they realize there's absolutely or they think that there's absolutely nothing they can do about it
 	
 	
 		yeah as far as steps to reduce crime if it's uh crimes like we're just been discussing
 		obviously we we need more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and more corrective <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> to put these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in to uh take them off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> but i don't think that's gonna happen because just like you said and
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 	
 	
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s a good example your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s a good example and it's just not gonna happen as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that commit rape and things like that i'm not sure what's right but i know that it's it's not right to put him in there and
 		let let him live for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and leers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before you do execute him or whatever because it's has to be very costly to feed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> and to clothe him and you know to
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i'm sure he gets to watch a lot of TV and i'm sure they have uh
 		exercise <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and movies and  and everything else you know they can
 		have a good time in
 	
 	
 		well i don't know what the answer is but i know that asking the question over and over and over again isn't working so
 	
 	
 		no it really isn't
 		it's a big it's a big problem and hopefully something will come out of it
 		so i don't know
 	
 	
 		i hope so i don't
 	
 	
 		i'm uh i'm pretty much of a hard person uh
 		i believe in capital punishment i mean you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> rapes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> or shoots someone or kills someone i mean you know if it's just downright outright
 	
 	
 		oh i definitely believe in capital punishment
 	
 	
 		oh
 		you bet i mean that's the only way to
 	
 	
 		it's when they it's when they're in on death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen years</TIMEX> that i don't i'm kind of curious curious about what
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and you spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands hundreds of thousands of dollars</NUMEX> to uh take care of them and all you know it's just unbelievable
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah you can appeal now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost almost a period of twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		can you really
 	
 	
 		yeah you can just keep going around and around and around the merry go round until you i think the i think it's uh the average is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> to get it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Carolina Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gosh
 	
 	
 	
 	
 		oh i know see
 		meanwhile you're living in a country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> situation perhaps you know
 	
 	
 		they're hoping i guess they're what they're hoping they're trying to prolong their lives and hoping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will forget what they did but it just uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		we have a serious problem in we have so many problems in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now and</TIMEX> and the the thing is the the fundamental
 	
 	
 		the drug problems that's another one
 	
 	
 		fundamental problem is the legal is
 		
 		
 	