
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		obviously there have been a lot of changes in the roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> do you do you wanna speak first about your opinions about what those changes have been
 	
 	
 		okay um i think although there have been some i'm still of the opinion that we're second rate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> in most areas
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i believe probably <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> is when you know the thing started that caused
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to be more liberated because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were at war and they needed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> and things have never been the same
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as far as the
 		as far as the job market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> started working outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> then but it's taken a long time and i think we've got a long way to go
 	
 	
 		uh  well i agree with you there i feel that there's
 		there's is a turning point ahead still ahead of us we haven't gotten there yet
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree with that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		excuse me but i do think that
 		there is a greater awareness of the the benefits that the the feminine side of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> offers you know as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> you know when you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		when you see some of what's gone on in the self development areas um you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> trying to find their feminine side is is probably something that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a generation ago</TIMEX> wouldn't have even considered as feasible
 	
 	
 		no
 		no and then i think it's a good turn i do see uh one of the reasons i also believe there's a lot to be ahead as i return to college and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> or so they think there is no problem they don't realize the struggle's just at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for them especially to go into professions that they could've just been laughed at and it can't be done anymore at least legally it can't be done
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's true that is fairly recent
 	
 	
 		i think
 		yes and i think just like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i mean it may be
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't want you in a certain profession they can't state it where i don't think the change has come like from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s side is they can still feel it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know  i think
 	
 	
 		i feel i definitely feel that that's true in the political arena it's gonna be a lot longer before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are in positions of authority authority on a on a majority basis you know there's always gonna be a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few</NUMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know whereas in education and in health care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> dominate because those are seen as supportive roles
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think it's interesting to just look at the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in history in in several cultures to to determine why in Western culture
 		they take the role that they do because it's it's a matriarchial society in a lot of different parts of the world that that puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in a much stronger position and yet  in the west it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just coming around to the point that we can recognize that the power that that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> offers to the society you know in terms of nurturing as well as
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		yeah i wasn't aware of that either until uh just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> when i took a sociology course that even existed that's how indoctrinated i was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty six</NUMEX> i grew up with the generation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> went to college and i'm now struggling to no and it
 	
 	
 		that's exciting
 	
 	
 		wasn't important you know you go be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> or be a beautician
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was my choice and uh
 		but yeah i didn't even realize there were societies like you say where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were were important
 	
 	
 		uh still a lot of that influence
 		yes yes and there's so much that's
 		um inculturated we don't realize in the home how we're
 		how we're influenced i think that even though my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> might've said you know i'm i'm in an area uh health care where there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> obviously but
 		my orientation was never toward being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> it was toward being a health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> in another area and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		even though i heard from my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> it certainly go you know pursue as far as you can you can be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> there was this under lying tone in our home because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> did not work outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that it was also okay to not do that and so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's been a challenge to to cope with both of my orientations i i have a very nurturing side that would in some ways like not to work outside the home
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i find myself looking towards what i'm doing and i'm leaning towards education and that's still another area of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but
 		that's what i wanna do you know have made i have made that decision that that's what i want to do even if it is the traditional thing it's still what i wanna do and i know it's like
 	
 	
 		um-hum hum
 		yes i think that over time we will recognize what
 		our given rights our our given uh gifts are rather that that are different from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and and it's okay that
 		that there are some differences but that there are also a lot more areas that can overlap that that at this point don't i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are told that they're probably not gonna be as good at math as as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> are and and they they
 	
 	
 		right
 		yes i'm suffering suffering through that too yeah
 	
 	
 		they may be influenced by that in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> work
 	
 	
 		i was very seriously
 	
 	
 		i don't know if i was by my by the influence or whether i just am not very oriented in math as i am to other like verbal
 	
 	
 		well i'm not because i have been tested by the office
 		
 		
 	