
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well how you doing
 	
 	
 		i'm fine i want to know where you're from
 	
 	
 		um i from um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX> where how about you
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 		i i am too
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		are you at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ United</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christ United Methodist</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no um i i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so that's how
 	
 	
 		well okay well um anyway um i'm with a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> and and we've been doing this as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund raiser</ENAMEX> i wasn't sure if they were still doing it or not but i know that's not what we're supposed to talk about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i'm having dinner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now and</TIMEX> and on the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> so just continue and you tell me something you'd like to tell me about food
 	
 	
 		well are you are you having a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> party
 	
 	
 		uh no i'm not actually i wish i were
 	
 	
 		well i was thinking now that would be a good place to exchange a recipe maybe  um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're not having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> either but um i'm going to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> it's pretty simple all i have to take is cheese  so i know i don't even have to make anything but
 	
 	
 		oh that's going to be easy
 		oh well i guess my my favorite recipe that i've seen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was fried green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> did you see that in the paper
 	
 	
 		no i didn't uh uh it's probably in reference to the movie i'm sure
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		um i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has heard about that and thought that that sounded really good are they i don't even i've never had fried tomatoes
 	
 	
 		well you know i don't guess i have i mean i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> originally and surely you know i don't even know that i've ever seen it offered to tell you the truth and but this this evidently is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> delicacy that i didn't know about
 	
 	
 		huh
 		i didn't know about it either now we i have had um  marinated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">green tomatoes</ENAMEX> you know where you marinate them with onions and cucumbers but i don't i've never had fried
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		well i tell you if you see that movie it'll make you want them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fried</ENAMEX> green ones
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it just they just really make it look good now i love things like fried okra
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i try not to ever have fried things but still you know if i  i think uh that the fried green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> would be something like that
 	
 	
 		are they pretty does it look like it's a pretty easy thing to make
 	
 	
 		probably you probably bread them and and uh you know like with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn meal</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		now i did i did go to a dinner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> that was um
 	
 	
 		fry them in grease
 	
 	
 		at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> auction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> and a lot of the things that were auctioned off were um services like a dinner for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and then if you bought if you bought it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> that might cater the dinner
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> had lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> um years oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX> and so they um auctioned off a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Filipino</ENAMEX> dinner
 	
 	
 		ooh nice
 	
 	
 		and um so it was really fun one of the things that we had were was fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um bananas</ENAMEX> but but not fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> i don't know what they're called but it's a it's kind of looks like
 		the dough that they use for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> rolls
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know what it's called but
 		they put <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> in there and with cinnamon and i don't know what else and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> and stuff and then they deep fry it
 		and they use green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> you know so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> kind of stay together  and i have fixed fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		as a um <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> dish
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and they're really really good
 		but um when you were talking about fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> it reminded me of this the fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		oh i bet that was good i know i would like that
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah it was really a fun a fun thing to do a fun way to raise money
 	
 	
 		do you work um in any particular what particular what area do you work in
 	
 	
 		i'm up at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> in what what area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um manufacturing
 	
 	
 		manufacturing because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is works for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		oh really huh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh he's at he's at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> but he's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of
 		what are you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of honey
 		telecommunications
 	
 	
 		okay okay so he's in a different group
 	
 	
 		uh-huh always it it's so funny you know his job is so complicated that i
 		to me it's complicated that i never can exactly describe this to anybody
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i never can either i i mean i never can describe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or anything try to um i try to talk real real basic level when i get down to them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well um now back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fried Green Tomatoes</ENAMEX> you be sure and see that movie
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we saw it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX> and it was wonderful
 	
 	
 		okay
 		was it
 	
 	
 		oh it really was
 	
 	
 		is it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> movie i mean is it is it something my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> would enjoy
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well it's either one
 		yeah uh-huh it it has it's a story that would appeal to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> liked it a lot huh
 	
 	
 		because he doesn't like going to see girly movies like like  um <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Steel Magnolias</ENAMEX> he didn't want you know
 	
 	
 		oh no now but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> liked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Steel Magnolias</ENAMEX> but it was more like this is more like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driving Miss Daisy</ENAMEX> did you see that and um and this probably is even a little more
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		masculine than than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driving Miss Daisy</ENAMEX> even but it's that kind of movie that has just a universal appeal
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah i mean like i have to rent Beaches and you know some of those other movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	