
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy</ENAMEX> what do you do in the way of lawn and garden work
 	
 	
 		well we have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> grass here do you have that there
 	
 	
 		um i don't know exactly what that is
 	
 	
 		it's a kind of grass that dies in the winter time
 	
 	
 		um i don't
 	
 	
 		do you live in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> or a house
 	
 	
 		yeah i live in an apartment
 	
 	
 		so you probably don't do any lawn care
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's actually correct
 	
 	
 		oh okay well we used to have a service come in
 		and fertilize and such but we ran in some into some money trouble so we do all of that ourselves now does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> die there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> in the winter time
 		is everything brown
 	
 	
 		um it turns brown yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		guess it freezes and everything so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so right now we do nothing because it's brown and it doesn't grow until
 		later on in the spring
 	
 	
 		so does that mean you have to replant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		but
 		no huh-uh it just goes dormant and then it starts it's you know it rejuvenates itself in the springtime there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh
 		that reseed in the winter time and grow something called <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">winter grass</ENAMEX> or something like that i can't remember exactly what it's called
 		and so it's green in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> but you have to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX> over all of this other stuff that's
 		there and it's kind of hard to grow it's kind of foolish  as far as i'm concerned
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so did you grow up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm actually from uh
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> area we lived outside  outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five acres</NUMEX> of land up against a hillside where i grew up and so we did have a garden about a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one a half acre</NUMEX> garden big size
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and grew standard things like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn beans</ENAMEX> and we had some trees apple <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees fruit trees</ENAMEX> you know and apple <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> do any canning and that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		did lots of canning and
 		we even
 		made an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> trip out to eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yakima</ENAMEX> area to get uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peaches</ENAMEX> and things like that to can in addition to the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> we got out of our own garden
 	
 	
 		huh
 		huh
 		we have a garden here but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's really hard to grow a garden because it's so
 		hot  and the sun is so intense that you know the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> come on and they kind of fry right on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> so it's real hard and the bugs you know if that doesn't kill it the bugs do so i have tried kind you know with just very little success
 		to have a garden here
 		did you enjoy it did you like to do it when you were there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i enjoyed um
 		working in the garden
 		um
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was a big um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of organic gardening
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and so when we um did our garbage and stuff we separated all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana peels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg shells</ENAMEX> and stuff that
 	
 	
 		yeah you had a compost pile huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and
 		always picked a different place in the garden to dump it out
 		had our own rototiller and
 		rough even though it was a large plot we used a rototiller for the whole thing and so that was it was quite a bit of work for all of us but we <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		how many how many were in your family
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> altogether
 	
 	
 		was it something that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> mostly took care of
 	
 	
 		actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> did more than his share but uh we always had our our assignments to help out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> did very little of the gardening although she did most of the canning and other things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what was your favorite thing
 		to eat
 	
 	
 		um oh to eat oh um
 		the our big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crops</ENAMEX> were were
 		green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> and i guess i liked the corn
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so  now that i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> i should be get be able to get lots of uh
 	
 	
 		you'd think so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> on the cob huh
 	
 	
 		so what took you to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i just graduated
 		i
 		i'm working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um on a post doctoral fellowship i just graduated
 		out west with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> in physics
 	
 	
 		where did you graduate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Brigham Young University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i knew it  i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> too that's why i was  when you were talking about your garden and everything and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> canning i thought this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s got to be  got to have roots there somewhere
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh
 		
 
 		yes and uh
 		so are you originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see
 		did did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> or were you more in the city
 	
 	
 		no it was more in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> but we did have a um a little garden out in the back because anything grows there  you just stick it in the ground and it it grows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is from southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and their family has a an orange <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lemon tree</ENAMEX> out back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they grow a few things they tried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> and stuff but not they don't have very you know just a small small backyard so there's not too much else they could do there
 	
 	
 		yeah do you have in in your apartment
 		
 		
 	