
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well how polluted do you think we are down here
 	
 	
 		uh well i guess we're not as bad as a lot of places but uh we're out here on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Plains</ENAMEX> so there's some place for it to go
 	
 	
 		i think so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i guess so and it's still a little bit flat around here and there's no specific mountains to hem it in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh we used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and although we were not in the smoggy area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> we used to visit down there and honestly you could
 		you could you could see the smog hanging over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> it's just about uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard that
 	
 	
 		yes we can and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine lives out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Bernardino</ENAMEX>
 		and uh uh just beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Bernardino</ENAMEX>
 		is the desert and separating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Bernardino</ENAMEX> from the desert are some mountain ranges and when the smog gets very very bad in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> it moves out there and then is bounded
 		by that mountain range and literally hangs over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Bernardino</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a very very strange thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's probably the problem with any of the coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> i think that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> has such a problem with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah although you know
 	
 	
 		you know the the the way that the air <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> move around the the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sea</ENAMEX> coast uh and it really just like making and stuff just hang over whatever cities happen to be on the coast
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i i do think that's what's one of the real problems although i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and i never noticed this kind of pollution as i i saw in uh you know southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think it's as bad yeah
 	
 	
 		and then um-hum
 	
 	
 		i know there's some because in my visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> i noticed that my i wear i'm a contact lens wearer and i noticed that i have to uh take out my contacts
 	
 	
 		yes um-hum
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> them
 	
 	
 		yeah i can't wear them as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">many hours</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> as i can other places but you know i mean that's not just <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> i mean that's also <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> is the worst city i've ever been at
 	
 	
 		uh oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		course now i hear that uh you now like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> is real bad for that
 	
 	
 		oh i see well i've never been down there
 	
 	
 		and also places in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sao Paulo</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		is that right well what are they doing down there that causes such a thing what kind of industries do they have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they have no they have no pollution controls whatsoever
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so whatever industry they do have even though they don't have as much as we have they just like fire away you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i see um
 	
 	
 		they control nothing i mean it's like it's like you know the situation it you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> even though there's there's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> uh it it's my understanding because i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> there that are Brazilian
 		uh there's an upper-class and a lower-class and no middle-class
 	
 	
 		oh i see um-hum um-hum
 	
 	
 		and so you know the lower class is working uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> which pollute the air and the upper classes make the money off of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see uh-huh um
 	
 	
 		and so pollution is a big problem for all of the you know underdeveloped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> because they're not going to they're not going to start instituting regulations that are going to impede their whatever industry they happen to have
 	
 	
 		um
 		profits i guess
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum yeah uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which you know  that's  kind of going to be the end result you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> i was reading in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s moratorium on regulatory
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh things right now that are going to impede business the first effect that it has had is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> had some new regs up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for um congressional approval that had to do with making industries uh itemize uh different types of things that they were you know
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		putting into the air you know part of the clean air act you know which is to help enforce the clean air act and so that of course you know the moratorium on new regulations has you know hamstrung that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right uh-huh i i know that
 		a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> simply do not have the governmental regulations and i think that unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is uh
 		on top of this or at least instrumental in trying to do something that nothing is really going to be done by private industry until they you know get that push it really wasn't done in our country
 	
 	
 		absolutely not
 		not any profit driven industry because you know they're just absolutely not going to you know sit still for anything that's going to take away from profits i mean we're we're living in the greed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> here i mean there is no there is
 	
 	
 		you know um um-hum yeah uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh  the greed generation oh what a terrible thing to say  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		sure i mean you know
 		i mean i've heard i've heard that before and i'm now beginning to believe it because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know what i mean i have some limited involvement in some in some what you would call i guess environmental type entities i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and i write letters for a number of environmental um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh purposes and you know it it is amazing to me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can sit here and look at the situation that we have globally and say you know what the hell
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i know um um-hum
 	
 	
 		because uh you know it's it's really apparent to me especially living in a city the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that the wide open spaces that where always the justification for why worry you know are going away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		oh
 		
 		
 	