
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what do you think about  your everyday occurrences that are that are an invasion of your privacy
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well the uh what i really  i don't like is the call the constant calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> selling things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> telling me i won things
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to solicit for different you know organizations
 		now that's what i really
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that that's the only thing i wrote down also because that's just a
 		it's terrible <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i  it seems like i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty</TIMEX> and the damn phone starts ringing and and it rings up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock</TIMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		never stops ringing right
 		that's right well you know the the great uh things of that its a is is an answering machine  i mean this is this is the one of the best inventions ever you know you just switch that thing on and uh
 	
 	
 		yes i know that's true
 		
 
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know people
 		it's like your name must be on a list or something because i know at my office i get calls
 		i mean i must get at least i probably average at least a call a day and and a lot a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> i'll get to and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> calls from
 	
 	
 		hum even in an office
 	
 	
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> selling insurance you know to the small business man
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunn and Bradstreet</ENAMEX> puts your according to what i've understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunn and Bradstreet</ENAMEX> puts your names your name out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> also as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> all i get calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> always trying to sell something oil oil investments or stock investments or whatever
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and now i getting the same calls at at the house
 	
 	
 		um-hum i know
 	
 	
 		and they get your and they get your name from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunn and Bradstreet</ENAMEX> and uh credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> they sell your name
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh well you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they sell your names i mean you know i that's also an invasion of privacy i think if the whole thing is a
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> does that by the way
 	
 	
 		oh they do
 	
 	
 		yeah i understand they sell their you know they sell names because it's quite profitable to them
 	
 	
 		well sure it is
 	
 	
 		and uh that is an invasion of privacy you're right
 	
 	
 		that's right well you know if you've ever gotten anything you know in your life your your name is somewhere  i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and boom they got your name forever
 	
 	
 		i know that's true
 		exactly magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> uh  from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from</TIMEX> subscriptions do the same thing it's the way they make additional money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but it's uh you know i guess it uh you have to be a certain income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> to uh have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> card so your name is valuable to i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitors</ENAMEX> calling
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		so i don't know
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		where where do you where you from
 	
 	
 		oh i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well so yeah we live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well we're in Plano
 	
 	
 		okay laughter
 	
 	
 		well you know the only call i really got that well was out of state i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did you
 	
 	
 		and that was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i was thrilled to death because that's the you know the furthest i'd gotten any call from you know and um
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got i talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and a lot of times i'll call <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> and i'll get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know from out of the uh out of the state
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh
 		yeah see well that's uh that there was another call on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday Saturday</TIMEX> that was also from uh that was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know why i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>  from out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> will uh i don't know you know but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'll be darn where you from not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> right yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really what part
 	
 	
 		yeah from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saddle River</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice over there yeah we're from more uh from sort of towards the shore central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> you know we're like uh
 	
 	
 		she
 		okay
 		well that's nice too
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah it was beautiful that's why i i really miss it i i don't really like it here at all
 	
 	
 		really yes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s been away since we've been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> so she she's been away for quite a while
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock Arkansas</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> so they just
 	
 	
 		yeah so their
 	
 	
 		they officed over there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so but anyway yeah this topic is it's a good topic as far as invasion of your privacy but that's the the biggest one i can think of is just all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitors</ENAMEX> calling
 	
 	
 		well yeah i mean yeah yeah and i know of course they call and you know before i got the answering machine it was ridiculous you know i said this is absurd i the you know i the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the minute</TIMEX> i get home the phone would be ringing uh
 	
 	
 		i know
 		that's a that's a good suggestion i might start using the answering machine more because you know it's so hard to  not pick up that phone when it rings
 	
 	
 		oh it's great i mean
 		well you know in fact i've been missing calls from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> switchboard because i i always have it on you know and i'll get that that that message that says uh uh to to uh um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you uh know end this call press <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and i assumed i you know was from the switchboard you know  yeah it is because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> i listened you know and it was
 	
 	
 		sure
 		you yeah you're probably right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know but um i i just got totally disgusted and and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> asking for for money for everything you know i mean it
 	
 	
 		i understand i mean i it's hard to believe there's that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		exactly and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i know they call you one time to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to the carnival carnival or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		oh i used to do that yeah i used to do that i'd say or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to the movies or something
 	
 	
 		right there's always a different and i my my pat answer now is well you just called me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX>
 		
 		
 	