
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Ashley</ENAMEX> um do you exercise regularly
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i do i uh go on long walks whenever i can and uh
 		well when i when i can fit it into my schedule and the weather's right i like to walk uh oh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three four miles</NUMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well that's pretty good i unfortunately uh am not um exercising regularly at the time um
 		i
 		we've recently made a move i used to be at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> where there's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> there and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i regularly played um racquetball
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um since we've moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> now um we don't have as many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> like that um
 	
 	
 		well that sort of same sort of thing happened to me i used to be a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swimmer</ENAMEX> i i taught at a university and i you know could use the pool  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> if i wanted and since moving away from the university environment i've uh
 		now it's kind of difficult to find a pool that's convenient and affordable to swim in
 		but uh what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> were you at
 	
 	
 		i was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um actually i am working at a university right now i just graduated with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">PhD</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young</ENAMEX> and i'm working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Iowa</ENAMEX> however
 		we had all free benefits for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young</ENAMEX> but um
 		oh it's we the benefits here as far as um using the physical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are not free here so and plus they're not as convenient we're we're further away so it's not as convenient for like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to come in you know for doing things together
 	
 	
 		did you say you're at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Iowa Iowa City</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i went i visited visited there once quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who was in the linguistics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i'm in uh
 		at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for Voice</ENAMEX> and Speech which is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um Department of Speech Pathology</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well you would do you have contact with any of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in linguistics
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		i just i haven't been here uh uh only for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> and uh i i'm sure that there must be some cooperation between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> but uh i'm not aware of anything as yet
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i
 	
 	
 		well if you ever run into uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy Reagan</ENAMEX> say hi to her for me  i think she's still there
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		okay usually when the temperatures are warmer um i live about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so um
 		from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> so i often will walk in which i guess it's i'm not sure how far it is um actually it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five minutes</TIMEX> and it's probably about a mile i don't know long it's got to be maybe a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well how briskly do you walk do you think how how fast do you walk do you think
 	
 	
 		what
 		oh i walk rather briskly but i don't i don't do it during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these winter months</TIMEX> it's just far too cold um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well a brisk walker can go maybe what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles an hour</NUMEX> so if it takes you <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a third of an hour</NUMEX> to get in you're probably going oh i would say <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">at least a mile and a half</NUMEX> probably
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah so anyway i could get a little bit of exercise that way um
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> of course even here in uh in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we do get a little cold weather but most of the winter i can go walking just about anytime i want to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this winter though it's rained so much that uh there've been times where see my uh favorite
 		uh area to walk is a a greenbelt they have right through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> here and uh
 		you know it's it surrounds a little stream over much much of its extent you can walk for miles there and never cross a street you you go under the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh when the uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is too high uh you'd get washed away i mean they have signs up there warning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to stay away so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we've had that uh a number of times recently not to mention the mud of course
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		well you can get you can do the other thing i do is uh i have a little exercise bike that uh wasn't too expensive i got a cheap one but you can really work up a sweat on it
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah if i were to begin to begin exercise now i think it'd be something that i could do um
 		indoors something that's convenient
 		um
 		you know
 		it's like an exercise bike or something like that although i haven't purchased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> purchased one yet sometimes i do i have this little trampoline
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		small type trampoline that i do indoor jogging on sometimes for exercise but i haven't really started been doing anything regular for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several months</TIMEX> since we've since we've moved to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i really prefer outdoor exercise i'm afraid that my favorite indoor exercise is eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple pie a la</ENAMEX> mode and that doesn't help very much
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well outdoor exercise is uh more convenient however
 		
 		
 	