
 
     		
 	
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um okay
 		we've got one he's uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen weeks</TIMEX> yesterday
 	
 	
 		oh wow congratulations
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		actually even though our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is a year and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half</TIMEX> we just got her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX> we adopted a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so we um traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> and we adopted her and so we're
 		she's just at a playful age right now we just do a lot of things play with her and take her to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> of course can't right now it's too cold to go out too much here it's been really cold
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		it's not not real toasty here either but i imagine it's a good deal colder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh although we were gone for most of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and we had a nice time in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> for our vacation visiting family
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		is that where you're from originally
 	
 	
 		no that's where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s from and we also visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> where i'm from
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and
 		so
 		we just love mainly we we like to spend time playing games and
 		um
 		just she's sort of at a playful age teaching her new words things like that
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 		right now uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s just uh dealing with grunts and squeaks and grinning and crying and
 	
 	
 		yeah so yeah your your activities probably consist of staying up at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		actually no he sleeps real well at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		he'll he he generally sleeps through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> uh he'll go down about till well he don't doesn't go down till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten ten thirty</TIMEX> which is a little tough when you got a lot of studying to do but uh
 		he'll uh he won't get up till like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere between six and eight</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		he'll be ravenously hungry by then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he's truly a jolly little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> and sleeps through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> too which is a real blessing
 		uh it it took about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX> before he started that
 		which i don't think it was quite coincidental but he started sleeping through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> about the time we took him out of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bed and</ENAMEX> put him in a crib in in the next room
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		suddenly he started sleeping through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> almost consistently
 	
 	
 		well we found that was important too for sleeping through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> um having um their their own room
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in fact it was almost trained out of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX> where at our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where it's just um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for all of us our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and us um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">first few nights</TIMEX> back she was terrified to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> by herself but now she's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		sleeping through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> again so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		um we
 	
 	
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> um
 		is we also other things we're trying trying to do um um
 		is potty train our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> a year and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half</TIMEX> that's a little some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think that's a little bit early but um
 		she was the foster parents our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> who had taken care of her before we could get her um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> generally potty train their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> a little bit earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so um we're having spend some time with that also
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 		and
 	
 	
 		that's got to be a a lot of fun
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'd
 		she doesn't enjoy it that much but um she's learning slowly but surely
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah uh uh it's you know
 	
 	
 		we have a little book it talks about giving rewards and so it's a pleasant experience and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well they they the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are gonna to eventually training wind up training themselves but
 		um they can be trained into it pretty early too
 		so  i remember some of the strange potty training experiences when i we were growing up amongst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and sisters
 		so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we're almost kind of not looking forward to that
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah but there's a lot of we we're just having lots of fun with with our little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> right now um she has lots of toys got little
 	
 	
 		anyway
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		she especially likes the little telephone and the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tyke</ENAMEX> bike that she has
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and then reading she likes us to to go through the books you know and she could say a few word you know she could learning to say the names of you know a lot of simple <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and um
 		and the you know the sounds that they make
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> says quack
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doggy</ENAMEX> says ruff things like that
 		so that's about her
 		her stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and she's running around she she started
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		when we first adopted her we she she wasn't walking yet but she was soon walking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a couple weeks</TIMEX> after that and now she's running all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	