
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay so what now what are your opinions on recycling
 	
 	
 		well i definitely think we need to start recycling i think it has got to be an individual responsibility
 		until i think if we wait uh which is happening until somebody says we have to do it it's gonna be too late
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i've heard reports around here that the landfills will be full by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard that too
 	
 	
 		and that's not too far away but i don't know how it is there it is very difficult here even if you care like i do to do much i take my paper i can take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and paper bags back to the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and i can take
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		plastic like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk cartons</ENAMEX> or if they have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in them
 		and there's some fire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> i can take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to and that is very inconvenient cause i have to wait until i have enough of them to make the trip worthwhile
 	
 	
 		well see i had started saving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and i have save <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a ton</NUMEX> of them and uh that's i can't remember where i went to take them but they wouldn't they wouldn't take them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's very hard to find a spot and then i don't know if you notice even doing that the amount of trash we throw away is incredible bottles that cannot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> that cannot be it could be recycled but there is no place to
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 		there's no really recycling facilities
 	
 	
 		no we have a pilot program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> going on i think in the north part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where they're having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> separate the garbage as the trash as they put it out
 	
 	
 		i think that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		and i think that's what it is gonna have to come to where we're just forced to
 	
 	
 		besides well like a law or whatever and that's how it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think so it's just because they have to you know
 	
 	
 		um-hum you get ticketed if you don't do it right
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh and i think it's going to come to that because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will just not go to the it's it's trouble for me to do what i do i mean i am willing to do it but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		plus you have to have a place to store all of it and see i live in an apartment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's very difficult like our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> is always full of stacks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and
 		so i don't know i think there needs to be more places i also have a real strong opinion in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> the state i'm from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i believe it's gone up to a dollar now everytime you buy a container no matter what it is whether it is glass whether it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> can or a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX> or a pop or whatever you pay
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> cents for it and then you take it back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and you get it back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh so that way that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> you to recycle
 	
 	
 		you're forced to and uh you also don't see the litter there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		it makes it worthwhile to take it back and i've just started drinking a new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> called Clearly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> i don't know if you've tried it
 	
 	
 		yeah i've seen them
 	
 	
 		and they have on the back it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cents</NUMEX> okay it's still <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cents</NUMEX> and it even shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that take them back
 	
 	
 		yeah well what some of them are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> some are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> cents i am looking at it right now
 	
 	
 		is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> one of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is not one of them see so i have to throw them away cause there is no place to take glass
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		no i don't think that there's enough being done now i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX> at their corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> and we have a paper recycling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		program that's um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> wide and i do the recycling for that
 	
 	
 		okay do they save like the paper they they use at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> paper good because there is a lot of waste there isn't there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i know there's a lot of computer paper though that you can't use
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um we use to have uh i mean i i don't even remember how much money that they've um mean i mean the money that they've made from the recycling program they've donated it to charities but i mean they've made a substantial amount of money from it
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		something else i think we can do is support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that encourage like i've decided Downy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric softener</ENAMEX> now has where you can buy a little carton
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you add water i'll i image everybody else will start doing that sooner or later but i am gonna stick with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downy</ENAMEX> because they were first you know i want them to have my business
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think packaging could be done much better there is so much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		well now you see some of this stuff and you're and then when they come out with the new things you are like uh well why didn't you think of that before
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and i think that it's just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have got to be aware unfortunately there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that just don't care and they don't wanna think about it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh i just look at it as i don't want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> looking at me and saying why didn't you do something you know i want to feel like i at least tried
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i don't know it just may overwhelm us
 		here when we run out of places to put it then we'll be forced to it may be too late
 	
 	
 		do they not ever i mean i don't know that much do they not ever burn trash or anything like
 	
 	
 		very little that's another thing and if you ever know like i know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway</ENAMEX> i only use a couple things form <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway</ENAMEX> that it says this is burnable material well
 	
 	
 		then that's pollution
 	
 	
 		that doesn't do me any good because i don't have any place to burn it
 	
 	
 		yeah i know i guess you run into the pollution factor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and then just like the glass bottles that that says on the bottle i can get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> cents but not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and there's no place i can take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i still throw away a lot of glass
 	
 	
 		
  
 		truly sad
 	
 	
 		yeah and then the packaging really grips me you buy something it's got a great big piece of cardboard and a great big piece of plastic
 		
 		
 	