
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um  Lee</ENAMEX> what advice do you have for someone choosing a college
 	
 	
 		well uh as a former uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> in a university and having been through college uh
 		and graduate school myself i guess my own um
 		advice would be to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> try to assess the needs of the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> um some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do very well in large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>
 		and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do very well in junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do very well in residential college environments um
 		and i think it really depends upon the individual the safest bet for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want uh
 		uh a good quality experience is a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> where they're gonna get an opportunity to have more personal contact and uh
 		where they're going to be forced by the circumstances to learn more than might be the case in a big university
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> did you go to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> for your undergraduate
 	
 	
 		no i went to a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> i went um i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> as an undergraduate and i looked at small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and frankly um
 		i think i had this sense that it would have been more difficult at small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and i think it would would have been definitely i mean i
 		i graduated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phi Beta Kappa</ENAMEX> summa cum laude and went on to do a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> and i think that uh had i gone to a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> i might have learned a lot more but i don't think my grades would have been nearly as good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think you can get away with more in a big uh a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> uh what what kind of experience have you had in this regard
 	
 	
 		well um
 		i went to a private university although it was a large private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bringham Young University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and that's uh has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty seven thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's big yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's it's pretty big
 		but
 		i enjoyed my experience there one thing i was thinking about this topic is um
 		i would try and get a lot of input from
 		from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who had gone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in the particular program and see how they liked it for example i made well i had a bad experience in graduate school
 		and i think i would never have gone to the place had i have went and visited the place and talked to some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who were currently in the program for example i um started graduate school um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		in well i don't know if i should give specific names but uh it was
 	
 	
 		well that's all right go ahead
 	
 	
 		um it was just in a physics program back east and um  well it happened to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Melon University</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the teaching assistantship situation just was not very good it turned out that um
 		there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> new teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> who went we all quit after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our first year</TIMEX> of graduate school  um
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		it turned out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">undergraduates</ENAMEX> had thrown a big fit the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> before that they weren't learning from the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">TAs</ENAMEX> and they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from foreign TAs
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAs</ENAMEX> also but the foreign TAs could not teach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> and so there was a huge teaching burden on us the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAs</ENAMEX> and so it's we were really bogged down and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what i think is one of the problems with with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> going to a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> generally and this happens at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cal</ENAMEX> out here
 		i i think that the the residential college experience is generally the best for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are particularly pardon me
 	
 	
 		you mean community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> type or you mean by residential college do you mean
 	
 	
 		well i mean uh let me let me give you an example of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that would fit that description
 		um i would say that uh some of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> in the country
 		are small residential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swarthmore College</ENAMEX> like um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amherst Wesleyan Williams College</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see oh
 	
 	
 		um  those are places that that in academia are generally regarded as the best places to get liberal arts educations
 		on the other hand you can go to a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and do very well and some big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> i don't know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bringham Young</ENAMEX> is like this but some have a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> feel to them you don't get a lot of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">TAs</ENAMEX> you i mean in other words that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who teach really know how to teach
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think that's what important for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh in my case
 		i went through uh between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty eight</TIMEX> and seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in college and it was just this big uh grade game for me
 		and i learned some things and i just luckily stumbled in the right area
 		um but i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> out of graduate school i had worked in industry before i ever came back and wanted to use my training as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>  to um
 		you know to get anything done and as matter of fact i'm i'm working on a book and a theory
 		uh which has its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> ultimately in theoretical physics and i'd never would have imagined myself wanting to do something like that i had such a negative
 		
 		
 	