
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what do you think have been the most significant changes
 	
 	
 		uh mainly the fact that they let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in law now
 		i think that had a lot to do with the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought about women
 	
 	
 		so lawyers
 	
 	
 		not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> but police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and
 		the whole legal profession in general
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because it used to be strictly male and the views on it used to be strictly male
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and now there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in it and i think that affected a lot of things
 	
 	
 		well i think that's a big contributor i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have uh really
 		um begun to penetrate a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> that were dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for centuries
 	
 	
 		oh i can i can definitely agree with that i'm i'm in a field that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say is strictly male
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah mechanics
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i think um
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the best things that has happened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twentieth century</TIMEX> has been the uh penetration of a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and  i think
 		it's gonna continue uh and even though it's pretty difficult now for
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i think uh
 		it's gonna bring very good things and uh we're going to be a lot better off as a society as it continues but it's a painful transition
 	
 	
 		oh yeah very painful especially when you have certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that take very dim views on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> that actually work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and i still hold down a job and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say well you're not home with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all the time your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are gonna turn out bad i don't think so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think there are a lot of attitudes that have to change and i guess that's the big thing
 		you know as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> change their attitudes that's gonna make the biggest difference women uh participating as equal partners
 		in our society is one of the best things that will ever happen and history will record that but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really don't like that idea and uh
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but you'd believe you wouldn't believe how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are against it
 	
 	
 		no i i'm not look at what happened with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> testimony before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> now i'm not surprised by that at all we have uh we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> old my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh works out of the home um and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i think just looking at how uh her uh views differ from those of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> a generation before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's it it's really changing attitudes and um the economic necessity and the political changes as you pointed out are going to make a big difference i think
 		um it's a painful transition but a really important <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and i think it's one of the biggest steps
 		we or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in general could take
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's a big step for humankind and i think uh it's it's real progress but there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with attitudes that have to change and i i guess in answering the question that's what i would say i'd say
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that overall it's just the attitude of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> toward equal participation and equal pay and equal political influence and all sorts of other things for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> because
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		that's really gonna be better for everybody but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are threatened by that as is reflected in what goes on
 	
 	
 		yeah that's for sure and you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are the ones that are fighting this
 		but you'd be surprised the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> going into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> doing you know even jobs you know on an even keel with men
 		a good percentage of them are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are fighting it and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> try and keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> locked up that's not necessarily true
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have these ideas that they got to be the little home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> and they have to stay at home or they're not doing good you know a good job
 		and that's not necessarily so but everybody's blaming it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> saying well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> don't let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> out
 		that's not necessarily so it's just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have to realize they can do both
 	
 	
 		well i think i think both
 		yeah both attitudes have to change and i think uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um it's it's evident evident to me as i look at all the television shows that now focus on the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> uh watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> last night watching
 		uh the show that preceded it Home Improvements all these television shows which reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are beginning to reflect new attitudes and those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are actually getting out and working and also keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> together
 	
 	
 		well and not only i mean  the the fact of the matter is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have have carried more than their weight and are still doing that and
 		um i see i think this is part of the problem for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as well as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i recognize that it's uh it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who've suffered from this too because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> need to learn to learn
 		
 		
 	