
 
     		
 	
 		um what
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		things are you looking for in a car what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> would you buy
 	
 	
 		well right now i have a uh small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> Tercel
 	
 	
 		for your next purchase
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think next time i want something just a little bit bigger uh perhaps mid size i really don't don't like the the real big cars
 		i'm thinking about maybe a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it's funny because i currently also have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> Tercel
 	
 	
 		you do
 	
 	
 		um
 		when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got married my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> gave
 		me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 		a used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">um Corolla</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we used that until we  until it's about run into the ground and then we um bought a used um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota Tercel i</ENAMEX> was still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at the time and um so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you bought what we could afford
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and
 		i think definitely um now we would also get a a larger car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		how did your uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corolla</ENAMEX> hold up
 	
 	
 		oh
 		very well
 		um
 	
 	
 		for real
 	
 	
 		it um
 		did very well i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you remember how many miles you had on it in the at the end
 	
 	
 		uh yeah it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a hundred and fifty thousand</NUMEX> and it may have gone further but um
 		it was very reliable though for us though
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tercel</ENAMEX> now has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty six thousand miles</NUMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i really haven't had any trouble out of it except the alternator went out at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a hundred and twenty six thousand</NUMEX> miles i think
 	
 	
 		oh that's to be expected i would think
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		hopefully hopefully it just doesn't  happen at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad time</TIMEX>  i mean when you're far away from anything or something
 	
 	
 		right and um it's really been great i have had no problems with it you know except little little minor things like you know belts and course you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> did you buy it new
 	
 	
 		actually i didn't i bought it from um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertz Rent A Car</ENAMEX> and it had like twenty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six thousand miles</NUMEX> on it  when i bought it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i see but well sounds like it's been a good deal for you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		another thing i may consider the main thing i look for in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is reliability
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and
 		um i just go by what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> says he's a mechanic and i remember growing up and and but he's always never wanted to spend a lot on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because i grew up in a fairly large family <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and we just didn't have a lot of money to spend on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so um i remember growing up and having like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramblers</ENAMEX> and stuff like that and think they're the most unreliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that ever existed i mean ours broke down all the time luckily my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was  mechanic and he could fix them but i remember
 		he said he said he would never buy um a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but then in nineteen eighty he bought a used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corolla</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i mean didn't even spend very much money for it i don't think he spent more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> for it but he said it was the most reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> he ever had purchased
 	
 	
 		wow
 		right
 	
 	
 		and he has bought nothing but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corolla</ENAMEX> since that time
 	
 	
 		uh
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and so um
 		but i don't know my feeling is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> to keep up at all are becoming more reliable also so i may consider buying um an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made car
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm trying to consider that uh that could do to the plight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> and all of that
 	
 	
 		my next my next purchase
 	
 	
 		i'm really trying trying to consider
 		but i don't know i i i don't want to have to spend a lot of money for car repairs
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> yeah one of my cousins
 		is trying to tell convince me that um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are becoming reliable reliable but
 		uh i'm not i'm not sure i just i know for example that both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corolla</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tercel</ENAMEX> have been very good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and reliable that that i've i've used
 	
 	
 		have you heard that uh or do you know anything about the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> being easier to steal than the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		because there's a lot of of um car theft going going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> right now i don't know about in your area
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa City Iowa</ENAMEX> very small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and i don't i don't know if there's even uh more than a
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> i mean um that's that that's not a big consideration here and i just moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> where i that's where i was going to school before and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		also there um there's i've never had that concern
 		um so i'm not really i'm not really sure
 		
 		
 	