
 
     		
 	
 		tell me what's the last movie you saw
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the last movie i saw in a theater was Hook
 	
 	
 		Hook
 	
 	
 		and uh it was very enjoyable um
 		i'm trying to think there's a lot of movies i want to see
 	
 	
 		oh yeah there seems to be a lot out especially around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> but we were
 		kind of busy and didn't really get out to see any of them
 	
 	
 		but it but what the last one you saw
 	
 	
 		uh the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> to see was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Doctors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and i thought that was real good
 		but i rent movies all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah we do too
 	
 	
 		yeah the last that seems to be the way we do it any more i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dying Young</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that good that's with um i'm trying to think who's in that
 	
 	
 		and last week
 		uh what's her name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay
 	
 	
 		and uh it was just really good
 		i knew it was going to be sad and i knew somebody was going to be dying
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it was is still has an interesting plot twist to it
 	
 	
 		um we want to go see JFK
 	
 	
 		yeah trying to
 	
 	
 		i mean i have heard lots of reviews and stuff but i still want to see it just to
 	
 	
 		i have been putting off to go see that one but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> wants to see it too
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		it just seems so much trouble any more to go to a theater
 	
 	
 		yeah it is and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> has grown so much that
 		um you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and stuff are all so crowded now you use to be able to get out to get a quick bit to eat and go see a movie and it's just not that way any more
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we usually stay in on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and rent movies and i think probably the last rented movie i saw
 		well no i take that back it wasn't rented i think it was just on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> at my in-laws <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or something but it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red October</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i
 	
 	
 		and i love that movie
 	
 	
 		yeah i went uh i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> to see that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and then i rented it i think when it came out too
 	
 	
 		yeah oh that would've been a good one
 		that would've been a good one to see
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but renting them just doesn't do them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		sometimes you're right it doesn't uh
 		but it beats watching what ever is on television
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true i mean i think like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Dances with Wolves</ENAMEX> just
 		you know would be a good movie on television but it you know the scenery and everything was so beautiful on the screen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we had a pretty quiet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> at our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and one of the things that we've been putting off for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> was to was to rent all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> movies
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so we did that
 		and
 	
 	
 		all of them did you
 	
 	
 		it was uh you know like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen hours</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> stuff
 	
 	
 		oh wow in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no it took us about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		okay i was going to say that's a long movie
 	
 	
 		yeah well it was still lots i'm telling you when that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that the last hour</TIMEX> you know uh number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
 		we felt like we were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> we were eating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> and drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and we were thinking this has got to stop
 	
 	
 		how many are there
 	
 	
 		there's three
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		yeah it's almost something around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's not as bad as as uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friday the 13th or Planet of the Apes</ENAMEX>  or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh but my i think my favorite though are old movies black and white
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i like the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> movies in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> and things like that
 		it's just i don't know there's just something about them i think it reminds me of my childhood
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		not  i just remember when i was little in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> we got to stay up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> and that's what was on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so somehow that reminds me again with all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and you know making popcorn and making homemade pizzas in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> and stuff so
 	
 	
 		we went through a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> where we rented a lot of the um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Hitchcock</ENAMEX>
 		the you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rear Window</ENAMEX> and all those and those are really good i mean you know the old black and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i watched uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Day Retrospective</ENAMEX> on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> just
 		i thing about her and different movies she'd been in and i realized how much i missed the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doris Day Rock Hudson</ENAMEX> movies
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		they were just always i can remember never missing one at the theater
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and because they were like fantasy and and they were an escape from the real world i think and even if i see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> or somewhere i'll want to watch it so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		oh they're those are some movies
 		and they come on uh every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then
 		are you still there
 	
 	
 		yeah i am still here yes
 	
 	
 		okay it got real quiet i didn't know
 	
 	
 		yeah i was just kind of
 	
 	
 		there was no static or anything i thought no
 	
 	
 		i am in a rest area and i was just kind of looking someone went by there i
 	
 	
 		i thought i'd lost you
 		so you are headed up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighty fifth</NUMEX> birthday
 	
 	
 		where about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Kingsport</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay that's right yeah um i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and i have traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson City</ENAMEX> before and i
 	
 	
 		you know where that is
 		oh yeah are they still there
 	
 	
 		um most of it was sold off to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>'s but there is still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that work that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i remember back when they first open in the early seventies there i worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Univac</ENAMEX> and uh just down the road and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> all the everybody just
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 		
 	