
 
     		
 	
 		well have you taken any vacations that you enjoyed lately
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and uh drove flew into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and drove up the coast
 		to uh through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and over to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Tahoe</ENAMEX> and flew out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay so you went up like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Highway</ENAMEX> for a way and then then went inland there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> was really great
 	
 	
 		is is that was that a new area for you to visit
 	
 	
 		most of it was because i had uh seen parts of northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and i'd been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> but never along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Road</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was quite exciting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> said he didn't know whether he wanted to ever drive it again though
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's the
 	
 	
 		have you been
 	
 	
 		it's scenic i guess i i've i've been to a part of that on a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> i i went up just a short ways up the coast to i believe it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Point Raid</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh National Seashore i</ENAMEX> think it was
 	
 	
 		um i don't remember that
 	
 	
 		and i only had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a day</TIMEX> so it was just a short drive up from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and back when i was out out for business
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well we went uh we liked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterey</ENAMEX> very much and uh it was just kind of a relaxed pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> with a lot of things to see and do and
 		and then uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muir Woods</ENAMEX> on the other side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> um that's another really bad drive but it's it's worth going to
 	
 	
 		uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redwood</ENAMEX> forest there
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are you from
 	
 	
 		originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i was raised up in Dalhart
 		so uh anything that doesn't look like flat plains is uh like i told someone once i always thought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> was real green
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because it was the greenest place i'd ever been
 	
 	
 		are you currently living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay see i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too but
 	
 	
 		where are you from where do you live
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well you're just a  a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well we uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i moved here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and that's a good vacation spot too  but it was nice living there
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		well we uh when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were young we used to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estes Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i i didn't live too far from there in fact i bicycled from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to there a time or two uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		how fortunate you were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX> i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's that is one beautiful place
 	
 	
 		uh i i uh didn't probably take advantage of it as much as i probably would if i moved back  you kind of take it for granted when you live there but
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i did enjoy the skiing and and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the and the winter</TIMEX> sports that that was available there
 	
 	
 		um
 		well i've never skied my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> keeps saying we need to go but uh we have never done it yet but uh everyone who does says it's great
 	
 	
 		yeah it's enjoyable if you do it more than once or twice so you get past the learning stage so you can start enjoying it it's a little bit frustrating when you're falling a lot but after  after you get past that it's a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		you have to enjoy the cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> in your face huh
 	
 	
 		well it sometimes can be yeah it it uh
 		you can get some nice days skiing as well though if if you're not falling you can stay pretty dry and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh it can be pretty nice the dry climate doesn't feel near as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold</ENAMEX> as as it does here in the winter time to me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think that uh no the dampness course our humidity is sort of medium compared uh well where i was raised is extremely dry
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		it's the the other extreme
 	
 	
 		yeah so we're kind of in-between but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> always said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> was extremely humid to her
 	
 	
 		yeah it's i i agree with you it's sort of in between yeah after having lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> a lot that was a little dryer than was probably comfortable it's a bit little too dry and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and this is actually a pretty good climate humidity wise in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		have you gone on any vacations lately
 	
 	
 		last uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> we uh we went uh and took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancun</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and uh we really enjoyed that trip
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		have they uh we were we were there when it one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> times it was open they were just building the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well it's pretty built up now
 	
 	
 		i was afraid it had become so commercialized
 	
 	
 		yeah it probably was more enjoyable when you went before it was too too built it's it's a real strip hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> now out out on that island
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		did you go over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Isle</ENAMEX> Mujeres
 	
 	
 		uh yes we we took a sailboat uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">catamaran</ENAMEX> ride over to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Isle Mujeres</ENAMEX> and they took us around let us shop a little while and then took us to some snorkeling uh
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		oh did you get to go out to that reef
 	
 	
 		spot
 		
 		
 	