
 
     		
 	
 		hi  what do you think about gun control
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh sort of mixed feelings about it i guess uh uh i i side i lean more towards the control side than than towards
 		you know just the the free free arming um on the other hand i it's it's sort of an issue of of uh
 		uh i'm not i'm not a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of of government control in general and so it's it's kind of a tough issue what about yourself
 	
 	
 		well i guess that i would like to to say that perhaps someplace in the middle where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could somehow qualify or
 		um have a legitimate use for the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> i suppose because also living in this area the the problems in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> come home very quickly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		i'm i'm sure yeah um so you would take a position where somebody without without a uh um
 		specific use in other words if they just wanted to have a a gun to have in their home uh you wouldn't you wouldn't like them to be able to do that is that
 	
 	
 		well i'm not so sure about that but i think somehow uh safety courses
 		or i don't know whether this could be something that was done in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but somehow people
 		i'd like to know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had them at least knew what the responsibilities were whether they followed them or not you know at least there's the moral issue that they they knew better
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		which is sort of you know flaky but still
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah i i have i i have the impression that that the
 		the majority of the problems that we have with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are not are are are probably not from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are are buying them through legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> anyway
 		um that may be wrong um you know i mean certainly there there are cases of of you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who find their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> or something and and
 		shoot a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> or you know things like that that need to be definitely avoided and that's that's certainly within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		a lot of the the crime i think that goes on i i don't know to what the degree the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are are purchased through regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> or they're illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know this morning in our paper it there was an article about somebody who had bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> because all you have to do is get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license so he went over there and got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 		and went up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and sold them for you know very high markups now in a sense that's a legal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> but certainly the the purpose is not very legal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh  yeah i i mean i think uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> or i i i don't know if anybody actually has implemented i think so um  at least there's been talk about doing uh
 		you know like waiting periods and and things like that um and and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i i think stuff like that  is perfectly good i mean basically if you if you don't intend to do anything strange you know if you if you're buying it for legitimate purposes
 		waiting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX> shouldn't be a problem you know and and things i don't know i've
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i uh i don't own a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and and don't really want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i'd just as soon a lot fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did um but on the other hand you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		know uh like i say i kind of kind of against government control in general uh
 	
 	
 		right and i suppose complete uh you know complete total ban would lead to more illegal weapons
 	
 	
 		yeah and i you know something about banning is that you know there there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> out there that it they're not gonna disappear anytime soon um and they're already
 		i know there's a ready market for them you know in the stolen the stolen stolen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> can be sold i mean their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thing a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a burglar</NUMEX> will pick up if he can is a gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right because uh because they they can be so easily sold
 		and you know their their i don't know how many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> have been sold in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but um it's not like they're gonna disappear all of a sudden
 		um even if you do do a total ban on them
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it's a real tough problem
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i i don't know i don't know where i
 		really come down on it i mean i i grew up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> right and that's and that's sort of almost a separate issue i think we've generally been talking about handguns  and that kind of thing right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and
 	
 	
 		but that's true i mean some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> grew up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we never had any in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so to me the you know the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i saw a gun up close was a pretty scary thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and i'm not sure that's good either
 	
 	
 		yeah  well we you know we i grew up with them i never really took to hunting i mean i did some of it but uh
 		you know we didn't have any we never had any handguns or anything like that we had you know had shotguns for for quail and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pheasant</ENAMEX> hunting and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know it was a whole different thing and and gun safety was taken very seriously and it was you know i mean before we go hunting we we took safety courses
 		but it you know that's that seems to me just to be a whole another issue  um you know the the thing that the  i yeah i'm not certain that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are are terribly concerned about other people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	