
 
     		
 	
 		okay here we go so what's your favorite team
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh  Cowboy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> die hard
 	
 	
 		naturally huh
 	
 	
 		yeah ever since i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last sixteen seventeen years</TIMEX> well as long as i can remember yeah ever since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy six</TIMEX> but um  yeah big time they are uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		everyone's jumping on the bandwagon now after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> they had what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patterson</ENAMEX>
 		and that uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is that
 	
 	
 		it's um like seventy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you're up
 	
 	
 		it's in the valley
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
  
 		so i guess you're uh
 	
 	
 		well i used to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Raider fan</ENAMEX> when they were there but now i'm a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">49er</NUMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		there you go there you go
 	
 	
 		you know and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 49ers</TIMEX> just went down down down this year
 	
 	
 		yeah but  if they would've made to the play-offs i mean they were they were the hottest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i thought at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the season</TIMEX> it's just it's kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's kind of bad that they miss out on the play-offs with a tie breaker or whatever but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah right right
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		so what what do you think's gonna happen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think it's um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i hope it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i really do i think it's their time to
 	
 	
 		you know i'm really i'm
 	
 	
 		everyone's picking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> but
 		i don't know i mean i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFC</ENAMEX>'s been getting beat up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> you know lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowls</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> they should have won it and you know missed that kick but
 	
 	
 		yeah lost by what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point
 	
 	
 		yeah pretty bad for the kicker but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think they'll do it i mean naturally Redskins
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> don't have a
 		much like for each other but um
 	
 	
 		well at least <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> was in the play-offs you know
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the the way they went out that didn't go over and it killed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> but they're young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i mean they got all those draft picks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> i mean their future's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean they're one of the young i mean they got so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX> i mean you never know what he's gonna do it's just that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s a wizard drafting people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum do you get to go to very many games
 	
 	
 		i went to  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> actually um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine have season tickets we've always it's always um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> we've taken turns in getting them and kind of
 		switched around on them everything and i just graduated and i moved back so i got to see more games finally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i went to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Tech</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock Texas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last four years</TIMEX> i so saw the games on TV but i hadn't been to any since yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> once i guess
 	
 	
 		hm um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you make any many <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">49er</NUMEX> games
 	
 	
 		no i've never been to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">49er</NUMEX> game i used to go to all the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Raider games</ENAMEX> when they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess it still want them back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		uh it would be nice yeah but uh i don't think that's ever gonna happen
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess there's not many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Davis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		you know um now i'm just waiting for something to come out out this way out in the valley
 	
 	
 		uh you got just so many
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> still has a chance i guess of getting a team someday
 	
 	
 		yeah there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> though i mean that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh uh that's just
 	
 	
 		so you plan on uh watching the game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah um going <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> actually so um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'll be out there for do it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> how about y'all
 	
 	
 		well that'll be nice yeah that'll be nice yeah we're gonna have a little few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over to watch the game you know just serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">d'oeuvres</ENAMEX> and stuff like that so we won't have to miss out on anything
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and there you go
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah i i just wish it would start a little bit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> because i guess well out there it starts at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> but starts at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> here you know that's
 		i don't i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know that they're wondering why their ratings go down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get don't like to
 	
 	
 		i know it's too late huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean but a time because lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know they got to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> they don't wanna be sitting around at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and
 		you know they start taking off but
 	
 	
 		yeah i was wondering for sure what time it started i thought it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or something but you say it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out here huh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> here like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six eighteen</TIMEX> so it'll be
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> o'clock your time huh that's terrible
 	
 	
 		but it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> good thing about living out there daylight everything
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		well i guess that ought to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah um okay then it's been nice talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX> all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay yeah all right thank you later bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	