
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what experience have you had with family reunions
 	
 	
 		well actually uh oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last eight or ten years</TIMEX> i have
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and i i should say have like done our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion
 		and uh oh you know we send out letters to everybody and we rent a place in this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> in a in a little town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh then everybody brings a covered dish and that sort of thing and uh
 		it's real nice because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> uh
 		had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and if we didn't do this like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> would never see each other the aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> that's the type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion we've had there you know
 		so uh
 		you know if we found you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> we don't do that  nobody nobody sees each other because everybody lives in different places you know
 	
 	
 		huh that's really good
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is all
 		
 
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is really scattered out so if we didn't have family reunions we simply would never see each other for example um
 		my
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		however all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> so we we usually have family reunions once a year and we'll go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and uh
 		go to  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> um
 		
 
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> puts a big deal into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion when they go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> um and um
 		she sometimes plans them and and sometimes helps in planning them usually um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Utah</ENAMEX> is so hot that um we pick there's the
 		they rent out this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> that's up on a mountain i mean you have to go up into the hills to get some cooler temperatures and have a enjoyable time
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's what we usually do and then have of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is one of the highlights also
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  yeah everybody fixes their specialty or whatever
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah well it really in your case and mine too uh i guess in most everybody's as far as especially more distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins aunts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> and so on
 		you just wouldn't see them if you didn't do something like that
 		well my immediate family like on my side uh has gotten large because there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of us and now we've all had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and now we all have grandchildren
 		so that makes just my immediate family like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so we do a separate reunion and we have a lake house uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seventy miles</NUMEX> from here
 		so we we've done it once we all get together down there
 		and um that works out real well because there's a lot
 		well lot of things everybody can do they can fish or they can you know swim or things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i know at the the family reunions on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side that we go to in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> um we usually um
 		have it at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and so you know swimming is always part of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the activities so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it really doesn't much matter where where or how you do it as long as you manage to do it every how often did like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> up there have them
 	
 	
 		oh there's a there's a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reunion reunion um</ENAMEX> once a year um
 		for for each for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s side and for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side i know and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> also um
 		so they try when they have family reunions they don't have them as regularly but when they do they try and make  big deal out of it and usually have you know something like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> show or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> um does something
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah we have taken like old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> movies from you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five thirty years ago</TIMEX> and and shown them at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandma</ENAMEX> also has some
 		we haven't particularly shown those at the reunions but my grandma has some home movies and we ever whenever we go to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we like to
 		see those those are
 		you know nice for memories
 	
 	
 		uh-huh we finally put ours on tape <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> there's places now that do that
 		and uh it really is nice when you when because you can get on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tape you can get about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty old reels</NUMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on there and it and then you can skip around and find what you want and all that it really has uh worked out good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		so how did you get on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> thing
 		
 		
 	