
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Ron</ENAMEX> welcome to the net and uh what did you do about your last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> repair oh and might you say what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you have and so forth
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> my last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unfortunately was a an expensive one because i had a brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town Car</ENAMEX> and and
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> ran a stop light the lights weren't working properly it wasn't their fault but we they didn't run it we both had green and she hit me and did about eleven <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> worth of damage to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		my goodness gracious that's
 	
 	
 		that was a huge repair bill
 	
 	
 		well that's still not enough for a total is it
 	
 	
 		i know i hated that
 	
 	
 		to get it's a very expensive automobile
 	
 	
 		so it wasn't enough to total it but that's my that's been my most uh
 		expensive repair probably in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> with the except of just service work because i buy a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every two years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh and do you buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i travel a lot so you know uh this last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i leased so i don't know and i leased it on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty four month</TIMEX> program it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've ever done that but i'll probably go back to buying them because i don't care to lease them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		did this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> have one of these expanding balloons or just are there normal safety belts in it that you had
 	
 	
 		no it has the expanding balloons
 	
 	
 		did that help you
 	
 	
 		uh it they didn't go off
 	
 	
 		they didn't go off
 	
 	
 		no i guess we weren't going that sort of upset me we weren't going fast enough according when i called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> about it and called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Motor</ENAMEX> about it but no sir didn't go off uh we were it was a bad rainy dark dreary day and
 	
 	
 		well what
 	
 	
 		and the street lights
 	
 	
 		but you were hit in the side weren't you
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that may be the problem you you might you may need to be hit from something the leaning towards the forward to uh activate it
 	
 	
 		yes
 		took off my whole front fender and hood and everything i tell you just
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 	
 	
 		took it all off it was uh uh my my doors were okay front and back and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it did uh right eleven <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> in damage it was a expensive then i get it back and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> after that i'm driving it in front of the local high school
 		and some young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> just wasn't paying any attention and runs in the back of me that's another twelve <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> worth of damage  so
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 	
 	
 		so i'm gonna get rid my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty four months</TIMEX> is up on this car i'm getting rid of this car
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i would think so that doesn't sound like you've got very good luck with that one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		my golly how about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">you Larry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i'm relatively fortunate about that uh here we somehow don't have many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> run into us although at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of each school season</TIMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> move into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> who are from big cities
 		and they sort of drive kind of wild for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two three weeks</TIMEX> then they finally settle down and realize that they don't have to drive that way here and uh that takes the strain out off of everyone that uh is driving a vehicle
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i understand
 	
 	
 		and i find that the most of the repairs i have to do here is body damage due to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> that we have to put on the road to uh take care of us in the winter time
 	
 	
 		i understand
 	
 	
 		uh i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty nine</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cougar</ENAMEX> and a seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX> so forth and i have to uh and i drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> most of the time
 		and i have to make sure that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> and so forth are kept off of it and once in a while we have to replace some of the plates in the bottom of it because it's rusted away
 	
 	
 		sure
 		well i understand that because i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> and we had the same thing up there continuously continuously salting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> for snow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i just i did i had this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cougar</ENAMEX> totally uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of it totally rebuilt uh to get some of the rusts that were in the fenders
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh done and then it all repainted and then  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> got here and so i put the cover over it then to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> off so i haven't had a chance to drive it very much
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but anyhow uh uh now are you gonna buy this next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or you going rent it a lease again
 	
 	
 		no i'm gonna i'm gonna buy it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> i don't like the rental i think i'm getting ready to retire myself and i'm going to i'm going to be you know driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for longer so i usually drive a car
 	
 	
 		are you
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and  and anyway and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i've only driven for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> so i'd leased this one for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> so i'll probably go back and buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and uh this next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> will probably be my retirement car
 	
 	
 		well that's an awfully big one that uh that one that you had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> uh isn't it too large for normal town driving
 		finding parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> and getting in and out the doors
 	
 	
 		well no sir not really not really uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no problem at all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> we have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyotas</ENAMEX> in the family <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> and we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and uh the not really no problem there at all as finding as far as finding parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> it's it's convenient in that in that regard
 	
 	
 		ah
 		yeah
 		well well that certainly would be a wonderful comfortable machine to take on long trips
 	
 	
 		yes it is and i'm and i travel i'm like a traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> don't travel a lot any more but uh when i do take it it is very comfortable to drive
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm very much aware of that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes i'm sure it is because that's the way that i enjoy this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX> that i have it only has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty eight thousand miles</NUMEX> on it but it's very quiet and very smooth riding machine
 	
 	
 		yes
 		is that right
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> is soon to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> it only has doesn't even have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty miles thirty thousand miles</NUMEX> on it so gosh been much in such good shape that'll probably be an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or ten year</TIMEX> car
 	
 	
 		um-hum do you do you feel that uh
 		
 		
 	