
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh how how's the crime rate up there
 	
 	
 		uh well we're right between uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so there's there's just been a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> bust uh here because i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pass through
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know on their way back and forth through the bigger cities
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um it's it's okay i mean there's crime everywhere it it's
 		probably not
 		it's not you know the
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		best place
 		to be but
 	
 	
 		is it anywhere near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Racine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's right next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Racine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really my uh old old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> uh was from there
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah uh actually i went i went and saw her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years ago</TIMEX> her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and uh
 		at this point they had moved out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and everything then they had moved back and she was going to school down here and i went and saw her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one summer</TIMEX> and uh we went up there
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i never been up there i just remember
 		it's a different area from down here obviously but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah it's like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> away from me
 	
 	
 		uh so you're a cheese head huh  yeah well we're i mean down here i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i mean this crime rate's ridiculous i mean it's just
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		i'm getting ready to move actually in the probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year or so</TIMEX> so i mean but
 	
 	
 		really it's that bad
 		the crime because of the crime
 	
 	
 		it's it yeah i mean it isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> but it's there's just so many uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean we've had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> uh since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> started like uh in high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh
 		incidents where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> shooting you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> or you know since you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school year</TIMEX> and everything like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shot right away i mean like in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first ten minutes</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX> you know so
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		it's just been it's ridiculous there's a lot of problems right now i mean the uh
 	
 	
 		with the
 	
 	
 		the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> out here is the former assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police chief</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darryl Gates</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>
 		so i mean he's not like you know beating up anybody but
 		there's just it's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and it's what you know you get and there's there's just getting a lot it's getting overcrowded and there's a lot of uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and stuff so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's it's getting pretty ridiculous
 		but uh i'm sure you know since you're near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> i'm sure you could
 		it's not exactly a peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> either you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no it's not
 	
 	
 		so it's the same situation really
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		so i'm actually in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> which is just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's a little suburb
 		but
 		yeah i mean
 	
 	
 		it yeah it's gotten worse too nothing's getting better
 		seems like it's always getting worse
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't see how it can get better i mean it's got to totally
 	
 	
 		i think it has to get worse first before it can get better
 	
 	
 		yeah stricter laws or something that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		they need something  and it
 	
 	
 		if i could solve problems i'd be a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but guess i can't
 		i'm just it's one of those deals where i mean you know try to look at you know look at at other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> what they do but i mean we're not like barbarics uh i don't
 		you know it's just too many problems with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting paroled before uh you know early and coming out committing another crime while they're still on probation we've had a lot of problems out here with that course
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i heard uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> cops are really strict like
 	
 	
 		well it's it's kind of yeah they shoot <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> then ask questions later you know that's that's their motto
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		whoa
 	
 	
 		they're they're not uh
 		you got to be careful if i mean i never had a problem i mean i'm not like
 		hang just you just don't hang out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or you got to be you know where not to be at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and the you know
 		just are certain places you don't even
 		certain parts of town you just stay away from you know
 	
 	
 		yeah same here certain parts of our city uh you just don't go by you just don't
 	
 	
 		right and you just
 		yeah you just leave it alone i mean
 	
 	
 		because then you're asking for trouble
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how old are you
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty one</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty one</NUMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		oh i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty three</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		that's pretty wild right next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Racine huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		actually uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Racine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		God i never thought i would ever run into somebody
 		look i'll read the paper every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> and something <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Racine Wisconsin</ENAMEX> will pop out you know but yeah it's just kind of a little town um
 	
 	
 		it's bigger than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenosha</ENAMEX> by a little bit and their crime rate's crime rate's a lot worse than ours
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah they just some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple months ago</TIMEX> he got out a machete did you read about that and started just hacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> with it
 	
 	
 		with with the machete no i didn't hear about that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Racine</ENAMEX>
 		it's sad i mean you can't even drive or walk down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		God
 		well uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wheaton Illinois</ENAMEX> where her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live and that's where that uh
 	
 	
 		i've heard of that
 	
 	
 		yeah it's just like forty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">few years ago</TIMEX> i guess there was some uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think it was some
 		um some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> was like shot uh
 		killed attacked some school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	