
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so  fishing huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you do much fishing out there
 	
 	
 		i use to i don't now
 	
 	
 		did
 		well you know we moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> we moved from northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to come out here and uh i
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		we did quite a quite a bit of fishing out there but uh out here in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> made lake
 	
 	
 		yeah that is what it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona Arizona</ENAMEX> is where i am from
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		i have only been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> that is all they have too is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> made lakes because of the desert
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's kind of the thing here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and it's it's a whole different kind of fishing than
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		than uh i uh am use to in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i'm use to deep sea fishing out there and fishing off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> and stuff and uh out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> you have to use lures and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh all kinds of different things i haven't had a chance to go out fishing much here but i use to do a lot of fishing out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State</ENAMEX> for a while do you know do you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> is well it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about thirty miles</NUMEX> outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> there is a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westport</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it use to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">salmon capitol</ENAMEX> of the world and when i lived
 	
 	
 		wow they did a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX> fishing up there then
 	
 	
 		yeah when i lived there i use to go deep sea fishing with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> all the time and it was really it was really neat but when i went back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> because that is where i am from well when i went back there to be with my mom
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was like a totally different kind of fishing i was like ah what do i do
 	
 	
 		yeah it is and uh the bait that they use is uh is totally different in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> than it is here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know we uh use to use live bait in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and they do use some live bait here but not a not uh whole lot not like you know you use to use in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i haven't i haven't been fishing since i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> because i have been having my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		two
 	
 	
 		two
 	
 	
 		two little boys
 	
 	
 		two little boys
 	
 	
 		one's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and one's one
 	
 	
 		wow you got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little ones then huh well i have got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> i have got a twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six</TIMEX> and a three
 	
 	
 		sounds like fun
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so
 	
 	
 		i'm stopping at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you are oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 		i only want to have to teach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them how to fish i don't want to have to teach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh that's we use to have a lot of fun when i was actually my my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> were born here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but
 		uh my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> girls i use to take them with me when when uh we would go fishing you know and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i use to like fishing off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> and stuff and we'd catch uh shoot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time she she caught a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh you know we caught uh what do you call uh those flat things
 		and we you know we'd get crab and stuff off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's that's stuff that we that we miss being here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we don't have much of a chance to get out to the coast and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's amazing how few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> actually fish
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> loved to fish she didn't like to uh she doesn't like to put the bait on but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know that was my job i just put the bait on and she'd catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>  in fact we use to go out and and this was not really that funny at the time but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's funny now you know i'd we would get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> poles
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i would you know i hook hers up she would be out there and i haven't uh i i wouldn't even be able to tie my hook on
 		she'd catch a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and she would yell at me to come and take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> off so i'd take it off and walk back and put my hook on she'd call again to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> off her hook
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean it went like that for a whole hour
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> gets kind of upset because him and i have an agreement
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i'll bait my own hook and i'll catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> but he's the one cleaning them because i won't clean them that's the only thing i will not do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		he gets really disgusted because he he says i i talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> i don't talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> they just jump on my hook
 	
 	
 		you'd talk to the fish
 	
 	
 		that's what he says because i'm really lucky at catching them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no matter what kind of fishing we are doing i i seem to have really good luck and it's like i don't talk to um and they just jump on my hook i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well uh that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh every time we go fishing she's the one that catches them and i'm the one that takes them off and baits the hook and  then it goes all over again so
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> got remarried and she got remarried to uh a commercial fisherman
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		and he was like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> don't know how to fish and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da da da da</ENAMEX> so him and i went out fishing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i and he goes do you need me to bait your hook and i said no i can handle it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i baited my hook and by the time we left i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and he had none he goes
 	
 	
 		oh my heck
 	
 	
 		he goes he goes tell you what
 		why don't you do my job for a while
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i said no thanks cause i don't clean them
 	
 	
 		oh that's funny
 	
 	
 		so he cleaned them all and i gave him and my mom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them and i just took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he was just so disgusted because he had never seen anybody that had that good of luck
 	
 	
 		now do you like eating uh eating fish
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i love fish
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		i i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> so i guess that's why because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	