
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i work with uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and uh in my uh occupation talking to them about college and going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> i think uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the advice that i give to would give to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> that have gone to college uh to uh college
 		i think uh one of the main things is that they they choose a local college that uh  or university
 		that will go along with their goals as far as what degrees they want to go into and they if they're in the local area they don't have to pay out of state tuition and all of those things
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's certainly helpful
 	
 	
 		and
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		say your last suggestion there about
 		staying within state i realize that there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> unless uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> has a real specialty
 		and there oh maybe are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> that are highly respected in that field they really ought to try to stay within their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		financing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> now is getting a very very high
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		and they can't help themselves on that either so it certainly is an advantage to stay within your own state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh that that's uh kind of the the advice that i give and then uh they need to take a look at the uh courses uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> of study and uh how it would go into their their major minor field uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what kind of placement uh they have in the particular area you know i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who uh went to a smaller college uh to uh went out in the uh premed area
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they had an excellent record of placing uh their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> after they finished the program and he was
 	
 	
 		that's very important
 	
 	
 		right he got early acceptance to a to medical school after he finished and uh if he would've gone to uh say the state uh it would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Utah</ENAMEX>
 		if he would've gone there uh i don't know whether he'd got accepted to medical school there or not
 	
 	
 		well that was certainly uh good advice to get him to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> who follows up and has such a reputation that others are happy to get their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that means that the quality of what he was taught must be  very very high
 	
 	
 		yes uh
 	
 	
 		and that's good for him too regardless of where he works he has uh a top level of information that will last him the rest of his life basically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and you you can do this for any of the uh any uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> or or for any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that are planning uh take a look at uh their final goals at least hopefully they've got a goal of what area they want to go out in and then uh
 		if it's law school or if it's uh medical or whatever
 		there are different uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> usually within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that uh have a little little better placement record or or getting them into into those higher degree or higher areas of education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well we have that  same situation here i'm i'm a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh the field i worked in was acoustics
 		and we have an acoustics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> here and we have lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> i guess in in acoustics and they have an excellent opportunity to
 		follow through on their fields because our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> is well known for it's research in addition to uh teaching obviously if we can do
 	
 	
 		um-hum you bet
 	
 	
 		high class research we must be well trained and and uh available to teach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> well
 	
 	
 		um-hum  and uh that would be school a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that the parents uh should seek out for their uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> if they're interested in that that field and
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and where it's well known uh the word gets out and that that might be a a case where even if it was out of state and they had to pay a little higher tuition then it would be well worth the the uh to to go to to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn Penn State</ENAMEX> is very well known in uh many of its uh many of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> and
 		uh we we get a lot we do we only we get our sort of say we get state uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> not only from out of state but from all over the world
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes
 	
 	
 		i mean they they they really come here we have a very high uh percentage of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX> is pretty well tops in many of its fields
 	
 	
 		um-hum you bet
 	
 	
 		and we have doubled in size in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		um-hum  well that's very important in in a choice of a college or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> that they look at those aspects uh wherever they might be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if it's uh financially if they can do that that's that's great
 	
 	
 		yes that's true
 	
 	
 		but they they need to know about the the costs and uh how they're going to be able to pay for this whether they can get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> loans or  are their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are able to help or whatever but uh
 		uh the bottom line is uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> that's gonna give them the best training prepare them for life
 	
 	
 		yes and then the basic thing is that you started out earlier to say the the bottom line is to give your
 		
 		
 	