
 
     		
 	
 		have you ever been on a boat
 	
 	
 		
 
 		of course my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is a big sailor so he likes to sail and he likes to do all that stuff but it's been a long time since he's had a boat
 	
 	
 		oh that's
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but we use to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Michigan</ENAMEX> and fix up you know work he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> that he was working on so we used to do that but i've never sailed
 	
 	
 		so have you been up that is that where you were born is up there
 	
 	
 		i was in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> i grew up around there and then um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		moved down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		now was it a sail <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> that he had
 	
 	
 		no it was called it was it was an old forty foot <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		oh so you couldn't do much uh water skiing
 	
 	
 		no i mean it well no and it it was never in the water  it was on dry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> so it was uh always kind of just sitting there so
 	
 	
 		oh good grief huh
 		well so did you fish
 	
 	
 		um he fishes i don't do you
 	
 	
 		uh i like to i haven't done a whole lot of it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and we use to
 		do a lot more fishing there but
 	
 	
 		huh  so do you from from docks or from what
 	
 	
 		uh well we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> so we would go out there and there was lots of rivers and oceans  all of that stuff we fished
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are you married
 	
 	
 		nope divorced
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		now you're right in Plano
 	
 	
 		um yeah we live sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifteenth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm up here on the north end of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		not too far
 	
 	
 		so are you by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarks</ENAMEX> sort of okay
 	
 	
 		uh yeah yeah above Legacy from from there north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alma</ENAMEX> yeah the clear uh in the boondocks  yeah way out here i mean it's a subdivision but nobody knows it's even up here
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you're far up there
 		oh are you
 		
 
 		oh
 		huh
 		and you moved here how long ago
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> years
 	
 	
 		oh yeah so you've been moved about the same time we did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">huh</ENAMEX> and you where did you move from
 	
 	
 		we moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> i was married at the time to a coal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">miner well</ENAMEX> he did you know strip mining kind of thing civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> but he um moved down here with that so we came down here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so that brought you down here
 	
 	
 		yeah we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> with mining too so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah so that was real different i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		oh so do i
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		where do they go to school then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shepherd</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shepherd</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> i have uh middle school
 	
 	
 		what grade what age
 	
 	
 		uh twelve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten nine</NUMEX> and three
 	
 	
 		so a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader fifth grader fourth grader</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> through
 	
 	
 		yeah i have a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifth grader</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		huh
 		so then you have little one
 	
 	
 		yeah and then i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little ones one's a kindergartner and the other one's just three
 	
 	
 		oh yeah so just <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well mine</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		little girl
 	
 	
 		now is your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or girl
 	
 	
 		girl
 	
 	
 		what's her name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Megan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Megan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">yep Megan Walls</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so yeah she's i know she's um in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		yeah so we're probably about the same age and same
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> game over there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow no Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		i know
 		oh really oh to win against that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> because our <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Megan's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> is on that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> she tried out but she didn't make it so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		who's her friend
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Mandy Philip uh Nichols Amanda Nichols</ENAMEX> she plays i don't even know what she you know a number we haven't gone to a game we were always gonna a game and we haven't so
 	
 	
 		no don't know who she is
 		yeah
 		what does she play in band
 	
 	
 		she plays the flute
 	
 	
 		oh are you musical
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		what do you play
 	
 	
 		i sing that's what i started in college on yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 		that's great so do you still sing
 	
 	
 		yeah so then i do bells handbells we have handbells at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and so i do that and do that kind of stuff and but i just started i'm uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know now i'm out of that whole field pretty much except for on the sides kind of thing but
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> related stuff huh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's about it i mean that's all i have time for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so that's what i do
 	
 	
 		so have you been out on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> at all in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		never
 	
 	
 		have you gone out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> Lewisville
 	
 	
 		um no
 	
 	
 		no you ought to go out there it's fun just for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> just to stay along the sides
 	
 	
 		we go we've gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> Lavon
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um
 		what's else is east <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbard Lake Ray Hubbard</ENAMEX> i guess so we've done those and uh camped there and that kind of stuff and we've camped up on um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Texoma
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh i bet that was fun
 	
 	
 		yeah but i don't know that i've boated there
 		i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah no neither do i
 	
 	
 		no well i'm gonna have to do a better grouping  get better friends
 	
 	
 		why don't we sign up for boating huh  just so they'd call us
 	
 	
 		i know because i thought well gosh  well i was figuring you know um as i was listening to this is sailing and and i thought it's probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the other end
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know i've gotten those basketball ones tell me about your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> well  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> plays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hendrick</ENAMEX> does that count
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah  they're <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade girls
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah they couldn't relate to that at all  it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Walnut Creek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> are you from
 	
 	
 		it's kind of by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> sort of area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because we have <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> there i do i do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruit nurses</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Flying Nurses</ENAMEX> and so we have <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Walnut Creek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		uh i don't why that rang a bell i know
 	
 	
 		oh that's
 		
 		
 	