
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> what does camping mean to you
 	
 	
 		well it usually just means sort of getting away from the normal
 		uh time spent at uh day to day job in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and trying to enjoy the outdoors for the most part
 		um i haven't done as much as i use to but i i still like to go once and a while and go camping
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum well when i think about camping is uh
 		well back from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scout</ENAMEX> days uh usually means hiking out in the mountains and and uh building your own camp fire bringing your own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in a pack um and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and things like that um things that i associate with camping usually
 		the hikes and camping that we do we
 		go to a lake and it might even involve some canoeing and
 		and then we might
 		i remember especially the fifty mile hikes where we'd hike from lake to lake you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> we'd be at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> lake and hike to another lake they might be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about five or ten miles</NUMEX> away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		the long ones
 		right
 	
 	
 		and things like that
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has recently joined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scouts</ENAMEX> and i i've become <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fairly active</TIMEX> with them and and uh
 		he joined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four months ago</TIMEX> and we've gone on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> uh camp outs since then uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of which involved uh back packing and and hiking they're a pretty active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troop</ENAMEX> and i've enjoyed it it's gotten me a chance to get back out and do a little bit more again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i haven't done
 		much recently that's just what comes to mind when i think of camping that is what i think of and was what i did when i was a boy scout um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yes uh
 		we uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> uh and i we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years</TIMEX> and and of course that was a great
 		uh state for camping uh to get up in the mountains and it was easy to go some place on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> it's it's a little more difficult for me now living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> just because there is so much
 		private land in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and there is not too much in the way of national forests and state lands that you can go hiking on here as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the west i don't know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> area is for for that
 	
 	
 		well i just picture myself and i was going to say i really don't know what's available here i know there's some lakes we could drive to but i don't know of any places where
 		you know you can do hiking and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		you can really yeah really get out and hike uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i grew up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> area and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cascade Mountains</ENAMEX> were just an hours drive away and that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that's where we did a lot of our hiking and camping um and then i lived
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		while i was going to school at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and there is also you know mountains there where you can
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do hiking and plenty of hiking and camping
 	
 	
 		yeah well camping camping i guess uh different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> look at it in different ways and and do different activities whether it's canoeing or
 		uh back packing or hiking some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just like to go car camping and get away and enjoy the part about building a camp fire and eating outside and and doing that sort of thing even if it is not back packing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camping</ENAMEX> can still be enjoyable
 	
 	
 		yeah i know for from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom  um camping</ENAMEX> is um
 		definitely bringing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> stove and
 	
 	
 		yes  the two burner stove
 	
 	
 		uh-huh even if we do build a campfire along side um the cooking is done on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> stove just because it is more convenient
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		although even when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i went camping when we were growing up uh we went in the tents always you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we we've evolved to the stage of uh pop up tent camper camping now  now that my our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have gotten a little bit uh uh
 		involved with camping and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> finally got tired of camping in tents and having to bail out the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> during rain storms and so forth so she talked me into getting a pop up camper so
 		our camping is sometimes a little more leisurely now than it use to be a little more
 	
 	
 		oh in the camper oh that would that is what makes it a little more luxurious
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 		yeah it's it's somewhere in between camping and going to uh a motel i guess
 	
 	
 		well i guess the main point is to get to um enjoy the outdoors and
 		you know especially if you go near a lake or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> or you know beautiful scenery you know
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scout troop</ENAMEX> does an annual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> float on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo River</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> and i am trying to make sure he gets his qualifications in by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX> because i would like to go on the trip with them because they
 		camp out for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> while on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo River</ENAMEX> and they're floating floating for that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many days</TIMEX> and i am looking forward that would be uh roughing it more than i have in a long time
 	
 	
 		that
 		
 		
 	