
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i assume most of the books you're reading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> since you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> have to do with studies
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's about all i get a chance for between that and um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> study as often as i can that's about the bulk of it
 	
 	
 		the uh
 	
 	
 		not a whole lot of chances otherwise
 	
 	
 		what year are you in in computer science
 	
 	
 		okay um officially a junior right now um
 	
 	
 		yeah and so the course work you're doing is what
 	
 	
 		well right now i'm taking a a uh my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourth semester</TIMEX> of of electronics dealing mostly with uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOSFET</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFET</ENAMEX> transistors
 	
 	
 		i thought you said computer science was your major
 	
 	
 		and
 		well okay they they're  are gonna uh computer engineering
 	
 	
 		oh computer engineering okay that's yeah okay
 	
 	
 		okay i am getting some programming right right now i'm taking my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first semester</TIMEX> in in
 	
 	
 		well
 		no no i actually i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> by training and uh i it is my impression that's easier for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> to learn about computers than it is for a computer science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to learn about computers
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well with this well they classify it as computer engineering technology so i'm getting a fair amount of programming as well as electronics
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right so who's books do you use for programming
 	
 	
 		uh it depends on which language they're working with um
 	
 	
 		well tell me what language we're taking these days
 	
 	
 		right now i'm taking C i've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three semesters</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pascal</ENAMEX> behind me
 	
 	
 		taking C okay is that just standard C or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX> plus plus
 	
 	
 		uh that we're working with what what they called standard uh ANSI C
 	
 	
 		yes right um-hum
 	
 	
 		um i'm not real sure what the difference is gonna be between C and C
 	
 	
 		well C plus plus is object oriented and there is uh quite a bit of difference and it quite often has you need a book up front to tell you about uh precompiling and that sort of thing and then it normally does a little shuffle up front
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then runs on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANSI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> or some other similar dialect of C so it does uh some preprocessing to begin with who's book do you use in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pascal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well what we're working with is
 		uh i don't remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s name
 	
 	
 		well how we going to talk about books  well maybe we better switch to pleasure then uh what do you read for pleasure
 	
 	
 		
 
 		used to be i read a good deal of uh science fiction
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Asimov</ENAMEX> for example
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Asimov um Clark</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Clark</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's uh
 		the big one was Asimov his he's his stuff was easiest to find
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		what got me started in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place was uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> gave me a set the uh um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> Trilogy
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's fantastic
 	
 	
 		back junior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and a when i was a in in junior high school he gave it to me
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's hard to put down those
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and he's come up with what  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more books
 	
 	
 		have you ever read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asimov's I Robot</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh parts of it i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> parts of it
 	
 	
 		i tell you that that is hilarious some parts of that you know the the one i
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah wait a minute matter of fact i did read i i <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robot</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have actually gone back and is is long enough that was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> science fiction book i ever read was I Robot
 	
 	
 		I Robot yeah that's pretty light reading for science fiction those kind of things
 	
 	
 		and it
 		and it was so good i went back and read it again because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asimov</ENAMEX> knows how to string things together you know
 	
 	
 		yes he does well the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trilogy</ENAMEX> is directly connected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I Robot</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah right
 	
 	
 		as a matter of fact his last book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they made the finally made the connection
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		that uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> robot whatever his i don't remember his name now
 	
 	
 		i can't remember the name either but
 	
 	
 		anyway he's still going in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> at the uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> they meet up with him
 	
 	
 		uh
 		huh
 		i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		he's on a base on the moon and somehow or another <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> has been so utterly polluted with uh uh uh radioactive fallout that it's utterly inhabitable uninhabitable even though it's been <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several million</NUMEX> years
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred thousand</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's it's  utterly uninhabitable
 	
 	
 		well while i was working i got enough i read on the job a lot of course just like a student does because you're learning all the time in research so i read
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i uh
 		started uh long enough ago that uh vacuum tubes were still in business when i was a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> you know  so i had to continually upgrade my education and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that was really good for me because that's what i'd like to do anyway i'd like to be a permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> you know so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah well i i got started on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>  late
 		i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty three</TIMEX> when i started to college for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yeah so you knew what you wanted to do yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i'd i'd been an auto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		started about twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> but uh decided you know i i had a pretty good idea that wasn't what i wanted to do any more
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		have you been in the military at all
 	
 	
 		no didn't go through military um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		so probably so probably the things that i enjoy reading relative to military you would enjoy The Web Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffin</ENAMEX> stuff uh which uh has to do with the military and other right wing things
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh not familiar with it
 		
 		
 	