
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		good so what common hobbies do  do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh i do um cross stitch and some needle point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross-stitch</ENAMEX> and uh needle point uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and needle needle point and i also crochet
 	
 	
 		and you do crocheting
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		my goodness i ought to have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> here talking to you i think
 	
 	
 		uh what kind
 		
 
 		what kind of hobbies do you have
 	
 	
 		well i don't whether we can call it a hobby or not and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> music was a hobby to me
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but as i have gotten older i found out that music has taken over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of my time
 		and uh now that i'm i retired about uh not quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX> that'll be uh i guess most of my efforts
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what kind of music do you do do you do you perform or do you
 	
 	
 		well i i
 		yes i play uh violin in um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different symphony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestras</ENAMEX> local a local <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State College</ENAMEX> and then one in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altoona</ENAMEX> which is oh forty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> away and
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and another one at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockhaven University</ENAMEX> which is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about forty five fifty miles</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i formed what is called a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State College Municipal Band</ENAMEX> oh about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten fifteen years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i play trumpet in that and conduct occasionally once in a while
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm pretty busy in keeping that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> going and trying to keep my violin playing up to uh an acceptable level of these other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestras</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh  it sounds like you are busy that's almost an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it does does take a lot of work  and then when i have spare time i uh also am an amateur radio operator
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but i don't
 	
 	
 		for uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> radios
 	
 	
 		um-hum i have so little opportunity i am hopefully <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year or so</TIMEX> going to uh rebuild my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and uh get back on the air a little bit more consistently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do have the equipment but as the antennas blew down the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX> i just went off the air and that uh that was the end of that
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah i've always thought that was interesting i've never know anyone or or used a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> radio but i always thought that the concept was really interesting
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it is it's it's a very interesting thing to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all over the world it's what it amounts to
 	
 	
 		um-hum i didn't know how far of a of a distance i guess depending on what kind of aerial that you use
 	
 	
 		depends upon the frequency and how good of an antenna you have and how conditions are about every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> or twelve years conditions change
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that uh you're signals get into different parts of the world
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		man i have at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time or another talked almost not every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the world but in all areas of the world
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		i oh i have when i was really active i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well over a hundred</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that i had talked to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		regularly
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum fairly consistently yeah well tell me about this work that you do and uh do you display display these sell them or uh how do uh
 	
 	
 		that's exciting
 		oh
 		uh well actually yeah i've i've done some original work not very much in cross stitch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i i did do one for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s mother
 		and unfortunately she passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> i finished <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after i finished it
 	
 	
 		you know that sounds exactly like things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> does but
 	
 	
 		and uh she never saw it she never knew anything about it
 	
 	
 		hum
 		that is a shame
 	
 	
 		it is and
 		it's kind of spooky the
 		the thing that i did i did the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty third</TIMEX> psalm the last verse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was i presume you're familiar with that
 	
 	
 		yeah and this is something that you would make into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> and hang on the wall is the way you do it uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah it's it's in uh it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> picture and it is hanging on the wall and i entered it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Fair</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> under original art work and i won <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> place with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i do pictures all around i've done some pictures oh i've done polar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bears</ENAMEX> and sayings and i've done um uh sunsets and quite a few wedding and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> announcements
 	
 	
 		where do you get the information to that enables you to do these different pictures uh are they already worked out so that you know
 	
 	
 		most of them are already worked out i have worked up some but not many of them and the ones that i haven't worked out there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> everywhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there's uh craft books and there's several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> that once you've you've been with a particular craft like this you get to know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> and
 		you end up having some favorites in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 		well that is a very interesting thing it it is awfully nice to have something to do that that you enjoy so much that you can put you soul into it so to speak
 	
 	
 		well
 		well i do
 		well and you can easily uh there's parts of me sometimes there's even a little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in some of my art work from needles
 	
 	
 		yeah i can imagine from needles yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but i've got uh a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> he's there he goes he's seventeen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>  and uh my cross stitch time has
 	
 	
 		yeah i can hear him
 		
 		
 	