
 
     		
 	
 		so you have a child
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah we have a
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years old</TIMEX> in child care right now
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in child care and we went through the process of searching for child care and uh finding what we consider to be real good child care at a uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		pretty reasonable price we think
 		how about you do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yes our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and he just turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		so we're  just starting into hunting for child care right now both of us are students
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		are you where are you student
 	
 	
 		uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Southern Mississippi</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		she's
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah uh are you gonna uh put your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in child care in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		uh probably um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring semester a year</TIMEX> from now he's gonna have to be in child care for uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		more than likely uh depending on how my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> schedule runs because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will be doing her internship that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> it'll be forty hour week not no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight to five</NUMEX> type of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so depending on what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> schedule looks like he may spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four six anywhere from four</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours a day</TIMEX> in child care by that point right now we're trying to avoid it but we just
 		a matter of fact just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> hired a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to uh watch him uh i get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at
 		certain time and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is already supposed to be on her way to her class
 		you know once a day this overlap happens where we can't one of us be home so for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty minutes twenty thirty minutes</TIMEX> a day we got a babysitter comes in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well that's a good experience i think and uh  there are a lot of things to think about and the articles that are written on the topic are pretty good and they kind of boil down to
 		uh any other important decision you really have to explore the alternatives and what we found
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um to be the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> was our own instincts about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were gonna be loving and uh  that's more important than anything else we could have sent uh her to a fancier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um facility um she goes to a home this is a um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> uh emigrated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in</TIMEX> in their lives they've been here probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty forty years</TIMEX> they've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and they have a loving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and uh they're both there and they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that comes in and helps them in the afternoon
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is healthy happy well adjusted and enjoys going to see her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> so it's a good experience i think if it's good i think it's very good for the child
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh that makes a big difference
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and if it's a loving environment i think it's very good and and that's really what we've learned about it she'll have to go on to something more stimulating in terms of a preschool in a year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um we feel real fortunate and we were able to uh
 		just uh
 		choose in the marketplace i don't know what it's like around uh Hattiesburg
 	
 	
 		there's a lot of child care available but invariably there's waiting lists
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we were a little slow getting on the waiting list with the uh okay the university uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>'s uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of um uh well their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Economics Department</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'll bet they're involved
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um they uh they have a subbranch uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Family Counseling</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> staff this this uh the child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> just off campus
 		but uh they have a pretty good size  waiting list  so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's uh i know it's it's a real uh hard thing to do even for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in in uh university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> out here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> they have a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a real good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> and there uh is is quite a waiting list to get into that so it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's a it's a it's an important decision it's an industry that's still a cottage industry and i think that it it really is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> beware
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well it's best
 		yeah a cottage industry's the best way to do it really because if you over
 	
 	
 		well it is the best way to do it interestingly i think that um my own interest in in development human development leads me to believe that that's a good sign and that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> is the way to go and that it will lead to a fundamental change in the way we learn because i think what we're gonna go to is much more commercial entrepreneurial learning ventures in the market as a matter of fact my future is banked on that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh professionally because i believe that that there are uh
 		pressing needs in the marketplace unmet by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools colleges universities</ENAMEX> for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh learning a lot of things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can learn watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> and in child care primary skills which turn out to be the most important skills in life
 	
 	
 		yes
 		it's amazing how much good things like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> will do
 	
 	
 		it's it's phenomenal it's phenomenal the the programming
 	
 	
 		is uh
 	
 	
 		the human operating system is my area
 		
 		
 	