
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 	
 	
 		what uh you have some ideas on the to help out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		i think that one of the things they're going to have to do is go back and take some serious look at what's important and what has a return on investment
 		uh there's an awful lot of federal programs that uh
 		they put <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> in it and it probably does a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> worth of good
 	
 	
 		right i i think they are going to be a lot more selective on on what they throw money at
 	
 	
 		and there's some things some programs that just don't seem to be working at all
 		uh an awful lot of the social programs and welfare programs they're just seem to be self perpetuating
 		and uh
 		certainly in a lot of the state and local regulations that are involved
 		just force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> into perpetuating the same activity and gives them no incentive whatever to solve their own problems
 	
 	
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get get where they depend on the benefit and they don't have much interest and there is no uh
 		uh enforcing uh ability i think to make sure that it doesn't get continued there's there's a lot of waste as a result i think of that
 	
 	
 		well some of the things that happen in welfare programs that uh
 		they are inclined not to give welfare or reduce welfare payments if there is a uh male present in the family
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's resulted in uh the family dissolving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is thrown out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so that they collect the welfare
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are raised under the single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> circumstance without uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> roll around
 	
 	
 		well uh i
 	
 	
 		and uh they wind up doing exactly the same thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i think there's uh there's a good opportunity if they'll take advantage of it with the with the the defense needs not as great as they use to be uh
 		if and combine the savings there with with the savings in
 		all these uh give away programs and and then waste that's in welfare and a lot of other programs i think they can start to get a handle on on the budget though what i am afraid is they will just
 		continue wasting money the way they have and and uh throw throw potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings</ENAMEX> into uh more programs that don't do any good
 	
 	
 		i think we can also do a lot to eliminate an awful lot of paper work and superfluous regulation
 	
 	
 		well there was there was was a study i don't know if you heard of it it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Commission</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		I know that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it it he was uh a private uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and he did a study on on cutting waste out of government and he came up with
 		i forget the figure but it was a tremendous amount of savings that could be cut out without really cutting benefits uh just the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste</ENAMEX> that went on you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i know that uh
 		well it seems like just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> when we were writing a proposal to work on some program we would sit down with an old Freidman mechanical calculator
 		and work out a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> page cost proposal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now when we write a proposal for the same magnitude of program
 		we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three eighty six</NUMEX> and it runs for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three days</TIMEX> and generates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three hundred</NUMEX> pages of uh nonsense to for somebody to go read
 	
 	
 		right yeah you wonder if all that is necessary and that's the same in government i guess it's is it all necessary
 	
 	
 		you know
 		and uh you wonder if anybody every reads it and if they do why
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it it perpetuates a lot more jobs i think is what it does
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i i think one of the problems we're having with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> uh is sort of the same factor that uh
 	
 	
 		but but
 	
 	
 		when i was going to school we had uh a principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant principal</ENAMEX> and everybody else was teaching except the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now it seems like there's uh as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> and administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> as we have teachers
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		and uh the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupils</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> has gone up by about fifty or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		well with the economy overall getting bad a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have had to really go into cost cutting and streamlining and that's something the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has really never tried hard to do uh
 		they just have to learn to live within their budget i think and and not uh allow this bunch to get out of hand like they have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there's no no need in spending all of this money on on a lot of welfare and these programs when you're going into debt to do it
 	
 	
 		and i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> also goes overboard uh on the way they do things
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh we have a
 		a new sewage treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> near here
 		that's uh one of the fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> approved things that does a super job of cleaning up the water
 		and they have an administrative building associated with it
 		that uh has
 		
 		
 	