
 
     		
 	
 		you been doing in your house
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh well since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> we painted a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and did some wallpapering in there i had to do most of it since uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was working
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		great where do you live
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Austin</ENAMEX> yeah and getting getting ready around here to do some uh major yard work as soon as the weather turns a little bit nicer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> okay great
 		well we
 		yeah as soon as soon as it stops raining a little bit huh
 	
 	
 		yeah well actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple days</TIMEX> has made me want to get out there and get started but  i figure i'd just be wasting my time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah great have you done much uh much in the way of home repairs
 	
 	
 		uh i've always maintained our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> as far as repairs and things like that except maybe i don't do heaters and air conditioners but
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i usually do everything else right up to replacing dishwashers and things
 	
 	
 		great how old a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is was built in probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX> seventies uh it's kind of a brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> not a whole lot needs to be done to it we've only we only moved here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah yeah great
 	
 	
 		what about you what kind of house you live in
 	
 	
 		oh well right now we're not we're living in a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> but uh we've we we've just moved here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh recently and we're living in that until we can find a place but
 		uh we lived in a brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> before this and did some uh various kinds of things uh made some storm windows to put up and
 		uh
 		uh really did a major rejob on the inside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> uh put up some walls and uh put in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX> we bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithville</ENAMEX> which is like forty miles east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> over toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> uh little old stucco <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> built in nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		we bought it to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">for</NUMEX> to get for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> getaway
 		and it needed a lot of work but we saw it when we first looked at it we can do this and uh sure enough uh it's oh nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months later</TIMEX> we sold it for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty six</TIMEX> and we bought it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow that's pretty good yeah
 	
 	
 		and we did things like paint uh inside and outside and basically repaired the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX> we put in expensive ceiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> which was kind of dumb on my part but
 		it was something i thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place</ENAMEX> needed because it had real high ceilings and uh just and just in general did everything we uh put in a hot water heater a new toilet and things like that kind of remodeled the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> cabinets
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		um-hum do you think it was worth uh the ceiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> on your resale
 	
 	
 		well  we weren't think talking about reselling it when we started doing it we were looking for something to do on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> loves to pick out paint and experiment and if it doesn't work try another color things like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so but when the offer came to us it was from a neighbor and they wanted their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> close to them and we thought well you know we're not we hadn't been out here but what once in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> and
 		and we had just bought this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> so we thought well what the heck let's make a little money on it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		sure well sounds good you think you'll do it again some time
 	
 	
 		yeah i'd like to uh
 		we have bought new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in the past and and we'll never do that again because it was just boring for after about a week
 	
 	
 		hum
 		is that right yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 		uh out in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we bought a really run down oh terribly run down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and uh it took us a year and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> to turn it around and make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost forty five thousand</NUMEX> in profit on it
 		and that was just
 	
 	
 		oh it sounds like you've got a good bit of experience in that
 	
 	
 		yeah uh it's just we you know we map out what we want to do and we go for it uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whoever's got time to do it and course you get the major things done like your you know have the floors redone or have carpet put in whatever but the rest of it we usually do ourselves
 	
 	
 		sure we're thinking about possibly building a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> now we aren't real sure whether we're gonna be able to do that or not but we just talked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">builder</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as a matter of fact
 		you know just uh beginning to think about sketching out some plans and talked about some of the different uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to go on you know different things
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh i think about that from time to time because we've never actually you know built one that we wanted you know the way we wanted it and things like that but
 		i'm not sure that our interest is that piqued in it to do something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah it sounds like you're uh really into uh remodeling what you get
 	
 	
 		yeah renovation renovation is kind of where we're at like our our favorite TV program is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Old House</ENAMEX> has been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and we would like to get ahold of something really old and redo it uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there again we might go back out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithville</ENAMEX> and buy another home  and because they're so it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that time has passed by so there are a lot of old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">big homes</ENAMEX> and they're fairly inexpensive
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		um-hum how far away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> is it
 	
 	
 		so
 		it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty miles</NUMEX> uh it's on the it's on the river and it's a quite nice little town they've been able to keep out a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and things i mean there's no KMarts or anything like that around so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		makes it kind of nice
 	
 	
 		ever are you um
 		looking to get
 		
 		
 	