
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		what have been some well i'll start out with some of my my vacations um
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um when i graduated from high school um my uh band my jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and we visited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> i visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria um Italy</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Switzerland</ENAMEX>
 		and that was pretty fun i also have visited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>
 		and just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last summer</TIMEX> one of my favorite vacations is i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you're a real world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so uh i i we my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i when we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> we visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> is uh  right there <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> is right in front of it and so that's where all the
 		killings occurred not too long <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple years ago</TIMEX> and uh also the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> if you saw what was that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> movie that was really famous
 	
 	
 		all right
 		oh yeah um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> or  yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		The Last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> yeah that was filmed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> so we had to see that when we went anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah that was a
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i are right now saving for a trip to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds fun
 	
 	
 		we would like to stay about a month uh
 	
 	
 		you'll need to save for that unless you have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> there you're going to stay with because
 	
 	
 		well we do have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that we can stay at their place for a while or as long as we want actually but it's you know it's in the southern part so but we want us to go all over the countryside
 		that's our next big vacation we've got planned and just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> itself is all we're interested in there
 		but mostly to this date uh our vacations have been more like uh anywhere where there's not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i hate resorts
 		and things like that i like to go where you can get out by yourself in the mountains done a lot of camping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we even toured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
 		but actually the southern part and uh she'd never really seen a lot of the different northern places and just the lot of the little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and  so we drove around went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humana Colonies</ENAMEX> things like that
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah they're not too far from here
 	
 	
 		we really i think she enjoyed it a a lot because she knew more of the history than course than i did of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> but
 		it was uh it was interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we live in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's hard to get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> on a driving trip
 	
 	
 		yeah got to go a long ways  uh yeah we also don't like to particularly go to tourist spots fact we usually choose to go places where
 		we at least for part of our trip will be visiting someone and uh even when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is well
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> program that i was in we knew some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
 		and so uh
 		we were able to stay with them for part of the time in fact they spoke English very well and and helped us around to see some of the places
 		and even when we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> uh
 		uh
 		we knew there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> contacts we had there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		uh
 		but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i that i uh met you know at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and so uh
 		it makes a big difference to us we like to go for go on a trip with someone who's from the area because i don't know i've i'm afraid especially if i don't know the language
 	
 	
 		right we had had a we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> once by ourselves
 		uh mainly because it was just something we could afford to do and
 		we heard it was interesting well we just had a real awful time because we didn't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> i don't think that would have helped us any anyway
 		it was just a miserable vacation and we decided you know we'll never go anywhere where they don't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> or somebody that can't help us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of that week</TIMEX> we felt like everybody was out to get us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that sort of thing and we weren't having the fun we thought we would
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it really makes a difference because i know even when we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> when we crossed the border we went over to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> we were so relieved it was so fun to be uh
 		you know it seemed like returning to civilization and where a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and uh  just the general living conditions were were somewhat higher also so it was uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		our last
 		major vacation was uh well we had to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> to see some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> because sickness in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so we took that in for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> and then we went to a uh
 		to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shaker</ENAMEX> settlement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>
 		and uh it's a it's been rebuilt and we stayed there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> and it was just kind of neat because we really like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shaker</ENAMEX> things and we were able to take our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> with us and he stayed with us and
 		it was just the thrill of our life to it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early fall</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> was beautiful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time of the year</TIMEX> anyway
 		
 		
 	