
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		had to uh face up to the issue of putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in a retirement home
 	
 	
 		well it's a topic that um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i often discuss because
 		um i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is deceased so um we think about that often times with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> but there's plenty of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> to help out
 		however on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s side um he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sibling</ENAMEX> who is mentally retarded and um and then his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and so we wonder you know how we're going to make ends meet once they're gone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> constantly says things like well you know well i wish if one of us goes i wish we'd all go like in a car accident so that nobody would help nobody would have to worry about it but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um it's a scary issue i think
 	
 	
 		well i've been very fortunate uh my father
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was very careful in laying plans for his uh latter years
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he was very concerned that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> be provided for so he went through a process over a period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX>
 		deciding where he wanted to be
 		and he made arrangements to sell his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and farm
 		and uh invested in a uh nursing home in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Central Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh moved in there
 		and uh he made that decision on his own and uh he made a good choice he found one that had uh pleasant conditions for for him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> living together and it had a uh nursing home attached to it
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and everything sort of worked out very fortuitously because uh they moved into the uh to the retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
 		and he died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
 		just just before his uh uh eightieth birthday
 	
 	
 		wow
 		wow wow
 	
 	
 		and uh it was fortunate that uh
 		uh he had made those provisions because at that point uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and her mental faculties were going very rapidly
 		and that's that's something that's very stressful to handle
 	
 	
 		yes i know
 	
 	
 		so uh we were very fortunate in having her in the right spot
 	
 	
 		one
 		um i think that's kind of the ideal situation is to have a combination retirement home nursing home and even you know if they need special care
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> is in a nursing home and
 		i don't think they've termed what she has as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> but it's you know she reverts a lot back to her childhood
 		and she doesn't know who you are often times often times she does the one thing that she retains as far as her memory is concerned is um hymns
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hymns</ENAMEX> she can sing them um and remember all the verses but when you talk to her she doesn't know who you are but
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that she is in uh it seems like a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there that are really bad badly off and they have them all combined together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> um
 		is um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who entered herself into the home because she has really bad <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> but mentally she is completely there so you know i don't know about that type of situation where
 		you know you have a mixture but there is a home here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that um it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist</ENAMEX> home
 		um for the elderly  and uh
 		they have that kind of situation it seems like what you were talking about with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and a nursing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and even a hospital somewhat attached you know for those who need
 		you know really special care and i think that would what be what i would desire if if i had to one of those
 		um
 		that's about
 	
 	
 		yeah my uh i have uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> who's in a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 		and they they had planned on that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> and actually uh made the payment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominium</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> uh oh fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before they moved in
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and uh so when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> finally got to the point her eyesight deteriorated and she could no longer drive and it was getting awkward to get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh she moved in it was only about
 		it's walking distance to where she lived  so she retained all her old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and uh they they look after her and they serve pretty good meals
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um it's kind of amazing the disparity that exists between
 		some
 		
 		
 	