
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		the federal budget  boy
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i was just writing something down that
 		came to mind as i observed what's happened in our society
 		um
 		we i think have become
 		uh dependent upon our federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to do things for us that really only we can do for ourself
 	
 	
 		i agree with that
 	
 	
 		and i think more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are recognizing that and in addition to that
 		uh
 		we have elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really don't know how to manage
 		the money uh they collect
 	
 	
 		well what we've got um in my view is  is a situation where
 		we've got more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you say that are customed that are accustomed to being taken care of and than we
 	
 	
 		i mean i think it really affects all of us to a degree <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen</ENAMEX> i think we are i mean i i went through a P H D program that was funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Navel Research</ENAMEX> that's now investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean we're talking about things that have done some good but have institutionalized corruption
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i really i think if you  from a
 	
 	
 		i mean uh you know i hate to admit that in a way but it's true
 	
 	
 		yeah i i really do think that i think the first thing that we need to do and it it would be a hard uh a hard uh medicine uh for everybody to swallow but i think we're gonna have to eventually balance the budget or we're gonna sink
 		we can't continue to pay the kind of interest that we're paying on the deficit
 	
 	
 		right well and we need to spend the money better i mean we do not need <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> around the world
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		there are lot of things we don't we don't need to be subsidizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> we don't need to be subsidizing water rights for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are wealthy farm i mean basically
 		you know it it is really true that this this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is suffering because um we are it's not that we don't have the resources we are just squandering them
 	
 	
 		oh yeah throwing them away uh it's just like uh uh programs that are federally funded that if they if the they don't spend their allotment
 	
 	
 		that's the way it was working on a defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> contract that's what happened
 	
 	
 		
 
 		then they're then they're subject to losing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>'s allotment
 	
 	
 		right well that's the way the that's the way the thing works
 	
 	
 		yeah and go into a spending frenzy at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> of the end at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> end
 	
 	
 		that's right i've seen that happen and it it's what's even sadder and what i think is the the tragic part of it that you see in this case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> and these other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> that are now being investigated for criminal violations
 		is that i think the attitude develops that we deserve this because we're the smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and without us society can't function and that that's no license to steal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right that's true
 	
 	
 		i mean i i honest to God believe that's what what's been going on and that was sort of seeped into the way we operated in those contexts
 	
 	
 		well and
 	
 	
 		and at the time i you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean it was it was acceptable it's no longer acceptable
 	
 	
 		well and well and so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have have uh the feeling that well if it's if there if it's federal money then it's free money well it's not it costs everybody
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh it you know just because you can uh get something from the feds uh that doesn't necessarily make it morally uh responsible
 	
 	
 		right and it it's not up to the federal government necessarily to do a lot of things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are now thinking it ought to do for example determine what industry should survive and what shouldn't survive
 		and do a you know variety of other things if we put the money in the right place which is investing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the development of human capital
 		in retraining programs for these poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really kind of went through school and got an high school education and thought they'd be able to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least</NUMEX> function in a competitive marketplace or went through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> or or went out into the marketplace and
 	
 	
 		well and and and  well don't even began to talk about the educational system i mean that is one example where it's being proven that throwing money does not create a good education okay
 	
 	
 		right
 		well and as the product of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> i can tell you you know if it were that good how come they haven't been able to mass merchandise it and deliver it to everybody how come everybody is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard MIT</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> education if it's that good and you really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but i'm even talking i'm i'm not even i'm not even talking about higher education we're i'm talking about the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that we've got now they come out of high school that can't read and write
 		and that also it just even the ones that that do read and write that really have a very poor poor grasp of of what a secondary education should have given them
 	
 	
 		right but all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who are responsible for handling these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were trained in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and my point is hey wait a minute something's wrong here these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are claiming this is the best well if it's the best then it should be translated right on down the line and the general i mean how long has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> been around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay so ask yourself some questions why don't we have a higher quality with one of the world's great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> both have schools of education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean this is a focus it's not like this isn't an interest of theirs this is a specific focus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the best funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> in the country
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> in the world hey wait a minute how come they can't produce something like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> want
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	