
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um go ahead tell me what you think do we get our money's worth
 	
 	
 		hey listen if i had my way i wouldn't pay my taxes not with the not with some of the things that i hear that our tax money is going for some ludicrous things
 	
 	
 		yeah did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> last night
 	
 	
 		no i did not i was
 	
 	
 		well they did a  thing on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five billion dollars</NUMEX> we waste <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> just on storing stuff for the military we don't need and uh
 	
 	
 		well how does this grab you how does this grab you
 	
 	
 		it's staggering
 	
 	
 		um this i i mean i'm i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> but this i heard this on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> program and it was
 		uh about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> and that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for Arts</ENAMEX> and they fund
 		they funded this thing this act on a stage and did a study on it between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> and wrote a report about that with our money
 	
 	
 		well there are a lot of things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think generally
 	
 	
 		and then it just frosts me terribly
 	
 	
 		well i think it's interesting to look at um
 		where the money  goes and it goes a lot of places where it probably ought not go and and i don't think generally i think what's interesting is
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		that  we probably represent the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in terms of their feelings about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and how it serves us given the extraordinarily large sum of money the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has to operate with
 	
 	
 		i believe that's true yes
 	
 	
 		and that what i think is gonna be really interesting is what we do about it i mean we are gonna have to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who represent us
 	
 	
 		that's correct
 	
 	
 		i mean and i think it's gonna be real interesting to see and and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> upon them uh
 	
 	
 		heavy involvement from the public
 	
 	
 		yeah right that's your i think that's the only thing that's gonna change it and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah heavy involvement from the public
 	
 	
 		our our anger is gonna have to to give rise to to more activity on our part
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i've i've said for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that there's full employment for the politically active and in our society uh there's very little full employment most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are getting worse off not better off
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty</NUMEX> percent of the public according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Moyer</ENAMEX>'s uh recent uh piece for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Broadcasting</ENAMEX>
 		which by the way is a very good use of government money i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> is wonderful but this special
 		focused on the fact that eighty percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are are seeing their real incomes and thus standards of living decline and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> are seeing theirs improve
 		that's not a formula for a better society
 	
 	
 		no it is not it's lopsided very much so
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> really plays a role in this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's right they pull the strings
 	
 	
 		i mean  well well they are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose strings are pulled and by i guess powerful interest
 	
 	
 		right the yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and it's really interesting to see how that affects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because essentially more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are not
 		likely to revolt in the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> used to think of of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> revolting
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are pretty much getting the picture that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get taken care of and others don't and they think it's unfair and when they recognize it's their tax money they're gonna do more about it
 		i think i'll tell you one quick uh one thing very interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address is gonna open up a telephone line
 		an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can call in and say what they think about what's going on in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> they expect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		opening it for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> that they'll get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred thousand</NUMEX> telephone calls
 	
 	
 		i'm sure they will
 	
 	
 		and i've thought for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> it would make a lot of sense to put create an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> number for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to call and and vent their frustration with government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one eight hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">capitol</ENAMEX> or something like that you know you just a number you could call from anywhere anytime i think that's coming and i think once once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really start to communicate how they feel things are going to change until then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i think you know it's gonna be really painful so the question is how soon are we gonna start to get our money's worth and as you said it's how soon we get involved and i think we need to create mechanisms to allow us to get involved like allowing us to call a toll free number and say hey look
 		do it this way not that way or i like this or i don't like that or this is how i feel about your spending my money on art that i don't think is art
 	
 	
 		yes i understand that but hopefully that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are listening to what our comments are take some action on it
 	
 	
 		well that's the good thing about what is happening because i think more and more the news media which takes a heck of a beating and and deserves some of it  is telling us more you know about the problems
 		so the more we communicate hey look we want a change here because you know as it turns out we've wasted a tremendous amount of money on our defense spending in this country
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 	
 	
 		over a very long period of time
 	
 	
 		right absolutely
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		we only see the tip of the iceberg it's only you know there's so much
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of it going on that it would really you know uh set us into a deeper <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> if we knew the whole picture
 	
 	
 		well you may be right  what i think is really gonna be interesting is to see how uh we as a society deal with it and i and i think it is what you say it's it's a
 		
 		
 	