
 
     		
 	
 		what are you cooking for supper
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's a good question i haven't figured that one out yet
 		personally i'm thinking of making a goulash
 	
 	
 		that sounds pretty good
 	
 	
 		but i'm publishing a cookbook right now so or getting it ready to go to the publisher
 	
 	
 		what type of food
 	
 	
 		all types
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		different nationalities there's going to be a different section for each nationality
 		it ranges anywhere from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> cooking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
 		there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> in it some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> dishes that i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> some for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> you know how to make baby <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> instead of buying it because it's so bloody expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well i'm kind of a house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and and i cook everyday
 		that's about the only thing
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		everyday too
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little boys
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i made a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana cream pie</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> gets testy if i don't have some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> in the house
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i made <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana bread</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days ago</TIMEX> and it's gone
 		everything i make disappears real quick so i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like it
 	
 	
 		yeah sometimes i i make things and they don't work so i kind of throw them away before anybody sees them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i'm a i i don't know i live out of cookbooks other than stuff that i've cooked over and over and over
 	
 	
 		yeah well see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do live by cookbooks not just house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> but like bachelors and stuff they don't know how to cook anything you know unless they have a recipe to follow
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's why i'm publishing this cookbook because it's simple recipes
 		it's nothing that's hard
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just everything in it is really simple
 		you are
 	
 	
 		sometimes i like to get a hold of a very hard book uh
 		and hard recipes especially some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> dishes
 		and where i've got to read it reread it and then keep it out while i'm cooking
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know something new not something i'm going to fix <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		just something for a special occasion
 	
 	
 		right
 		but i guess i know for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i both been fixing a a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken dish</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> and
 		it's really really strong with garlic and black pepper and
 		we've always thought nobody would like it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		we recently served it to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> we had and and uh they all had to have the recipe
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and i didn't go easy on anything
 	
 	
 		that must have made you good
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's delicious it's like when it when it's like birthday time and you say well what do you want to eat we always say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicken Adobo</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just it's very pungent thing and and we just didn't think anybody would like it but they all went nuts about it and i've already heard that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them have already fixed it at home so
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> school before we got married and he can cook all kinds of fancy dishes and i can because i went to cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> too but i
 	
 	
 		maybe
 	
 	
 		i favor the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> kind of cooking because i grew up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so that's what i like to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		where did you grow up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> and it was a horse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> and we cooked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> style you know i mean you don't peel your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> when you cook them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you just cut them up and there you go
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think a lot of the lot of the things that i <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife cooks</ENAMEX> they're they're from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> from her background
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because that's where we picked up the recipes and we have a lot of regional cookbooks from that area
 		so it's especially when we're baking something <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> we just go to those little city cookbooks and we know they've been tried and tested and and everything so
 	
 	
 		yep
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> published a cookbook when she was married to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> which was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>
 		but um
 		and she published hers so now it's my turn
 		i'm trying my luck
 	
 	
 		uh we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		anywhere near Alamogordo
 	
 	
 		uh no we lived up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so and then up in the mountains but we picked up a lot of uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> type dishes and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's usually what we'll fix if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s coming because they uh they expect it
 	
 	
 		there's some really good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that comes out of there i'll tell you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we don't even like to go out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> around here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		there is none around here that's really <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
 		they're all fake
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		you know and when you taste the food you know it
 		there's just a difference
 	
 	
 		in this part of the world there's you know there's a lot and there's some from the interior of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and country <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> cooking and things like that so
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		you can get into some unusual things but i still find that you know especially even when we go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>
 		that i'd rather have the food from there they just use more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> and it's right near the border
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you'd be surprised how fake the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> are out here they
 		knowing how close we are to the border i mean you only have to drive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> to get to the border
 		you'd think that there'd be good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> cooking here
 		
 		
 	