
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Lee</ENAMEX> tell me about your ideas on this uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> government supporting health insurance and so forth
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i think it's inevitable that we are going to see national health care and the reason is because the market place doesn't seem to have performed adequately uh the invisible hand that which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX> wrote
 		has uh provided some very good health care and uh much
 		i think inadequate health care uh and in some cases the absence of health care has resulted from market <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">place forces</ENAMEX> and i think
 		um it's inevitable it is just a matter of
 		uh time and mistakes and they're both inevitable
 	
 	
 		well what is this going to do the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> who are supporting this work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and hopefully are doing uh a good job
 	
 	
 		well it's gonna make it tough for them and it's it's gonna be a difficult transition i don't know uh how it's gonna uh
 		play out in terms of the particulars but i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society society</ENAMEX> will be willing to tolerate the current health care crisis for too long
 		our uh
 		physical mental and spiritual health uh it's really uh very costly and uh as a society  we are paying a staggering price for this my
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well this is what's bothering me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> another question do you think that there should be some control uh innovated such that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are not allowed to charge ridiculously ridiculously over priced things
 		we realize that for the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> some things are very important uh matter of fact in some respects their life might depend on it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but by the same token some of these charges they make for
 		well well minor endeavors shall we say on the parts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are really out of line there should be some control of that
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		yeah there are abuses of they're abusive of privilege
 	
 	
 		yes and that's what's giving the local um insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> hard times that's the one thing we have no control over are these charges that happen when you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and you get something done and they want to charge twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> for it
 	
 	
 		right
 		well this i think is one of the things that national health care of some sort of evolutionary process over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next ten or twenty or thirty years</TIMEX> will address because i know this is addressed by uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> i i have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who is uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> practicing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they made the transition uh and i think that the uh for example duplication of magnetic resonance imagers uh
 	
 	
 		yes we've had several of them my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i both have had that recent
 	
 	
 		i've i had one myself and uh
 		they're wonderful technologies but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> more than they need or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> times the number they need
 		so i think that what the marketplace doesn't do because of the way the system has worked and it doesn't allocate resources optimally because
 		there is a tendency uh at least there has been a tendency to drive up the price of medical care primarily because the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> could pass on the bills
 		what's begun to change all of that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> paying the bills uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> ultimately have begun to squawk because they've seen their health care cost rise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so i think the evolution will be interesting uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> has a system that is apparently working and uh it'll be interesting to see how how
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh much more attention we pay to that i do think though that it's inevitable primarily because of the pain uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are feeling uh under the circumstances and i believe that
 		it will contribute to something that we would at this point call national health care whether it's subsidized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and and operated by private insurers
 		uh i don't know i like that idea i tend to be one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who believes the market place can under varied circumstances
 		with the profit incentive work very very well uh i we would be a lot better off if we if we contracted our national defense to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> who rather that operated as a government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> because we would probably have much less waste
 	
 	
 		see that that bothers me about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> see uh my
 	
 	
 		that's that's that's the problem with government uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of these programs and that is one of the things that we as society are going to have to deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is gonna have to change in this regard
 	
 	
 		do you think that these that these insurance things should be covered on a state basis or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> government basis
 	
 	
 		you know that's really a tough one for me to answer i don't uh uh i would like to see the greatest improvement in management
 		my my field my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> is the cognitive sciences and i recognize that a lot of these things that are done are done um
 		as a function of the operating systems in place and those operating systems have to change and and as we become more efficient in developing machine operating systems we're going to develop more efficient human operating systems
 		and so a state or federal application uh could work uh it all depends upon the way we structure the environment we may have to do
 		
 		
 	