
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> i'm calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay great i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		okay well good
 		you know our subject is on boating and sailing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and quite honestly with the exception of being involved in a part ownership of a little bass boat i have never really got into sailing or boating
 	
 	
 		i do uh quite a bit of sailing i own a sailboat that i keep parked up on the scout lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout troop</ENAMEX>  and we take it out and we do some teaching of sailing with the scouts but
 	
 	
 		oh do you well great
 		
 
 		well that's neat
 	
 	
 		i haven't really been taking it out recreationally too much lately  since it's i don't have a trailer hitch on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> anymore so it's hard for me to get it somewhere but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		i've seen some nice nice sailboats the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that used to live next to us in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> before we moved twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> or whatever he had a sailboat used to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> it
 		right in the uh driveway and it seemed i think it held probably uh it must have slept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah this one is not that big it's a day sailer it does have a little kind of cabin thing that you can store things in but you couldn't really sleep in there unless you sort of
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		stuck your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> out the whole  it back into the main part of the sailboat but
 	
 	
 		i i understand
 	
 	
 		but it's there they can be black holes to throw money into
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> are kind of expensive to maintain
 	
 	
 		i'll tell you it's
 		oh they are and you know we have a swimming pool at our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i think of all the time now that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are gone and away and married and going to college or whatever that i put in there i just could not imagine a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> because i know it's a lot of maintenance
 	
 	
 		especially a bigger <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the bigger they are if you get a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> cruiser or a big ski boat
 	
 	
 		oh gosh yeah
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		power boat then there's always uh stuff to go wrong with it the sailboat at least doesn't have an engine to mess up but you still have to
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		worry with the hull and the condition of the sails and spars and rigging uh everything that's in it it takes a  a pretty good amount of maintenance to keep <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> up but
 	
 	
 		you bet i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i were first married her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and ancle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> they kept a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Bay</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and we used to go out with them and back then they had bought an older
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Craft</ENAMEX> and we were involved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> in just uh as we visited we were involved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> in just helping him redo this and refinish that we just worked all the time but their boat slept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> plus had a little kitchen
 		it was sort of neat we but i think that was the last time we were really involved in that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years ago</TIMEX> it is a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		well it's a lot of fun i think um just from the standpoint of  getting away from the dodge here and when you work hard and you're under pressure and everything <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX> long a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> can be a lot of relaxation
 		uh to especially with a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> out or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out or whatever uh or a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> or something depending on how much you like to rough it and but it's uh
 	
 	
 		you bet
 		i visited my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 		and he had a place on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ozarks</ENAMEX> and he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i never seen so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> in all my life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually park their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when they get to their place they're staying and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouse</ENAMEX> or condominium whatever they own and they they go <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> i mean they go if they wanna go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> to have a cocktail they use the boat
 	
 	
 		use the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> for transportation
 		they just go across the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and get a and tie it up and go in huh
 	
 	
 		and that was sort of neat yeah that's that's that's true that's exactly how they do it they go to dinner that way go to all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that was sort of a neat setup i enjoyed that we spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> with them i enjoyed that
 	
 	
 		yeah that would be fun
 	
 	
 		but i'm envious i'm envious of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		i've just never  i've never moved up to a really big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sailboat um</ENAMEX> once i get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> into and through with college he's gonna be starting uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rice</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> so he's going off but
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> once i get to that stage where i'm not paying for something else and uh i i don't have to worry about a lot of other scheduling things where i've actually got the time to go out and enjoy it uh
 	
 	
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		i might do something differently i might just donate my little one to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout troop</ENAMEX> and let them keep it and maybe consider getting a a better one for me uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		think you think you'd really enjoy it
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i would uh i the sailing part of it i like uh because it's so quiet
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and if you get a big enough one then you've got a little motor on it also
 		where if it's light wind you can still putt around a little bit and have fun
 	
 	
 		oh that's
 	
 	
 		or if or if the wind dies you're not stuck in the middle of the lake i've with my little one i've been out there many times on a calm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's great
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where all of a sudden the wind stops and you're just stranded out there trying to pick up what little gusts you can to work your way back in and
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 	
 	
 		and that gets hot and and wearisome doing that and if you have if you're have big enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> to have the little
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		auxiliary <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motor</ENAMEX> on there at least you can kind of drop the sails and putt on back in
 	
 	
 		and putt putt  sure well that's neat  where do you work who are you with
 	
 	
 		but it's fun  i own an insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> a managing general a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesaler</ENAMEX> of insurance uh out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		well good
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout leader</ENAMEX> though so i'm i'm out with
 		
 		
 	