
   
   
      
         
            Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bombshell</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> 's lead is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> responsible for the safety and
security of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear stockpile falsified reports certifying its ability
to deal with Y2K problems. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the finding of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economic crisis has left its stocks of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> and plutonium
increasingly vulnerable to theft and diversion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with word that because most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are behind schedule in their attempts
to eliminate Y2K problems from their computer systems, it's likely that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> receiving welfare and other anti-poverty benefits will have their
payments and/or services interrupted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the goings-on at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>
(which is also fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and carried inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ),
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> agreed to deeper economic, environmental,
and social ties, but haggled over the form and wording of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s official
apology for the brutal acts it committed against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> concluded that despite its claims
to the contrary, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Weapons Agency</ENAMEX>" never performed the
required tests on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> essential computer systems. Also, it's
revealed that overall the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> got a "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-minus" grade for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its Y2K</TIMEX> efforts
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> oversight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. The paper quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX> saying
nevertheless that "there's very little real mischief going on here."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> nuclear security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> saying that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy is the world's greatest proliferation
threat--since the ruble was devalued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
slashed the salaries of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>, which means not only
fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> protecting the nukes but also more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> prone to the temptations
of selling them. Several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, agreed. But the nukemeisters on the other side display to the
Post the same lack of alarm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> finds at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>: "I am not
particularly worried," says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s atomic energy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>, only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">421</ENAMEX> computer systems used nationwide
for the major health, welfare and nutrition benefit programs are ready for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2000</TIMEX>. The piece goes on to quote a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> with Y2K
responsibilities complaining that the problem is wrongly viewed as merely an
information technology issue, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who warns, "If social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> are disrupted, you'll have more than computer problems. You could have
civil disturbances..."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> finally issued an
unsigned document that refers to some of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s prior expressions of remorse
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, but stops short of actually apologizing. But the document does
contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> breakthrough: the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> reference to the
"invasion" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The paper explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is hesitant to go further
than this: it fears <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> demands for compensatory damages.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> were in serious
merger talks (a story that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> runs on the front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's front says most energy experts
conclude that such a merger would be good for oil and gas production worldwide,
thus benefiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. The resulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would have an increased
capability to develop new oil deposits. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature er, refines this
point, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> brings with it a far more aggressive approach to
exploration.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that after a long fallow period, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> is recruiting
again. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> has narrowed its focus to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> with
which it either has or intends to develop, close ties. The list includes, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Tech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard, Grambling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
A&M, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>. (What
happened to those traditional spook stomping grounds, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>?)

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> story about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> and nuclear weapons control includes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">definitive Washingtonthink</ENAMEX> quotation. Despite the revelations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-chairman</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> definitely sees a glass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> full: "There aren't as
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lying to us as there used to be."

         
      
   
