
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Tuesday</ENAMEX>

and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s decision to extend the
deadline for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s withdrawal from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has postponed
voting on the new spending bill until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next week</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead) all report
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> now have until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 27</TIMEX> to complete a limited
withdrawal from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s demands are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">met</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> will remain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> and that the delay
might hamper future air and missile strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> due to the
influx of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> and humanitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s agreement to allow U2 spy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> to monitor troop activity-regarded
as a major concession to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-also entails <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> schedule of reconnaissance flights.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead, which makes the front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , says that
although the major budgetary issues have been agreed upon, some smaller
negotiations, combined with the sheer enormity of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 billion</NUMEX> spending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>, have delayed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> vote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that
the vote has been rescheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> voting
immediately afterwards if the bill is passed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that
wrangling over controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>-free zones on commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, an issue
of special concern to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, was one of several factors that
delayed the vote.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> weekend papers feature front page stories on the awarding of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main political
parties (read: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>) for their efforts to end sectarian
violence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> did not name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator extraordinaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX>-both of whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cited as worthy of the prize-as co-winners.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that the new budget deal shows a marked
increase in defense spending, reversing a post cold war trend. Apparently,
armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have successfully convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
defense equipment and troop quality are not keeping pace with the demands being
made upon them. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Projects</ENAMEX> supported by the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.4 billion</NUMEX> funding increase include
missile defense, military readiness, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> deployment, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s Y2K
problems.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All the weekend</TIMEX> papers report the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Parker</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX>, who was suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>, had been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> cite his success as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> and later as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>'s
circulation and visibility. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> mentions that his career was "marred
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> decisions:" his publishing of the bogus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler Diaries</ENAMEX> and, despite his
personal knowledge to the contrary, publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX>'s denial of writing
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Primary Colors</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> is owned by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Co.</ENAMEX>, includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX> account, but does not mention the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler Diaries</ENAMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> as a
driven, dedicated and loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
