
   
   
      
         
            Outlook Bats <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.00</NUMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' lead says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will provide
several <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion dollars</NUMEX> of aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, as part of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX>
international package to help stave off financial turmoil there. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's lead covers a local election race; the
off-lead describes the international reach of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pop culture. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with a new poll showing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX> handily
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Lungren</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 to 42%</NUMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> gubernatorial
race. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's top national story (fronted all around) is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s
killing of a prominent abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnett</ENAMEX>
Slepian, was shot in his home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sniper</ENAMEX> who was lurking in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bushes</ENAMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last four years years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> have been
wounded in the region, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just days ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> had warned of possible new
attacks.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says that details of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> are still
being hammered out, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid package itself has not yet been
publicly announced. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may approve the package during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recess</ENAMEX>, but since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> are concerned about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s financial straits they
are unlikely to pose major objections. Nonetheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is
approaching the issue warily, recalling the Congressional storm over a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
commitment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 billion</NUMEX> to bail out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. The bulk of the international
loan to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> will come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 billion</NUMEX>
plus), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inter-American Development Bank</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX>
together).

            Money is not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s only gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's lengthy lead
reminds us. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> tracks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sao Paulo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bart Simpson</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seoul</ENAMEX>,
and the word "cool" to every spot on the planet. The article meanders into a
debate over whether the near-universal <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language helps fuel the overseas
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pop culture (or vice versa--do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> learn <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> movies?). The piece then raises the host of moral debates associated
with the global onset of pop culture--should <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>, for example, really
be mandatory viewing for half the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>?

            All papers have big spreads on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace wrap-up. Among the
articles: A WP front pager details how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s personal charm and
famed wordplay ability nudged the negotiations through tight spots. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> stresses the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intermediary</ENAMEX> role the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will assume in policing
the agreement's implementation. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, wary
and weary from empty past peace accords, have greeted the latest installment
with "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> jubilation."

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> front, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX>
vote, which apparently gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> a mandate for military intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
However, the resolution was softened to the point of ambiguity by the dissent
(and eventual abstention) of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the UNSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> "skirts an outright threat to use force." Of particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s capacity to protect the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> unarmed international monitors arriving in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to oversee the implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke-Milosevic</ENAMEX> deal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NYT Week in Review</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">WP Outlook</ENAMEX> sections are awash
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s arrest, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. Of particular interest is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genaro Arriagada</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s defeat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arriagada</ENAMEX> argues for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s release on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fronts: that international law governing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s
arrest is extremely nebulous, and that the arrest impedes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>'s path toward
reconciliation.

            An excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" article visits the bizarre <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Onion</ENAMEX>,"
the popular, crude parody <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. When they're not busy painting their
fingernails <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> there dream up headlines like "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>' Discovered
Between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Coasts</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bulungi Suspected of Making</ENAMEX>
Country Up."

            The millennial blooper award goes to Outlook. Outlook's name-the-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00s</NUMEX>-decade
contest raked in creative entries from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pre-Teens</ENAMEX>" to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O-Zone</ENAMEX>." Outlook's
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">verdict?</ENAMEX> "We considered dozens of qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, and it was so difficult
to choose a winner that we didn't."

         
      
   
