
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>, I Presume

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> struggle over who will be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> leads
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> has already gained the crucial support
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> and has received verbal support from "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100-plus</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> will need <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">112</NUMEX> votes to gain an intra-party majority when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> meet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 18</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says
that most of the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> majority positions will be up for grabs in the
coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, pitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> and ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> against each
other. All the papers mention <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX> as a serious threat
to take over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>'s spot as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority leader</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the increasing likelihood of imminent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Citing a "senior foreign policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> to Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> has lost hope for any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
concessions and is ready to use force "sooner rather than later." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will abandon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> arms inspections as a
means of restraining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in favor of traditional methods like sanctions and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece quotes a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>'s warning,
" If [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>] tries to use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction he should know
that we will obliterate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead reveals that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>, which recently decided to
overhaul the way insulation on commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX> is tested for flammability,
received warnings about its test's unreliability as far back as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. The
change in fire--safety regulations-prompted in part by the crash of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swissair</ENAMEX>
Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX>--will cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front page article reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX> landed safely
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Space Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> aboard the space shuttle
Discovery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>, whose age-related experiments required him to provide <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">urine samples</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> gravity, was understandably wobbly upon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de</ENAMEX>-shuttling.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> correspondent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> appraises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Man in</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX>" in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> book review. In a quote waiting for a paperback rear
cover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> writes, "The novel contains passages as powerful and as beautiful
as anything written...by any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>."

            A front page WP report explores the way health-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> rely
on media buzz to generate private donations and government funding. As a
result, says the piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> give more money to fight <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> than the
equally common <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>, and it's harder for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diabetics</ENAMEX> to get
financial assistance than for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS sufferers</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Magazine</ENAMEX> piece describes and denounces solitary confinement, a
punishment now inflicted on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent to 10 percent</NUMEX> of prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>. Out of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just one hour</TIMEX> a day, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> grow slowly insane and even
more violent and unstable than when they entered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>
believe the treatment is inhumane. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wardens</ENAMEX> disagree.

            A local story from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> makes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> via the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>. Apparently, the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has ruled that a club
can't be called adult if they let in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. And if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> can't be labeled
adult, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> can't close it down. These developments trace back to one
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> strip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>'s attempt to avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>'s wrath by admitting minors
accompanied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> adds: "You could take your
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to see the movie 'Striptease.' Why can't you take him to see a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">striptease?</ENAMEX>"

         
      
   
