
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Budges

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s passage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 billion</NUMEX> federal spending bill
leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The papers report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is expected to
approve the bill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with the continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> talks, stashing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> story inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says the participation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s King
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> appears to have created some optimism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reports two
sticking points: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> want to put a specific number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>-including some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> cops-on trial for terrorist
attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> are insisting that safe
passage rights for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX> extend
to making the trip in private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, not just mass transportation. All the
majors' fronts except the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 2</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial, at
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> made his opening statement, comparing the government
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th century</TIMEX> Luddites going around smashing machines with sledgehammers.

            The papers all note what a kludge the budget process has become. For
instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> bill incorporates numerous
policy decisions that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> never debated. And they all tick off examples of
its extremities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , for example, reports that it includes
legislation to carry out the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chemical Weapons Convention</ENAMEX> (previously passed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, but not implemented) as well as a measure to keep the world safe
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">airborne peanuts</ENAMEX>. Ritually, everybody but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> mentions some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>'s physical dimensions--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> gives the most stats of this sort:
weight=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> pounds, height=<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16 inches</NUMEX>, and the number of pages=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,825</NUMEX>. This sort of
thing reeks of press-released pre-packaged "color"-space-consuming and
boring.

            All the papers mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of the bill as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perfectionists</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> never explains that it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.O.P.</ENAMEX>'s
hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who were complaining. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> does mention this, but
it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that play the point high, explaining
that by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>' lights, the bill spends too much and cuts taxes too
little. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> even goes out of its piece saying that the vote revealed
a severe split in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> that may be hard to patch up.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> budget story notes a last-minute deal in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> won approval of a provision requiring health insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to
cover post-mastectomy reconstructive surgery, and explains it this way: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>
was trying to undercut his election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s strong support among women
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. This is a bit brisk for a news story: Isn't there any chance that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> is concerned about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> not being able to afford reconstructions?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and the WSJ front-page business news box report that according to
the latest government figures, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign trade gap for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> reached
the highest level-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.77 billion-</NUMEX>recorded since the present method of
calculation was adopted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> analyst
estimates the deficit is actually now the biggest since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1985</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
papers attribute the weak exports and strong imports behind the gap to the
global economic downturn.

            The LAT fronts high a story about the emerging tension between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of legal, medical and financial software on the one hand, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> on the other, as the software nibbles away
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>' traditional turf. The piece reports that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> is trying to ban self-help legal software via a statute
barring anyone--or anything, the paper wryly notes--from practicing law without
a license. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the attacked programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quicken Family Lawyer</ENAMEX>, features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>, who while not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law</ENAMEX>
School.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that the power of the Internet will only expand professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">software</ENAMEX>'s reach. An example the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> gives is the recent spate of web
sites that facilitate the sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> to those logging on and filling out a
questionnaire. In telling this story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> makes an interesting choice:
deciding to publish the web address for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> site. This is tantamount to
free advertising. Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also intend to start publishing the phone
numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> in stories about them?

         
      
   
