
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">House to Beat Wild Pair</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s announcement that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> deaths dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, a story making everybody's front. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> is not among the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
statement that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> should vote their consciences, with no need to fear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> retribution, when the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> decides today
whether or not to start an impeachment inquiry. That story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
resurgence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s stock and currency markets, spurred by evidence of a
political deal there to allow public funds to be used to rescue its crippled
banking system. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> explains that the rally shows that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s credit crunch is the number one issue with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>.

            The papers note that the main thrust of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> results is that while the
new treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are making a huge dent in the death rate, the infection
rate continues apace--at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 40,000</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> cases a year. In other
words, they say, prevention is not improving. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> who points out that there have been no new federal funds spent on
prevention in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>. Give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> credit for being the only
major to put the sustained infection rate in its headline. And although, for instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
mentions an upsurge of unsafe sex practices among gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and the problems of
instilling effective prevention among intravenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> never
mentions the words "gay" or "sex" or "intravenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>."

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> explain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remark about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> vote allows <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> facing tough re-election fights to avoid the
extra baggage with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that resisting any impeachment inquiry--described by
the papers as a sure thing--might bring. After all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> points out,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> votes will be more valuable later on than they are now, should
an impeachment bill eventually come to the floor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> delivered this message to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen members</ENAMEX> at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> meeting. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statement came
as some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> openly complained about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> pressure on them to vote
to block or limit the investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s response, quoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , has the familiar
I-didn't-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">inhale</NUMEX>-and<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">-I-</ENAMEX>didn't-impale flavor: yes, he was talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, but "a large number called me."

            The LAT front features a big picture and accompanying story about
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600,000</NUMEX>-strong nationwide protest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> calling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to quit. The story is pushed inside everywhere else. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> alone,
the rally drew <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, a new political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> appears to be forming behind <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuri Luzhov</ENAMEX>.

            The front pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> give lots of space to
purported inside stories of what it's like to do business with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> if
you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> or AOL. Most of the narrative in the two
articles obviously comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> produced in discovery for the upcoming
government anti-trust case against MS. Such a press preview amounts to the
government's air war before the ground war of the trial itself.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an inside story reporting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> passed a bill designed to restrict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>' access to adult material on the Internet.
The bill, explains the paper, is designed to be narrow enough to withstand the
court scrutiny that struck down a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>. The legislation would ban
the Internet availability to young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of material that includes "actual or
simulated acts of sexual contact, actual or simulated normal or perverted
sexual acts, or a lewd exhibition of the genitals or female <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX>." And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> stipulates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> found making such material available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>
online would face fines of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $50,000</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to six months</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. The
story utterly overlooks an obvious fact: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> would be a clear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">violator</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs a fascinating front-page "cover story" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">little-known South Carolina</ENAMEX>-based but itinerant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> descent thought to number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 100,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX> are said by
many law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to be a criminally based society, specializing
in home repair scams generally targeting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>. In addition, the group
keeps their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out of school and encourages its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> to get married off in
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">low teens</ENAMEX> or younger--often to blood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> gap in the story: no
mention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gypsies</ENAMEX>, whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX> seem to resemble in many
respects.

            Front-page stories at both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and WSJ detail the opulent
lifestyle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> gathered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
to ponder an increasingly straitened world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> catches the
financiers nibbling on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pea pancakes</ENAMEX> topped with caviar, while at another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> spies a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six-foot-high ice</NUMEX> sculpture of an eagle bedecked
with oysters, shrimp and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
