
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Market Bull</ENAMEX>

            The Dow's big day leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and is the right-hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> at the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> off-leads the story in deference to the
opening of bidding on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Redskins</ENAMEX>.

            The DJIA starts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at a record high and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' consensus is that
this is due to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> interest rate cuts, increased merger
and acquisition activities, and a general sense that the global economic crisis
is on its way to being handled. The LAT throws in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s renewed
hold on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and says the list of causes are "the right reasons," but
never says why they are right or what would make for wrong ones. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
adds some more technical reasons to this list: the growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-2</ENAMEX> money
supply (what we've got in checking accounts, savings accounts, and money market
funds) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' closing of short positions (buying stocks now to close
out past sales of borrowed stocks that were bets the market was going south).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> note the quickness with which the market came
back from its recent <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> drop, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> saying that it was
"the shortest bear market in history."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s events are a kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">salute</ENAMEX> to raging bull quote-machine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abby Joseph Cohen</ENAMEX>. In these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>
redirects any suggestion of personal brilliance back to a cool, professional
assessment of market conditions. But in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> coverage, we see
another side: there, she is said to gush that her prediction's come true.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that an overlooked theme of the market rebound is that
"most individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> never lost their nerve." The same point is made on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial page by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Floyd Norris</ENAMEX>, who says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> weren't
dissuaded by the overseas financial crisis nor the losses suffered by
high-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rollers</ENAMEX> in hedge funds. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes on to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
are "much more brave" because among other things, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> has cut rates and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has funded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> has apparently advanced a good banking
plan. It's hard to reconcile these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points of view. Either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> care
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> such high-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">falutin</ENAMEX>' matters or they don't, right?

            Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> refer to a warning
made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> about the dangers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' "irrational
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exuberance</ENAMEX>." But it's not clear from any of these stories whether the market's
gain of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 3,000</NUMEX> points (this upswing is noted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ) since
then is confirmation or refutation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s fears. And it's hard to see
what would make it clear, which is why these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> market move stories are
different from many news stories. Daily market moves are radically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underdetermined</ENAMEX>. And hence the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> shouldn't spend so much space on their
meaning. They really don't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            The USAT front brings startling news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>: the
government's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Product Safety Commission</ENAMEX> is recalling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly ten million</NUMEX>
foldable playpens because their raised rivets can strangle toddlers by catching
on their clothes or pacifiers. This has already happened to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. It's not clear from the story why the recall is being done now.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s acquittal on all
charges <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> fraud and embezzlement
trial. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> were banned topics in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>,
it's apparent that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> thought the state case was an attempt to
pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX> to cooperate in that matter. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> never seriously contemplated guilty verdicts on any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
counts.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has thrown
out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-sodomy</ENAMEX> law, which was once upheld by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court. The story is carried inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . The decision is being
heralded by gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>. But since both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> point out that the case
prompting this decision was one involving heterosexual contact and that there
are plenty of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that still likewise ban oral and anal contact
between opposite sexes, it's not clear why this isn't a big deal to the general
population too. Perhaps because such statutes aren't often used to arrest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterosexuals</ENAMEX>? The stories don't say.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> provides some facts from a recent survey conducted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 47 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> bathe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 60</NUMEX>
percent change their underwear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> never wash their hands.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> once came to the same conclusions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one July day</TIMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro</ENAMEX>, this story cries out for context: How do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> come out in a similar
survey?

            The last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> for truly unconstrained opinion in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> is the
photograph. If you doubt this, go get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and turn to page
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>." There, accompanying a story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
speaking their minds about other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, you'll find a looming picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, cropped so close that none of his hair is visible and you can see the
sweat that's bubbling out of every giant pore in his face. Note that the verbal
equivalent: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, looking like a crazed criminal with something to hide,
said..." would never pass muster. What did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> ever do to deserve this?

         
      
   
