
   
   
      
         
            Landscape by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hieronymus Bosch</ENAMEX>

            Not much news as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas week</TIMEX> begins. Just kidding. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impeached</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> said he wouldn't become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> after all, and
the most ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> came to an end. No great
Times about what to put on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            Everybody leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> president
in history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted to impeach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for perjury before a grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">228-206</ENAMEX>) and obstruction of justice (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">221-212</ENAMEX>) largely along party lines.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other impeachment votes failed: for perjury in a civil suit (defeated
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">229-205</ENAMEX>) and for abuse of power (defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">285-148</ENAMEX>). Just before the impeachment
votes, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> motion to bring a censure proposal to the floor also failed
(defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">230-204</ENAMEX>), winning support from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie Morella</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter King</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is unlikely to convict, which requires
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> vote. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , reminding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of earlier predictions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that impeachment would never pass the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> on a partisan vote and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> would suffer losses in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midterm</ENAMEX> elections, warns: "In the toxic politics of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century's end</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, the inconceivable has become the commonplace." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports
the surreal detail that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> debated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> were holding a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> meeting to plan <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s decision not to assume the speakership (and to quit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>) is attributed mainly to pleading from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, but also to the fury
of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who threatened not to
support him in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> vote to choose a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX>, in an op-ed piece, praises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s "leadership by
example" and urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to resign. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> editorial titled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Challenge by Example</ENAMEX>" also praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX> and notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> early
on called for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s resignation, but says that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to do so now
after an irresponsible impeachment vote "would itself set a harmful precedent."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> fear that white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supremacist David Duke</ENAMEX> will run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> seat.

            The papers pronounce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Dennis</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX>, the little-known deputy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whip</ENAMEX>, to be the likely next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, having quickly won the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> and majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, both of whom seem to have concluded they
themselves lacked sufficient support to win the job. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> emphasizes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s support is truly decisive, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX>'s elevation would
further expand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s already-impressive power base. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX>, a well-liked
moderate from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> suburbs, is known as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>" because he is a
former high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>. Not much more is said about him.

            The halt to air strikes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is reported to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> in
power, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> less likely than ever before to return, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> mapping a new strategy of "containment" against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, with military forces
remaining in the region indefinitely. No <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> are known
to have occurred during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the four days</TIMEX> of attack. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> is quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>
program has been set back "by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a year</TIMEX>." In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">op-ed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Steel</ENAMEX> writes, "the political fallout is likely to be more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beneficial</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> than to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." In particular, he
argues, economic sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> are less likely to be enforced by
member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> A "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
describes how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> came to be named after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erwin</ENAMEX>
Rommel: Under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> protocol, the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> planning the operation
had to call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Desert</ENAMEX> [something beginning with "s" or "f"]. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX> is quoted saying, implausibly, that
"nobody" recognized the connection between "desert <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rommel</ENAMEX>. The story
also says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> approved the name.

         
      
   
