
   
   
      
         
            Big Wheel Keep on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turnin</ENAMEX>'

            Margin-to-margin headlines at all major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> announce that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> has
voted to begin an impeachment inquiry, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> such vote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
history. The vote split along party lines, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> supporting
hearings. The inquiry has no deadline and has authority to investigate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">non-Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matters. It will not begin until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> reconvenes after the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 3</TIMEX> elections.

            All the majors acknowledge that the outcome was largely expected. Still,
opening an impeachment inquiry has "deepened the crisis shrouding" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
says the New York
Times --a choice of words certain to send a chill down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Spine</ENAMEX>.
No matter the outcome, the inquiry "permanently scars the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency"
adds the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 3</TIMEX> elections will have a profound effect
on impeachment hearings. A big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> loss will 1) erode <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s support
among his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) make it possible for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to remove
him without any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defectors</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> reacted gracefully to the news--"detached, even serene" according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> --saying "It is not in my hands.... There is nothing I can do."
Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> are happy because, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> suggests, the
vote means <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next four weeks</TIMEX> at least will be peaceful. Maybe it's because,
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report, a party-line vote means
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can call the investigation a partisan witch-hunt.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a nice front-page primer on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. Considered the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>'s most important creation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Fathers</ENAMEX>, it gets little
relatively respect from contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. In other
news: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Representatives</ENAMEX> were
present at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the three hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> debate, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> were present for the bulk of it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> have front page stories on the stock market,
which fell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> points then recovered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late in the day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says this
is a bad sign for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> focuses on the recovery, which was
fueled by rumors of a rate cut; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> waffles, reporting that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are thoroughly confused.

            The top international story (not on the front page of most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>) is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> had harsh words for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> chief
ended its annual meeting by with guarded optimism.

            Only the LAT front pages the award of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelist Jose Saramago</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> is not only a card-carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>, he,
like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, is an official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>--one of
his stories depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> losing his virginity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Magdelene</ENAMEX>. The WP
includes this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gem</ENAMEX>: "It's never been easier to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> than now," says
Saramago, "because there's so few of us." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> wishes the WP
corrected solecisms in its quotations, even solecisms committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laureates</ENAMEX> in literature.)

         
      
   
