
   
   
      
         
            Netescape

            A major business development, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s nearly consummated purchase of
Netscape, leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The move also gets a front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . (According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> online edition and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> broke
the story.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
puts the story above the fold, but leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s latest weapons inspection
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snit</ENAMEX> and off-leads with word that driven by budget constraints as much as by
the reduced threat of nuclear attack, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> is quietly recommending
unilateral reductions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear warheads. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> go
top-front with the same picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>: At the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">DMZ</ENAMEX> complete
with howitzer backdrop, decked out in scrambled-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> ball-cap and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> field
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jacket</ENAMEX>, he's doing a grip-and-grin with a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. Judging by his
105mm smile, he's finally enjoying the military lifestyle.

            The papers report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL/Netscape</ENAMEX> deal is actually triangular, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AOL</ENAMEX> buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $4 billion</NUMEX> in stock and then licensing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>'s
e-commerce software to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Microsystems</ENAMEX>, which hopes to use it as a vehicle for
disseminating its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Java</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> as an alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s Windows.

            Everybody reports that the deal could have big ramifications for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>,
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> making the point that the deal formally bonds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
whose charges that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> uses monopoly power to block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>' products
have played central roles in the current anti-trust trial. Indeed, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were emboldened to deal because of their
perception that the case would weaken MS. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX>'s claim that the deal would "blow an enormous hole in the
government's case," because it shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> have retained the
ability to change the landscape <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>--in ways that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> claims
is illegal when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> tries it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and WSJ make this
point too but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> adds that on the other hand, the government
could argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX> was driven into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front reports that one of the highest-ranking female law
enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, a higher-up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>, is being
investigated to see if she used her position to steer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government business</ENAMEX> to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinate</ENAMEX> who is a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.

            The WP front covers a lawsuit in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is suing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> for
becoming pregnant against his will--she had, he says,
promised to take birth control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> claims that she became pregnant
accidentally. That factual issue may be settled at trial, but it seems that
there is a larger legal issue well worth addressing. Since court findings of
paternity cost the imputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years</TIMEX>' worth of support, it seems
only fair that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> be held accountable for any promises they make about
attempting to remain childless. In the absence of that, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s promise to
take charge of birth control and then not doing so remains the only form of
monetary fraud <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> can think of that is not only not punished, but
is in fact regularly rewarded.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" does a long take-out on the increasing
attempts by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to market their products inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, especially
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Everybody from software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> being one of
them) to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> has been finding new ways to do this, and parents
are, says the paper, finding more product solicitations coming home in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' backpacks. The good deals and cut rates are often dangled as a way to
help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> get stuff they need, which is particularly attractive to school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX> strapped for funds in an environment in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> keep
turning down so many school bond issues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> admits it
school-markets too, by handing out free papers on campuses, ostensibly to
promote reading, but also to increase the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s circulation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> item about the opening of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6,400-square-foot</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> about to become the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenny</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby McCaughey</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">septuplets</ENAMEX> and their other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. The story describes such features as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">648</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square foot playroom</NUMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> with a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> tub," and an intercom system
connecting the various parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. The story says scores of businesses
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> contributed materials, services, money and land for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
Yet no money figures are ever mentioned--an interesting omission when the
typical story about welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> enumerates the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> "giveaway" check
down to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX>. The story's lucre lacunae comport well with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>'
theories about how all this came about--it quotes a neighbor saying, "Looks
like God is going to provide all these things."

         
      
   
