
   
   
      
         
            Car Wreck

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead with the gathering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> momentum for impeachment and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s response to it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs that story as its off-lead, going
instead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX>, which also gets the
biggest print at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>.

            The main thrust of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> leads is that the ranks of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> declaring themselves to be firmly against
impeachment is shrinking. This despite fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> polling indicating that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do not want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> to vote for
impeachment. The poll in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> offers a slightly different picture
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>: yes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are against impeachment, but if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> votes to impeach, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58 percent</NUMEX> of them say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should then resign. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a front-pager about its new poll likewise showing that a clear
majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> oppose impeachment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s lead editorial proclaims
that "A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> so out of step with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it claims to represent ...is a
greater danger to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic</ENAMEX> than all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s selfish lies."

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> find the wavering of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Shays</ENAMEX>
particularly important, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shays</ENAMEX> had long been an announced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> of
impeachment. Both report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shays</ENAMEX> will soon have a personal meeting with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to discuss the matter. The LAT passes along a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> rumor
according to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' lone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Sanders</ENAMEX>, was also changing
to a pro impeachment vote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Souder</ENAMEX>, another early
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of impeachment, is still solid, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says he's
reconsidering his position. The paper sums up the situation as trending against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> appearing to be at a loss about what to do. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says: "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> appeared to be moving steadily toward
impeachment."

            Everybody notes that the congressional hearts-and-minds battle seems to have
shifted away from official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>: to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Way
radio spots, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>-organized phone campaigns, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>-led prayer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vigil</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> both report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX>
Strip--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--gives a powerful boost to hopes
of eventual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> statehood. And both report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> watched as
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> raised hands to overwhelmingly revoke the
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> parts of their charter. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> version emphasizes the uptick
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> take dwells more on unanticipated
obstacles to the peace process: like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s decision not to go through with a
planned troop withdrawal this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, because of recent violent protests in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front continues to peck at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton/China</ENAMEX> connection with
a piece claiming that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have come across new evidence about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> political contributions. These contributions, were not, as was
originally thought, designed to influence the outcomes of particular races such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s, but, says the paper, were part of a broad campaign to acquire
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> high technology. Giving the money, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> now think, was, in
the spirit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> corporate lobbying model, designed to enhance the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>' political access so that they could more effectively argue for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-friendly trade and technology policies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that one
fund-raiser in this effort, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX>, now cooperating with federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, pleaded guilty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and was sentenced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>' probation.
As if supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' contention, the sentencing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> expressed
doubt about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> assertions of ignorance concerning
fund-raising abuses and said he was surprised that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> had not appointed
a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> to investigate further.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports in a front-page feature that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has a dress code
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> crash test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummies</ENAMEX>. They are supposed to wear <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">matching cotton</ENAMEX> shirts
and shorts and black-leather oxford shoes. This is so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> can clearly see
how the limbs flail in a crash. Why the shoes? Because that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
crashes are usually wearing. However, socks are optional.

         
      
   
