
   
   
      
         
            Definite Articles

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s vote to recommend impeachment for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> leads at all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HJC</ENAMEX> approved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> articles of impeachment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> by votes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21-16</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20-17</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21-16</NUMEX>. The articles accuse
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) lying before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> grand jury, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) lying under oath
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> sexual harassment case, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) obstructing justice by
attempting to influence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> voted
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> line with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey Graham</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>), who voted
against impeachment for lying in a civil case. The papers all note that the
votes came just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> after another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> apology, this time from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Garden</ENAMEX>, in which he expressed profound regret, asked for a censure
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and, once again, did not admit to lying under oath. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> will vote on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> article, which alleges abuse of power, on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says the timing of the vote, which came
immediately after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s apology, lent "a dramatic-some said surreal-quality
to the moment of judgement." All the papers mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> now joins
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to face impeachment.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
points out that the events leading up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> began as "a
civil sex harassment suit by an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX>."

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> papers all feature front-page articles on a second-hand effect
of suing tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>: rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. An arbitration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> has awarded a
total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 billion</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who successfully sued tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> on
behalf of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> award of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, which will be split among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that represented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, is
the largest fee ever in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> will split fees of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.3 billion</NUMEX>. Cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> are responsible for
paying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.

            An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> piece reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX> has an
extensive file of information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>. While the article explains
that the excitable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press has gone ballistic over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>'s refusal to
share the files' contents, the real story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> practice of monitoring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electronic</ENAMEX> transmissions around the globe and screening them for targeted
search terms like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last January</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Parliament</ENAMEX>
wrote, "within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, all e-mail, telephone and fax communications are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">routinely</ENAMEX> intercepted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States National Security Agency</ENAMEX>." A subject
of much controversy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> eavesdropping has gone practically unnoticed
(and perhaps underreported) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> cites an intelligence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> who says the reason for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apathy is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> is barred by law
from targeting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, even when they are abroad.

         
      
   
