
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stations of the Cross Examination</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>'s statement
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> may have to be part of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> peacekeeping
effort in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, a story that also makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
fronts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads go with efforts by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> impeachment resolution when it comes to a floor vote
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has himself made calls to key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> as part of this effort, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is also taking an
active role. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the budget talks beginning today
between top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> and the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.
Object: avoiding a government shutdown. According to the paper, bones of
contention include: additional funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>, whether or not to authorize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population sampling</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>, and emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> aid.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s comments at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing constitute, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , a
shift for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, which till now has not publicly discussed
possible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> roles in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> deployment to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> makes the
shift seem bigger than the other papers because it emphasizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s expressed
personal recommendation that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> not be sent, an option other
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> have been leaving open, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> stress that he didn't flatly rule this out.

            The papers make it clear that the response of some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> suggests
that the task of selling a ground deployment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> may be "formidable."
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, report the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , drew the
comparison with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> troop presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>--at first said by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration to be only a remote possibility, but still in place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
after the cessation of fighting there. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> makes it seem that such
concerns were only on the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, while the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> make
it clear they were voiced from both sides of the aisle.

            Such political resistance explains why some administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">floated</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX> the idea of an all-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> military ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> being
dispatched to the region, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dominating any air effort. But, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> points out, this seems unlikely to work because when an all-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> was on the ground in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, there was severe tension between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> involved and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, which didn't have ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> at risk.
Another problem, pointed out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> sternly warned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> against any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> deployment and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> said such a move
would plunge the world back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.

            Buried deep in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story are the numbers. To give context to the
whole discussion, they should have been placed much higher. It seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> are considering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, and under one plan, even
60,000.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead recounts the psychological consequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s economic mess. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is seeing a big rise in suicide, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, insomnia, over-drinking,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-smoking and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ulcers</ENAMEX>. Most stunning stat: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least 50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> are
expected to be hospitalized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> after trying to kill themselves.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a front-page look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McLean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> church by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s religion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanna Rosin</ENAMEX>. It turns out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s place of worship is a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12-steppy</NUMEX>,
New Agey kind of a deal, emphasizing recovery from various addictions.
Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> gets lots of support from fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregants</ENAMEX>. The story
quotes one fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parishioner</ENAMEX>'s request that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> pray for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>: "I have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who is going through hell right now...I believe he is in trouble with
the world because he desires to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> well in the task to which he
has been called."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> inside describe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s latest move
to fight the erosion of its long distance business by downscale dial-around
services like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-10-321</NUMEX>--it's introducing its own downscale dial-around
service, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lucky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX>. Ads for the new service will feature <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Hagman</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jeffersons</ENAMEX>." But there's one thing they won't feature: any
indication that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX> points to an odd passage in an anti-drug pamphlet
with a foreword by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>. The book claims to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> look for
the warning signs that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are using marijuana or other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. These
signs include, says the pamphlet, such obvious ones as staying out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>
and unexplained needs for money. But there's also this unobvious one: Beware
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s "excessive preoccupation with social causes, race relations,
environmental issues, etc."

         
      
   
