
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruff Treatment</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with the release <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> majority of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> proposed articles of impeachment, to be voted on by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. The articles charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> offenses: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Perjury before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) Perjury in a civil case
deposition; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) Obstruction of justice; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Abuse of power.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> quote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX>'s reaction that
there's "nothing in the allegations...that brings anything here up to the
standard of an impeachable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Kennedy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> saying almost the exact same thing, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
added the quintessential spontaneity-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> complaint: the no-notice
release was unfair. The coverage adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> responded by
tendering a censure proposal, calling for a condemnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that he
would acknowledge by signing. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> will allow
it to be brought to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> vote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> note that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> aggressively embraced censure.
Both papers explain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic anti-</ENAMEX>impeachment strategy is to push
for a full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> censure vote, in the hope that this will siphon some key
moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> votes away from any impeachment bill.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> will probably present the videotape of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case deposition.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> explains why: because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has claimed that he wasn't
listening when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert S. Bennett</ENAMEX> denied that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had engaged in
any kind of sexual activity with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> believe
the video clearly shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> paying close attention.

            Before the advent of the impeachment articles, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> was busy
hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second day</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Ruff</ENAMEX>
did the heavy lifting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> note that for the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, via his testimony, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> promised that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> would not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pardon</ENAMEX> himself or accept a pardon from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> give the most space to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruff</ENAMEX>'s tortured attempts to show that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sworn denials of sexual relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> were not perjury. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruff</ENAMEX> argued that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> misled
about this, he did not commit perjury because he did not intend not to tell the
truth. But if he misled, then didn't he intend to have his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> end up
believing a falsehood? And isn't that just as injurious to the legal system as
perjury? If arranging to have someone killed is as bad as killing them, why
isn't arranging to have someone believe what's false as bad as lying to
them?

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> revealed that management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Covey</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is floundering, now comes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> with a front-page feature
detailing how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyncom, Inc.</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> the personal appearances of the
likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Covey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Peters</ENAMEX>, is in financial trouble. Recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyncom</ENAMEX> flops:
Spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and losing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a million dollars</NUMEX> getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 5,250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>'s big basketball arena to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Peters</ENAMEX>, and losing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> when only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> showed up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Dome</ENAMEX> to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Covey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front reports on a bit of unintended technology first revealed
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> publication <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Scientist : The Palm</ENAMEX> III pocket
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> can intercept the signal used to open an infra-red <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> lock, the type
found on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chryslers</ENAMEX>. The stolen code, explains the paper, could
only be used once and can only open the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, not start it.

            It's thrilling to have so many smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. In response to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
concern in this space that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision banning probable
causeless car searches after routine traffic stops would prevent arrests like
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">snared</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> received many
well-researched and well-reasoned letters. The point expressed by most of them
was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> was in fact arrested for gun possession after a search based
on probable cause--namely the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> thought he saw a gun bulge on him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>
enough, but the whole matter gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to thinking: if probable cause is so
essential to a legal search, then how come those X-ray machines and metal
detectors you have to go through at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> are legal? They're not just
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to suspicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. Why should travel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> subject you to
searches travel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> does not?

         
      
   
