
   
   
      
         
            Not So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Livingston</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s split-screen crisis leads all around--with banner headlines
referring to both impeachment and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> the order of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. The papers note
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeachment debate begins this morning and presumably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
day of military actions will soon follow. So at some point then, there will be
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the same time charges raining down on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and bombs
raining down on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s.

            The papers report that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first two days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, there
were no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX>, and that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are claiming that at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqis</ENAMEX> have died. The coverage also quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chiefs Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Shelton</ENAMEX>'s comment that targets successfully hit included
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX> there housing his security
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. He is also quoted saying that other strikes were "not as successful."
None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> briefing technique on display here: While
Shelton illustrated the successful hits with before and after photos, the
misses were not illustrated. It's reported that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> sites struck
by cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of the youngest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> asking if her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> was one of the key <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> for the rule of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Nobody explains
whether or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> seems to have been hit intentionally.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> all run <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s forceful response to the
suggestion made previously by senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> that he ordered the airstrikes
to distract from the drive to impeachment: "I don't think any serious person
would believe that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would do such a thing." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also note a
general climb-down among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> bigfeet from such suggestions, and
indeed, everybody carries <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s remarks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor that "no
matter what our debates at home, we are as a nation prepared to lead the
world."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front features a story stating that while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> have targeted military, intelligence, and communications
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>, they have avoided hitting known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> chemical and biological
weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> in order to avoid unleashing plumes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poisons</ENAMEX> into the air that
could kill <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes the oddity of this given that one
of the stated aims of the strikes is non-proliferation. A piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times front offers something of an answer: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> military
strategy is "containment-plus," the plan to use force whenever needed--not just
this one time--combined with financial incentives to motivate some indigenous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to rise out of the chaos thus created to topple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>.

            The papers note some international criticism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> passed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> dissenting vote a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> strikes were terrorism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> all called for an immediate stop to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">raids</ENAMEX> (using its time-zone-assisted later deadlines, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this yesterday</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says there were protests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was the site of bitter
debate over whether or not the impeachment debate and vote should proceed while
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> are fighting overseas. Everybody notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>, in his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> floor speech since being chosen to be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>, claimed as
precedent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> impeachment hearings, which he claimed went on when
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were deployed in the field in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>...." No member
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> nor any paper but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> caught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s mistake. But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , befitting its reputation for solid historical reporting,
notes that in fact, the last <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX>
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> case.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s other big whoops of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> got a lot more attention. Because
of the imminent release of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roll</ENAMEX> Call piece based on a story
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> is apparently working on indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> has had
numerous affairs during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33-year</TIMEX> marriage, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> preemptively fessed
up. He suggested that his situation was different from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s because
his affairs were "not with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and I have never been asked
to testify under oath about them." Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX>, just to reassure the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>, you wouldn't mind doing that now, would you?

         
      
   
