
   
   
      
         
            Who <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do You Anti-Trust</ENAMEX>?

            Like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> dominate. The
former leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with the latter. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> story is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fronted</ENAMEX> everywhere, except the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , which saves it for the business
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>-hosted <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> peace talks, already not going well,
were sent into an even deeper freeze <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early Monday</TIMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">grenade</ENAMEX> attack on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beersheba</ENAMEX>.

            The papers report that so intent is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on salvaging the talks that he
canceled a scheduled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> fund-raising trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to stay personally
involved at the rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> site of the talks. And indeed, in the course of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, he presided at a three-way meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>--their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of state
are also trying to keep the sides talking--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> has flown to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> he owns in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> and was standing by to help, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hosni Mubarak</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> has been in contact with both sides. But apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> are
still flunking chemistry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> quotes an un-named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> official
saying that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> do not deal seriously with each other without an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and another saying that it pretty
much takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presence to get talks going.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> at the conference reacted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">grenade</ENAMEX> attack by
insisting that it would only discuss security issues with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, a
stance the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> calls a "dramatic negotiating ploy," probably not the
most apt phrase, since there's little doubt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> concern about
safety from terrorism is heartfelt. But both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and LAT
report that later on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, other issues were actually discussed--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> doesn't say what though, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> refers only vaguely to
the topic of further redeployments of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> coverage makes it very clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
decided to make its case very much about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's lead runs
under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gates Singled Out in Trial</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> started its
case, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, by contrasting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' video deposition
(displayed on a "larger-than-life screen" says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
says "<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-foot</NUMEX>") in which he said he knew nothing more about an alleged
market-carving meeting with browser rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> than what he read in the
newspaper (actually he mentioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , a fact included by
everybody--including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> --except <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ), with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> email in
which he states "...there is a very powerful deal of some kind we can do with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>...We could even pay them money as part of the deal, buying some piece
of them or something." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also notes that in the direct testimony of
Netscape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Barksdale</ENAMEX> released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barksdale</ENAMEX> claims <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> used
threats and bribes to get various PC <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and Internet service
providers to go with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>' browser. Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> feature an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exec</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">email</ENAMEX> in which he claims, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> delivered a characteristically blunt query:
'How much do we need to pay you to screw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX>? This is your lucky day.'"
Wonder if "screw" kept that quote out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX>'s Newspaper.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>' top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is widely quoted as calling the email evidence "snippets
taken out of context." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is pretty free with descriptions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>,
saying that in his video depo, he was "slouching" and was "visibly testy." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barksdale</ENAMEX> testimony is the subject of a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .
Meanwhile, a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed by a semi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor CEO</ENAMEX> wonders,
"If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> violated the law by giving away browsers, why didn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Netscape?</ENAMEX>"

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story reports that military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, concerned
by a recent spate of public <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>-driven criticisms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>--in service-oriented publications and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and
on the Internet--are threatening service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> with punishment if they utter
"contemptuous words" about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the recent
criticisms represent a "downturn" in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s standing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> should never be puzzled again about its target demographic for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyson</ENAMEX>
fight broadcasts. According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iron Mike</ENAMEX> himself cleared
that up at the hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> where he regained permission to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>. "I represent," he testified, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimps</ENAMEX>, whores,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
