
   
   
      
         
            Watch on the Potomac

            The papers all lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s defense before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>. The journalism consensus is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate-</ENAMEX>era <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and ex-special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>
constituted a deepening of the scandal's heretofore ditzy discussion. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> headline refers to a "day of
dialogue." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
sees a "sober debate." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> says that compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> appearance, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s session was "much more sober and
substantive." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s legal team
"offered its most comprehensive rebuttal."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>? As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> featured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoe Lofgren</ENAMEX>
saying that one reason not to impeach was that it would be bad for the economy,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asa Hutchinson</ENAMEX> cited as a pro-impeachment consideration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s use of the word "intimate" when he should have said
"sexual." And at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Coble</ENAMEX>
responded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness Fr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Drinan</ENAMEX>'s assertion that vengeance was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motivating GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> by saying, "If anybody thinks vengeance is
involved, I'll meet them in the parking lot." That's the current state of
congressional deliberation--challenging a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70-plus</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duke</ENAMEX>-out. The day
proved once again that there is no hearing in a congressional hearing. They
should call these things congressional talkings. The papers agree that the real
targets of the discussion are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-20</NUMEX> moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> undecideds.
But if so, then call those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> session and leave the rest of
us alone.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> front carries word that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled
unanimously that, absent indications of additional criminal activity, police
cannot automatically search a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> after making a routine traffic stop. The
story is also carried inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The papers note that the
decision is a surprising exception to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s trend in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">upholding</ENAMEX> and widening police conduct especially in the area of searches.
Neither story mentions one notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> who might never have been caught
had this decision come down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>, initially held
because of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> found in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> after he was stopped for driving without
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plates</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT front carries a stunning medical result published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> , sure to add <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> to the second-hand smoke debate. Examinations of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bartenders</ENAMEX> made before and after the implementation last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s public indoor smoking ban show, says the medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX>, a substantial post-ban lessening of respiratory troubles as well as of
eye, ear, nose and throat problems. The changes were detected <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> after the ban began. (Hats off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> for putting the number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bartenders</ENAMEX> high up.)

            A congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" he has to speak off the
record because "I get in a lot of trouble if I'm quoted, especially if the
quotes are accurate."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX> was acquitted of
charges that he illegally accepted gratuities. But according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reliable Source</ENAMEX>," he's still really into legal gratuities. It seems that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX>'s special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Smaltz</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">18-carat</NUMEX> gold watches made for his
staff (let's hope that this was done out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smaltz</ENAMEX>'s pocket and not his office
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX> is quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> saying, "I surely would like a
watch. I think I earned the watch."

         
      
   
