
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Spared</ENAMEX>

            New developments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> continue to dominate all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' fronts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> had "backed down" and that weapons
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> would return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> as soon as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> finally called off
the possibility of attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>; on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> reveal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had merely postponed the attack for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> while his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> assessed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s alleged concessions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> additional
letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to stow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and give the
inspections another chance. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> remains wary. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
emphasizes in its lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> says it stands "ready to act" if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> breaks more promises. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> notes that the extra <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> won't go home immediately--they will stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> issued <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> criteria for judging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>'s compliance. Among the
conditions: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspectors</ENAMEX> must have "unfettered access" to weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
must turn over all documentary evidence of producing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass
destruction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also indirectly endorsed the overthrow of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>,
calling him "an impediment to the well-being of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and a threat to the
peace of the region and the security of the world." This caused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> Deputy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tariq Aziz</ENAMEX> to snap back on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remarks were "a
flagrant violation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> resolutions as well as international
law."

            The WP fronts an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX>'s guide to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> voted for
what on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">National Security Advisor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Berger</ENAMEX> held out for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Shelton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staff</ENAMEX>, favored gong ahead with the attack on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> didn't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s concern about
possibly killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iraqis</ENAMEX> (a "medium case scenario") in the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overture</ENAMEX> won out. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> front page ventures the comparison between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s restraint in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> crisis and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s performance
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> missile crisis.

            The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> fronts a story on the thriving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> drug industry and why drugs
are ever more expensive. Drug sales rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16.5%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> as drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> hone
their marketing savvy, and prices for many generic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> have increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. Part of the high prices can be attributed to soaring costs for
clinical trials--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $150 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>--and new, expensive chemical
ingredients for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. But, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , profit is the principal
factor--plus which, unlike other industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has few
drug price regulations in place. Among those hardest hit by the rising prices
are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> whose health care plans must absorb inflated prescription drug
prices, and uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes,
the need for more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> will exacerbate the cost problem.

            Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> has an op-ed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that can be
(and is) summarized in exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sentence: "There is simply no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitutional</ENAMEX>
basis for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to censure a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> fronts
a story (carried inside elsewhere) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s
tiff with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. While in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> for an economic conference,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who is jailed on sex
and corruption charges. Exasperated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s perceived affront to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commented</ENAMEX>, "Maybe when I go to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, I would like to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
