
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impeach Pits</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> lead with a court-ordered scientific
panel's finding of no credible evidence that silicone breast implants cause
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, a story that also makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front</ENAMEX>, but runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s ever-increasing hardening of partisan lines concerning
impeachment. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon/Mobil</ENAMEX> deal announced
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, which would create the world's largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. There is so much
uncertainty about whether the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 billion</NUMEX> deal will get government approval,
that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> observes, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' stock prices dipped on the
news. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columnist Alexander Cockburn</ENAMEX> warns in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that
will in his opinion definitely go up if the deal flies: gas prices.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's inside package on the merger says in the short-term prices will
go down, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> quoted are less sure about the long-term.

            The implant leads point out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s findings could make it much
harder in the future for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> that their silicones gave
them <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, lupus, or immune system and/or connective tissue problems. Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> did not address the health
consequences of ruptured implants, nor, adds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , problems of infection
or painful breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hardening</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that the findings fit with
other recent scientific results. The paper mentions in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, while USAT
saves this information for the last paragraph. And the LAT surprises
with word that the panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are barred from speaking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. Still?
Why? How is this possible?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead says the committee <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> won a vote allowing
pursuit of alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fundraising abuses, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is
considering not presenting any defense whatsoever to any areas the committee
has raised--because, in the words quoted from presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
Lockhart, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HJC</ENAMEX> has been "hijacked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX>, says the
paper, deemed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s investigation "in chaos" and asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
to take charge, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> apparently will not do. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, which has been tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lo these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many months</TIMEX>, agrees with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>, in an editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Out of Control</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page gets off a good line
from the other direction, saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' increasing intransigence
given their reading of public sentiment shows that "polls are the crack <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>
of politics."

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> focuses on all the political carping, it barely mentions
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> hearing was largely given over to the testimony of
convicted perjurers, legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and several retired military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, all
discoursing on the nature and significance of perjury. By contrast, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in its front-page story, is quite taken with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> perjurers, an
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, both of whom had been found guilty of lying
about sex. (But how galling it must be for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Dershowitz</ENAMEX> that neither
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> mentions his name.)

            In his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> doles out some important context to
the recent news that an international aid effort has produced <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> in pledges of aid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday Times</ENAMEX> recently reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> once diverted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>
million earmarked for low-cost housing to luxury flats for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>'s
elite instead, and moreover, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> found <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 40 percent</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$323 million</NUMEX> was wasted, looted or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misused</ENAMEX>.

            An inside story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports on the novel fundraising project
undertaken by a fourth-grade class in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> suburb. They have used the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX> they have raised so far to free <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">601</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from chattel slavery in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>. Send your generous donations to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highline Community School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aurora</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> heralds yet another cyber innovation: Starting
today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> can register with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selective Service</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s web site.
Not only is this a blow for convenience, but also a social control masterpiece.
The only way to symbolically protest a paperless draft would be to burn
your...computer.

         
      
   
