
   
   
      
         
            More Money! New Money!

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s leads splay in all directions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with the rampage of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Georges</ENAMEX>
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly 200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are dead, and the powerful storm is
now headed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Keys</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-column <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> are negotiating for a financial settlement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
sexual harassment suit which is now on appeal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times leads with favorable new polls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT /CBS</ENAMEX> poll shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s approval ratings have risen
since the release of his videotaped grand jury testimony. A backlash may be in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who favored releasing the tape. (A different poll
analyzed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front reaches similar conclusions: Just <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
now would opt for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s removal, down from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the bill passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> that
would grant temporary visas to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 142,500</NUMEX> additional foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> with
high-tech skills. This bill, which would be effective during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, has particular relevance for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> and technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> based
in the west. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, citing the need to protect domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX>, worked several compromises into the bill, including a provision which
diverts a portion of the visa revenues to funds to aid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The
measure is expected to be passed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and signed into law.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's lead cites "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> familiar with the situation" on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and Jones <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have discussed a
settlement "in the range that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> contemplated during past
negotiations"--i.e. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $700,000 and $900,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which also
fronts the story, gets much more specific. Citing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> themselves as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> initiated the discussion
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and proposed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> settlement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, counter-offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX>, and negotiations are proceeding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apace</ENAMEX>. The impetus to settle comes because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' appeal will be heard in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-October</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> views the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> revelations as a possible asset to her
suit.

            In other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> developments, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> set a
tentative schedule for impeachment hearings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> will vote on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> about whether to launch an impeachment inquiry; if yes, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
will vote on the measure very shortly thereafter. Amidst the developments, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> detects mayhem among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> are tripping over one
another's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> initiatives--"a classic case of too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX>,"
commented another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> both report in front-page stories that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> will sign an
international treaty banning nuclear testing within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
announcement follows a similar pledge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>.

            Everybody but the LAT fronts the new padding for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pocketbooks</ENAMEX>. According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> report released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, income for
the average household has risen since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> (outstripping inflation by a rate of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 2</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>), and the poverty rate has declined. Significantly, the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> below the poverty line decreased. Nonetheless,
the papers note, this does not mitigate the long-term trend toward inequality:
the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> still control <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of the wealth.

            Speaking of money, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> pays tribute inside to the new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> bills.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX> launched the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 billion</NUMEX> worth of redesigned
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 greenbacks</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The objective? To foil counterfeiters. (The old $20s
trailed only the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> bills as a counterfeit cinch.) But the new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20s</NUMEX> might not
bring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> cans and subway tokens tumbling out of vending machines just yet:
The machines must be reconfigured to accept the new bills.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> tries to decipher the baffling
marketing phenomenon of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beanie Babies</ENAMEX>. These "little stuffed critters," worth
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.95</NUMEX>, have been flagged among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> as rare and valuable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX>'s
items. As a result, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manic Beanie speculators</ENAMEX> value their collections at
upward of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>. But there is growing fear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beanie</ENAMEX> phenomenon may be
on the verge of collapse either as new rival toys flood the market or, more
likely, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> click their heels <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and realize that their
closets are cluttered with stuffed toys.

         
      
   
