
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balk in Iraq</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> deadline to announce whether
she will appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s role in
questionable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fundraising activities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with news that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is not
cooperating completely with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Wilson</ENAMEX>'s anticipated
last minute judicial and regulatory appointments.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that after reviewing essentially the same evidence
concerning fund raising improprieties for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> must finally decide
whether to begin a thorough, independent investigation into possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
abuses. The primary issue for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s decision is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> knew that
money he solicited in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> was going to be used as both soft-money, which is
unregulated and used for nonspecific party activities, and hard-money, which is
regulated and can be used to pay for re-election ads. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that
extra pressure is being put on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>, which
has expanded its investigation to include campaign finance, and could
potentially include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AG</ENAMEX> herself--particularly her repeated refusal to
appoint a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> does not
make clear who imposed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> deadline or what the ramifications are if no
decision is made.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNSCOM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> see little evidence that the
latest standoff with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has improved their ability to search for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have already denied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>' requests for documents, calling
the requests "provocative rather than professional." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspectors</ENAMEX> fear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> plan to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stall</ENAMEX> and doubletalk their way out of random weapons searches
without blatantly refusing to cooperate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that this strategy
has effectively eroded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNSCOM</ENAMEX> in the
past.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT Sunday Report</ENAMEX> focuses on the changing role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Once viewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> as "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are now significantly
contributing to the economic well being of poor rural areas and gaining new
respect in the process. The piece says that the government decision to allow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to work outside their hometowns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> has prompted an increase in
prosperity in the form of money sent home by the new class of urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , sworn enemy of sports utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> everywhere,
illuminates yet another danger that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX> pose to fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>: high-mounted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headlights</ENAMEX>. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> are concerned that the annoying glare larger
vehicles cause in your rear-view mirror at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> poses a threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visibility</ENAMEX> and causes premature eye-fatigue.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Magazine</ENAMEX> cover story marvels at the resurgence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death, disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> wanted to pass over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adulterous Charles</ENAMEX> and make his son <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the throne. But by hiring a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to manage his image, wooing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> with occasional jokes, and
bonding with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> has staged an astounding
revival. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> now appreciate his many good works and his affectionate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fathering</ENAMEX>. The story hints that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> does not much like his cold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> gets a rare private interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> and confirms that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> does have "large ears, as advertised."

         
      
   
