
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kindest Cut</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post
               , 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s decision to reduce key
interest rates by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-quarter</NUMEX> of a percentage point. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> such cut
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> promises that it will be the last--though financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> aren't so sure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> sets the scene for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s impeachment
hearing.

            All the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that the rate cut will stimulate consumer
spending by lowering the cost of home equity and credit card loans. All papers
also report that consumer spending, however, is currently at healthy levels.
Why cut rates? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> --alone among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>--makes it clear to the
layperson that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s move was directed at the bond markets. Certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are having trouble selling bonds, indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are
worried about financial crises abroad. The rate cut is meant to reassure
anxious Wall Streeters that the hale and hearty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy will remain immune
to international crises.

            Most quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> aren't convinced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s prediction that further
rate cuts won't be necessary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> surveyed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by a macroeconomic forecasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> expect rates
to be lowered yet again.

            On political (i.e. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>) beat, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with the news that, on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> will spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> detailing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> pattern of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obstructing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> in matters including, but extending beyond, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
affair. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> to question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.

            How will <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> play on TV? Some quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> note that he's a seasoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">appellate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, others stress his lack of experience with matters political.
(It's a classic round of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> "expectations" game--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s most modest
reviews come from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> hopes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s performance can "energize the lagging drive" to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Papers also report the popular reaction to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s release of the Tripp
tapes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>--dubbed a "zaftig little rascal" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> --is
generally perceived as childlike, weak, and sort of, like, stupid. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> is
said to be a meatier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--genuinely caring at times, staggeringly
manipulative at others.

            The lead international story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> have
begun to regroup now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> have left. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>
lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX>'s ratification of the peace memorandum finalized at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surgery</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Atlantic Saves Sailor's Life</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via</ENAMEX>
Satellite E-Mail, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boston Physician Assists Injured Man Competing in Yacht</ENAMEX>
Race" as a front-page feature. The solo sailor--a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commando</ENAMEX>--almost died, but is now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Capetown</ENAMEX> and intends to continue the race.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> who admire a stiff upper lip will be impressed by excerpts from the
doctor-patient correspondence. A sample: "My right elbow does not look good.
Some yellow spot in the middle of red, and it feels like dead. Waiting for your
help ... Have been sitting on the bloody <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin floor</ENAMEX> almost completely naked
... watching as my life drop by drop leave me."

         
      
   
