
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde Still Seeks</ENAMEX>

            Impeachment politics dominate, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s decision
to expand its inquiry into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising activities leading
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes instead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
announcement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> will indeed merge.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> will probably, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, vote on party lines to issue
subpoenas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> bearing on prior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Justice</ENAMEX> investigations into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> fund-raising. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles LaBella</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising investigation, will probably be ordered to testify, and
their superior, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>, will be ordered to turn over memos they wrote to
her. Another subpoena will probably go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself, requiring that he
ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> comply with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s request. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> plays the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> subpoena high, putting it in the headline and in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also plays it high. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> is a bit more offhand,
mentioning the subpoena of the memos and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX> in the subhead, but holding
off until halfway through the story before placing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s subpoena
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> in a list of bullets. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that previously, separate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> investigated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> fund-raising without
uncovering illegality by high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, but goes
on to quote a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> saying that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 20 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaBella</ENAMEX>'s memo has been reviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> believe
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">the other 80 percent</NUMEX> contains strong evidence of illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
fund-raising.

            The papers all report that despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s being invited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> to
appear before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> said he won't be coming.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> saying of any
appearance by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> that "It won't add any new information and can be put in
the category of a stunt." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockhart</ENAMEX> made this
comment not about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>'s plan to take testimony today
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perjurers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead lays out the political dilemma voting for impeachment
instead of censure presents to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Voting</ENAMEX> for impeachment will
probably produce a party line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> vote, which will impair the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s ability
to work with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> on other issues. And will make censure, which is more
likely than impeachment, look like a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> victory.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>'s purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> will rejoin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the
biggest pieces of the Standard Oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> broken up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX>, and will leave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> with control of vast oil
reserves and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> agrees with the
view expressed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-lead
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: the merger will cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10,000</NUMEX> jobs ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says it could be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX>).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" tells of what it calls the abortion debate's
cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">celebre</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> murder prosecution of an abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly twenty years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Steir</ENAMEX> is charged with knowing that he botched
an abortion but failing to have his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> admitted to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. Later that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, during the long drive back to her home, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> died. Given that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Medical Association</ENAMEX> found no basis for criminal charges, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> and many pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> fear the case is an example of what
may well become the newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who provide abortions:
selective criminal prosecution. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> quibble: The piece describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steir</ENAMEX> as a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> procedures." Why not write that he "had performed 40,000
abortions"?)

            The LAT front reports that new studies show that although <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> was
slow in coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is now the place on the planet
hardest hit by the disease. The infection rate there is now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> per
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> denial and ignorance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is widespread. In a survey
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">township</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soweto</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX>
believed they were at little or no risk, even though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly two-thirds</NUMEX> said
they never used a condom.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX>-point drop <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> keep the story off
the front page. Are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> getting the point that spilling a lot of ink
over a market going one way so soon after spilling an equal amount on a market
going the other way is more than a little ridiculous? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> can only
hope--and adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> should also quit announcing the raw point totals of
market moves in headlines. The percentage of the move is much more
meaningful.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> cites the doubling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharper Image</ENAMEX>
stock on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> as a symbol of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> excitement can be triggered by
Internet angles--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> says its web sales have tripled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>.
But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, web sales only account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
revenue. And this should indeed sober everybody up fast, because let's face it,
have you ever seen anybody actually buy something in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sharper Image</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> has gotten a lot of coverage about how he raised "soft money" for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>, but a small item <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Reliable Source</ENAMEX>" tells
you something about how he spends it. And it's not exactly saving the planet or
reinventing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> family holiday photo greeting card was billed
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110,000</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
