
   
   
      
         
            NetanYahoo!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace deal, signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine days</TIMEX> of intense
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' tone is cautiously optimistic: They concur that the
agreement--in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> cedes more <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and
gets promises of increased security--essentially retraces the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993 and 1995</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oslo</ENAMEX> accords. Nonetheless it lays groundwork, both personal and substantive,
for further talks.

            The deal was almost derailed at sunrise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> threatened not to sign the accord unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">released Jonathon Pollard</ENAMEX>, a well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. After several more
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of haggling, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> finally agreed to sign the accord, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s reported refusal to free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollard</ENAMEX> receded to a public announcement
that he would "review this matter seriously." (Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> TV and radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX> had already trumpeted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollard</ENAMEX>'s impending freedom. This infuriated
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> in
"unprintable terms.")

            Under the agreement, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> will cede <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">an additional 13 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>
Bank land to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and will release <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, will take concrete measures to combat terrorism: They
will expunge anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> clauses from their charter, jail <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>
wanted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> for terrorism, and crack down on illegal weaponry. In an
unusual twist (which has rattled some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> will monitor the
implementation of these provisions.

            The agreement sidesteps the most prickly points of contention, including the
status of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, border issues, and the fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>.
Nonetheless, it represents a bold political shift for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> in particular,
whose campaign platform opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> accords.

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" dimension of the agreement almost overshadows its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> turns somersaults because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> shook <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s hand
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> !!!--times. The physical tableau is striking: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, both "tall and hale" (thanks, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ), beside the ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> in
his inevitable headdress and frail, bald <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as always emerges the tireless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cynically</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perspicaciously</ENAMEX> says, "It was in the cards that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> would come to a wall, blame each other and call on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to save the ... talks." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, for his part, got the public
back-patting he craved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just 11 days</TIMEX> before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> elections.

            An interesting detail: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that the signing concluded just
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 minutes</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> time)-which sparked some controversy
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX> was already well underway. A prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rabbi</ENAMEX> voiced fears that the live broadcast would tempt even devout <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> to the
television.

            The LAT fronts the latest bad-novel twist in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s shooting of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> incumbent: the arrest of his shady campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Low Tax" Looper</ENAMEX>. Looper, who is already under investigation for theft,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peculiarly</ENAMEX> disappeared from public view after the murder, and was nabbed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. His name will remain on the ballot, but he will undoubtedly
be trounced by a write-in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>: the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burks</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Business</ENAMEX>" article says that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> are psyched for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2000</TIMEX>. Production is rising, and special <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year 2000 champagnes</ENAMEX> (complete
with special silk ribbons and red wax seals) are headed for the market. The
price for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> double-magnums auctioned off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for a charity
fundraiser: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500 to $4,000</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
