
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Shutdown</ENAMEX>? No, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Shut</ENAMEX> Up!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s partisan
spitballs: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> declared that congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are so
scandal-frenzied that that they haven't yet passed the appropriations measures
necessary to start the new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> immediately issued
retaliatory fire. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> report that the ranks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
without health insurance swelled by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Georges</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">100mph</NUMEX> whirl through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keys</ENAMEX>, a story also carried on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts. Despite 300
deaths in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> have yet been reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16.1%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43.4 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>) are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uninsured</ENAMEX>, the highest number since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> who are uninsured
held steady, while the middle class suffered a hit. This development is
surprising, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes, because the economy is so robust. Among the
possible explanations for the trend: Fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are on welfare, which is an
automatic gateway to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> coverage; small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, which dominate the
new-job sector, often do not provide health insurance; and costs associated
with health care and health insurance are increasing.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead (mirrored in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page article) reports
that an "invigorated" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> averted a federal shutdown--the new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
starts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>--by signing a temporary funding measure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> used
the opportunity to castigate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for putting "partisanship over progress,
politics over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" and dallying on important issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> quarterbacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> counter-attack, calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
remarks a "gratuitous slap" from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fundraiser</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>," a reference to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s imminent departure for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-day</TIMEX> fundraising trip.

            Acrimony spewed fast and fierce <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-lead peddles
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s telephone interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>
called for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to waive his attorney-client privilege and cooperate
with the impeachment inquiry. Gingrich lashed out against "the level of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrogance</ENAMEX> and duplicity by this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. To this day, they haven't told the
truth."

            In more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> developments, reported all around: Another batch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
documents is headed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Printing Office</ENAMEX> for release to the public
late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edited</ENAMEX> versions of the taped conversations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> will also be released sometime thereafter.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> both run inside stories, albeit with different
slants, on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s down<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">-to-the</NUMEX>-wire race for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s elections. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> emphasizes that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schroeder</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Social Democrats</ENAMEX>--have fundamentally
identical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX>. Since both pledge to continue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s strong social
programs, support the introduction of the euro, and implement tax reform, the
election may come down to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' personal opinions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>. But do the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> themselves know what they think? Not yet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that one in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> remain undecided. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> article sketches out
possible post-election coalition arrangements.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports inside that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> for a review of
all military Internet sites which are accessible publicly. While not catalyzed
by any particular event, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s action reflects a variety of security
concerns, including the online availability of personal data about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX>.

            Now, a royal example of how to decline a gift: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP Style</ENAMEX> "Names
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Faces"</ENAMEX> column reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auckland University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Injury Prevention Centre</ENAMEX>
donated a pair of panties to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX>. Not just any panties, mind
you--they had special hip-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX> inserts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 98-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Mother</ENAMEX>.
The gift was returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> with a note of polite refusal from the
Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>-in-waiting--thank you, but the gift was too much of a
"personal nature" to accept.

         
      
   
