
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Seizure</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times top non-local story report <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s arrest of former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' waning hopes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> will mean big gains for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> sense a pre-scandal atmosphere as
elections draw near. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> hopes of gaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> seats
and the magic number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> are slim. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> may even go on the
offensive-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> campaigns are waiting anxiously on poll results for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State candidate</ENAMEX> whose commercial attacks his opponent's
participation in the impeachment proceedings.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead story, which makes the fronts at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> weekend
papers, reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> arrested a convalescing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and will extradite him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
says that although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> has called for the release of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">82 year-old</TIMEX> former
military strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (and permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>) on grounds of diplomatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immunity</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> have "shrugged off the protests." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> has been
accused, among other things, of atrocities against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also notes the impending legal struggle's implications for
future attempts at international prosecution of human rights violators.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NYT Week in Review</ENAMEX> article examines the legitimacy of McCarthyism
in light of information recently recovered from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> records. Sensitive
documents dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign policy and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Project</ENAMEX> were
given to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> and may have accelerated the development of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> hypothesizes that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> had died
during his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> term, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> likely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> would have been front runners
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> Outlook piece says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> agree: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>
will not exist in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 to 30 years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s dissolution, while welcomed by
the culturally confident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celts</ENAMEX>, may produce an upper lip-testing identity
crisis among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, who lately find themselves better known for soccer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hooliganism</ENAMEX> and tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> than for bus stop queues and dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">handshakes</ENAMEX>.
While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ran a similar article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Wednesday</TIMEX>, the Outlook piece
delves deeper into the historical and political background of the crumbling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> features a special issue on the business
of sports. A story frets that media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>' purchases of sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> will
change the way games are played. Who'll stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anaheim Angels</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX>) from
forcing star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> to play when it will boost ratings on their own networks
or from altering rules to make sports more TV friendly?

            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Magazine</ENAMEX> stories explore fan loyalty. In one, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> sound off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, demanding cheaper tickets and more
dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> is noncommittal). In another, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knicks</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> complains that her courtside seats have shot up in price even as the team
declines. Other stories profile a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superagent</ENAMEX> winning mammoth contracts for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player clients</ENAMEX>, a rookie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> learning how to play the
endorsements game, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Stern</ENAMEX>, who micromanages the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league</ENAMEX>'s image, coordinating everything from media coverage to promotional
"sock giveaways."

         
      
   
