
   
   
      
         
            Still the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>

            
lead with the illegal gifts acquittal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX>, the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>. The story is also the top national
story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . Pictures of a happy Espy adorn the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> tops.

            Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Smaltz</ENAMEX> had prosecuted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> all
hold that the not guilty verdict <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> a growing consensus that the statute
under which the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smaltz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> operate must be at the very
least substantially amended. Referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX>'s own remarks, all the papers
raise the question of the ineffectiveness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIC</ENAMEX> by mentioning that the
non-conviction took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 million</NUMEX>. Nobody mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
is on the verge of a similar low-bang-for-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX>-buck result, but the thought is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inescapable</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Espy</ENAMEX> saying that when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> holds
hearings on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IC</ENAMEX> statute, "I would like to be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>."

            Since there is no dispute that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $35,000</NUMEX> worth of goods and
bennies from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> with interests before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> and since some of those
parties pleaded guilty to making illegal gifts, it's easy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to
wonder how the clean-sweep verdict was possible. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and LAT
do a good job of laying out the legal complications: both explain that the usual
rules don't apply if the gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giver</ENAMEX> has a prior personal relationship with the
giftee, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are still struggling with
whether or not the illegal gratuity statute requires a concrete quid pro quo
(either past or promised). There could have been another factor, which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> gets into far more than the others: race. The top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the
paper's story explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX> is black as were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> and that at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smaltz</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> that race could not be taken
into account in deciding the case. Which, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> adds, he declined to
do. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> doesn't mention the racial composition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> until the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-to-last paragraph. The WP waits until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the second-to-last</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> never mentions it.

            And none of the papers mentions the oddity of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>
leading a continent-hopping lifestyle that included trips to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Cowboy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bull</ENAMEX> home games and a taste for expensive luggage and
crystal.

            Word comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> intend to appear before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> to offer a vigorous defense of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, who
will not appear. The story off-leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , but in a sure sign of
scandal fatigue, it's below the fold at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and
runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> forgot one thing
while they were crafting their merger into the world's largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>: to
register their new corporate Internet address. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
discovered that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> with no connections to them had beaten
them to it. Such "cyber-squatting" is legal and can be quite profitable.
For instance, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX>
to secure "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Altavista</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>" from a squatter.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief economist</ENAMEX> of the
Conference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> could overtake the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> as the world's
strongest economy. She thinks that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy will continue to grow
healthily, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> has more unused capacity than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and its interest rates
are comparable or lower. The only big question is whether the move to the euro
common currency will create service jobs, the sector where <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> still clearly
lags behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>

            If you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal has dragged on and on, consider this inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s estate demanded up to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$213 million</NUMEX> in compensation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>-related seizure of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s tapes and papers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> compared the value of the tapes to that
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gutenberg Bible and the Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
