
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bare Market</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>'s decision to grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lawyers <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two 9 AM-to-midnight</TIMEX>
sessions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to make their case against impeachment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times puts that story on the front but leads with the ever-worsening
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> trip. The big bone of contention is whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
is abiding by its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wye</ENAMEX> promise to free <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>. Another
is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>-ruled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX> will have the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> trappings of a visit to an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with upcoming statistics from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX> suggesting
that the food-poisoning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria E. coli</ENAMEX>--usually associated with inadequately
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cooked hamburgers</ENAMEX>--may be causing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice as much</NUMEX> illness as previously thought.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead is another scientifically based <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
life: New computer-assisted studies match up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> left at violent crime scenes
surprisingly often with the DNA of known burglars, indicating that contrary to
traditional dogma, burglary is a good predictor of violent crime.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads communicate almost exactly the same
information: The tart letters back and forth between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> The likely schedule of events, culminating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>'s judgement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor vote will be close, but
will produce an impeachment bill. Both say that until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> the impeachment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tide</ENAMEX> had ebbed considerably but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s answers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX>
questions made it rise again. Both have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Shay</ENAMEX>'s quote about
those answers: "I mean he still doesn't get it....He still doesn't tell the
truth." Both have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> saying that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> votes to impeach, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on trial quickly. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories are near <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> because they both reflect the standard
no-shoe-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather m.o.</ENAMEX> for many a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monday Washington story: Watch the Sunday chat</ENAMEX>
shows.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> follows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s lead about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> ignoring warnings
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> now implicated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> deaths with a top-front effort today
revealing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> responsible for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s largest study
of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, which included <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, was at that time also
on the payroll of the drug's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>. The
paper says that according to legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, this seems to be a crime under
federal conflict-of-interest law.

            The "cover story" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section checks in on what
happened when management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yoda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Covey</ENAMEX> merged his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> with rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quest</ENAMEX>. According to the paper, there's hardly been one effective habit on
display, much less <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock is but <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three dollars</NUMEX> above its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-year-old</TIMEX> initial offering price, and sales of its business consulting
products and services are flat. Meanwhile, there have been time-consuming
wrangles between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> over such significa as the dress code and the
company logo. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> quoted sums up the situation this way: "It's proof
that the great business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gurus</ENAMEX> know how to run everyone's business but their
own."

            The WP front features a story about Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivalists</ENAMEX>. In the
fourteenth paragraph, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> stops to explain something: "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> stands
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'year</NUMEX>,' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2K</ENAMEX> is shorthand for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>."

            Today, some poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> actually) at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has to write about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Power</ENAMEX>'s
expected announcement that it has agreed to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PacifiCorp</ENAMEX>, yadda yadda,
but elsewhere in the paper, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> lucks out. Today, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asra Q. Nomani</ENAMEX> is an island of lust in a sea of lucre, filing
a long, long, look at the slow, slow-sex industry known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tantra</ENAMEX>. There are
some of the usual trappings of a financial story, but most of the multiples
here aren't P/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Es</ENAMEX>. For instance: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Known as 'Shara</ENAMEX>,' Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seabrook</ENAMEX> slips off a
white-gauze sarong from over her white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-string bikini as she climbs on a
massage table to straddle the table with Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s live-in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>
Sarver, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, a Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>, who sits naked, his face <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just inches</NUMEX> from hers."
Who cares what the market does <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?

         
      
   
