
   
   
      
         
            Newtered

            Election postmortems lead all around. In the aftermath of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> midterm
election since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> gained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> seats, the
headlines stress <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> disarray. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times top says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> "Takes Stock of Losses." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">header</ENAMEX> says a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP Shake-Up</ENAMEX> is Possible"--right next to a big picture of a
befuddled-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> juxtaposed with the caption, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Will Gingrich Survive?</ENAMEX>"
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
big type says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scramble Over Blame</ENAMEX>," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> sums things up similarly: "Shaken
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> Count Losses, Debate Blame." (Question to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's photo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>: Was it really necessary at this very satisfying moment for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, to run a picture of him that suggests he's having cramps? Didn't he
smile at least once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>?)

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the single biggest lesson learned from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s
vote is, in the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page wash-up, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impeachment</ENAMEX> isn't
a winning agenda." And the problem, at least in the eyes of some of the more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stalwart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement conservatives</ENAMEX> quoted in the coverage, was that, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
side, there wasn't enough of any other agenda. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX> complaining, "We just ran one of the least
ideological campaigns we've run in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>...." and a similar complaint from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Tate</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
points out the dilemma the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> face if they respond by simply
ideologically souping up, with this quote from a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>: "We've got to reach out and have more than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> white males
running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Republican Party</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> pass along a classic non-concession concession from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>. The
Times version: "I mean, I totally underestimated the degree to which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would just get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sick</ENAMEX> of 24-hour-a-day talk television and talk radio and
then the degree to which this whole scandal became just sort of disgusting by
sheer repetition." In other words, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX>, in
a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section piece, it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s fault. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> goes
on to resurrect a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> quote from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> in which he said he
would never again as long as he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> make a speech without commenting on
the scandal. And then for good measure, he quotes conservative muckety-muck
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>'s assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s analysis: "mind-boggling." It's that
sort of chagrin that's behind the rumblings of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> coup all the papers
report.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also say that an immediate consequence of the vote is at least a
drastically scaled-down impeachment inquiry. They all report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> is
now leaning towards having his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> call only one
witness--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a separate article about this as
its off-lead.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says look for a quick negotiated resolution of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
flatly asserts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> is now so slim that "there is
little chance the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">218</NUMEX> votes required for impeachment can be assembled."

            The other big political story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> is the election in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro wrestler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Body</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>. The political
upstart garners front-pagers at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and an inside
piece at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>'s out-of-the-blue arrival on the scene is
energizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> in ways not seen since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> candidacy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>, who will now become the
highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> for campaign money,
but was turned down. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>'s ad campaign was
managed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hillsman</ENAMEX>, who did the ads for the previous title-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> for
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shocking Minnesota</ENAMEX> Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">By A Former Wrestler</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Wellstone</ENAMEX>'s upset
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> win of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> seat. (A previous pre-election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ex-Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seal Ventura</ENAMEX> barely mentioned that there has been some controversy
about his military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. This would be a fine time to elaborate.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> effort is accompanied by a color picture of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">governor-elect</ENAMEX> trouncing a previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, by stomping him into the
ropes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> piece also includes the sounds-pretty-right assessment
of that astute political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulk Hogan</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>'s victory proves that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want a real
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in power to lead, not a play plastic puppet like other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
