
   
   
      
         
            Quotations from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s
suggestion in congressional testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that he foresees a cut next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> in the fed funds rate, which determines the cost of money throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">puts Greenspan</ENAMEX> on its front in column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>.) The big story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> has publicly rejected
what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> calls a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">plea-bargain</TIMEX>-style deal" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> off formal impeachment proceedings in favor of some quicker but lesser
punishment such as censure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts also report on
these developments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with the pledge by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> that he would sign a nuclear test ban treaty within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>, a
story no one else runs on their front page. But there is a chicken-and-egg
context--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> goes on to explain that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> says it will sign
only if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> lifts the economic sanctions imposed on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
after their surprise nuclear tests <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last May</TIMEX>, but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will not do so
until <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> makes a formal decision to not test its nukes. The story does go
on to point out some hopeful developments in the relationship between the two
rival A-powers: at meetings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX> agreed
to resume high-level talks about the region in dispute between them, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>,
and also to set-up a communications "hot line."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> rates is like all the others you've
ever read, with this difference: it's about rates going down, not up. The
likely move is said to be in response to what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls a "drumbeat
of pleas" from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> (and, it could be added, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>). The papers
say that the cut is likely to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> point, down to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.25 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes big-shot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Sinai</ENAMEX>'s prediction that the
upcoming cut is but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of many. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> points out however, that
there do not appear to be any similar coordinated cuts forthcoming from the
central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s leading economies. By the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says a
survey it took among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> rates the chances of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> recession
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> as one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that during closed-door meetings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> signaled
his intent to expand any impeachment inquiry into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>, campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> abuse and technology transfers to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> immediately
responded, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> by accusing congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of trying
to prolong the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter so as to maximize gains in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> describes the atmosphere around the scandal as "escalating
partisan tension."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has been running a good "first draft of
history" series <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX> on the current global economic crisis. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
installment, about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missteps</ENAMEX>, compares the ineffective <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> aid to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> to the fatal mistakes of the "best and the brightest" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, even
going so far as summoning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert McNamara</ENAMEX> to explicitly make the
comparison.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front (and an inside story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) reports that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> made a rare and particularly vigorous campaign
appearance on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> senatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schumer</ENAMEX>,
during which she characterized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX> as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clone</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says that the appearance leaves little doubt that in
the current campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> will fill the role that "in normal times"
would have been filled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reports that at times, the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lady</ENAMEX> appeared "dazed and distant," especially when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> standing directly
in front of her twice tried to ask her a question.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 60</NUMEX> leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>
from around the world have signed a petition defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
against "inquisitorial harassment by a fanatical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> with unlimited
power." Signatories include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmond Tutu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Garcia Marquez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s coverage reminds one that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> maintains the mystique of
his brilliance by a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delphic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vocabulary</ENAMEX> favoring oblique metaphor over
definite policy pronouncements. (Or as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> puts it, "Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>...as usual left himself some wiggle room.") <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s testimony was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">epic Chauncey Gardiner</ENAMEX>, featuring talk of "rain drops," "storm clouds," and
"contagion." As a result, in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> article about his testimony the
directly quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> is almost always meaningless without gobs of
explanatory text. For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s comment that
"We have to bring the existing instabilities to a level of stability reasonably
shortly. I think we know where we have to go. I do not think we underestimate
the severity of the problems with which we are dealing," and then says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> widely took this as indicating the quarter-point rate cut. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s statement, "If we give indications to
world financial markets that the fiscal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>...is being dismantled, I
think there is a price to pay," should be translated as warning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that
"eating into the [budget] surplus with either tax cuts or spending increases
could rattle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
