
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Medium Performances</ENAMEX>

            The grinding on of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s impeachment hearings
continues to dominate. The coverage focuses on the multi-media-illustrated
presentations made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Schippers, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbe Lowell</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HJC</ENAMEX> is expected to vote
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> flatly assume that a censure proposal will be
defeated and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> article of impeachment will pass. It remains
unclear whether an additional censure measure will be put before the full
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> Everybody has the detail that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> has sent out a letter to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> advising them that the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> will probably begin reviewing
the impeachment matter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Thursday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts all run
stories describing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s low-profile campaign to work on wavering
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> are
considering whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should make a fresh public comment on the
matter and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says there is "speculation" (not the best phrase--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s
entitled to know whose speculation we're talking about here) that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might even make a deeper public apology before leaving for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.

            The papers note that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> used snippets from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case deposition and his appearance before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> grand jury
as well as from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> tapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees
the qualities of a campaign ad in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX>'s playing of a montage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s testimony before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>, in which he was shown to frequently respond
to questions with "I cannot recall."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> note that in defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX>
pointed out that impeachment wasn't wielded when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> suspended
habeas corpus, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> misled the public about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lend-Lease</ENAMEX>, nor against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> in connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and WP
report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowell</ENAMEX> also observed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> tapes showed the president
orchestrating a massive cover-up using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, whereas the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> tapes showed "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> talking about going
shopping." Now, of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> tapes also contain much trivia and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky-Tripp</ENAMEX> tapes also contain more serious matters. Shouldn't the papers
point this out?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schippers</ENAMEX>' presentation is seen as harder-edged. It's noted by both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> that he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> he'd found evidence of as yet
unspecified further criminal actions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> but left it out of
his presentation because of time constraints (says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) or because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> asked him to (says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ). In response, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , committee <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoe Lofgren</ENAMEX> said this tactic was "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCarthyite</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">both Lofgren</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX> had this
reaction.

            It wouldn't be far-fetched to suppose that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> was ultimately
behind <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> impeachment stalwart Bob
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> was a keynote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> at a meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of</ENAMEX>
Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens</ENAMEX>, which views interracial marriage as genocide against
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communists</ENAMEX>. In a letter, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> declares the accusations
unfounded. The source of the allegation is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dershowitz</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and an inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story each report that despite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>' findings that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> should remit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for misusing party funds for ad
purchases in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> voted unanimously against requiring such a payback.
The papers opine that the climb-down is an invitation to further questionable
use of ad money in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next presidential</TIMEX> race.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a story inside saying that a new study by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guttmacher Institute</ENAMEX> has determined that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">650</NUMEX> "intact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dilation</ENAMEX> and extraction" abortions, procedures where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is partially
delivered and then aborted. This is the procedure called by abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>
"partial birth abortion." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> avoids taking sides in the debate
simply in its choice of nomenclature by identifying the procedure as the
"late-term method that anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> call partial-birth abortion." Since
it's not possible to be partially born, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> prefers "partial
delivery abortion." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes on to note that the number of
non-surgical, medical abortions--achieved by taking a drug like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU-486</ENAMEX>--is
rising rapidly, now taking place at the rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 8,000</NUMEX> per year.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hewitt</ENAMEX> will appear on the show to apologize for a
previous broadcast of footage about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> drug trade (purchased from a
documentary-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>) that is now known to be fake, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> playing drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and a drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lair</ENAMEX> turning out to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film-maker</ENAMEX>'s hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
