
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s push for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">new International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> strategy to avert further global economic
turmoil. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's lead forecasts that during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> proceedings, more grounds for the impeachment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will be added to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> counts currently pending. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the story that preoccupies everyone's front: the
latest act in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> circus, namely the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4610</NUMEX> pages of evidence released
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>.

            The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">three-volume</ENAMEX> set of documents includes excerpts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s
taped conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and grand jury testimony from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vernon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettie Currie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX>, and other key figures. With so many fresh
details, it is hardly surprising that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> emphasizes a different aspect.
All papers note, however, that the new evidence does more to disclose the
details we've all been wondering about than to substantively change the
investigation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also agree that the tapes portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> as a manipulator, which
plays into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> hands. (From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> analysis: The "friendship"
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> seems "less a real friendship than a temporary
alliance between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> who often do not even
seem to like each other very much.") The LAT highlights the improbable
assertions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, that despite hiding
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval</ENAMEX> Office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> during one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> encounters
(according to a synopsis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s account), she remained uncertain about the
nature of the encounters: "I had a feeling, but I had nothing to base it on
other than a gut." The WP fronts a story about strenuous efforts by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to settle the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> testified. As all papers note, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> strongly denied that his
job-search on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s behalf was an attempt to get her to lie in the Jones
case.

            Citing "an informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>" throughout, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Schippers</ENAMEX>' new impeachment counts against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will involve accusations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> tampering, obstruction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>, and making false statements under oath (as distinguished from more
serious and difficult-to-prove perjury charges). Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> counts already set
forth, one which relates to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege will be dropped, because
Schippers views privilege as the domain of the judicial not the legislative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branch</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schippers</ENAMEX>' presentation will be countered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">investigator Abbe Lowell</ENAMEX>, who will downplay the gravity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
offense.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead story, also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , describes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposal that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> distribute preemptive emergency lines of credit
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that show relative economic stability but nonetheless could
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">succumb</ENAMEX> to panic swings. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> observes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "hasty
presentation . . . suggested the idea had been cobbled together
quickly"--perhaps to deflect attention from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s new releases.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
words came on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> as the release of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> report showing
that fewer jobs were created and unemployment rose incrementally during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>--developments which raise some fears that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> malaise is
spreading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> proposal contains a number of weaknesses,
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> point out. First, these "lines of credit" are as-yet vaguely
defined and may not differ significantly from current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> policy. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> and
more crucially, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> needs to collect its money before it can activate such
a plan. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> (among other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">debtor nations</ENAMEX>) still owes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18 billion</NUMEX>.
Approval for the payment is mired in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are staunchly
opposed to additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> funding.

            And now for some comic relief: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Arts</ENAMEX> section reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> literary great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel Proust</ENAMEX> has just joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asterix</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tintin</ENAMEX>. His <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-volume classic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Remembrance</TIMEX> of Things Past has been remade
into a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> comic book, which has been selling like mad(eleines). All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">first-run</ENAMEX> copies were scooped up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>. This naturally has sparked a
heated debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, where attempts to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">democratize Proust</ENAMEX>" affront <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
custodianship of high culture.

            Anyone sending mail to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is out of luck. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front page
reports that almost all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s mail service has shut down because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">railway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> are demanding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX> in back pay from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>. Predictably, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> is owed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately</NUMEX> that same
amount by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, it's email time!

         
      
   
