
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Errin</ENAMEX>'

            The congressional election aftermath produces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s two lead stories.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times go with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>'s submission to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> questions about his conduct in matters
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The move, which once upon a time would have been seen as dynamite, is
now widely viewed as a pop-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> in the hands of chastened <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> looking
for an impeachment exit strategy that won't shoot them in the other foot. And
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead, the electoral shove has come to putsch, as various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> maneuver to topple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>. (An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> story the
WP honors inside.)

            The papers report that the questions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> focus more
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conduct after attention was directed towards his
possible relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> than on the relationship itself. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>'s cover letter asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to respond in writing
and under oath by signing an attached affidavit. The questions range from
asking whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> took an oath to defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, to whether he
ever gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> cigars. All the papers either quote or describe some of the
questions, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , fulfilling its tradition of supplying primary
sources whenever possible, runs the entire list of them in a separate article. Even though
everybody's story makes it clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> was asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to admit
or deny the details in the list, unlike the other papers, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">House Panel Asks Clinton to Admit Lying Under Oath</ENAMEX>,"
makes it seem that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was left without a choice.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> also announced his revised plans for substantially downsized
impeachment hearings. His main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, who will be
called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 19th</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> developments taken together
"raise the likelihood that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could be disposed of
soon." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> somehow keep straight faces while they pass along <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>'s whoppers about all this: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The new shape of the hearings has nothing to
do with the election results, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He's calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> because "He's someone
everybody wants to hear from."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Livingston</ENAMEX> has in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX> been conducting a
telephone campaign that could lead to him running against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> saying there are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> besides himself who have flatly decided not to vote for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>--no small matter given the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s reduced edge of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> seats. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, the paper explains, will cast secret ballots for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 18th</TIMEX>, with the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voting on the matter in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> all front the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins</ENAMEX> are about to publish reports of separate successful experiments in which cells culled from the very
early stages of a human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">embryo</ENAMEX> have, in a test tube, been grown into
undifferentiated cells that could be used to grow various kinds of human
tissue. The breakthrough is thought to pave the way for implanting cells
developed to have certain healthy properties into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> as a way of
treating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> or defects. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> bring to the fore
ethical questions the new science is sure to raise: issues of genetic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineering</ENAMEX> and harvesting embryos.

            Everybody reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Labor Statistics</ENAMEX> accidentally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prematurely</ENAMEX> posted on its web site its information about the number of jobs
created <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. A surfing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> shared the inside scoop with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>,
thereby roiling the financial markets for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> sees a trend, reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just last Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> web site accidentally disseminated false test
election results. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also takes note of a model of Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>: the dissemination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report.

            The USAT front section "cover story" examines a classic example of
unintended consequences. The profusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> and customized license
plates may delight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, but it's frustrating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, who say the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,800</NUMEX>-some special plates make identifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> much harder than it used to be.
The paper mentions a case in which a robbery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> remembered the getaway car
sported a tag with mountains on it, which would have ordinarily have been a
great tip--except that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now have plates like that. And don't forget,
the paper points out, about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, issue
the license <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plates</ENAMEX>, meaning that any given sequence of letters and numbers
could be shared by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX> reports that once again "civilian" political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX> who sent him their election predictions did a far better job than all
those "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>" on TV. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Nearly 20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamen's</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX>
predicted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> gains in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> of them were only off by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> seat
in their total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> calls. The occupations of the best guessers
included: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Dept.</ENAMEX> program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>,
ex-congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Marshal</ENAMEX>'s office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>, and--thank
God--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
