
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hoffa Gets His Due</ENAMEX>(s)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James P. Hoffa</ENAMEX>'s victory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>' presidential election.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with an in-depth look at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s burgeoning high-tech industry and goes with the Hoffa election as its
top non-local story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> of approving
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> linked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> deaths since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX>-educated labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffa</ENAMEX> takes over as
an election that was eventually overturned because of his opponent's corrupt
campaign financing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffa</ENAMEX>'s most recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">legendary James R. Hoffa</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $6 million</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 4 years</TIMEX> he
campaigned for the leadership position. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the union
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, down from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.3 million</NUMEX> during the seventies, but it
still holds considerable influence over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> industry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT Sunday Report</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> approved a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> used to treat
adult-onset <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> despite "explicit warnings of danger" from within the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>. Even after the product was recalled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX> it remained--and
still remains--available by prescription in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rezulin</ENAMEX>,
can cause liver damage that has led to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> deaths in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. Part of the outrage over the drug's availability stems from the numerous
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> also available to treat the same symptoms. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX> notes, "Nobody is
going to suffer if [<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rezulin</ENAMEX>] is taken away."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX> held elections for local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headline
calls a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Enthusiastic Step Towards Democracy</ENAMEX>." The voting was peaceful,
turnout was high, and the mood was optimistic throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has promised a full transition to democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> after years
of military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> piece reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justices</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Kennedy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Breyer</ENAMEX> spoke out publicly against what they perceive as threats to
judicial independence. The unusual move was a reaction to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who threaten to impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> based on their rulings and to
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> who attempt to influence elected state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>.

            A depressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Magazine</ENAMEX> cover story follows the struggle of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> trying to save their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Canavan disease</ENAMEX>. The parents
desperately lobby the cautious and slow-moving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Drug Administration</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> to approve experimental gene therapy, but when
the treatment comes it does little. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is still alive but slowly
dying.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Gore Sr.</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 90</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tipper</ENAMEX> were at the bedside of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> when
he died peacefully of natural causes in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carthage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Wynn</ENAMEX>'s considerable
clout in both the gaming and political arenas. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wynn</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirage Resorts</ENAMEX>,
employs a full-time tele-survey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> that polls <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> on numerous
political issues. He then shares this information, along with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of dollars, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> most sympathetic to his cause. The piece
says that his methods are successful: many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nevadans</ENAMEX> consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wynn</ENAMEX> "the most
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
