
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Augusto Justice</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the ruling by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> must remain under arrest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
subject to extradition elsewhere because his status as an ex-head of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> does
not confer legal immunity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with another in its series of important stories about the
abuse of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison system</ENAMEX>--this one reporting an
investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s conclusion that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX> fatal or serious inmate
shootings at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s most notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> were not justified. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kevorkian</ENAMEX>'s arrest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in connection with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euthanasia</ENAMEX> broadcast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>" makes the fronts of the majors
putting out editions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Lords</ENAMEX> ruled that a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
state, unlike a sitting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, has but limited immunity: he or she can be forced
into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to answer for actions that are not part of the legitimate function
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. This finding prompted, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to observe that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is therefore vulnerable to prosecution
only because he stepped down in favor of a democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. But the
crucial ruling, both leads report, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3-2</ENAMEX> decision that torture and
hostage taking are not legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> functions. Therefore, they
explain, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> matter will be disposed of in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>
presses its extradition request, unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Straw</ENAMEX>, decides
otherwise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the early betting is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straw</ENAMEX> will not
intervene. On the other hand, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>, appreciative of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stand</ENAMEX> during the
Falklands <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>, has already publicly appealed for his release.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> ruling is a watershed in human rights law,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says it marks a potentially significant broadening of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">powers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to pursue those charged with crimes against humanity. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> refers to the development as "a wake-up call to tyrants around the
world."

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> claims to have presided over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120-plus</NUMEX> mercy suicides, in
this most recent case, he directly caused death. And indeed, as the papers
point out, he openly admits he took this extra step to encourage a legal
showdown. The papers report that in filing a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree murder case against
Kevorkian, the county <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> said that the consent of the dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was no
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX>. In a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story about the legal ins and outs of
the case, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are quoted making the following argument against a
murder verdict: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder</ENAMEX> requires malice, the disregard for human life. Therefore
a homicide undertaken out of regard for life cannot be murder. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and LAT make it clear that it's not just murder at issue,
reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> is also being charged with violating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>'s
brand-new ban on assisted suicide.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> run inside stories reporting that according to
a human rights group, a recent crackdown by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregations</ENAMEX> that
do not formally accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has resulted in the
arrest of seventy church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>, shot while fleeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, is now the subject of a nationwide manhunt.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says another was beaten with a wet rope and a nightstick, and
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are using heavy fines as a prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> in this campaign
of suppression. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also usefully points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> recently signed a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> document protecting religious freedom.

            Do you feel the need for a new government sex scandal? Relax, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> has
dropped anchor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , following up a story in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> , report that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> admiral has been
accused of improperly steering military contracts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> owned by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he was committing adultery with. Although the admiral is named in both
stories, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is not. This seems unfair.

            A story inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> may not be convicted in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> of illegally recording her conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. First,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> requires showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> knew she was breaking the law when she
taped, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s immunity agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> means the tapes
she gave him cannot be used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. So he has to find other
copies.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story running in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who suffered a heart attack became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on a
domestic flight to have his life saved by a defibrillator, a device only
recently available on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> serves on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Public</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Commission</ENAMEX>, where he has promoted the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">installation</ENAMEX> in office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> of...defibrillators.

         
      
   
