
   
   
      
         
            Getting DeLayed

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s string of moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> taking pro-impeach stances leads
all around. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> quote a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>'s reaction:
"The bottom's falling out." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is now a "near certainty."
The bunker's eye view that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times gets is, "If it isn't over, it's pretty close to over." Taking
account of the latest vote announcements, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> both
calculate that to stave off impeachment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would need to win over nearly
all of the undecided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
says he'd have to win over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspaper</ENAMEX> also carries
this assessment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Friedan</ENAMEX> of who's behind the push to impeachment: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
bunch of dirty old white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>."

            The consensus is that the most damaging announcement for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Quinn</ENAMEX>, who had previously said he would oppose impeachment. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> agrees, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX>'s stance was "most crushing." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LAT</ENAMEX> explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX> was more than just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote, because he had been
working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to try to persuade fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> to oppose
impeachment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> attributes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX>'s unanticipated change of heart
to arm-twisting by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>.

            The papers describe various last minute scenarios being floated at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, none of them having yet obtained presidential imprimatur: a televised
address, and various alternative punishments, including the proposal of a
post-impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> censure made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has little appetite for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
deal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> makes this a little more plain, quoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>'s harsh comment about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>: "Those who have the power make the decisions.
Those who had the power, but lost it, have no right even to kibitz." There's
also the idea floated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Castle</ENAMEX> for censure plus a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX>
fine. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeez</ENAMEX>, why didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> ever think like this? They could have stuck
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> for the bill for the extra <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> he gave us.)

            The LAT front runs a piece about a comment made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> while
he was still in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that has caused an uproar in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.
The episode is also covered inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said that he'd
been moved by the tears of three little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who begged him to
help free their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, imprisoned for murdering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>, as he also was by
meeting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of slain <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> exploded in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condemnation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> was stupefied by the comment. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>'s
observation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> seems particularly insightful: the root of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">firestorm</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> are sensing that for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
eyes the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> are now being viewed as on their level.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial page is given over to a full-page argument for voting no on impeachment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
favors censure over impeachment because it says the latter in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s case
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">assaults the Constitution</ENAMEX> in that it threatens what it calls "the jewel in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy," an orderly succession of presidential power.
Meanwhile, opposite the editorial page (yes, that's what "op-ed" stands for),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>, noting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s recent comment that he could not, even to
avoid impeachment, say he lied under oath, because that would be a lie, has a
question: Why stop lying now, when a lie could save your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presidency?</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers' advice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> goes just a touch further. Why not make the
following confession to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everything</ENAMEX> I say about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter is a lie." This statement if true, is false and if false, is
true, and hence has befuddled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wittgenstein</ENAMEX>. It
would be great fun to see, say, an ex-exterminator from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> take a crack at
it.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s WSJ front page offers a lengthy example of what the "free" in free press means. If you
were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an unmarried forty</NUMEX>-something very beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesley Friedman</ENAMEX>
who had cashed out her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> temp business for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21 million</NUMEX> and had moved to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm Beach</ENAMEX> but couldn't get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, you could pay for one of those tiny
little ads in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> . But ugh,
then you'd be getting asked out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant professors</ENAMEX> or public interest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who didn't make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> somewhere. Far better to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>
write an endless front-page piece on you, describing your new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> dating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outfits</ENAMEX>, your likes and dislikes and the earning power of your ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX>. But
it's not clear how much mail you're going to get from the article. After all,
you let them quote your theory of dating: "The cost of buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> dinner at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> she prefers is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $150</NUMEX>. 'A high-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> probably costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> per, ah, an encounter, whatever you call
it....These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are getting off cheap' if they expect sex after just one or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dates." Good luck, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesley</ENAMEX>--you've put the high back in high
maintenance.

         
      
   
