
   
   
      
         
            Keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abreast of the Voters</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX>'s elections dominate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with its latest poll indicating that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> are too close to call.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with a nationwide look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' last-minute attempts to motivate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, in a campaign that at this late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says, still
lacks a national theme. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the last frantic hours
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s gubernatorial and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> gives much of its front to election
coverage as well, but leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>' threat to do battle with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that according to its plus-or-minus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> poll of
1,105 likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX> said they preferred the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> in their local
congressional race and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX> preferred the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> is
thrilled to note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> runs the preceding information about margin of
error and sample size in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first few paragraphs</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead also comments that polling shows many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> to be very close. Besides the very tight
congressional races, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> races (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> gubernatorial contests
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>) could easily come out either way. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
passes along some of the more incendiary <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-minute</TIMEX> phone, radio, and leaflet
election messages such close races give rise to. Such as this from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> radio appeal targeted at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>: "When you don't vote, you let
another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> explode."

            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> where media-based campaigns are the standard, even the LAT
seems stunned that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s two senatorial and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> gubernatorial candidates
threw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> into last-minute ads. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX>, spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> just for TV time on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The other major effort seems to be going into attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>--all but
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> "publicly sought divine intervention."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>, having tried to show the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> he's serious about
upholding his end of the just-concluded peace accords by arresting scores of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, is now, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , being threatened in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaflet</ENAMEX> with violent retaliation. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> pass at the story, running inside, includes this not-quite-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda</ENAMEX>
warning from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s chief of police, "If anyone from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Qassam Brigades</ENAMEX> [of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>] gets near a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, shoot him in the legs!" Meanwhile, the
Times adds in a separate story (an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agence France-Presse</ENAMEX> dispatch) that,
not to be out-thugged, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX>- and Iranian-backed terrorist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization, Hezbollah</ENAMEX>, speaking at a rally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX>, told a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> that
getting rid of the peace deal requires killing not just <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">settlers</ENAMEX>, but also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the LAT front <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> warnings to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
that it could face a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> or allied military strike if it doesn't reconsider
its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> decision to shut down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>'s weapons inspection effort. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs the story inside.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front section "cover story" is a close look at the growing
problem of Web sites that sell prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> to loggers-on. The
paper says that medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> in every state view the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> as illegal or at
least not meeting accepted standards of medical care. The story reports one
countermeasure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX> has put into play: the
establishment of a "teaser sting site" (one of a dozen relating to various
spurious health claims and get-rich-quick schemes) that promotes fake impotence
and sex aids but leads to nothing more than a warning that such e-commerce is
dubious. Unlike a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> on sex sites, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
story contains no Web addresses. A policy change?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX> reports that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>'s race in Storey
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, a much-prized voting bloc is working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. And he means
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brothels</ENAMEX> staffed by a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">195</NUMEX>
licensed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Magazine</ENAMEX> cover story articulating
how the national conversation has been utterly taken over by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of
the comfortable, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> offers a front-page story on a
previously unappreciated grave national crisis: the difficulties involved in
shopping for furniture. The story's hard-luck cases include:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> car and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armani</ENAMEX> suits but shabby furniture, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
was able to drive home her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Grand Cherokee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> she saw it, but
twice has had to wait twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> for furniture ordered at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX>, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management consultant</ENAMEX> who despite having hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decorator</ENAMEX> and ordering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX>
worth of furniture including a hand-carved entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, has still only
received one of the pieces. There is no indication in the story that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't afford furniture and don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> to put it in.

         
      
   
