
   
   
      
         
            State Bars None

            None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> share the same lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with the imminence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s forces
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, a story everybody else runs inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the opening on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s national DNA database, which is
also on the USAT front. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX>'s plans to dramatically
shorten the government approval process for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, which could mean much faster
access to new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>, a story on nobody else's front. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s latest poll results
indicating that in the wake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s vote to start an impeachment
investigation, public support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-held <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> has dropped considerably, most of all among likely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">independents</ENAMEX>. The poll also indicates that support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> is up. The poll also finds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, now with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>
percent approval rating, is currently more popular than before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
vote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the numbers offer hope to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> of avoiding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment in favor of some lesser punishment.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are scheduled to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> to approve an order that gives allied military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> to order airstrikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. This means apparently,
that air strikes could come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as today</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, says the paper, in a
last-ditch attempt to avert bombing, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> is still
holding talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> demands <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> is pressing, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , include the withdrawal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and allowing
humanitarian aid into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> issue making the talks sticky, says the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , is how to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX> from taking advantage of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> show of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            The despair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> have targeted is
everywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's on-the-ground front section "cover story." A woman
refugee gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kelley</ENAMEX> a lock of hair she says she took from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-month-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">godchild</ENAMEX>, slain in a massacre by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
"Please give it to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," she tells him. "Maybe he'll decide to save the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." In light of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator mythology</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, one
hopes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> checked this story out before repeating it, but if so,
heaven help us.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> DNA database, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explains, is actually a
computerized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of the fifty databases set up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> holds the promise of reducing rape and other crimes by catching
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">criminals</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> does an excellent job of canvassing the
issues raised by the database, which include: What types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> should be
required to give samples? Should mass screening be allowed? The story points
out that the established and quite successful DNA system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> has opted
for a wide range of criminal samples as well as mass screening. It is
undeniably curious though, that when the paper turns to explaining how <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> can
be used forensically, the discussion is completely generic and never mentions
the most famous unchallenged DNA identification ever: that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
via the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> dress stain.

            The LAT front details a concrete consequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>'s decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to block funding for the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar association</ENAMEX>: no
one is disciplining the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s negligent or dishonest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, now has, says the paper, a backlog of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,556</NUMEX> unresolved complaints
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. Before the funding shut-down, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. Now it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> howled in protest when this column stated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>
would have been a violator of a bill working its way through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that
criminalizes making obscenities available on the Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are
absolutely right: It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> of the obscenities of
the criminal referral. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>.

            The papers have consistently savaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> stance of
apologizing without admitting. But isn't that what's going on in the following
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s Note" from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WP ?</ENAMEX> "The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 20</TIMEX>, 'Rugrats' comic
strip's depiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worshipers</ENAMEX> and use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaddish</ENAMEX> were
inappropriate and should not have appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington Post</ENAMEX>. We have
expressed our strong disapproval to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX>, which produces the comic, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creators Syndicate</ENAMEX>, which distributes it. Our comics screening process failed
in this instance, and we apologize to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who were offended." Note the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonesque</ENAMEX> use of "inappropriate" without ever saying what was wrong with the
strip. And what, pray tell, does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s "comics screening process" screen
*for*?

         
      
   
