
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Can't Need</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s promise to withdraw his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> in
the face of threatened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead covers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' latest moves in its
attempts to arrive at a budget, stressing the tentative approval by key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s requested <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18 billion</NUMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>. The death of the gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who was kidnapped and beaten in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> grabs
front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , and is the subject
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's lead editorial, which points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>, like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, has no hate-crime laws.

            The papers report that even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> agreed to back out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> authorized airstrikes against him that could begin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX>
if he doesn't actually do that. They also report that in the meantime, about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> airborne and ground-based allied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>--including some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>--will verify
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> have indeed pulled back, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> to
return to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. If this doesn't happen, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> air plan to be
implemented would begin with cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and progress to a full bombing
campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that each stage of the plan could be flown only
after being approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassadors</ENAMEX> (something the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says is
not clear) and that only military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> would be targeted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
account stresses more than the others the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> to the
airstrike plan.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have extracted something in
return for infusion of fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> billions into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> coffers: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a promise by
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">IMF</ENAMEX> contributors to push the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to require above-market rates and
reasonably short repayment periods for its loans (to lessen high-risk borrowing
in aided <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a requirement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">IMF</ENAMEX> release written summaries of
its board meetings and other major documents <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within three months</TIMEX>. The paper
says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> are close on a number of the remaining
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> issues, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> plan to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 billion</NUMEX> to hire <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. But since agreements have not yet been reached, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed
another short-term funding bill-- the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1st</TIMEX>--to tide the
government over for a few more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>.

            Another budget story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front addresses the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or so
line items that appear in print for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 billion</NUMEX> defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> just passed--so-called "virgin births." The list <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>,
reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , includes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> to study the tactical applications
of caffeinated chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>.

            The papers report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicine</ENAMEX> goes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who discovered that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nitric oxide</ENAMEX> (not, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> admonish, nitrous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oxide</ENAMEX>, which is laughing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>), known best as an air pollutant, is also produced
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, where it regulates blood pressure, nerve firing, and immune
responses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> waits until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> paragraph of its story to
mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nitric oxide</ENAMEX> is central to the process of getting an erection and
as such is a key element in the workings of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
erections make the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>
makes the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph, erections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th</TIMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature cites a
strong consumer trend: the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> have buying habits that formerly were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX>. The piece quotes a finding that while
aggregate spending by or on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-12 roughly doubled every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade between 1960-1980</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, it has tripled. The money goes, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , to such surprises as fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Airlines</ENAMEX> pre-schoolers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fliers club</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty Financial</ENAMEX>'s mutual fund
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, which features a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> coloring book and a savings and
investing bingo game. One suspicion-raising feature of the story: the three
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> mentioned in vignettes are all upper-upper-end <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly</NUMEX>-pure-white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>
within a radius of fifty miles of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
