
   
   
      
         
            Fade in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times each lead with the onset <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s
debate about whether to initiate an impeachment investigation against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
plays that story as its off-lead and goes instead with word of a private
meeting over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> at which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s top financial officials
told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>
that their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are in far worse trouble than has ever been publicly
admitted.

            The coverage makes it clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s discussions will
be highly partisan, but also that due to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
majority--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reminds that the committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">count</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> Ds, and that
with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Bono</ENAMEX>, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rs</ENAMEX> are white,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>, conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a few days</TIMEX> the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> will be voting
on whether or not to authorize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to start an impeachment inquiry.
There is more of a question about how many crossover votes this will get in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> implies that in a floor vote, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> from
conservative or swing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> might cross over. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> quotes a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
chat show prediction by a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 100</NUMEX>
might do so. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that the consensus is that despite all this,
there aren't sufficient impeachment votes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> note <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
talk show comment that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Schippers</ENAMEX>, may
well recommend that some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s charges be dropped while adding some
others. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the additions might include lying under oath and
concealment of a felony. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Saturday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , citing an informed
source, reported that there would be new charges of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> tampering,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> only mentions the latter new charge. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schippers</ENAMEX> will express the personal regret he feels as a registered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>
about the charges he's tendering. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says he may name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> as a co-conspirator. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> as saying that he
doesn't see the need to call her as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Japan</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> that the capital behind his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> has dwindled so low
that if international rules requiring capital on hand to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 8 percent</NUMEX>
of total outstanding loans were strictly enforced, they might be banned from
operating overseas. Indeed, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s remarks
suggest that some of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> don't even have the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> capital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
requires for domestic banking. According to the paper, the situation was
clouded by the conflicting remarks of other senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> banking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT front tells a disturbing tale about the current state of
security of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>. It seems that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, at a naval
base near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Murmansk</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailor</ENAMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crewmen</ENAMEX> aboard a nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">submarine</ENAMEX> and took control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty hours</TIMEX>, repeatedly
threatening to destroy it, creating the potential for what one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> quoted
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls a "floating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chernobyl</ENAMEX>." The episode only ended when the
sailor, who had locked himself in one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX>'s torpedo bays, killed
himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, you won't be surprised to learn, said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">submarine</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the vicinity were "absolutely safe."

            An inside story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX>
will publish a harsh report condemning the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and criminal justice
system for "a persistent and widespread pattern of human rights violations."
The paper quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX>, who is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Senegal</ENAMEX>, as
saying that "it seems to me that the international community, in terms of
standards, is moving really ahead of the standards obtained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> today." Hmmm...where would you rather be arrested, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Senegal</ENAMEX>?

            Revealing little story in the WP business section by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Segal</ENAMEX>. Seems that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>
University law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> was unhappy about the lack of attention the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s
student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> has been getting from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prof.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Turley</ENAMEX>, who has been spending
a lot of time lately on TV commenting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">l</TIMEX>'affaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> appearances
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between January and August</TIMEX>). So the student devised a little experiment. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, he called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, leaving a message that he was a GWU student
asking for an office appointment. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Thirteen minutes</TIMEX> later, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> called
up, leaving a message falsely identifying herself as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>. The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>'s" call was returned in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">32 minutes</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s call was never
returned.

         
      
   
