
   
   
      
         
            I <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dub Thee Surplus</ENAMEX>

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> federal budget surplus in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-nine years</TIMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> preparations for airstrikes
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the financial markets' reaction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> rate cut.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> leads record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
ceremony commemorating <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the estimated $70 billion</NUMEX> in the federal plus column.
But it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's inside story that rolls out a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> from some
place called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carleton College</ENAMEX> to best summarize the moment: "He came in hoping
to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, and ended up being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Eisenhower</ENAMEX>."

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> stress the partisan carping the surplus
has inspired: the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want credit for passing a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> tax increase without
a single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> vote, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want credit for pressuring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> to commit to a balanced budget. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that few
things irk <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> more than not being given credit for ending permanent
deficits.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> helpfully includes some non-partisan explanations for the
surplus: the peaceful dissolution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, which kept defense
spending from going higher, the moderation of health care costs, and the extra
tax revenue wrought by the stock market boom.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stresses that for all the credit-claiming, the current budget
process is still, to put it Times ly, "untidy"--with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only nine days</TIMEX> left
before the congressional recess, the paper notes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 2</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> spending
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> required for government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> have been completed. Also, the papers
explain, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> now disagree about what to do with the surplus--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
wants to reserve it for dealing with the coming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> crunch,
although he wants to use some of it for keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and to
solve the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> problem, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are against that spending, but
want to allocate at least some of the surplus to tax relief.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead and front-page stories at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , all indications are that the discovery earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of massacred ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> has galvanized
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> into planning imminent military action--probably airstrikes--against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. Nobody has pictures in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to match the one of a
massacre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> that ran (in color) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead puts the dubiousness of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> economic analysis and
the folly of giving much newspaper space to it on full display. The story's
headline and first paragraphs emphasize <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">238</NUMEX> point drop in the Dow
and the dip of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bonds below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever,
and say that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>" see these developments as a flight from international
stock markets (probably the wrong word--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, all stock markets are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">international</ENAMEX>--what's meant is "overseas"). But this leaves unexplained why
this flight didn't roost in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stock market as well as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bond
market. Also, the concerned tone of the story takes too narrow a point of
view--basically that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholder</ENAMEX> or bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>--whereas there is good news
here too. After all, bad news for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX> is good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX>--housing
mortgage rates are wonderful right now and off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> yield dip can only
get wonderfuller. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page market piece has many of the same
tics, but at least mentions the plus for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. By the way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the recent dip in new-home
sales is probably mostly due to a non-financial factor: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurricane Bonnie</ENAMEX>.)

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> told "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>"
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of whom was, according to the paper, almost surely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>) that
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> assured her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX> that he was not having an affair with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, but was merely "ministering to a troubled young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."
Depends what you mean by "ministering."

            Another sign that the press may be ending its post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> free pass for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military comes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial, "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insatiable Pentagon</ENAMEX>," which calls the current arguments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> about
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$271 billion</NUMEX> budget is enough "surreal." But in case you
think such criticism means the defense business is headed for a correction,
check out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Glassman</ENAMEX>'s stock tip column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , in which he
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, "It's almost certain that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will use a good chunk of the budget
surplus for defense." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX> goes on to note that some leading professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> consider such stocks as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop Grumman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raytheon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> to be excellent buys.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's TV column notes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> passed a motion condemning the new sitcom "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Secret Diary of Desmond</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>," a show about a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butler</ENAMEX> and personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> that includes cavalier references to slavery. The show has also,
reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , been protested by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX>. Wonder what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LACC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> position was on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Heroes</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
