
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail Voting</ENAMEX>

            On a slow news day, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the quiet hope among
some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeachment inquiry will die a swift death. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> goes with an affirmative action-related
piece: complaints from some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, mostly in the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>, that their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have been excluded from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> on the basis of race. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the growing vote-by-mail
trend.

            The LAT front says that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> believe that losing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeachment vote would be much better than winning by a narrow margin and
sending the unpopular impeachment proceedings to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> (which would likely
kill impeachment anyway). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is in a tough spot: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> cites a
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> poll which says that while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> oppose impeachment,
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68%</NUMEX> of "self-identified <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>" want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressmen</ENAMEX> to vote for it.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are
increasingly butting heads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> over
race-conscious policies. The issue--whether diversity should be a selection
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">criterion</ENAMEX> in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>--has not been directly addressed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court, even as desegregation orders are lifted in many areas across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Magnet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, which accept top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> yet also seek to preserve their
racial diversity, are particularly flummoxed by this issue. A spate of upcoming
court cases across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> may determine the future of race-based
policies.

            Voting by mail was once confined to the legitimately absent or the
physically impaired. Now, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , it has become widely popular
among stay-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> can vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 21 days</TIMEX> early
without explaining their early voting. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> will soon become the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> state
to switch to an all-mail ballot. Alarmingly, individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> can bundle
their campaign literature into a vote-by-mail application (which incidentally
does not require identification). Among the downsides of mail-voting: Extra
costs and the potential for corruption--ineligible, dead, or nonexistent voters
can wriggle onto the voting rolls.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead carries another voting issue: soft money. More soft
money than ever is flooding presidential campaigns--and earlier than ever. The
soft money is no longer principally funneled through national political
parties; many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> have established political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>
which are thinly veiled conduits for their own interests. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX>, for
example, will rely on funds for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Building America's Conscience and Kids</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>" for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> Presidential campaign.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front hints at a coming waterloo for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>. The evidence is a spate of recent purges of government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">air force</ENAMEX>, and intelligence service. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> believe--nay, hope--that the purges indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is
teetering. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also runs an item on the purges, saying that they have
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">rattled Montenegro</ENAMEX> (adjacent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>), which fears a crackdown from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>.
Both stories note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has played a key behind-the-scenes role
in the dismissals.

            The LAT fronts an interesting piece describing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> as a low-profile,
high-volume refugee haven. Floods of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> (and, to a lesser extent,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnians</ENAMEX> and others) have found <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> to be hospitable. However, this
has make no impact on the West; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>' main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for refugees
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNHCR</ENAMEX>) gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $17 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>,
whereas it provided <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$149 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to handle the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 1 million</NUMEX>
displaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> within former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> that denounces the ineffectiveness
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> policy: "We win the battles, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is
winning the wars," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> says. Specifically, he warns that international
support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> raids cannot be "recycled indefinitely" and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is
becoming "more captive to a fragile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> consensus." Rather than swallow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s bluster about inspections and sanctions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> should actively
pursue the removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> from power. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kissinger</ENAMEX> proposes not only
strengthening the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Saddam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance groups</ENAMEX>, but also implementing a much
firmer policy on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>--i.e. actively destroying command areas and suspected
weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> provokes the next crisis.

            A massive piece fronting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money & Business</ENAMEX>" describes the
recruiting process for college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>. In the mad scramble
for lucrative investment banking and consulting jobs, interviews can be quite
grueling. Says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>: "I walked into the interview, and
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> even says, 'Hi, how are you doing?' he asks me, 'What's the sum
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> consecutively?'" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Answer</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5050</TIMEX>. Don't despair--the student
flubbed it also.)

         
      
   
