
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excess Baggage</ENAMEX>

            The blow-by-blow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> peace talks continues to dominate, leading
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . This is also the top international news
story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , which leads instead with word that
bilingual education continues to thrive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> despite
passage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> of a statewide initiative substantially restricting it.

            The big peace talk development <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> that he would take his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> home
if his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> security demands were not met. The most pressing
demands appear to be for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> to repeal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> charter's provision
calling for the destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and to turn over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> a
number of suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and LAT
report that things had unwound so much that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> had packed
their bags and some of their luggage was transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>.

            It's not clear from the coverage why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> didn't make good on their
threat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> saying it was just the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>' "childish ploy," intended for domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> consumption. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> and the right wing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s own party
are warning him not to roll over. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> cites this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> and adds
another: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, who is inclined toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> sentiments, knows how much a
breakthrough before the congressional elections would mean to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, and
hence wants to deny him this success. This <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political angle is very
prominent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reporting, which says flatly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants a
deal far more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> he's hosting do. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> makes a bathetic and rather yuppyish reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s role,
saying that thus far, he has "invested <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than 55 hours</TIMEX>" in the summit talks.
Do you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> ever wrote about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Bunche</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dag Hammarskold</ENAMEX> as if
they billed by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs a front-pager reporting that as part of the
just-concluded budget agreement, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23 million</NUMEX> to
continue work on a drug-eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fungus</ENAMEX> that could destroy opium <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poppies</ENAMEX> and coca
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> who co-sponsored the funding says that the technology
should be finished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> feature makes the point that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Patrol</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> that most directly polices the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
border, is no longer just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglos</ENAMEX>. Currently, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">patrol</ENAMEX>'s rank-and-file <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>.
This is a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>' beefing up of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Gatekeeper</ENAMEX>, which
targets illegal entries from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> area. The expanded
hiring recruited heavily from southwestern border <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and emphasized fluency
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> often come in for special pleading in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>
and failing that, special abuse, from those they detain.

            The WP front features the surprisingly successful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> gubernatorial candidacy of Jesse "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Body</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>, a
libertarian former professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy Seal</ENAMEX> and talk show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> has, reports the paper, stimulated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> with an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unpackaged</ENAMEX> campaign the likes of which have not been seen since early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX>.
Before dismissing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX> as any kind of a stereotype, consider his response to
a question about his stance on gay rights: "I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have been
together <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41 years</TIMEX>. If one of them becomes sick the other one is not even
allowed to be at the bedside. I don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should be so hostile,
so mean-spirited....Love is bigger than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts feature stories about so-called
"smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>" that can only be fired when held by the
designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>, because of a distance-sensitive transponding device such as
a finger ring. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> could, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> write, unify both sides of the gun
debate in that they promise to boost <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> sales for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> developing
them, while reducing accidental shootings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and "take-away" shootings
of cops. But, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , there are still concerns: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> test
has found that there are reliability problems, many due to limitations of
battery life, and even if perfected, the technology would make no dent in gun
suicide by rightful <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, or in the gun deaths lurking in the form of all
the "dumb" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> already out there.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> mourns the way-too-soon passing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Georges</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> are encouraged to
discover the legacy of fine stories he left behind, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and
before that, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Monthly</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
