
   
   
      
         
            Plugging in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> politics continue to dominate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with the de facto
Speakerhood of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Livingston</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with the fractious
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> caucus he will try to lead, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> also addresses in a
front-pager. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes instead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> hearings at which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> said middle-ground outcomes like censuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had no
constitutional basis. The hearings are also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
make the front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>, which leads instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court's allowing the continuance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>'s program of subsidizing poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s attendance at private and religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. This voucher story
makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts, but is played inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> each give the who's-up-who's-down
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrangle</ENAMEX> but there is no clear sense communicated about what it
all means. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> bothers to tell us that to hold together the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP caucus Livingston</ENAMEX> may have to, to coin a phrase, "resort to scotch tape and
bailing wire," but doesn't tell us much about the ideological differences
operating except to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> has been slammed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>
editorial page and is also disliked by something called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional Values</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>. The coverage tells us that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> is apparently all about tone
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and (could this be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> effect?) that he's a black
belt in karate. But that's about it. For a topography of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, turn to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> account, which nicely articulates the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of
its conservatism: pragmatic, economic, and social.

            As for the lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in the hierarchy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> don't even
communicate what they do. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> has no idea what to make of learning that,
for example, the vice chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX> is challenging
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> exception to this complaint is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's
reporting on the job of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delay</ENAMEX>, it seems, was able to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> support to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Livingston</ENAMEX> because he possesses the only really up-to-date
list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' phone numbers and addresses.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> observes that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were looking for a way to
gracefully abandon impeachment, this was not in evidence at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>
hearings. The other papers see things the same way. Although it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elbow Patch</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tweed Day</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> shows that often the academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> were just foils for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' speechifying. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> testified
that the standards for impeachment should be kept very high, but some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> made it clear they felt that lying about
sex qualified.

            It's a bit sobering to read that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX>, refuses to bury <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s career in public life. His model for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'98</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'62</TIMEX>--down but not out. If, writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> clobber the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential vote, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> would be
positioned for a comeback, this time as a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.

            As an apparent conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> looms, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports on a visit made
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> now enroute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>. The paper
reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> is deployed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> than it's supposed to
have, with the result that flight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> cannot be sustained at the tempo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> would like. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> denies that the
carrier's recent fatal flight deck collision had anything to do with
shorthandedness, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> has experienced a rise in its flight accident
rate. The story quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> civilian defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>'s assessment: there's plenty
of money, it's just being spent on the wrong things--glamour weapons instead of
parts and manpower.

            For those wondering how long <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> could stay in
business, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a story inside about the independent counsel
appointed to look into conflict of interest charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli Segal</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">one-time Clinton</ENAMEX> national service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nine months</TIMEX> after getting the case,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IC</ENAMEX> recommended against prosecuting <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Segal</ENAMEX>, and no further action was taken
against him. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX> after that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> still exists, albeit
down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> working <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> time. Why? Well, says, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> had to continue operating while those investigated or required to
testify appealed for reimbursement of their legal expenses. And there's the
cost in time and money of, as the law requires, turning over all paperwork to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Archives</ENAMEX>. And best of all, since any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> must be audited by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every six months</TIMEX>, someone must be retained to preside over the
office while it's being audited. That's how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segal IC</ENAMEX> is still managing to
spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $250,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
