
   
   
      
         
            Rest for the Wary

            All papers lead with the narrowly aborted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Just hours
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> was to launch a massive air strike campaign (at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m. EST</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
signaled its willingness to let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspectors return. After reviewing
the overture, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s conditional concessions
"unacceptable" and remains poised to attack.

            The letter, sent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early Saturday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tariq Aziz</ENAMEX> to
inspectors return, apparently unconditionally. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> spoke with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aziz</ENAMEX> over the
phone and seemed convinced of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s sincerity. However, a later annex sent by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aziz</ENAMEX> laid out several conditions for the resumption of weapons
inspections--including the lifting of the oil embargo on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dubious,</ENAMEX>
than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> canceled the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> leg of his <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> trip
(which he was secretly planning to do anyway, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) and
sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> instead.

            The papers note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is now in a tricky situation, with huge forces
amassed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> stalling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to order the attacks earlier in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> to avoid precisely such a situation. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> has successfully weakened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s international support; says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , "the wily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> has lost none of his tactical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cunning</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has now voiced its aversion to the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Counsel</ENAMEX> is divided over the sincerity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s latest proposal. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.N.S.C.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> are now at odds over what the "annex" says; while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will not tolerate the conditional annex, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eckhard</ENAMEX>, has said that the annex "does not constitute conditions." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
still strongly backs the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> position.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Danzig</ENAMEX>, the soon-to-be-sworn-in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>, outlines possible defense strategies against
"NEW"--nonexplosive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, such as biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> or computer viruses.
Declaring that "we ought to assume that successful attacks should occur,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Danzig</ENAMEX> proposes various response strategies such as "educating medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, preparing responsive plans and stockpiling antibiotics." Also on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danzig</ENAMEX>'s wish list: "giving our computer systems <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">redundancy</ENAMEX>" so that the
effects of a computer attack are mitigated.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead chronicles the myriad ways that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cripples</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> health care costs huge amounts (even with health
benefits caps); young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who could be promoted are dying; the supply of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> is depleted; and in some hard-hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are downsizing because they anticipate a lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>.

            In an inside article charmingly entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paris Finally Gets the Poop</ENAMEX>," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> is becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> of "dog toilet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enclosures</ENAMEX>"--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are actually using them. In case dogs miss, "moto turds"
sweep through for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> (encouraged by a hefty fine for messy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dogs</ENAMEX>) are also getting their scoops out--a rare example, says the article, of
civic activism in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
