
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Temporary Husseinity</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with the deployment of more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>,
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>--via remarks not just by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but
also by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JCS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Shelton</ENAMEX>--once again warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> to accept weapons inspections or else. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s military moves:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ordering stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-52</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> along with
anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. Another development that has in
the past served as an immediate warning of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>: the withdrawal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonessential State Dept.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> (in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>), and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> and humanitarian aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. None of the papers mentions that such evacuations not only serve the
obvious purpose, but also reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s ability to deploy foreign "human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shields</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
points out that, unlike the previous go-round with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX>, neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is currently attempting to find a diplomatic way out for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that in a closed-door meeting at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> continued to argue against using <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has been joined in this position by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> would be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">depots</ENAMEX>. The ><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hoagland</ENAMEX> agrees and adds that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has prevailed over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> in insisting on a "substantial air
campaign." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> passes along former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> national
security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent Scowcroft</ENAMEX>'s suggestion: take out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>,
until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> grants inspections. But the paper points out current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> acknowledge that no bombing campaign, no matter how extensive, can be
expected to eradicate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s covert weapons development efforts. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> nor subsequent strikes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> significantly eroded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s interest in or capability for weapons
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. And, adds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is bedeviled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s way
of interpreting events--after all, he has told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>
was a great triumph for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads stresses in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paragraph that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is
prepared to strike with no further warning. How soon? Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> is planning to fly to an economic summit on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, not in her regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, but in a special airborne command and control
craft known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doomsday Plane</ENAMEX>. The same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, the paper reminds, she used while
traveling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX> just before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> strikes into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>.

            The fronts at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> cabinet
has ratified the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> pact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hailed the ratification as an important step, but both
papers stress that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> salted its approval with enough conditions
requiring specific prior actions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> to produce at the very least
delay if not an outright breakdown in the peace process.

            An inside piece at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Makashov</ENAMEX>, has called for quotas on the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and denounced a
television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> as "worse than the worst of the yids." In a speech, he
also told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX>, "Don't behave as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yid</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Makashov</ENAMEX> defended his use of the phrase by citing the writings of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pushkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dostoevsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gogol</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says anti-Semitism had been rare
in post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s economic swan dive last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAO Schwarz</ENAMEX> now offers
something called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ultimate Sleep-Over Party</ENAMEX>" in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can
"camp out" in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $17,500</NUMEX>. The paper further press releases
that "some proceeds go to charity." It would be nice if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> made
sure this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> was more than just free advertising for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">shi-shi</ENAMEX> toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> by
following up to see just how much of those 17K checks actually ends up going to
those in need.

         
      
   
