
   
   
      
         
            <I><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monica's Choice</ENAMEX></I>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with more tough words from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is the only other paper to front the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
story at all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's top national story analyzes the stock
market's resurgence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s decision not to consider two
campaign finance reform cases. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with an analysis of the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$206 billion</NUMEX> proposed settlement between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> are highly skeptical of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s compliance and that "there was an unusually strong consensus
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> bombing was almost inevitable." The real test,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , should come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> when surprise weapons
inspections begin. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> echoed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Administration's strongly worded sentiments; next time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> said, there will
be "no warnings, no wrangling, no negotiations, no last-minute letters."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> could be deployed within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of any decision to
attack. Other interesting stories from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> package report
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision to terminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> strike came just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> were to launch; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> are miffed at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> for insinuating that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> tipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> off to the
imminent attack. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> remarked of the attack plan, "We had to inform our
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> tobacco suit story notes that if the case is settled, "the
industry got off relatively cheaply in strict financial terms." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Smokers</ENAMEX>
themselves, rather than the industry, will essentially shoulder the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$206</NUMEX>
billion cost through <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">35-cents</NUMEX>-per-pack price increases; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says
that this is not enough to seriously dampen consumption. Health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> have
already criticized the settlement as too lax, but the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> general
are eager to settle and get the money. For the settlement to take effect,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> representing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> must sign by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead, tucked inside elsewhere, says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
elected not to hear cases from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> about campaign finance reform.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> emphasizes that prospects for spending reform by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> elections
now seem remote, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is generally disinclined to pass the necessary
legislation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead about the soaring stock market is buoyed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s
figures, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> finished above <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9000</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX>
higher than it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1st</TIMEX>. Factors in the market rise, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , include interest rate cuts, high corporate earnings, and the
waning prospect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment. However, doubts linger as to whether
the market can maintain its course in the face of the global economic
crisis.

            The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> fronts a terrific story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s arduous decision-making
process. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s announcements and hints on forthcoming interest rate moves
are pegged to a delicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> dance; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ill-timed or misunderstood word can flip
markets. The WSJ paints <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> as a highly autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>;
he "makes major policy changes only at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOMC</ENAMEX> meetings--partly so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> doesn't
look like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man show it often is." Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> decision on interest rate
cuts is coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has signed a book deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's Press</ENAMEX>, a story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fronted</ENAMEX> everywhere but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> (which gives it to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style"</ENAMEX>) and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . The book (working title: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica's Story</ENAMEX>) will be ghost-written by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Morton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> book. It could come
out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as February</TIMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . All papers note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> fee is unexpectedly modest--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says it's just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> plus
bestseller bonuses. For free, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> also has agreed to a television interview
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>. A date has not been set, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is still
ironing out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s office the legal nuances of a media
appearance, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> guesses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> may haul in a seven-figure sum for a separate TV deal to be broadcast
outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>

            From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> self-reference corner: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Business</ENAMEX>" piece
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analyzes Slate</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial coverage, saying
that irreverent descriptions of jowly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's
inaugural courtroom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>, "seemed mightily unfettered
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>." "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>," who also edits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Email</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>," recommends the piece to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legions</ENAMEX> of you out there who sent in
comments about the trial coverage.

         
      
   
