
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Bill Pass</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>?

            Everybody leads with the formal defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, to be delivered not by him but for him by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> saying, "It's time to make
our case. We plan to do it in a serious way." (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Last minute</TIMEX> cut of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallagher</ENAMEX>
from witness list?) In response to the articles of impeachment the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HJC</ENAMEX> is
likely to propose, the presentation will include, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says, arguments
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did not perjure himself, obstruct justice or abuse his power. The
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> defense will stress the incommensurability of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s admitted actions and the threshold of impeachability, to be
exemplified, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>.

            The papers say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> is almost certain to approve at least one
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> of impeachment. Therefore, they say, the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for all of this
is most of all the upwards of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> undecided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. The WP
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> was left out of the witness package because this is now a
constitutional fight more properly fought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> (not personal)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> gives a more convincing reason: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendall</ENAMEX>
grates on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> nerves. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> has fresh polling saying that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> oppose impeachment, with most favoring censure. And that's
the position taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's lead editorial. But, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> hasn't decided yet whether he will allow a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> vote on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">censure</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> witness list will include a law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> who
will argue that articles of impeachment approved by this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
would not be binding on the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, to be installed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page features a column
by that prof giving his argument. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> say that
many in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> feel this sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> and theoretical testimony will be
less effective than some sort of further personal expression of regret by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says a further gesture by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is still a
possibility. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> needs to show he's more concerned about impeachment than about
protecting himself from post-presidential prosecution. (Question: Why does
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> need to worry about personal legal consequences--can't he just pardon
himself right before he leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead scares with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, which wants a germ
warfare capability to match <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s, has had some success recruiting former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> who specialize in this
area, by offering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> salaries of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>--more than these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> can earn
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is trying to defeat this trend, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
by spending money to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> bio-warfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> gainfully employed in
less volatile lines of work in their native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' fronts all report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> decided that there
is no need to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to look into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
fund-raising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , follows its long-time harsh stance on the matter
by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s move "obstinacy" and the conclusion of "one of the sorriest
episodes in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> history." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial on this
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is right because the campaign finance laws are vague and weak, and
notes that the anger about her decision coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is ironic since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could most easily remedy this.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , which for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a year</TIMEX> has reported on the small number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> to be law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>, runs as its
off-lead the official answer it finally got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. (The response also runs
inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>, writing on behalf of
the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>, recognized the low numbers, but said they wouldn't improve
until the pool of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant lawyers</ENAMEX> becomes more diverse.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead runs under the headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Says Clinton Acts Pale</ENAMEX>
Next to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>." Isn't this an odd locution for a paper with a style sheet
so famously politically correct that it bans such non-issue locutions as "to
welsh on a bet"? After all, "to pale" means "to be whiter" and if as the
headline would have it, "whiter" means "less bad," then "white" means
"good."

         
      
   
