
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> Way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twice Tony</ENAMEX>

Times lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s passage of an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 billion</NUMEX> tax cut package
which is unlikely to pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> or be approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> runs the tax-cut story below the fold and
leads instead with an extraordinary first-person epic that recounts a harrowing
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500-mile</NUMEX> trek through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            The tax-cut measure, approved by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">229</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">195</NUMEX> vote, is opposed by most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, who are concerned that it would cut into the surplus set aside for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> security. "I insist that we reserve the entire surplus until we have
seized this historic opportunity to save social security," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
commented from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , picking up on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' arguments, detect possible hypocrisy in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s position: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has previously sought to dip into the budget surplus to fund, among
other things, the peacekeeping mission in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, increased embassy security,
and farm relief. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> used the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> session to point
out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is working on real issues. "We are not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fund-raiser</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> pointedly remarked.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's lead leaves the impression that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> resent
many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban's</ENAMEX> practices, particularly the mandatory veils for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and
the ban on music. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX>, officially forbidden to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, are often
covertly educated at home by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. The article also showcases
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s devastation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roads</ENAMEX> are still pockmarked with "jagged craters
gouged by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> bombs and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank mines</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>'s
sweep struggle to survive in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>-infested <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT front page carries a long historical narrative about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>'s deliberations, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early- to mid-1960s</TIMEX>, over whether to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to
derail its development of nuclear weapons. The article's main source is newly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">released State Department</ENAMEX> documents about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>. Among other things, the piece says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> before him) sounded out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> on
heading off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s nuclear capabilities, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> flatly ignored
the overtures. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> tested its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead gives a gripping play-by-play drama of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meriwether</ENAMEX>'s fateful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few weeks</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meriwether</ENAMEX> is at the helm of
the hedge fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term Capital Management LP</ENAMEX>, which was recently bailed out
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coterie</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> and brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. Among other details the
Times describes the tense atmosphere at the rescue board meeting in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, in which rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> were persuaded to take highly unusual
collective bailout action.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports inside that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> southeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, agreed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> to establish a
multinational southeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, however, may be
more symbolic of military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> than effective in providing real military
assistance to troubled areas such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            The op-ed columns do battle over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX>. "Hardly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> passes
without a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> hailing the
coming of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX>," laments <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Judt</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece.
Bingo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>! The op-ed page in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook</ENAMEX>" features a piece by none other than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>,
entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Way</ENAMEX>." Quick primer on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> says it
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> of democratic socialism and liberalism ("Our approach is neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laissez-faire</ENAMEX> nor one of state interference"). Judt uncharitably likens it to
vague triangulating, falling somewhere "between Communism and capitalism. TP
leaves it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to judge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victor</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
