
   
   
      
         
            Wye Not?

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s decision to give in to pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>--upset
on all sides over the course of the peace process with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX>--and stand for re-election <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX> before the
scheduled end of his term. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> also runs a front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> and goes instead with the
latest ripple in a story that's been percolating below the fold for a while:
allegations of vote-buying by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> bid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> in its
successful drive to land the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter Games</ENAMEX>. What's new, says the paper, is
consideration as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s impeachment
trial) has agreed to lead a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> investigation into the
charges.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s move to new elections, the papers explain, is not finalized yet,
but virtually guaranteed, with the field likely to pit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> candidates
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. The cause of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s unraveling, the
papers say, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-brokered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> deal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Wye accord</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
right, dominated by adamant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> and the devoutly religious, was unhappy
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s response of opting out of scheduled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> troop
pullbacks hurt him with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and the left, which had come to accept land
for peace, and infuriated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. The papers say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> is now in
limbo until the outcome of the new elections, even though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
reports, polls show <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> support it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts report on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s handing
down of stiff prison sentences--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 to 13 years</TIMEX>--to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> who'd been trying
to start <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s first democratic opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports on
the sentencing of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>, while the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also mention a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Dept.</ENAMEX> spokesman
denounced the sentences. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> seems unbending--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that in a speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party chief</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>, stated, "The Western mode of political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> must
never be adopted." The papers note that this crackdown comes at a time when
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">unquestionably Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have more personal freedom than they've ever
experienced before under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> rule. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s explanation for this stern crackdown: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
always been worried about any movement that might tie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in one province
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in another." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a second piece inside reporting
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> cited the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> sentences as proof that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration's policy of economic and diplomatic engagement with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has
failed.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">octuplets</ENAMEX> are continuing to get front-page coverage. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
it's tempered with concerns about the ethics of so fully unleashing
state-of-the-art reproductive therapy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> saying
flatly that such extreme multiple births are not a victory for science and
warning against "exuberant therapy." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes another saying
the event is "a wake-up call for the medical profession." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> problem emerging
via the coverage is that the fertility-enhancing technology is so expensive
that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have to pay for it out of their own pockets, instead of via
insurance, whether or not a pregnancy results--they pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to use
increasingly potent measures, greatly increasing the chance of high-multiple
births.

            The LAT front fascinates with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Shogren</ENAMEX>'s exclusive
look into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s mindset as he holiday-partied at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Shogren, a party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>, snagged a
lengthy interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> believes that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 or 30</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, he will be vindicated. He is determined to find a quick way out of the
crisis, but is stumped about how to do that. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> were
"gloomy and distraught" and it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> who was cheering them up. He has
been buoyed from recent personal advice not just from a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>, but also from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Wright</ENAMEX>.
Besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX>'s spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> against harboring hate towards your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attackers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cited a practical reason for not being more prominent in his
own defense: focusing on himself rather than his job would make his approval
ratings plummet.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are so despised by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> is their bent
for comments like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Glassman</ENAMEX> tosses off in his
column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: "(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX>, a former high school wrestling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, may
be a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">House?</ENAMEX>!)" Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glassman</ENAMEX> be so quick to
criticize another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestler</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, with only one year
total of formal education--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
