
   
   
      
         
            Stiff Warning

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s finding that there
is no reason to continue looking into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election fundraising. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
which has hawked the story on its front and editorial pages harder than anybody
else, off-leads the denouement. Earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL/Netscape</ENAMEX> deal
was in the works, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> went with something else, but leads with it
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> now that there's a fork in it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with word from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> that a
single charge of perjury against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might win a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor
vote, but additional charges such as obstruction of justice would not. The
paper also says that the idea of a resolution censuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is gaining
congressional momentum.

            If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> decision seems familiar, that's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> made it once
before, but then reopened the investigation based on new evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
attendance at some meetings where ultimately illegal approaches to fund-raising
may have been discussed. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explain that the
gist of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s finding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was that there was no compelling evidence from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s remarks at these meetings that he was contemplating flouting the
election finance laws. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> expressed strong emotion about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s
decision. "We need to take these matters out of the hands of the Attorney
General...," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> is quoted saying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , while Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> saying, "Once again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> has
failed to follow the law. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> has made
it clear she is committed to protecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." The papers agree that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision clears the deck for a much more trouble-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> run at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL/Netscape</ENAMEX> tandem as a "corporate odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>," referring
to the former's pitch to the "technologically challenged" and the latter's
status as the epitome of leading edge siliconsciousness. Yet the story spells
out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' common vision of a not-distant world in which the Internet
is accessed primarily by high tech but easy-to-use and low cost appliances that
would be as ubiquitous as cell phones are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says
many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Netscape</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> may be reluctant to work for AOL because of its
"middlebrow" (why not "middlebrowser"?) reputation, setting up a big run on
Netscape by headhunters.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> run reefers to stories inside about
increasing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> concerns (also noted inside by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ). Both papers
report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> is adding stricter health warnings to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> labels. In
addition to the current warning against taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> is
already taking any heart <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nitrates</ENAMEX>, the labels will now also say
that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> could be risky for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with heart problems or very high or low
blood pressure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> explains that this is based on a close look at
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX> cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who've died--mostly from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX>--after
popping the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>. The point is that when sex itself is risky because of
underlying cardiological problems, then impotence remedies should be avoided.
is implicated in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> airplane crash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>, which would be a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. A bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> prescribed for the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> was found in the
wreckage. It's known that in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 3 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, the drug disturbs color
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX>, which could make reading cockpit instruments and runway lights
problematic.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" says more and more
"not-so-wealthy" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting hit with the alternative minimum tax, which
was designed to keep the wealthy from dodging federal tax entirely through the
artful use of deductions, credits and the like. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> cites the example of
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>" who was amazed to receive an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> letter
informing him that he owed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,175</NUMEX> in AMT. This report would be a lot more
compelling if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> had told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s income was.
But absent this information, it's a little hard to get worked up about this
issue. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Papers doubts that there are many veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> tax
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> who aren't well off.

            The LAT front and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page put forward a total of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pieces on the ethics of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> broadcast.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K. op-ed</ENAMEX> calls the broadcast a "snuff film" and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wonders</ENAMEX>, in light of the shows big rating and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX> advertising revenues,
"Shouldn't the profit motive end where life and death become mere commodities
for public consumption?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX>, in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> column, is worried too, but decides that the show was
justified by its prompting of honest debate on a topic now more shrouded than
oral sex. And he quotes the show's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Don Hewitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Wallace</ENAMEX> appealing to the
same principle. Messrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hewitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> make the same case in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . It wasn't sweeps numbers they were after, they claim, but important
news. None of this coverage mentions a simple way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> could have been much more
convincing on this point: donate all ad revenues produced by the show to
charity. How about to a hospice?

         
      
   
