
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cave Mandela</ENAMEX>

            After a week of much news uniformity, lead diversity makes a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
appearance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead furthers the emerging picture of
connections between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> defense team
with details on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s interactions with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the effects of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
impeachment-related vote on the midterm election campaigns. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times lead apparently goes as far as it can get from the presidential
scandal--with word that the major oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are probably not going to build
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipeline</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian Sea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> along a route that was pushed hard by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. (Pushed because it would pass only through the
relatively friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azerbaijan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>--binding them
further to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>--instead of passing through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says
the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have probably decided the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-backed route is too expensive
to build now. Actually, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> the decision does have a scandal
angle: the paper quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lost the power of moral
persuasion with the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> because of the scandals surrounding him.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead reveals that contrary to standard practice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> did not instruct their chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> not to talk to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. Since it is now known that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> much
of the information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> they used to elicit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s problematic
statements during his deposition, the LAT wonders: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Did Starr</ENAMEX> help to pave the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way for Clinton</ENAMEX> to commit the alleged perjury that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> then
proceeded to investigate?" The paper quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s response: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
had no reason to know and did not know [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Tripp</ENAMEX>] was talking to the Jones
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> also features a story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp-Starr-Jones</ENAMEX> nexus, but
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> focuses on how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says she abandoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. Incidentally, unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> piece does not
mention the earlier reporting by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> feel stuck dealing
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal often at the expense of local issues. But the paper
also says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> say any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> advantage stemming
from the scandal has been eroding recently. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager election piece
sees a general trend toward voter uncertainty about who to blame for the
scandal, which could altogether neutralize it as a voting factor.

            The death at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 91</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Clifford</ENAMEX>, multi-presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisor</ENAMEX> and late in his life a figure in an international bank scandal, garners
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">front-page</ENAMEX> notice at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and a picture-with-reefer at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>. In
contrast to the generally glowing obits is the piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page by
historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kai Bird</ENAMEX>, who argues against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise Man</ENAMEX> Theory
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> still clings to. Citing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wise Men's</ENAMEX> too-long silence on the
realities of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> they knew all too well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> argues that the likes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford</ENAMEX> have always valued loyalty over truth, and hence their wisdom has
rarely done the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> much good. All this on a page long congenial to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>, even to the point in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> of running scandal advice from such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card-carriers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Richardson</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NYT Week in Review</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> real nuggets. There's the item revealing that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>, the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX> and (the probably
wishing he was late) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX>, were required to submit urine samples for drug
tests, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> revealed they were not. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> adds
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> are tested, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is not.)

            Then there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>' new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne Daley</ENAMEX>
reporting from the field that while perhaps racism is on the wane in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>, sexism is not. She regales the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> with story after story in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of all stripes treat her badly and/or assume that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
is the sole being in her marriage with decision-making ability and authority.
There are no joint checking accounts, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> seem to understand that makeup
and cleavage are civic duties. And there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>'s story about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> said about her in her presence to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lelyveld</ENAMEX>, the
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>: "In my day, if you had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who looked like
that, you would be embarrassed. In my day, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> needed a little more meat on
her bones."

         
      
   
