
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomahawks</ENAMEX> and Doves

            Everybody leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> air strike against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Banner headlines
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abound</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's--"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S. Bombs Iraq</ENAMEX>"--the biggest and boldest.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
headline is the newsiest: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Impeachment Vote in House Delayed As Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Launches Iraq Air Strike, Citing Military Need to Move Swiftly</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times 's is close behind, and is the only one that gets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
involvement into the big type. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, in a televised speech shortly
after the strikes were announced, appealed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> report released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> that documented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s systematic obstruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>'s weapons
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX> efforts in violation of promises it made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, a report that
was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, and was below the fold at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ,
but was inside elsewhere. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that the strikes mark "a clear
policy departure" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, in that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had
previously indicated that keeping the inspection effort viable was a reason not
to engage in a major military action.

            The papers report that sea-launched Tomahawk cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombers</ENAMEX> were the weapons used. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> were
launched in what it termed the largest military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says some of the strikes targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> Guard
bases in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had died in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> were
wounded as a result of hits there. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guard</ENAMEX> and says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulances</ENAMEX> had been seen near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> forecasts that the next wave of attacks will
include B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>-launched cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117 stealth attack</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has some particularly good detail on why the current action may be more
effective than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> air war: it will involve a much higher
percentage of precision <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, the cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> now have satellite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guidance</ENAMEX>, there isn't the distraction of also trying to attack an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> deployed
throughout the region, and the targeting is now being done off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that according to intelligence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, the first wave of the strike caught <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces off-guard</ENAMEX>, before
they could get very far into their usual defensive practice of dispersing their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes on to say that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> plan that the
current operation was apparently spun out of projected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> dead, most of them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">combatants</ENAMEX>.
Although the stated goal is anti-proliferation of mass-destruction <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and
enhancing regional stability, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> report an
additional one: giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> a motive and an opportunity to overthrow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>.

            Much is made of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s non-support of the airstrikes. USAT
calls his stance "almost unprecedented." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> terms it a "surprising
break with the tradition of congressional support for military actions once
they begin." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>-to-be Bob
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> said he would leave it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to evaluate the
timing. (A classic example of criticizing by not criticizing.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Solomon</ENAMEX> was "furious in accusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of using
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> air strikes as a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX> to impeachment," and that former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Eagleburger</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>'s timing "smells to
high heaven." In their lead stories, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s
demurral much lower than everybody else. But once the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> broaches the
topic, it adds this quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>: "the suspicion some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s motives in this attack is itself a powerful argument for
impeachment. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of lies, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has given <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of people
around the world reason to doubt that he has sent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> into battle for the
right reasons."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that planning for the mission started in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> during the last round of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> intransigence. All the majors save the
WSJ omit mention of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX>" in their airstrike news stories. This
is as it should be. If important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> question the timing, their
questioning should be reported, and if there is evidence of suspiciousness in
the timing that evidence should be reported as well. But absent such findings,
it's irresponsible to talk about "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX>" in a news story. All kinds of
things have been portrayed in movies, but unless their connection to real
events is shown, they're not news. But at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> also raises
a legitimate question relating the domestic and international situations:
"Could the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> handle war and impeachment at the same time?"

            At the very least it looks like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>-naming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-stressed. Leave it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>'s column to notice that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> name
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Fox</ENAMEX>," was the nickname for a "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>-era German
general." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meaning Erwin Rommel</ENAMEX>.)

            Everybody dutifully reports that one factor in the timing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">onset</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> desire to avoid beginning an operation during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX>, which starts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> quotes an expert
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> movements saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> don't restrain themselves this way. So
why should we? There's a further incoherence here that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> don't get
into. Why is it a sign of respect for your religion to kill you before instead
of during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your holiday</TIMEX>?

         
      
   
