
   
   
      
         
            Taking Stock in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>

            The top story at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s home-front
political battles arising from his just-signed peace deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>.
This is also played above the fold at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>, which leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s own
study revealing that despite being the most populous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> stands
31st in per capita share of federal education spending.

            The papers report that as soon as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> landed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>
began vigorously defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>. According to the coverage,
he portrayed the agreement as his success at getting the very best possible out
of the land-for-security <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> peace process he inherited from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predecessors</ENAMEX>. Everybody quotes him saying, "We have closed the holes of the
Swiss cheese created by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes his direct pitch to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">militant Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>: "You are us and we are you. We love you."
Koo-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">koo-ka-choob</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> could face a no-confidence vote
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> doesn't give a time frame, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says
it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. In view of the no-confidence threat, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes the oddity
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> slam, since it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doves</ENAMEX> who may save his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
with conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> expressing great disaffection. All this political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intrigue</ENAMEX>, even though, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three-quarters</NUMEX> of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> approve of the accord.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> include in their lead stories reporting on
unrest among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> as well. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that violent clashes
broke out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ramallah</ENAMEX>, resulting in the
death of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, pursuant to the
new agreement, raided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> there, confiscating documents and
weapons and making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> arrests." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lawmaker Hanan Ashrawi</ENAMEX> was a witness to the death, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> quotes her
only on the general political situation and doesn't seem to know about
this.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front continues the sprawling series on adoption it started
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the main points of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s installment is that the demand for
white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> is so great that even though it is not legal to bid
on or buy an adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, there has arisen an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of
adoption-related <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intermediaries</ENAMEX> who sell various kinds of access to
child-bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. In effect, the paper <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> there is only the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">thinnest</ENAMEX> line between buying adoption services and buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.

            The story of the upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> murdered in his home
continues to garner a lot of coverage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a front-page
encomium, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports inside that for quite some time, he had
received phone and written threats. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports on the manhunt for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">sniper</ENAMEX> and also that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>-based computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> who hosts an
anti-abortion web site called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Nuremberg Files</ENAMEX>," where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s name
had a line drawn through it shortly after he was murdered, denies any advance
information about the shooting. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial has this reaction
to the crime: "If an armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police officer</ENAMEX> has to be stationed outside every
abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>'s home and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours a day</TIMEX>, let it be done."

            It's well-known that convicts paper the legal system with suits, briefs and
motions to spring themselves, but a WSJ front-page feature reports on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> who has put the same kind of energy into stockholder suits and makes a
decent income from it. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , one
convicted tax cheat has taken in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $30,000</NUMEX> making (dubious) allegations
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholder fraud</ENAMEX> against various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. All this without owning any
stock in any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            In the aftermath of the recent revelation that a celebrated 19-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Felicity</ENAMEX>" is actually thirty-two, the LAT front reports that
according to a new study from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the movie and TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under age thirty</TIMEX>--most of them white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>--are increasingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dominating TV</ENAMEX> and movies. Since it is obvious that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> will want to
immediately correct this grievous social injustice, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> feels
compelled to confess that it is a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
