
   
   
      
         
            Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire Till You See the Whites of Their</ENAMEX> Izods

            Everybody leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX> vote to propose to the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
an impeachment inquiry targeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The headlines at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
mention that the vote to do so was along strict party lines (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> voting
yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> voting no), while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times relegate this news to the small print.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the proceedings were a "sober" debate, weighted by "the
gravity of the moment." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> sees a "heated session," but one that
was "filled with history lessons" and at times resembled a "law school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tutorial</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes much "partisan quarreling," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
sees a debate that ranged "from sober constitutional discourse to bitter
partisan scrapping."

            As had been tipped in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> press accounts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that the
majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Schippers</ENAMEX> outlined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> possible grounds for impeachment,
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">augmented</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s list with new charges of conspiracy to obstruct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> and concealing knowledge of false testimony, replaced talk of perjury
with talk of making false statements, and dropped talk of abuse of power. And
minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbe Lowell</ENAMEX> described all this as a "laundry list" falling far
short of the standards for impeachment. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the ensuing
discussion by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> sometimes grasped for the imprimatur of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX> used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>'s hallowed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">cancer on the Presidency</ENAMEX>" line to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
behavior. (But several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey Graham</ENAMEX>'s question: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX>
this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peyton Place?</ENAMEX>") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that the resolution
passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was almost word-for-word identical to the one that launched
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> impeachment inquiry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. By the way, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> that makes
it clear that this unrestricted resolution means any subsequent impeachment
inquiry might include an investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign
fund-raising.

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes how media-infested the whole process has become,
noting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> started with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' appearances on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> talk
shows, and that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point during committee debate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> told
another, he'd respond to him later on--when the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX>."

            There's a curious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ellipsis</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> when it quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McCollum</ENAMEX> arguing that impeachment is not obviously too harsh for what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> did. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> leaves out the part in the middle where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCollum</ENAMEX>
mentioned the exact number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred</NUMEX>) because
they lied to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> or in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Why the little dots
treatment?

            But in an inside piece, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> does efficiently paint a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's</ENAMEX>-eye view of the world right now: There could be
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. There could be a government
shutdown by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the week</TIMEX>. The world's top financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> looking for money and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> for the global economic crisis, and by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> will probably vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to begin an
impeachment inquiry. Jeez, just typing all those sentences makes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>
want to escape into phone sex.

            A column in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> noted the concomitant rise of church
marketing and spiritual business consulting, and now comes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reporting that with
unemployment low, some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are recruiting at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manpower Inc.</ENAMEX> even gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> a
donation for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation member</ENAMEX> placed.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" details <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an unheralded</TIMEX> breakthrough in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military equipment. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever, a service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps</ENAMEX>--is buying boots that were designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. This is a departure
from the prior practice of going out to civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and telling them
how to make a combat boot. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matterhorn</ENAMEX> footwear by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cove Shoe Co.</ENAMEX> is lighter,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cooler</ENAMEX>, more shock-absorbent and water-resistant than its traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>. What's more, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cove</ENAMEX>'s brand-name label
is stamped on the heel, the next time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> are ordered in harm's way, they
will become the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> ever to go into combat in designer footwear.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> story about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third quarter</TIMEX> performance runs under
the headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Motorola Operating Net Tops Estimates As Firm Benefits From</ENAMEX>
Restructuring." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story on the same subject is headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX>
Posts Loss for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Third Quarter</TIMEX>."

         
      
   
