
   
   
      
         
            Credit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cards</ENAMEX>?

Times lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group of Seven</ENAMEX>
industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s planned exodus of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> meeting resulted in a statement--described in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph as a "vaguely worded communiqu,"--which cites the world's
worsening financial problems and recommends "exploring" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
call for extending emergency lines of credit to emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> buffeted by
financial troubles. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> have voiced support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
proposal, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> maintain reservations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on the subject highlights <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> meeting's focus. After
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> met with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> unveiled its own <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> aid package for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration immediately criticized it as not addressing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s more
fundamental need for bank restructuring--to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> Finance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minister</ENAMEX>
shot back that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> plan will never lift off unless a reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead, a national story with a local focus, says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> HMOs
will leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX> because they are not recovering their
costs. (Thirty-one other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> are withdrawing in selected areas.) This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> will force <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 250,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> nationwide either to enroll in a
different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>-covered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>, or to switch to a standard, more expensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> plan. Yet even as so many HMOs pull out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, there are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concurrently</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> HMOs hoping to expand their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> involvement and still more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> with applications pending.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager explores the tangled web of geopolitical
relationships around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azerbaijan</ENAMEX>'s massive oil reserves (which could potentially
produce <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 million barrels</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> a day). Maneuvering around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, both with vested interests in the region, is among the
bedeviling challenges for big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Administration.

            All papers run stories on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, in which incumbent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Henrique Cardoso</ENAMEX> is expected to triumph handily despite the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s economic turmoil. Described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> as "one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hemisphere</ENAMEX>'s most impressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardoso</ENAMEX> is seen by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> as the only
realistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for surmounting the financial crisis which has seen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s
stock market plunge <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX>. Among the alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>: a left-wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> expected to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-quarter</NUMEX> of the vote and, more exotically, an
"excitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> known simply as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eneas</ENAMEX>, who calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> to build an
atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>" (in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's words).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs an op-ed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>. Breaking his silence on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal, the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "has broken faith with those who
elected him." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> proposes the following punishment: "A harshly worded rebuke
as rendered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of both parties," to be administered in the well of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>. "Let it be dignified, honest, and above all, cleansing," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> news article points out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s op-ed represents a
possible boon for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> is breaking rank with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who advocate impeachment.

            The cover of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Review</ENAMEX>" (plus an inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book</ENAMEX>
World" piece) is given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Gourevitch</ENAMEX>'s extraordinary book on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rwanda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">massacres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Wish To Inform You That Tomorrow We Will be Killed With Our</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gourevitch</ENAMEX>'s narrative demonstrates the "collective criminality"
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan Hutus</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors hacking neighbors</ENAMEX> to death--as well as the
all-too-familiar inaction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. The NYT</ENAMEX> reviewer, who notes that
clothed skeletons still litter the floor of one death-church-turned-memorial,
fears that the rehabilitation envisioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gourevitch</ENAMEX> may yet be a long way
off.

         
      
   
