
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courting Disaster</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the ruling by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s highest
court that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> cannot be tried in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> for anything he did
while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>. (The story makes everybody's front.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> go with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s unveiling of its
economic reform plan, thought to be crucial for keeping the world's spreading
economic downturn from taking hold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Hemisphere</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with a story first fronted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> : the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>'
eleventh hour decision to unleash anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign ads that refer to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> via the ancient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX> common law precept that a sovereign is immune from prosecution, and held that the
Nuremberg principles did not apply because there is no international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>
handling charges that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> ordered mass murders and torture. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> are left with the sole option of appealing the decision to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX>, which with its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX> and conservative make-up, is not likely to
reverse the decision when it takes up the matter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as next week</TIMEX>. Until
then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> remains a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> at a luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, sufficiently
medicated, reports the paper, that he is probably unaware he is under arrest.
Yes, he's still under arrest, which is why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front-page reefer
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Court</ENAMEX> Frees <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>" is a bit off.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> plan generates <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23.5 billion</NUMEX> in additional
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funds</ENAMEX> via roughly equal parts tax increases and spending cuts and
proposes reducing the expenditures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s lavish social security
system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the austerity moves are "likely to produce a
punishing recession," but suggests this cure isn't as bad as the disease of a
currency devaluation, which it says, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is determined to avoid. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> emphasizes an aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s financial plight that should be
familiar to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>: the question of whether or not the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has the will to pass it.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can't be trusted" is how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> sums up the message of the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> ads, one dominated by the famous finger-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wag</ENAMEX> that accompanied the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s denial of having sex "with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>." The paper
goes on to quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> responding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by accusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of
trying to distract the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> record. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in
its front page follow-up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, reports that despite previously telling his
party's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to steer clear of the scandal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> personally
approved the ads. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are
gleeful because they think the ads will create a big backlash against
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            It's become a commonplace of the debate over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> investigation that it
cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $40 million</NUMEX>, but until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, there's been no public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nail</ENAMEX>-down about where the money went. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , fed information by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, fronts some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> expenditures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> ethics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Dash</ENAMEX>, for instance, gets a meta-Socratic <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> an hour, putting
together, says the paper, many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-hour</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. And there was the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$729,000</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> on travel. Not to
mention the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19,000</NUMEX> per month to put up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in a luxury
apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. And the real oral obscenity of the whole case may be this:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s lunch with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> came in at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$127.42</NUMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attacked training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> associated with terrorist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX> and government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> stressed that the incoming cruise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> were not targeting bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> wondered why,
since bin Laden is not protected by this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s policy against assassinating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads of state</ENAMEX>, since he's not one. Well, according to the LAT front,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> do not in fact believe the policy constrains
them in their dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> add however that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
acts against terrorism, unlike say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> assassination plots against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>,
must be publicly acknowledged afterwards.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> feature describes the advent of a new
kind of for-pay Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>: sites that, using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> data, track the comings and goings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, says the paper, are not pleased, concerned that
their activities will be exposed to everybody from stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrorists</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>' watchdog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (just what are all those planes
doing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamptons</ENAMEX> anyway?).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP TV</ENAMEX> column reports a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> criminal defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is suing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldo Rivera</ENAMEX> in connection with on-air comments <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX> made. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> says
that during a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> show about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex scandal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX> promised to
pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> to anyone who could find a case brought against someone for lying
about sex. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> claims he sent in information about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> such cases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX> is refusing to pay because, he says, he had offered the bounty for
"cases like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s, of a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX> of a sex lie told in a
dismissed civil case." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that the cases submitted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> include a federal case, but involving a lie sworn to in a criminal case.
Guess it depends on what "case" means.

         
      
   
