
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Settling News</ENAMEX>

Times --lead with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$850,000</NUMEX> settlement reached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>, which will end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-1/2 year</TIMEX> sexual
harassment case against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. Under the agreement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> offers no
apology to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>--a condition which "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>] had once called her most important
demand," notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must pay Jones within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX>; the money
is expected to come from insurance or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legal defense fund. Real estate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magnate Abe Hirschfeld</ENAMEX>'s flamboyant offer to pay Jones <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> is not part
of the settlement. The agreement must first be approved by the federal judge
who dismissed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> suit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, but this should be routine.

            Purveying the logic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> side, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> commented, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has decided he is not prepared to spend one
more hour on this matter." One jubilant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> quoted in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says, "What this means is that not a single one of those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">750 days</TIMEX>
[left in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s term] will be taken up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>." All papers conclude
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> settlement brings <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> one step further toward closing the
impeachment proceedings.

            In other scandal developments, carried in all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> counsel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> sent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> boxes of new documents on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> volunteer who has alleged that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
of groped her. The new information--which was not made public--"did not contain
a formal accusation of wrongdoing against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," avers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . The
papers concur that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> is unlikely to delay the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> impeachment
inquiry. In a separate development, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s former law partner
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX> was slapped with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-count indictment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuses Hubbell</ENAMEX> of lying to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has already brought two
indictments against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell; Hubbell</ENAMEX> has already served <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX> in federal
custody. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s frustrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Nields</ENAMEX>, commented, "It is not normal
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> to keep indicting the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> over and over again."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front stories on a landmark <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$206 billion</NUMEX>
settlement proposal reached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--a topic
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ran as a lead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Wednesday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> had sued to
recover costs of smoking-related medical care. Under the agreement--the details
of which should be finalized by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>--tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would face various
marketing restrictions, including a ban on billboard advertising. Before the
settlement is implemented, it must be ratified by most of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">38</ENAMEX> states
with pending or contemplated suits against tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            With few major new developments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> standoff, all papers run
front-page stories on violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Troops</ENAMEX> and riot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>
fired on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> demonstrations by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of anti-government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>,
mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. At least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are dead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> writes that it was the
"bloodiest day of street battles since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">then-president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> last
May."

            An excellent piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX>" section chronicles the growing dissent to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Consensus</ENAMEX>," a post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
methodology that favors open markets and freer trade. Alarmed by the global
financial crisis, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, notably <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>, are pushing for stronger
global economic regulation. Specific proposals have ranged from establishing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">new U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> for economic affairs to setting exchange rate
targets. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, buoyed by the "spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> capitalism,"
tends to be averse to increased global regulation.

            Those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">royals</ENAMEX> are feuding again. This time, says a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> in the doghouse. Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>' media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gurus</ENAMEX>
have spun the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> as steady and reliable, in contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s wildness.
This is sacrilege against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Di</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> stories also contain unpardonable
hints that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> is tired of the shadow of his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth II</ENAMEX>,
and actually wants to be king someday. As implicit punishment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> will skip her dear son's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">50th</NUMEX> birthday fete <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> for, um, an
unfortunate scheduling conflict.

         
      
   
