
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl Cuts</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> election results, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schroeder</ENAMEX> defeated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>, a story that makes everybody's front. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf Coast</ENAMEX> arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Georges</ENAMEX>. The big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , is the flooding that is likely when the storm hits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>,
where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> have taken <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> in such locales as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Superdome</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">convention center</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>'s final total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>
home runs, achieved via his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> straight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HR</ENAMEX> game, a story that gets
top-of-the-page-with-picture coverage everywhere.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX>'s policies differ little from those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>--and his election expressed a hunger for a new face more than a new
direction." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> sees a bigger difference, saying that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> campaigned on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s rise from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazism</ENAMEX> and its role in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX> talked about jobs.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that strategy worked because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> are "tired of history
lessons" and concerned that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> is fraying. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> cites both
the "new face" and unemployment angles.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Democratic Party</ENAMEX> polled <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41 percent</NUMEX> of the vote, but will
still need, note the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, to enter into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> with another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> to rule <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possibility mentioned is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDP</ENAMEX> will hook
up with the left-leaning/enviro <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Greens</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> mention that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greens</ENAMEX> have long opposed the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">set-up</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> adds that any
such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> would have to worry about radical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greens</ENAMEX> bolting. Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>: the successor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> gained parliamentary strength
in the vote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the numbers are such that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX> doesn't
have to enter an alliance with the neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says he has
promised not to. There is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other recurring difference in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>
coverage: all but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> render the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>'s name "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX>," while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ochs Sulzberger</ENAMEX> bund foregoes that "oe" for an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">o</ENAMEX>" under an umlaut.

            The sort of story that, post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, has been far too scarce appears today
on the LAT front: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s long-time defense business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>
Vartabedian reports that new government information out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> shows that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> still can't protect itself against embezzlement and overpayment.
According to the story, there have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> embezzlement in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, featuring such dodges as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> creating fictitious contracts and
then honoring them--with checks to themselves. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> case in the story: an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> who arranged for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more $900,000</NUMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> who tried to alert <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to this were...removed
from their jobs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> financial controls have gotten
weaker under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> "reinvention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." Of course,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> should have mentioned that this hardly counts against the idea of
streamlining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>--it only shows that not all reinventions are equally
good ones.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two weeks</TIMEX> before the federal
government runs out of money, twelve of the thirteen spending bills remain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unsigned</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that getting very little attention beneath all
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> mayhem are special provisions that have added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX> bill, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of millions</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> and housing bill and to
the energy bill, to name a few. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is rather stinting on details,
compared to say, its coverage of dress stains, and runs the story on page
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature explores a
worrisome unintended consequence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticide strictures</ENAMEX> in the food safety
law passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>: to ensure compliance, some top pesticide
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> have resumed testing their products on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, a practice that, although legal,
they'd abandoned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, scores of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> are now swallowing small doses of toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>. Sometimes, the
paper reports, test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> are told that they are ingesting a "drug" not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticide</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> has formulated and signed an "affidavit of integrity" declaring that
"he has never: committed adultery; abused his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; engaged in
homosexual activity; experimented with illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>; or been charged with or
convicted of a felony." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, where's the cigar clause?

         
      
   
