
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> Yields

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s announcement that he will not run
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
citing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> present at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> conference calls, say
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> will also resign from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, whom he called cannibals, of having
"blackmailed" him into resignation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX> edition, citing a prepared statement
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, does not report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> will definitely give up his
seat in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, but does quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> as saying it is
"unlikely he will fill out his term." The papers all note that long--time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-La.) announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the day</TIMEX> that he himself
intends to seek the post.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car bomb</ENAMEX> explosion at a crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> marketplace gets top
international coverage at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> papers. All report that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> were
killed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystanders</ENAMEX> were injured, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
government has halted all discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wye Memorandum</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Islamic Holy War</ENAMEX>" is responsible for
the attack.

            Front page stories at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble</ENAMEX>, the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bookseller</ENAMEX>, will purchase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingram Book Group</ENAMEX>, the
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesaler</ENAMEX>, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> cash and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400 million</NUMEX> in stock.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> that currently buy books from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingram</ENAMEX> are
nervous--unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> quash the deal, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">booksellers</ENAMEX>' biggest
retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> will own their main source of wholesale books.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> television has decided not to air <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">prime-time</TIMEX> special about the theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> that downed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX>, always on the qui vive for a good conspiracy, may want to do some
background checks on those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who protested the
special--allegedly for fear that it would be perceived as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>
report.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> obituary remembers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX>, who died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 83</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kane</ENAMEX> co-created the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Caped Crusader</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detective Comics</ENAMEX> when he was just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years old</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> run front-page pieces on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s decision not to run for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>,
raised by a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hell's Kitchen</ENAMEX>, has held, among a
series of impressive jobs, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> professorship, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chair</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, and an ambassadorship to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Business</ENAMEX> article says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> have grown so
pessimistic about the economy that they are "investing" in bonds with negative
interest rates. That's right, guaranteed losers. Why? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are in such disarray that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> will pay to put their money
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Treasury</ENAMEX> bills at a small, but guaranteed, loss.

         
      
   
