
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Bill</ENAMEX> and Change for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with the drop in unemployment from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.6</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.4 percent</NUMEX>.
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> say that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>'s strong employment
levels occurred despite recent corporate announcements of upcoming job
cutbacks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Papers wonders why these papers think layoffs that will
happen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX> would have any effect on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s employment
statistics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>
statistics show a troublesome gap between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, whose production is
down due to overseas financial trouble, and service industries, which continue
to produce lots of jobs, but at lower wages.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have requested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX>
Committee allow them to present an expanded defense over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 3 to 4 day</TIMEX> period
instead of the currently allotted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that if the
Committee allows it, this move might push the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s vote on impeachment into
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> explains that this would mean more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> votes
and also adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is considering accepting a fine and censure from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Congressional negotiations are stalled over a dollar amount, however,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX> are proposing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> upwards of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 million</NUMEX>. All the
papers report that the expanded defense would focus on the independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counsel</ENAMEX>'s misconduct and on the definition of an impeachable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> imprisoned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> wants
to donate a kidney to his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>--again. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, serving time
for burglary, has already given one kidney to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and his selflessness
is now causing a dilemma for local surgeons and medical ethicists. The case has
been referred to a university bioethics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that must weigh factors such
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hippocratic Oath</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, do no harm") and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the estimated $40,000</NUMEX> a year
cost of dialysis that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison system</ENAMEX> would have to pay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> had not met before the first kidney transplant, but have stayed in
close contact since.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> announced the formation of a presidential exploratory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>, meaning he'll try for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs the story on its front, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> --despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
close ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX>--runs it inside with a front-page
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reefer</ENAMEX>. The papers agree that, while still a long shot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> poses the most
serious threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s nomination.

            A fascinating WP piece reports that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
press, military, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> have publicly condemed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> who was
beaten and stoned by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Wednesday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say that his
failure to defend himself by firing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> has humiliated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> asks, "...have we turned into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp state</ENAMEX>?" The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soldier</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">draftee</ENAMEX>, suffered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> lacerations, blurred vision
and hearing loss. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> says, "He should have opened fire....In a
situation like that, you shoot to kill." Such criticism has outraged many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> as well, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezer Weizman</ENAMEX> who notes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who
haven't experienced anything of this kind don't have a right to speak."

         
      
   
