
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dally With Sally</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with a sweeping <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-days-to-elections
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times both go with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that it refuses to
cooperate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also fronts this
story).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s statement "the boldest move yet to evade
international disarmament efforts." In protesting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> decision to keep sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in place, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> plans to end
cooperation with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100</NUMEX> plus international arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> and shut down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
weapons monitoring operations immediately--though some surveillance equipment
may remain in place. This latest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> intransigence comes on top of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> move to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> spot checks. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> also wants to oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons monitoring mission to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> immediately convened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> to denounce <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s move but
proposed no specific solutions to this latest crisis. (A separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" piece describes the debilitating fissures within
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and international strategies for handling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead concludes that despite the media blitz, "neither party
appears to have strong momentum" going into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s elections. The WP
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front their own election stories--an above-the-fold WP
piece says that a shift in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> power is unlikely, though the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> may well gain several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seats. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> focuses on the
new "cautiousness" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> as they struggle to redefine themselves. This
caution is reflected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' "modest agendas": The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> tend to
adhere to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, HMO reform, and education, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
seek tax cuts, increased defense spending, and more state control of education
initiatives.

            Arguing that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> can take the form of accountability," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Minow</ENAMEX> (in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook"</ENAMEX>) defends <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconciliation Commission</ENAMEX>, which has been bombarded with criticism since the
release of its final report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. Specifically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> supports the
"dignity" which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRC</ENAMEX> accords to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, and its refutation of the "amnesia
and denial that so often follow periods of national atrocity." With the
experience and knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> now must set about actively
transforming its future. A separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who participated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRC</ENAMEX> says
that despite some flaws in the process--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' lives did not materially
improve, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> may still lie about their full involvement--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRC</ENAMEX>
symbolizes an attempt to move forward, rather than sink into the "spiral of
violence and revenge" that often engulfs the aftermath of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th-century</TIMEX>
atrocities.

            All papers front stories on new evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> had an affair
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with one of his slaves. Carefully researched DNA
evidence points "within the limits of scientific certainty" ( LAT ) to the
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> has descendants through his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX>. Hemings,
who was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29 years</TIMEX> younger than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>, was herself the mulatto <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> have long discredited the idea of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> liaison and are stunned by this revelation (which will appear
in full in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> ). Echoes of the current scandal abound;
they are developed in an intriguing inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> article. Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalist Thomson Callender</ENAMEX>--who exposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Hamilton</ENAMEX>'s adultery--wrote
a story about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson's</ENAMEX> affair in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX> Recorder (even after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> had paid him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>!). Partisan reaction was severe: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> called
Callender a "clot-hearted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scot</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> himself wrote that "the
federalists have opened all their sluices of calumny."

         
      
   
