
   
   
      
         
            Not Erection Results

            The elections rule. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> slugs the story "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> Dash <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> Hopes," and
its front-page "cover story" says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> brought "good news for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
wasn't on the ballot," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
main headline reads in part, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> Hold Off G.O.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P. Advance</ENAMEX>, Weakening
Impeachment Prospects...." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times headline lavishes its big type on the victory of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race, the re-election to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX> and the victory of the initiative permitting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>-run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>.
And the headline over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead credits the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> with scoring
significant upsets-- the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , like everybody else, stressing the defeat
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonse D'Amato</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauch Faircloth</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>.

            The papers cite the general satisfaction exiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> expressed--with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, with the economy, and with their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> in life. And everybody says
6o percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should not be impeached. The upshot is
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will not achieve a filibuster-proof <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Although, as everybody notes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> do retain control of both
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            The press consensus is that the only real bright spots for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
are the victories of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> gubernatorial
races. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s re-election instantly makes
him the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple</ENAMEX> says
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bushes</ENAMEX> are to be reckoned serious presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen</ENAMEX>
Dowd only seems to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-joking when she suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> form
a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> ticket in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> story details a little-noticed aspect
of the emerging e-marketplace: large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are moving slowly into
Internet marketing, not really any longer because of misgivings about its
power, but because it threatens to destroy traditional hands-on sales <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>,
which still constitute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 90 percent</NUMEX> of most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' order flow. For
instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ponies up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> who has made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
additional sales <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> with the help of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automaker</ENAMEX>'s Web sites, but who
also worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> might someday just take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>' orders directly and get
rid of him.

            With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> relentlessly rah-rahing over the latest exploits of the home
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>, often, amazingly, on the front page, it's sobering to take in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed on the rampant
criminality of professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. According to the piece, it's
look-the-other-way day in the front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Vermeil</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX> is quoted saying this about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linebacker</ENAMEX> charged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> with
involuntary manslaughter in a crash in which the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> died: "I think
it'll be good for him to get back and get with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX> and get going
again." Then there's another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ram</ENAMEX> who plays on despite having pleaded guilty to
aggravated assault in a case where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> suffered partial paralysis and
brain damage. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dolphin</ENAMEX> wide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receiver</ENAMEX> who, despite one conviction
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> arrests for beating his fianc,e, was offered a new contract by the club
and has never been disciplined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Benedict</ENAMEX>, claims
that a study he helped conduct shows that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> has been
charged with a serious crime.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caldor</ENAMEX> department store
chain has apologized for unwittingly publishing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 million</NUMEX> copies of an
advertising circular in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> smiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> are depicted playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scrabble</ENAMEX>
around a game <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> where the pieces clearly spell out the word "RAPE."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , famous for applying wholesomeness principles to its copy,
outdoes itself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reliable Source's</ENAMEX> item about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election day</TIMEX>
get-together of old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> includes this quote from one of them: "If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> went
off in this place, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s known supply of [equine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">droppings</ENAMEX>] would be destroyed." Can't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> see that whereas the
actual phrase used would go by virtually unnoticed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s baroque
translation only forces the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to dwell on the matter?

         
      
   
