
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Too Much</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with its poll indicating that despite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">bad day</TIMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s job approval rating hit <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> runs a story inside about its
similar poll findings--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly two-thirds</NUMEX> of those it surveyed approve of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s job performance--but leads with the warning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration's senior national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>: whenever necessary, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will bomb you again to prevent the
development or use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and/or germ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. (Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>: Ixnay on
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Himmler</ENAMEX>.") USAT fronts this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> story as well. Both it and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> cite their own polls' finding that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 80 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> approve of the just-concluded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
each focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s struggle with the issue of whether or not it still
has the option of brokering some sort of resolution to the crisis besides a
trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Predictably, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> find a party
split--generally, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are open to alternatives and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
not.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> policy shift is that henceforth,
it will not view action by or relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>, nor
approval by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> or any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX>, as required for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. It is a measure of the times that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> paragraphs in, this
story veers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s acknowledgement that she'd been misled last
winter by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s denials to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> of an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. But then the story regains its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of gravity, making the point
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> policy turn, with its open-ended commitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>, means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has de facto abandoned the recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> policy mantra that military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deployments</ENAMEX> were okay only if
accompanied by a clear exit strategy. This should have been put high in the
piece, above the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> swerve. Similarly, the LAT front-pager on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
policy, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">estimable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Wright</ENAMEX>, pushes down to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">14th</NUMEX> paragraph the
claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is now "almost irrevocably involved" until the objective
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toppling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> is achieved. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> inside piece on all this focuses
instead on the sparse details of what is currently known about damage to raid
targets.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead, assessing the damage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, makes the point that--despite the
widely reported <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> claims of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX>--Western assessments of
few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian casualties</ENAMEX> gain credence because, contrary to past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>, foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have not been invited to view bombed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> first--the opening wave of strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
included a female <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> carrier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>. A sign of the gradual normalization of
the once-hot-button "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in combat" issue: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> runs the story on page
18.

            A story inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports another <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>--the inaugural combat
use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX>. The story's headline speaks of the very expensive and
long-underused <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s "vindication," but this seems to be overselling. The
story's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> saying that "vindication might not be the
right word," and waits until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> paragraph to reveal that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
had not yet been able to assess the damage done by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>' strikes."

            The LAT fronts, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs inside, news that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX> has given birth to octuplets. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX>'s headline mentions that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had taken fertility <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are creating incredibly expensive
and complicated births--shouldn't they be flagged as a big part of the
story?

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> run front-page pieces saying that the
recent dip in the national savings rate isn't necessarily bad. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing,
notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , to some extent, the savings rate is based on
conventions such as not counting capital gains as income that make it look
worse, and for another, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , with much of the rest of the
world mired in recession, this may not be a good time to tighten our belts
anyway. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> mentions something else that seems like it could in
fact be a silver lining in this supposed cloud: the big fear that the majority
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> will wind up working longer than they expected because they
didn't save enough for their retirement. But wouldn't that delay the huge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomer</ENAMEX> claim on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, thus giving that system more of a chance to
get well?

            While engaging in his regular drubbing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> today
along the way actually gives him some very practical advice: under pain of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial, sign a very tough censure deal, and pay off everybody's legal
fees by auctioning off the pen.

         
      
   
