
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS Coupes</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of the leads address a common theme: strengthening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' rights.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with a new proposal by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that would
solidify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' protections against being refused hospital treatment on
financial grounds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times goes with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will propose expanding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> to allow those with disabilities to continue receiving
benefits even if they work. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead states that the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is well positioned to pass new
controls on managed health care plans. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a focus on the latest industrial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giants</ENAMEX> to be suspected of profiting during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>' use of
slave labor--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> explains that new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human</ENAMEX> services regulations coming
out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> would make it clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> cannot delay care while
awaiting coverage approval from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says
it's unclear how many cases there have been of this sort of insurance-based
"dumping," but adds that during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1998 fiscal year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> noted a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>
dumping cases. The story says that hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> insist they already treat
all emergencies, and that the real, continuing problem not addressed by the new
guidelines is what to do about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who present at emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> for
routine primary care.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> disability proposal--similar to a bipartisan bill that
didn't make it to a floor vote in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--is designed to correct the
feature of current law under which the disabled usually have to choose between
working and keeping their health insurance--particularly perverse in the many
cases when it's precisely the insurance that provides the therapy and/or
medicine that allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to hold a job. Currently, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight million</NUMEX>
disabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of working age receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $50 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental Security Income</ENAMEX>, says the paper, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 1</NUMEX>
percent of them work.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> cites a signal reason why prospects for federal health care
reform are looking up: the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> looks more favorably
on it than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> did. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>-elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-sponsor</ENAMEX> of a defeated bill that would have allowed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> to sue an HMO
for damages when the plan's withholding of authorization was linked to harm he
or she suffered. Some such provision is likely to be revisited, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , in this next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> vote-getting compromise mentioned is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> would be allowed to sue their HMO only after they've exhausted
all the plan's internal administrative appeals.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says some of the information in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford/GM</ENAMEX> story was first revealed in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> congressional
inquiry, but is relevant again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and is being augmented with additional
evidence because of new class-action suits being filed on behalf of former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave laborers</ENAMEX>, in the wake of recent similar and successful legal moves
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. There is no question that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> had large German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subsidiaries</ENAMEX>, nor that these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX> provided ample slave-labor-produced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">materiel</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> war effort. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> was the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> was number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. The primary issue to be litigated, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , will be how much knowledge and control the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automakers</ENAMEX> had with
respect to their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>. Virtually none, say the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Still, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> will probably be interested to learn that as late as
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 1938</TIMEX> both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ford</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> received the highest
Nazi medal. One defect in the story: It says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s role in the German
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rearmament</ENAMEX> effort in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> was "much less significant" than that of the
other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. But a little elaboration is required--after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>
is now joined at the balance sheet with longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> auto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colossus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX>.

            Online advertising, reports a front-pager at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , appears to be taking off. Some say
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 80 percent</NUMEX> of the Net's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> ad slots went unsold, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-half</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> spending for cyber ads totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$774 million</NUMEX>, double <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>.
Plusses of the new ad medium: It's excellent for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">start-ups</ENAMEX>, where on-line
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commerce</ENAMEX> is often stressed, and on-line <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> seem more accommodating to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> than print or broadcast, especially regarding old-line
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>-and-state issues about blurring the line between editorial and
advertising content. Big negative: Still-high per-consumer-reached costs.

            There's a curious lapse in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s effort by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's generally
excellent media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX>. Kurtz somewhat breathlessly reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne Daley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , was mortified when
right in front of her, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX> made a sexist remark about her to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lelyveld</ENAMEX>. But this is hardly a scoop and in any
case, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX>'s scoop. He neglects to mention that the story was published
more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks ago</TIMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>'s byline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
