
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwarf</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> stories on its front, but leads
instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> elections, which garner big
front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> at the other papers. The only real news there is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s only black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, ascended to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
posts.

            Everybody stresses that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conduct in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter was part of a general pattern of misusing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to
prevent the dissemination of damaging information about him, but it's also
pointed out everywhere that his testimony will contain the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> revelation
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has exonerated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> travel office
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">firings</ENAMEX> and in connection with the transferal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> background files to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. It's apparent from the accounts that the other major area of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alleged Clinton</ENAMEX> dissembling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has in mind is his original raison
d'^tre , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX>, both in connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> trial of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Guy Tucker</ENAMEX>, and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
apparent involvement in the channeling of funds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX> after the
latter's conviction. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> goes out of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for his encouragement, in a TV interview, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX>'s continued silence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> most clearly the dimension
in which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s testimony is an advance over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s previous written report:
that document spoke of possible grounds for impeachment, whereas according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "should be removed from office."

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> write from advance copies of his prepared testimony made
available by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, and they all report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> during
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s appearance. They also all mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has not yet replied to
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> questions submitted to him by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>, pleading lack of
time given the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> crisis, but it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> that mentions in this
connection that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> played golf on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. On the other hand, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also has a quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> in which he gives up the game of merely
being a disinterested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">searcher</ENAMEX> for truth. Asked if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> needed to hit a home
run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> is quoted: "I'd settle for a line drive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over third</NUMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also mention that neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> nor committee <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
are pleased that the time to question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has been limited, but none mentions
that in his testimony before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> likewise limited the
amount of time he sat for questions.

            A WSJ front-page feature depicts the interactions of a computer industry
consortium focused on keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> at bay, the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOISE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>:
Netscape, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> and Everybody else. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claims that in the
service of their goal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have engaged in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabal</ENAMEX>"-like behavior, and
that the fate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> may affect the future of the software industry
far more than the outcome of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> anti-trust trial. The story states
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> explanation of why such consorting is not an anti-trust
issue the way it says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s activities are: "monopolies and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> play by different rules."

            Ever wonder where, in a tickerless financial world, all that paper for
ticker tape parades come from? Well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports, in the
"Business Bulletin," that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX>'s parade at least, some of the stuff
was a resume. No word on how the paper, er, pieced the story together.

            There is a bunch of coverage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on the prospects for any internal,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-supported overthrow of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pager</NUMEX> describes
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> as weary of the squabbling between <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>,
and says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is still funding is likely riddled with
double <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. And a confluent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial concludes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> cannot be
overthrown without an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> invasion and occupation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has a
front-page effort that quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> as saying the plan of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> rebel is
akin to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pigs</ENAMEX>. The piece also includes this ringing assessment from
another expert: "The only military skill [the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>] have ever
demonstrated is the ability to fight each other over smuggling rights."
Apparently, there is no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
