
   
   
      
         
            Never Mind

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s
abrupt decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to drop (after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two days</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
campaign finances from the areas it will consider in its impeachment inquiry.
The move is also fronted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
which leads instead with the coordinated decision of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to
cut their interest rates. This story is also flagged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news index where the move is
called the effective birth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> monetary union (officially, still a
month away), but it's missing from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>' fronts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with word that the unseasonably warm weather much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is
experiencing has been bad for seasonal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> like ski tourism and for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">winter</ENAMEX>-related commodities like heating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> off-lead adds that the warm spell has hurt
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> retail sales, primarily because shelves are stocked with winter
gear.

            The LAT explanation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>'s finance plug-pull is a quite bald
political one: that there is enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> evidence to support going forward.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the move came after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> read the
DOJ fundraising-related memos the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> had just gotten. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
spells this out: the committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">honchos</ENAMEX> think the memos contain no evidence of impeachable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">offenses</ENAMEX>. Of course, there is another reason nobody mentions: while it's
likely that few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> currently have interns working, er, under
them, almost all of them get off on soft money.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> raises another explanation for not taking on a new area: speed.
The paper quotes incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s observation that there will be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, which could be a deciding
difference, since everyone reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeachment vote will be
extremely close.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that draft censure resolutions--some
requiring a fine and/or a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fess-up--are being much discussed in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, especially among moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            Those who think the drive to impeachment is simply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
mean-spiritedness, should note that according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , at a press
briefing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> asked if there were any questions on
something other than impeachment, "He was met with a chorus of nos from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>...."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-nation <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> interest cut is a drastic
shift in policy, coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two months</TIMEX> after these same central bankers
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adamantly</ENAMEX> refused to cut because of fears of inflation. But it's clear now,
says the paper, that if anything, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> example cited:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>) are on the verge of deflation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" notes that at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s impeachment
hearings, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perjurers</ENAMEX> who testified were not sworn in.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> weighs in against the ever-widening
search for what he calls "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> guilt money" in the coffers of now-respectable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> says this is wrong because there
are so few <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> left who will actually benefit from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confiscation</ENAMEX>. What will mainly happen, he writes, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> will get rich
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> will get powerful, and there will be a revival of the Shylock
stereotyping of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> would draw the line at restitution for actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> represented by pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. The pro bono point is probably right,
but otherwise <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> disagrees. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> will think what they will think,
but there's nothing inherently unseemly about seeking to return money from the
wrong hands to the right ones. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> is wrong if he thinks there
still aren't plenty of right ones--because it's not just the actual survivors
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> who were grievously injured by the profiteering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. Any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis</ENAMEX> is also among
their direct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. As long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">WW II</ENAMEX>'s damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> walk the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>,
fighting for them is a just cause.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corrections</ENAMEX>" box admits that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 15th</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in</ENAMEX>
Review" piece about foreign translations of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> movie titles contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
bogus examples--Internet spoofs that got by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. But like many a
correction, this admission is incomplete: the wrong titles are not mentioned.
You have to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> to find out, for instance,
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barb Wire</ENAMEX>" was erroneously translated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> as "Delicate
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Orbs of Womanhood Bigger Than Your Head Can Hurt You</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
