
   
   
      
         
            From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Hyde</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are dominated by the political reactions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX> vote forwarding articles of
impeachment to the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. Most of the leads report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> specifies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Delay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> cite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>) have called for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to resign and then have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remarks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> rejecting the suggestion, saying the possibility
has never even crossed his mind. And all but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s renewed
denial that he committed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>-related perjury.

            All the papers save <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">USAT</ENAMEX> cite worsening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> prospects for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, with the LAT quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schumer</ENAMEX> as saying the odds for
impeachment are now "quite strong." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> factor that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker-designate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>'s pronouncement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that he thinks
a censure alternative should be kept from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> consideration. This would
remove a non-impeachment option that would have still allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticize Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are
planning various procedural moves to try to force censure before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
anyway. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> cites fresh polling--with nice high mentions of sample size
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">865</ENAMEX>) and margin of error (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX>)--indicating that popular opposition to
impeachment has slipped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has some unusually harsh language from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> is quoted
and I think it's reflective in his foreign policy....<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> knows it
and that's why he jerks his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> all the time." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Tauzin</ENAMEX> saying, "You see he's lied to me personally on a very serious
matter," referring, says the paper, to the energy tax in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> budget deal.
The paper explains after these quotes that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has never been well liked
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page pic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> touching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX>'s headstone
reveals the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand-yard</NUMEX> stare, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> looked fatigued and that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of his day</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> "his eyes had
narrowed to slits."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts do "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-in-the-street" stories
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> public sentiment regarding impeachment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT 's</ENAMEX> is focused on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abilene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. And of course, both pieces
quote a colorful array of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> on both sides of the question. Now, what
do these pieces really accomplish? At least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has the excuse that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canton</ENAMEX> has been an uncanny bellwether of presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> in several
elections. But still, such <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> are utterly random and anecdotal. Polls are
bad enough, but these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> are basically bad polls.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature describes a
stunning reason why nuclear proliferation may finally have become unstoppable:
the radical availability now of the raw computing power nuclear weapons
programs require. The story convinces right off the bat, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineering</ENAMEX> school explaining how you could craft a supercomputer
with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple of thousand bucks</NUMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten-minute</TIMEX> trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fry's Electronics</ENAMEX>. After all, the paper
points out, the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX> was designed on computers running
at or below the speed of most current PCs. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ,
under newly loosened export regulations, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has procured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 300</NUMEX>
high-speed computers, some of which have "ended up in the wrong hands."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Justice</ENAMEX> lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case, has since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last April</TIMEX> been charging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $50</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>, compared to his regular fee of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$550</NUMEX> an hour. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boies</ENAMEX> lowered his fee
in order to keep his share of work on the case, would that be illegal?

            In case you're wondering who exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> thinks he is, consider what
he says in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> in response to the claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do
not support impeachment: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX>, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX> had taken a poll, he would
never have preached the gospel."

         
      
   
