
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viagra Falls</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the latest developments in the federal budget
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wrangle</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headline says a final agreement is near, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's says the process is stalled over party differences. (Over their
front-page budget stories, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
sport end-in-sight headlines.) But hey, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--they're both right.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s recommendation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that, because of
newly discovered fire hazards, the insulation be replaced on almost all of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX>. Running <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>/insulation as its off-lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes
instead with a story tipped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on the LAT front--the feds
charging fugitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Robert Rudolph</ENAMEX>, already wanted for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> abortion
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinic</ENAMEX> bombing, with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Atlanta Olympics</ENAMEX> bombing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are concerned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> is being helped to evade arrest,
possibly by anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sympathizers</ENAMEX>.

            Taken together the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> summarize the to-the-moment budget state
of play: IN: the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 billion</NUMEX> education initiative, originally proposed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as exclusively for hiring new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, but as per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">desires</ENAMEX>, local school districts will now retain the flexibility to use the new
money not just for hiring, but also for recruitment, testing, and training of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>; a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> disaster assistance measure for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>; grants to help
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX> pay heating bills; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$950 million</NUMEX> towards a national anti-missile
defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18 billion</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>. OUT: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Billions</NUMEX> for fixing up
dilapidated school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, and national student testing. STILL UP IN THE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIR</ENAMEX>: How to conduct the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>, what to do about pornography on the
Internet, whether or not to require federal health insurance to cover the cost
of contraceptives, and whether or not to keep international family planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> from using <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> funds to influence abortion laws; and whether or
not to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> to promote overseas <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> sales.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> usefully reminds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of a list of items that long ago
fell off the budget bandwagon: a tax cut, new tobacco regulations, a bill of
rights for managed care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and campaign finance reform. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
stresses the political angles available now for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>: the coalescing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to argue that they care about more than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>,
while allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is still
politically relevant.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> stories about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> move point out that the
combustibility of insulation is thought to be a cause of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swissair</ENAMEX> crash off
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nova Scotia</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">229</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The stories note the switch to safer
insulation can be done during regular maintenance, and that it will cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billions</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> will eventually make it mandatory.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front section "cover story" reports that since adopting the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-outfit-fits-all approach through the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have seen a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91 percent</NUMEX> drop in assaults, thefts,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vandalism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> and drug violations.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> run stories inside reporting on the latest
statistics compiled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan Guttmacher Institute</ENAMEX>, which indicate that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s teen pregnancy rate has dropped considerably in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> headline says it's the lowest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 years</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> header says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that the stats indicate a
shift among teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> and towards injectable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contraception</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norplant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Depo-Provera</ENAMEX>, especially among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. Both
papers say these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> are attractive to those who only have sporadic sex
and have trouble with consistent contraceptive planning. This is a little
code-wordy. Do the papers mean that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in question forget to take their
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>? Then they should say so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> further mystifies by citing as
an added explanation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Depo-Provera</ENAMEX> is especially appealing to some
teenagers "because it is impossible to detect." How do you detect an ingested
birth control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>?

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> responded to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s comment here that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> story
about the upcoming congressional elections buried mention of its polling sample
of "but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,004</NUMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It has been pointed out to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> that this is
actually a somewhat larger sample than occurs in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> polls, and is
plenty large to be accurate to within a few percentage points' margin of error.
Further, in a very interesting letter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of polling points
out that although his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> usually delays mentioning the sample size until the
last paragraph or so of a story, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> doesn't use jumps off the
front page, these mentions usually occur much earlier in stories than do
similar references in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that do jump. These are all
good points. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> would suggest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) putting the sample and
margin of error information in the subheadline instead; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) Doing a story some
time explaining how nationwide elections can be reliably predicted by talking
to fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than you see at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> sales have er, come down. Reasons cited: the cooldown of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> hype, fear of side effects and managed-care's crackdown on reimbursement.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> is quoted saying that one factor appears to be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> effect: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> aren't interested in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>-wait for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-minute</TIMEX> ride.

         
      
   
