
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan But Surely</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with details of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s agreement with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>'s
comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>--apparently driven by his desire to finish by the end of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>--that he might narrow the impeachment inquiry by consolidating or dropping
some of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> potential charges described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with a new poll it conducted together with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> that apparently indicates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> now stand a better
chance of re-election than at any previous time during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. The paper
calls that a "good sign for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>." (The paper waits until the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> and
last paragraph of the story to reveal that the poll sample was but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,004</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>.) But a front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent members</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> seem to have instead taken to heart other recent polls suggesting an
emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Republican</ENAMEX> backlash inspired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s initiation of an
impeachment investigation--no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, says the
Times , is currently running a commercial mentioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
scandal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the crux of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> accord is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>
on-the-ground international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> reconnaissance flights designed
to monitor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s withdrawals of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. The other key element,
reported high by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the main thrust of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s commitment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to local elections for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. If the detail
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> seems familiar, that's because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> said they'd been agreed to, whereas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> said
merely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> appeared ready to accept a monitoring force.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> suggest that free elections would result in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s
outright independence. And both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX>
separatist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> wants nothing less. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quantifies the situation,
noting that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> outnumber <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Both
papers observe important loose ends of the emerging deal that could unravel it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> did not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persuade Milosevic</ENAMEX> to allow the international war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> to have
jurisdiction in the region, and the LAT passes along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> might take some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> hostage, thus boxing out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s ability to deter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> via the threat of airstrikes. The LAT
quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>'s response: the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> wouldn't want to interfere with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer force</ENAMEX> because some of is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> would be from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX>-state,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> illustrates its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> story with a top front picture of a
dead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-week-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just five or ten years ago</TIMEX>, it was possible for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to advance to a pretty ripe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> before ever seeing a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. But
not anymore--not if they get a newspaper. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> are invited to notice how
often nowadays the main front-page picture of their paper depicts death.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> fronts run stories about the arrest for
spying of a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> who served as a codebreaker, allegedly for
selling (for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX>) the identity of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> to be nuked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> started a nuclear war. The accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> had been living in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> after retiring from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, but was tricked back to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> by someone working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>--said by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retired FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>--posing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spymaster</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that
this is the latest in a long string of espionage arrests of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-</TIMEX> and low-level
military intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> suggests these have been
facilitated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> access to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> intelligence files.

            In the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> anti-gay murder, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
resultant call for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beefed-up</ENAMEX> hate-crime laws, the ink is flowing about their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisability</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed by a law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's lead editorial all
question whether such laws further the cause of tolerance and suggest that they
represent a threat to the sanctity of prote cted, even if contemptible,
personal thought and speech. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX> carries the ball
somewhat for the other side, arguing in his op-ed that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> paved the
"road to Laramie" by demonizing gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            Due to technical problems, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s column erred in saying that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> led with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. It led with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> passage of a
banking rescue and reform bill.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" states that according to a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> study,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connecticut</ENAMEX> ranked number one in the list of deficit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>
send more money to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> as taxes than they get back as spending. Second
place was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> topped the list of surplus <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s No-Duh! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline</ENAMEX>, from the WP front page: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impact of Market</ENAMEX>
Turmoil Felt Beyond Wall Street."

         
      
   
