
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toupee</ENAMEX> or Not Toupee

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the New York
Times lead with a hardy perennial: the restart of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace
talks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times also front the story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> leads with word that next
month some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal activist groups</ENAMEX> plan to run midterm election TV
spots supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of pursuing his
scandal at the expense of other issues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with what looks
like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> story, but is really a national one: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Wilson</ENAMEX>'s
okaying of moving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s presidential primary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to March 7th</TIMEX>, where it
will be preceded only by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary. The
paper says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> worry that the move could result in half the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three quarters</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> casting ballots within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX>, "compromising
the democratic benefits of a more deliberative primary process." The LAT
also stresses "wide speculation" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>'s move was personal because it
could benefit his presidential bid by giving him a strong showing early on. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> top-front story on the primary move only lightly touches on this
point, after the jump.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USAT</ENAMEX> leads say that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s surprise White
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> meeting between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasir Arafat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>
accomplished an agreement in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel</ENAMEX> accepts a further <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> pullback
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> (in addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> points out helpfully, to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
percent already governed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>). This had been a
sticking point in the past, the papers explain, now apparently unlocked by the
idea (of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> origin, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) of having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly a quarter</NUMEX> of
the evacuated land be declared a nature reserve and hence not occupied by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> either. But a familiar loose end remains loose: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s demands
for specific <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> actions to tighten security in the area. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> characterized the latest talks as making
substantial progress savors of a glass-half-full feeling, while a
glass-half-empty sense comes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>
declined to describe the session as a "breakthrough," and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> as "stone-faced" (although in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's photo, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are smiling somewhat).

            Although it's obvious that successful <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> diplomacy could be a
powerful deflection from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s scandal and could help immeasurably in the
upcoming elections, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> don't make much of this. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> plays it
highest, putting the thought in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> paragraph. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> waits until
after the jump, and although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's story mentions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s
domestic political concerns, it never mentions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead says some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> are worried that a
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ad campaign would siphon off money needed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX> is already "irked" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> for unleashing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>'s particularly aggressive anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>,
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>.

            Stories inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that a study coming out
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> demonstrates the shortcomings of a flagship program designed to help poor
absentee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> earn more and pay more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support. The program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parents</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> Share, which tries to help mostly black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> high-school drop-out
absentee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> via training and counseling, has been found in an independent
study not to have increased their earnings and to have only marginally
increased the amount of money they give their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> mentions in
its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> paragraph a very relevant limit on possible success--that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the program have arrest records. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> doesn't get
around to this until its twelfth paragraph.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column, higher earners
put in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> than those with lower incomes--the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent work
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about an hour</NUMEX> a day longer than the bottom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A century ago</TIMEX> the
situation was reversed. The curves probably crossed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>.

            In an op-ed, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George C. Wilson</ENAMEX> wonders
why, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> now expects most of its missions to be related to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peace-keeping</ENAMEX> and counter-terrorism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> continue to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
to keep buying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion submarines</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> to keep buying stealthy
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$160 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> to buy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40-$60 million</NUMEX> vertical
take-off-and-landing troop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> instead of much cheaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>.

            Wonder why only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>'s speech declaring complete
victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s recent floods--in which he compares the triumph to the way
in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> stood up to the democracy demonstrators
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>. And why does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> run it on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>?

            Meanwhile the bulletins flow like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> on the WSJ front, where a
feature reports that--drum-roll, please--the comb-over is losing market share.
What's more, according to the story, the world is still guessing about whether
or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> wears a toupee.

         
      
   
