
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy Not</ENAMEX> Spooked

            All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> --lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy's surprisingly
strong <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third-quarter</TIMEX> growth rate in the face of the world financial crisis. As
measured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July-September</TIMEX>, the rate was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3 percent</NUMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.8%</NUMEX> in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> (and far exceeding the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> gain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports was
forecast by Wall Street).

            The data, released by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, is treated by all with
a blend of optimism and caution. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX> pulled a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX> and
rocketed up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX> points, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> predict that the economy will slow next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. All papers report that exports fell. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report
that consumer spending rose at a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.9%</NUMEX> rate, below the rate for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months of the year</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.1%</NUMEX>, though neither mentions it). Meanwhile, the WP
goofs by reporting that the consumer spending rose at a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.6%</NUMEX> rate in the third
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>, down from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first six months</TIMEX>. Interpretations as well as
numbers differ. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which calls the consumer spending numbers "very
robust," is less discouraged by the declining rate than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , which both emphasize that consumer confidence is sliding. Another
interpretive discrepancy: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> consulted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> say that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> will probably still reduce short-term interests rates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> say that such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> action is now less likely. Only
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> article points out that the economy's growth supplies the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> with pre-election pep-rally material.

            In other economic news (fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ; enfolded into the lead
support <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> loans to
economies vulnerable to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s malaise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> also outlined some new reforms
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>, such as charging high interest on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> loans to encourage prompt
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">payback</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Court</ENAMEX> voted unanimously that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> has
the right to bring criminal charges against former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>, and seek his extradition from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. This unprecedented
decision directly contradicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British High Court</ENAMEX>'s ruling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. An
appeal is pending, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s action may give more
impetus for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to overturn its ruling.

            As all papers report inside, documents released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> show that on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 25</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> grand jury judge ordered a special investigation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for leak violations. The ruling cited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> news stories as
evidence of possible leak violations. The special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>--whose name is
being kept secret--was given the authority to hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and subpoena
testimony and documents from the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Candidates Deploy Wives as Evidence of Constancy</ENAMEX>" adds an
interesting twist to the pre-election ad wars: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candidates</ENAMEX> (especially older
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>) are putting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> on the air essentially to inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> how
long they have been (faithfully?) married. Among the venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Anne MacKay</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39 years</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy & Mary Barnes</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 years</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike & Kathy Simpson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>: also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 years</TIMEX>.

            The WP fronts an interesting story on a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> secret
electronic surveillance system established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> along
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Burma</ENAMEX> border to eavesdrop on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX>. The specifics of
the surveillance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> are intriguingly murky: It is tiny, staffed by less
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (mostly or all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>), and possibly mobile. The
interceptor device is "run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>" (whatever that means), but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> generated has helped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to crack <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX>
cases--each involving <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 220 pounds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a long feature on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Halloween Horror Nights</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Studios Florida</ENAMEX>. These
spooky events, which have been going on since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2</TIMEX>, feature everything
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chain Saw Drill Team</ENAMEX> lurking outside the haunted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> to a deranged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> who brushes with unsuspecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
good-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naturedly</ENAMEX> complains that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> here are almost as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tight-lipped</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> estimates that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Horror Nights</ENAMEX> bring in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> in revenues for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
