
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dot Commie Plot</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the continuance of the deadlocked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Queenstown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> carries that story inside and goes instead
with another struggle between sworn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> anti-trust suit against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, which goes to trial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> leads all quote a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>'s
information-free comment that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Queenstown</ENAMEX> atmosphere "justifies continuing
these discussions." The main issue is whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will cede a further
parcel of land in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> in return for
various security guarantees, but there's no clear sense in the reporting of
where things stand. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes an official saying real bargaining is taking place, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that right now, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are just anxious to find some
sort of an agreement that all sides could declare a success. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
says that failure to reach an agreement would be a "devastating blow to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s prestige and to the search for a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is
alone in pointing out another source of pressure: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> accords, which
govern the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> peace process, require a final settlement
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>'s borders by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4th</TIMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, while remaining at the
conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>, have not met face-to-face for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX>. The LAT
communicates the dimmest view of what's behind this, referring to "once-bright
hopes" for the summit, and saying there are "ominous signs that things were not
going as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> implied." Citing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> press reports, the
paper says when the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> did last meet in person, the atmosphere was
"tense and at times insulting." In particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> was adamant about
using the biblical terms for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> preferred by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>, and
he complained to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> about the region's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX>.

            Like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> story on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's lead surveys the case from both sides and says
that a key issue will be just what happened at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> meeting between Netscape
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. But also like that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> effort
doesn't explain why if the case pits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> against the feds and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> won't be present in the courtroom. A story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> essays to compare the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX>' cultures, claiming along the way
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> has large, drab <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> has large, cheery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. Well,
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> at least, most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are small and cheery.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> has sued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> over what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>-based retailer
says is an attempt to obtain the trade secrets of its computer system for
identifying and mining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> preference data. Besides the on-line book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>, personally named in the suit is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief information officer</ENAMEX>,
whose previous job was at...<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>.

            The off-lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> follows up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s earlier reporting
on the transfer of satellite technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> describes how quite generally, liberalized trading
rules worked for by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, not only generated increased sales for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
high tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> but also may have allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to obtain a wide range of
sophisticated technology that has already been put to military use.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> led with an enterprise piece about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
prison system is unique in the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in using deadly force to break up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inmate</ENAMEX> fights. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> have killed twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> who were
fighting. This is the latest installment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s repeated looks in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> into the dark corners of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s penal system, all the more
commendable because this degree of follow-up is so unusual. In a profession
obsessed with scoops, it's nice to see some digging instead. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>, take note.

            On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> dedicates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty-some</TIMEX> column<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-inches</NUMEX> to a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" story about widespread plagiarism in political speeches. The story
points to instances of word theft involving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and a host
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. The piece retells in some detail for the umpteenth
time the story of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Biden</ENAMEX> was ridden out of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> presidential
election for what the paper calls "burglary." Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> never mentions
any of the well-documented instances of plagiarism by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, even though
many of them are more recent and at least as flagrant as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX>'s.

            
               Absence-minded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs the following correction: "An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> race misstated the congressional
voting record of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles E. Schumer</ENAMEX>. He was present
for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 77 percent</NUMEX> of the votes this campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>; he did not miss <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>
percent of the votes."

         
      
   
