
   
   
      
         
            Watch This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX>

            It's almost a clean sweep of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX>--his last Tang go
leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front page is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All Glenn All</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and includes a huge spectacular blast-off photo. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> of its front page to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>, but leads with the
death of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A. County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff Sherman Block</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s highest paid elected
official) from a brain hemorrhage in the midst of a re-election campaign where
the main issue was whether he was in good health. Only time will tell if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's reporting was insufficiently aggressive when, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX>
after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX> underwent emergency brain surgery, it ran a headline saying that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>'s "survival is expected."

            The papers see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> launch, viewed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX> and carried live on just about every television station, as a magic
unifying moment for the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Captivated Nation Cheers</ENAMEX>" is how a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headline puts it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> hold
a favorable view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>. And both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> note that
the euphoria all but smothered criticisms that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>'s presence was merely a
publicity stunt. True, in a separate story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> does note that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> has marketing tie-ins (for which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> refused compensation)
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> and with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn Action Pack"</ENAMEX>--toy figures of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut cum senator cum astronaut</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> follows up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">curmudgeonly</ENAMEX> editorial describing the mission as "a testament more to past
eminence than present value" with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Editorial Observer</ENAMEX>" saying that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>'s original blast-off
wasn't that important. But otherwise, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is pretty much in step,
running no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> stories inside. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remarkably</ENAMEX>, even when
discussing the potentially dangerous loss during the launch of a protective
metal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, there is no mention in any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> leads of the space
program's last "special" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christa McAuliffe</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead reveals that as part of the case federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>
are building against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>, they have
filed still-secret charges against an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX>-born former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army Green Beret</ENAMEX>. The ex-soldier
is alleged to have switched from being a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anti-terrorist specialist</ENAMEX> to
being an anti-U.S. terrorist. The article all but comes out and says the man
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> asset, in that it cites his odd military record--he apparently joined
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> as a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> while in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-thirties</TIMEX>--and puts him in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>-managed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insurgency</ENAMEX> there.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> died using his jeep to take an explosion a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> suicide bomber
intended for a bus full of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. (The story is carried
inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .) The papers say that the event is the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real test of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>'s determination to honor his recent commitment
to increased <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> security. He seems to have passed, by immediately
condemning the bombing and placing the spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>, the terrorist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> implicated in the attack, under house arrest. He has also rounded up
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.

            The political story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>--those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>-driven
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ads--continues to develop on the front pages. The WP
elaborates on a point first made by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> --that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
had a hands-on role in the ad campaign. But leave it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> to
observe that for all the press hoopla, very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> have actually seen the
ads, because so far, they have only aired in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>, in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> launch television coverage,
probably speaks for many when he sees the event as a magic opportunity to
escape a relentless political scandal. Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is wryly doing
the same when it quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeleno</ENAMEX>'s description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> who has
managed to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> imagination for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 40 years</TIMEX> "without a
stain."

         
      
   
