
   
   
      
         
            No Flights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fancy</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the New York
Times lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s decision, in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s
apparent stand-down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>, to lift the immediate threat of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airstrikes</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with what it calls "the first sign of
trouble" with the just-brokered <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace accord--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s
postponement of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>'s vote on it, citing doubts about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
compliance. (This story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead is a sharp slide in a leading measure of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consumer
confidence, a story also flagged on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's front-page news box.

            The papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> emphasized it would not hesitate to take
military action if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> violated the commitments it recently made to
peaceful behavior in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX>
activities will be monitored by a multinational aerial reconnaissance effort,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American U</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> (in its inside story on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>) mention another element of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deterrence</ENAMEX>: the decision to send an unspecified number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>--possibly
including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>--to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>. From there, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> could intervene in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , in its front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
story, doesn't mention this deployment.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are very concerned about whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> will respond to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> pullout by resuming their armed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insurrection</ENAMEX>, which is what prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s incursion in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.
The paper reveals that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> recently held extensive talks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>, urging them not to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
in the region. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also points out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> agreement allows
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to fight back if his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> are attacked. With on-the-ground
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reportage</ENAMEX> and interviews, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> stresses the militant attitude of the
Serbs remaining in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> mostly does the flip side, describing
the return of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> to their ravaged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. A statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">variance</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> produced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's number
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference Board</ENAMEX>'s
study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> divined a consumer confidence level at its lowest ebb
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and also a big decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' expectations for the future.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> saying that every recent recession has been
preceded by a drop in this latter measure, although, the paper adds, not every
drop has been followed by recession. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>
saying that recession would be very unusual in the current low-interest
environment. However, such studies are closely watched, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
because consumer spending accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will unveil a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$156</NUMEX>
million effort <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to combat <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> groups
where, despite the general decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> mortality, the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> remains a top
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">killer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> run inside stories on a fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> finding
that in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is cutting life expectancy and will reduce the continent's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next ten to fifteen years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> cites experts
who believe that barring a medical miracle, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Botswana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX> will lose up
to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story on the USAT front and inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> is warning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> not to take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hours</TIMEX> of flying,
because the color discrimination problems sometimes associated with the drug
could make it hard to interpret cockpit gauges and runway lights.

            A letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , who claims to have worked
for some of the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, asks an interesting question: Why
is the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> of monopolistic business practices
when, he says, those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> discourage the purchase of non-Windows
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCs</ENAMEX>?

            The back pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also disclose that a just-released
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s report found that high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
committed a "monumental and calculated abuse of the public trust." How could
the WP possibly justify running <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s reports on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>?
Well, it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report--it's the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s report on
wrongdoing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>, an investigation that got started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than eight years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
