
   
   
      
         
            81 Questions. How Many Answers?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-page written affirmation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> that he did not lie--though he misled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and is sorry
as usual--leads at all papers. In responding to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> questions posed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> interspersed numerous "I don't remembers" with
short statements which did not always directly answer the question.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s responses "shed little
new light on issues surrounding the impeachment inquiry," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times concur. However, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s terse and limited responses,
he did provide some fresh tidbits for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> to mull: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s responses marked the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time he had acknowledged
discussing methods for handling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, his
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>, shortly after the story broke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also noted
for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and reelection
campaign had hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Lenzner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladino</ENAMEX>--though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> insists that their investigation was not the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Secret Police Operation</ENAMEX>" to scrutinize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
has alleged. As an accompaniment to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>
submitted a letter emphasizing that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> did NOT commit or suborn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perjury</ENAMEX>, tamper with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, obstruct justice or abuse power" and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s response was "in good faith."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s confirmation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>
of their merger discussions (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> gives it the Business front). If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> took over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>--the most likely scenario, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say--the resultant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could be worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$160 billion</NUMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . Though both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> stocks leaped at the news, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> uses paragraph <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to cite
cautious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> who worry that various factors--among them the "intense,
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>' chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>"--could yet derail
the deal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> at each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to consider the
agreement, which would then be subject to anti-trust scrutiny by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Commission</ENAMEX>. The merged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would be particularly vulnerable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anti-trust</ENAMEX> charges in its retailing and marketing operations, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , as opposed to the more competitive exploration and drilling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arenas</ENAMEX>.

            All papers run the predictable "It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> and what are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> doing?" stories. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> spotlights the "early-bird" shopping
trend; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> likewise hones in on the bargain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX>, opining that
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> have transformed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> shopping experience into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> giant
national hunt for deals." The LAT optimistically reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southland</ENAMEX>
that revved-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> clogging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> "reinforced a growing belief that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> will have a prosperous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday season</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>."

            An interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living Arts</ENAMEX>" article ponders the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> attributes the increasing involvement of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGOs</ENAMEX> to "the growing complexity of the international agenda," advanced
technology and communications, and declining government involvement in the
post<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-Cold War</ENAMEX> era. But how effective are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGOs</ENAMEX>? is a question of continuing
debate--all the more pressing because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGOs</ENAMEX> lack the democratic accountability
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> must face.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts a story on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canterbury</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">modern-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pardoner</ENAMEX>--whoops,
make that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul</ENAMEX> II. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To usher in the Year 2000</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX> has declared
that anyone who quits smoking or drinking (or eating) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
can get an "indulgence"--a ticket bypassing purgatorial repentance and
smoothing the way to heaven. Upon reading this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> hastily cast away the bottle
and entered a state of deep and transient sobriety. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, that may not be
enough--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papal</ENAMEX> inner circle insists that it's the spirit of participation
that counts.

         
      
   
