
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Self Serbice</ENAMEX>

            The top news is divided between the upcoming midterm election and the
situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with its new poll finding the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in a virtual dead heat in their contest for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the eruption of a financial squabble between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> campaigning
for seats in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> on the one hand and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the
Times lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s carefully conducted withdrawal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> in the face of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> airstrike
deadline.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead states that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s latest sampling gives the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> edge among likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, which is within the poll's 4
percent margin of error. (And the margin of error is given in the second
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paragraph</ENAMEX>, although the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in the sample is in the 13th
paragraph.) According to the paper, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47 percent</NUMEX> of those surveyed say policies
proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the right direction,
while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s policies would lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the
right direction. The paper takes this to mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> like the balance of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> alongside a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. (Of
course, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other possibilities left unmentioned: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a significant
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the same
direction, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are incoherent.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> provides further
interpretation when it quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>'s comment, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX>, this
election looked like a baked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>. Now it seems to be more like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pudding</ENAMEX>," and finds this to mean "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voter</ENAMEX> excitement has dimmed."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead details "unusually bitter" feelings expressed by
several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> desirous of eleventh<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-hour</TIMEX> cash that the party
high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> is instead putting money into erasing party debt and the launch of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s presidential campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates</ENAMEX> apparently also feel that party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have discouraged donations by making dire predictions of a loss of as
many as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> seats. The comment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rangel</ENAMEX> is quoted as
directing towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Romer</ENAMEX>, sums up the mood:
"Keep your money and shut up your mouth."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead) say that
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> a detailed negotiating session between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> and top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> resulted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' pledge to withdraw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,500</NUMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army units</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early Tuesday</TIMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> reported <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> had left the area. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
also says that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> caught some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> heading in the wrong
direction. But once confronted, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> turned them around. The LAT
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> "has probably done enough to escape airstrikes for now...." In
the wake of the pullback, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notices a harbinger of the region's
next problem: the reemergence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> freedom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" front report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has sued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, charging that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has misclassified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> (many of them
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>) as freelancers, wrongly denying them benefits in the
process. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes that the suit marks the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has officially weighed in on the increasingly
contentious issue of holding down employment costs by outsourcing work to those
not considered full-time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s move could extend
well beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, and mentions another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that might get
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross-haired</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half</TIMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial and a paper has finally done a
piece on the oddity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> not testifying in person. Even though he is the
personification of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, an inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story observes that defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> might have viewed him as so "prickly and combustible" as to undermine
his own case. The paper quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who once questioned the world's
richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> live: "At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point he just started screaming, saying that what the
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> was doing to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was socialistic....[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hen</ENAMEX> he got angrier
and called it communistic."

            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> found <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s mention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead story about
how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> was lagging in its share of federal education funds a bit brisk.
They were right. The piece posed a number of issues that cried out for further
attention. It stated that ranking <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">31st</NUMEX> in federal funds per pupil meant that
somehow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> was not getting its "fair share." Well, ideally every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s per pupil amount should be the same, and failing that, one should
expect fair per pupil spending to follow something like a bell-curve
distribution, with most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> over time clustering around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of</TIMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>. So 31st really isn't that bad. And is it right for a paper to promote
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> that hard anyway? Shouldn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ask first if for
instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi</ENAMEX> need the money more?

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, a computer problem halted trading at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX>. The papers give precise accounts
of the standstill with one glaring exception: none mentions the brand of
computer that failed. Is this lazy reporting or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>'s agreement not to
hurt any computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock price?

         
      
   
