
   
   
      
         
            Cost of Livingston

            Everybody leads with the jockeying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>'s gavel. Everybody has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> as the
treat the alternative effort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Cox</ENAMEX> as, albeit fading, still
on the table, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> snags a late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX> in which he says he can't match <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s vote count. The
leads also note that several other top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> slots are likely to be
contested in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> vote coming up on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 18th</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> makes the point that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> used the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> chat shows to politick for their jobs, an
unprecedented exercise. And an odd one, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> at stake are
completely controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caucus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> votes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes this trend too and quotes some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> who don't much like it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> emphasize the main reason most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> wanted the tongue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>: they say he was a lousy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>. (Now
they tell us.) "There was really no clear agenda for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. And when there's
no agenda and there's no real direction, what happens is you can't, you really
can't have a message," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Boehner</ENAMEX> is quoted saying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .
And then he drives the point home with a little too much information about
himself: "You can put lipstick on a pig <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long, but it's still a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>."

            It's not enough that this story leads all around. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also try to
portray it as exciting. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> speaks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> having "scurried" back
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to participate in "party brawls," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls the
episode "dramatic" and "a fast-moving tale." That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speakermania</ENAMEX> grips the papers
this way shows they're a bit out of touch with what seems to be the point of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s election results: the public doesn't care about what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
cares about. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> redeems itself though, by making the only valuable
policy point lurking in all this. Livingston, the paper notes in a sidebar to
its lead, isn't locking up the nomination because of his ideology, policy or
personal style. It's his money --the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> he's given to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> from his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign PAC</ENAMEX>. The paper points
out that such personal "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>" PACs allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to take in and disburse
more and bigger donations than are allowed by the limits on contributions to
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, irked about last
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">spring</ENAMEX>'s tell-all book by an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s inner workings, has
told this term's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supremes</ENAMEX>' secrets are to be kept "forever."
The paper points out that this stricture is not legally binding. USAT
goes on to note that a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Kozinski</ENAMEX>, thinks the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, now an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, broke the law and hence,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> is "no longer welcome" to appear before him. The story does not
explain how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> can control which government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> try cases in his
court.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> after
announcing economic sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> in response to the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX>' atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> tests, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has dropped many of
them--those that were holding up deals involving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>. Sanctions preventing lending by international financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> remain
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has decided to waive even these in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>,
but no such loan has actually been consummated yet.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , which has always been sensitive to aviation safety stories,
follows up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s decision to change the way
electrical wiring insulation on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX> is tested for flammability with a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section package of stories covering various aspects of the problem.
It's sobering to learn that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the world's passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> contain wire
insulation that could be a fire hazard. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> quoted calls wiring the most
serious issue in aviation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports on the activities of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> dedicated to fighting negative images of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. The story says that what they're fighting is the
depiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as "pushy, controlling, selfish, unattractive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">materialistic</ENAMEX>, high-maintenance, shallow, domineering...." A fine goal, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> has its work cut out for it--the most prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> this year
pretty much fits those pejoratives to a T and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> didn't make her up:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
