
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Floor</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s approval of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a fourth</NUMEX> article of impeachment
and rejection of a censure proposal dominate the front pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
papers. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> article of impeachment accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of giving
false or incomplete answers to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> questions previously submitted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HJC</ENAMEX>. In its original form, the article accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of numerous,
far-reaching offenses, including making misleading statements in televised
appearances. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> voted to limit the charges to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> responses in what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> calls a "tactical retreat." The amended
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> was approved by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21-16</NUMEX> party-line vote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> will hold a floor vote on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> articles late next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, but will likely not do the same for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>-sponsored resolution for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">censure</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who says, "Impeachment
by the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is starting to look inevitable."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report details the current crisis faced by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hog
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> devaluation. Due to a glut of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>-production, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog</ENAMEX> (the terms hog
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> are interchangeable, the article explains) that was selling for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$118</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year ago</TIMEX> now fetches <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $45</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s leading hog <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," has been
hit hardest by the price drop. The true gluttons appear to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, who have done little to pass lower livestock costs on to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> front-page piece says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> has conducted
investigations on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> suspected of running marijuana and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX> drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> probes were
conducted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> to sniff out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smugglers</ENAMEX> who likely used their access
to conveniently located military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> to avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Patrol</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Magazine</ENAMEX> drives home its theme (yes, another theme issue)
with its cover. The masthead is printed upside down at the bottom, alerting you
to the message that modern design--from toothbrushes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web pages</ENAMEX>--aims to
catch your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> with "the shock of the familiar." The new style in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web pages</ENAMEX> is
"logical as well as luscious": <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> color, less confusion. In desks, it's
creative clutter (though the clean-swept desktop also has its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX>). In
modern art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, it's jumbo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jeeps</ENAMEX>, subway signs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>-It notes. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">chairs</ENAMEX>, it's casual, cheap, and computer-designed. Also "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">100 Years of Stuff</ENAMEX>,"
which includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isadora Duncan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grecian</ENAMEX> robes, the electric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, and Penguin
Books. At the height of a high-consumption <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday shopping season</TIMEX>, it all
seems familiar.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> running back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricky Williams</ENAMEX>
was awarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heisman</ENAMEX> trophy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downtown Athletic Club</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, who holds the all-time college
rushing record, also plays <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">idolizes Bob Marley</ENAMEX>, and hopes to someday teach elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
