
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right-Hand Man</ENAMEX>?

            The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s narrow rejection of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>'
rights bill. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'s self-approved
extension of the budget deadline. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the problems associated with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few days</TIMEX>' sudden
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leap</ENAMEX> in mortgage rates.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead, also fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
voted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-47</NUMEX> to quash a health care bill backed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. The bill would
have guaranteed access to emergency care and medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> and made it
easier to sue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> for improper denial of care. In the lead paragraph, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> states the causes of the bill's demise: "heavy lobbying by the
insurance industry and of the sex scandal that has enveloped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Explanation</ENAMEX>: distraction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been too bogged down in
scandal to lobby hard for the bill.)

            But the national budget may meet a happier fate. With the unanimous <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">421-0</ENAMEX>
passage of a temporary spending bill, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> now has until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to come up with a budget package. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>, incidentally,
approves the concept of voting oneself deadline extensions.) But even the new
deadline may not be enough time for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to resolve all remaining issues.
Among the sticklers: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s education initiatives; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> funding;
the use of statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX> in the upcoming census; and even whether giving
contraceptives to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> requires parental notification. Only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
spending bills were completed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, and all unfinished measures will
probably be glopped together into one mammoth spending bill.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead attributes the mortgage rate rise--in some cases
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amounting</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a percentage point--to the stuttering global economy. Called
the most dramatic mortage rate development since the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1987</TIMEX> stock market
crash, the rise is forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to pay more than they
anticipated, or to make last-minute changes of plan. However, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , rates are not expected to rise much further.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> both run stories on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>
witness selection. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> emphasizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> may be among the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> called to testify (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> having relaxed his objections),
but probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will not be called. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story plays
up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s partisan disagreements over the witness issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
want the heavy-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hitters</ENAMEX> in the scandal, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> badly want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> is barreling toward "full <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> law."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> voted to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koran</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supreme</ENAMEX> law of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. Human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> fear that this could escalate
into further, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taliban</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">esque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repression</ENAMEX>. The bill must still be passed by the
upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a bottom front story on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s court victory by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">psychotic killer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendell Williamson</ENAMEX>, against his therapist. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
verdict, which netted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX>, states that the therapist did not
sufficiently follow up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX> after terminating their sessions, and
did not sufficiently explain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX>'s condition to him. These sins of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">omission</ENAMEX>, according to the verdict, factored into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX>'s shooting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shortly after the sessions ended. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Psychiatrists</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are
understandably worried; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> in question intends to appeal.

            All papers run stories on the appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX>.
The tapping of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariel Sharon</ENAMEX>, who strongly supports <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>, is widely seen as a move by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> to appease his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s far right. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> are upset,
the appointment may conversely smooth peace negotiations: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> will have
already secured the far right, the logic goes, so he can afford to yield more
in the peace negotiations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon</ENAMEX> has already shown himself to be
rather handy with diplomacy: He has vowed never to shake <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>'s hand, and he also remarked on a previous occasion that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> doesn't know his right hand from his left.

         
      
   
