
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Folding Greenspan</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s surprise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> interest rate cut leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
runs the cut as its off-lead and goes instead with the apparent federal budget
deal, which makes everybody else's front.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s cut in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important interest rates came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two weeks</TIMEX> after its
previous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall St.</ENAMEX> went from ticked about insufficient credit to
upticked--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">330</NUMEX> points to the good on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. The rate move, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note,
was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to come without a regularly scheduled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> meeting in more
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. And, observes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> such occurrence
since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. A move without a meeting is taken by the
papers to be a sign of the seriousness of the overall economic environment.
(Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says there's no evidence that there's any orchestrated
rate cutting by central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> around the world in the offing.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>
tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> he's worried that the cut indicates that some particular
bank or investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> is about to have a big problem, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says
there are no immediate signs of this. Another tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> it means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> admits he made a mistake.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and WSJ explain that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> made the
move on his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> but after consulting with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The
papers quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> saying they expect further interest cuts soon.

            In its top paragraph, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead characterizes the new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7</NUMEX>
trillion federal budget--expected to pass <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>
with a surplus and as containing the biggest peacetime increase in military
spending since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (complete, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notices,
with an aircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> contract for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX>, and a cargo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>
contract for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lists what it considers the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>'s leading features: money for hiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, relief for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2 billion</NUMEX> in basic medical research funds, funds for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, tightening security at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>, replenishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>,
and sending <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>. Another done deal: federal health plans will
now be required to provide contraceptive coverage for federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>,

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also describes this piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> budget reasoning:
"[B]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ecause</ENAMEX> of the killing of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, it provides <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> to develop a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor center</ENAMEX> to more easily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> and a tightening of security at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>." Only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> would it cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> to
(not) save a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>'s life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> got a provision
written into the budget bill that extends the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> hunting season in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, but never explains how a federal bill could do that.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead (ditto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead editorial) says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> of the budget wrangle was a big victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who
showed he can still influence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> even while it's considering impeaching
him. Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> apologizing yet again when he said, ""Just think what we could
do for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> if we had these priorities <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year long</TIMEX>, instead of just for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX>"? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial on the budget manages not to feel Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s gain, saying of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>: "They reached belated agreement on a
single massive bill that takes the place of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> lesser bills they should have
passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>. They achieved the agreement in part by bending the budget
rules. The omnibill contains something extra for everyone. The extra spending
will eat up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a quarter</NUMEX> of the vaunted budget surplus projected for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX> just begun." The wry headline over the editorial: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Deal</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> features a big front-page "cover story" ramping up to the
beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> anti-trust suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quotes Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' recent assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s case: "I'm not worried
about it at all." The story mentions but does not explain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things that are a
bit puzzling: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">won't Gates</ENAMEX> be called to testify? and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Why is there
still a case concerning browsers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 98</ENAMEX>, when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX> a federal
appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> backed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in a case involving browsers and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Windows 95</ENAMEX>?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> also does a good story on the case, mentioning along the way
that the trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has implied he thinks the case is headed to the appeals
court over him, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the case says it's
going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.

            A short while ago, amidst all the editorial stones thrown at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for not confessing to his misdeeds, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> challenged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to make sure that they themselves were not failing to come clean
about any misconduct in their own glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. There was no
response--miraculously, no paper did anything like what it demanded of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
So <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> will simply say that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Star</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s largest paper)--know they have
unpunished plagiarists on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
