
   
   
      
         
            One <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flu Over the Cuckoo's Nest</ENAMEX>

            Financial news dominates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s Dow drop of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">210</NUMEX> points. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">combines</ENAMEX> this with the meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G7</NUMEX> finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> and
central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> aimed at calming the world's markets. The top non-local story
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> uses the down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> as backdrop for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>'s call for stronger regulation of global finance. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s congressional testimony defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve</ENAMEX>'s role in helping to set up a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.6 billion</NUMEX> private-sector-funded rescue
package for a leading investment fund, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term Capital Management</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead says that Wall Street is concerned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s
quarter-point rate cut didn't add enough credit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> banking system to
prevent the overseas economic crisis from inducing a recession here. The paper
depicts the other dominoes it sees waiting to fall: if the stock market
continues to be unconvinced, then consumer confidence will be weakened, and
then consumer spending will drop and then...kablooey. The WP paints
essentially the same picture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes another down factor on the
Street: that in light of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term Capital Management</ENAMEX> scare, there's fear
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brokerages</ENAMEX> will stampede out of lots of hedge funds, causing
many to fail at once.

            All of this illustrates the basic economic problem in the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, made
only worse by the information revolution, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel Camdessus</ENAMEX> calls
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "contagion"--transnational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of panic that lie beyond the
tools of policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. As a result, a new report showing growth in orders of
electronic equipment, as well as petroleum products and transportation
products, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> says portends healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
manufacturing activity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming months</TIMEX>, means nothing right now. It's a
duck/rabbit world, economics, and right now, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> make clear, it's all
duck.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ducking</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , was what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> was doing
in his congressional testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> is quoted as seeing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s Long-Term machinations an example of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of rules for welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, another for rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>. Another quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said, "We hear a lot of
speeches about free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> and the marketplace, but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> don't
like to practice it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> acknowledged that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s action raised the
problem of moral hazard, which is, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , that rescuing
those who make risky investments only encourages more of the same. But, he's
quoted, a liquidation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term</ENAMEX> would have made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> too frightened to
take risks, and risk-taking is "a necessary condition for wealth creation."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s suggestions, described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , include
a middle path: require hedge funds to disclose more about their activities.

            The papers continue to track the hardening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N./NATO</ENAMEX> position
regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. They all report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> sent a new
warning to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> to identify and prosecute those responsible for
atrocities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Dept.</ENAMEX> has warned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to
get out--the latter a traditional precursor to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action. None of
the papers mentions it, but such a warning preceded by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few days</TIMEX> the
recent cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> attacks into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. The talk this time is generally
of manned airstrikes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> figures they could happen as soon as the
end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says everything will be in place in two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that the settlement offer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lawyers
"inches up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX>" but is still far short of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> is
asking. A story on the WP front says the offer is now <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX>, where it
was once before, pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> agreed to
negotiate after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> dropped her longstanding demand for an apology, but was
"enraged" when on TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> said any settlement was the same
as acknowledging her allegations. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports, Jones
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are preparing a motion to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> held in contempt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for
his misleading testimony about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. If there's no settlement, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, they will file it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s reference in this space to "some place called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carleton College</ENAMEX>"
brought an avalanche of protesting e-mail. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> felt sure that
they had encountered deep-seated elitism, when actually all they had run into
was a playful desire to keep the newspapers fun. It is perhaps a sign of the
age that e-mailers defended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> school by citing its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News and World Report</ENAMEX> ranking or by listing famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>, but
no one wrote to say he or she'd gotten a great education at the place. Time to
fill that void: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> did not go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Papers thoroughly enjoyed attending...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carleton College</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
