
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad Dash</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s
apparent resolve to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for lying under oath. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the defection of several republican
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> from the pro-impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$206-billion</NUMEX> settlement between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the tobacco
industry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead cites "several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>" who say that despite the
resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s ethics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> and the ineffectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
testimony on public opinion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> will vote for impeachment. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that this goes against public opinion and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> consensus. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp welcomes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s move on hopes that it will produce a
poignant rejection of impeachment when put to a vote on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> have already expressed
opposition to impeachment. This means that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> remain united,
then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> more "nays" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will kill the impeachment effort.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> portrays the tobacco settlement as a victory for cigarette
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">makers</ENAMEX>, noting that the agreement apparently ends the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s legal war on
smoking. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also sees it as a clear victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, which will
maintain its revenue stream and receive "significant legal protection for years
to come." A quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> expresses the less
than joyous reaction from the anti-cigarette lobby: "To those who say it's not
enough, I say we simply couldn't afford to come away with nothing."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All the weekend</TIMEX> papers report the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s ethics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Dash</ENAMEX>, who quit to protest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s appearance before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dash</ENAMEX>, who had advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> not to appear before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>,
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> an "aggressive advocate" of impeachment and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused Starr</ENAMEX> of "intruding" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s power.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> broke an illegal alien smuggling
ring that allegedly brought <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The workers
endured long, dangerous trips to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and once they arrived were often held
captive by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> calls it the "largest alien smuggling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> ever dismantled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> history."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van Gogh</ENAMEX> self-portrait was sold for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$71.5 million</NUMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie's</ENAMEX> auction
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Arts</ENAMEX> piece. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait</ENAMEX> of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Artist Without His Beard</ENAMEX>" is not known, but the tidy sum represents nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the painting's estimated price and the third-highest amount ever
paid for an auctioned artwork.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Gore</ENAMEX>, Sr. will no doubt take great comfort in learning from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> correction (of an article about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Clifford</ENAMEX>'s memorial service)
that he is not "late," but actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 years old</TIMEX> and living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carthage</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
