
   
   
      
         
            Tapes' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Crap</ENAMEX>

            The big stories are about the promise of good things, foreign and domestic.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead with a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> peace deal apparently almost in sight.
USAT fronts that but leads with hints from top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> is likely to cut interest rates again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>. The paper quotes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-chairman</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federales</ENAMEX> to the effect that the central
bank is intent on keeping credit loose enough to prevent a slowdown in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> flags the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> scenario in its front-page news box.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that starting yesterday
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> entered into intense one-on-one
bargaining. Everybody writes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-backed land-for-peace deal has been
basically accepted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also say the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> have arrived at
compromises regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian National Covenant</ENAMEX> (which currently calls
for the destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>), the arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> wanted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the
release of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX>, but that the issue of whether or
not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> might declare the territory he administers an independent state
still remained a sore point. The papers report that the discussions are being
conducted under the rule that no agreed-to provisions would be final until an
overall agreement is reached.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> have the most physical details about what went
on behind closed doors, right down to seating arrangements. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> papers
report that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who had been at the summit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>
(accompanied, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy</ENAMEX>) invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> to
join the talks and that once there, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> delivered an impassioned speech
calling on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> to press for peace. The papers report that the
deal being worked out involves a finishing-touches meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> from
now, probably in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>-governed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
attendance. This has not been confirmed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            Meanwhile, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">settlers</ENAMEX> blocked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and held prayer rituals to drive home their demands that
no more land be returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> control. And, adds the paper,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> pressing for the repatriation of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> jails
took to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to terrorist
attacks began a hunger strike outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" notes a trend among those arrested for
Internet porn: they have a disproportionate tendency to kill themselves. Of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> arrested in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 3rd <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-nation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> porn raid, reports the
paper, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> have since offed themselves. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suicides</ENAMEX> tend to be respectables
who've never previously been in any kind of trouble and are desperate to escape
the impending humiliation, like the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">asphyxiated</ENAMEX> himself, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">microbiologist</ENAMEX> who slashed
his wrists, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> who shot himself in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that, according to a study released
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4 million</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> of all black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--are ineligible
to vote in the election <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> because of a felony conviction. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says this is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times the national average. The study found that
the proportion of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> has increased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times faster than for
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are
looking into whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s tapes were doctored. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
op-ed by former <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ben-Veniste</ENAMEX> makes the observation
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s ardor about the tapes apparently has its limits: he never for
instance, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX> before his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. The reason,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Veniste</ENAMEX> suggests, is that her testimony might reveal that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> knew about
the tapes before he swears he first heard of them--which could suggest a
working relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>.

            Tucked into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section story by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Powell</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race is this sentence: "He's angered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bubba</ENAMEX> vote, the
black vote, the gambling vote and the anti-gambling vote and all that in just
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> that you can't defend the usage here by
observing that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually use the B-word, because a lot of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> also use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-word, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> would never run. No, this is a
perfect illustration of the truism that there's still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in this country
that "respectable" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, even (especially?) sophisticated newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
can slander--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey, Posties</ENAMEX> , time to rework that
style-sheet.

         
      
   
