
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Goes</ENAMEX> Solo

            The intensifying showdown with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . As the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
increased its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX> presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>, the total isolation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> became apparent. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> signed a declaration that blamed the crisis on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s intransigence.
Even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>--which traditionally have supported <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s argument that
sanctions should be lifted--have voiced no opposition to a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
attack.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> rhetoric was sharp: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> warned that
military strikes, if they occur, "will be significant." Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX> said, "We have thought well beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hour One and Day One</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Week One</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tariq Aziz</ENAMEX> reiterated
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s stance that sanctions should be lifted before <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> inspectors are
reinstated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aziz</ENAMEX> did indicate, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> would welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
intervention--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>, who has been burned too many times by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s
broken promises, shows no inclination to head to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that "an attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and possibly a massive one,"
could come at "virtually any moment." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is more cautious, citing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who say that "military action is not likely for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX>,
although it could come sooner." Possible reasons for delay include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s upcoming swing through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and a last chance for diplomacy.

            The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> fronts a story on how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.W. Scripps Co.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garden Television</ENAMEX>, broke into the "clubby" and expensive cable programming
business--in which would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> must even pay cable systems for channel
space. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripps</ENAMEX> essentially got lucky--after stumbling on the concept of using
"retransmission rights" as a bargaining chip--and its boomer-friendly content
took off, once aired. Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripps</ENAMEX> had no free rise: It initially had
to promise <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of its ad revenue to cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>.

            A nerve-racking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cover Story</ENAMEX>"
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> nationwide, in an effort to accommodate more traffic and
increase runway efficiency, are practicing "the simultaneous use of
intersecting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runways</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> could be taking off and another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landing</ENAMEX> on
intersecting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runways</ENAMEX>; it is presumed that the landing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> will stop well before
the intersection. Though a number of near-misses have been reported, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>
wants to extend the practice to flights <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at night</TIMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front stories on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$433 million</NUMEX> lawsuit
against the gun industry filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. The suit
charges that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s suburbs knowingly overstocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, confident
that they would be distributed to illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>, and that the gun industry
constitutes a "public nuisance"--that is, by enabling illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> sales, it
increased the burden on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s civic services. The lawsuit, reminiscent of
the fight against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX>, may serve as a model for upcoming suits in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>.

            In a long <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> writes deferentially of how
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is once again responding to the call of duty" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> crisis.
Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> context as a springboard, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> opines the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> shoulders too
much responsibility for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and international affairs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> should be
more organized, he says. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">trans-Atlantic</ENAMEX> commitment has made <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> a
safer place. But <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> needs to do more to repay that debt."

            Biotechnology grows ever more bizarre: A human skin cell nestled in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gutted cow</ENAMEX> egg turned into an embryo
and divided--or so claims a small biotechnology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Worcester</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story. This extraordinary revelation,
made public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, has spawned questions not only about the legitimacy of
the results, but also about possible misuse of federal funds. If the experiment
is true, its implications are so surreal that they bear repeating: The first
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">embryo</ENAMEX> may have been cloned--with the aid of a cow <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
