
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin It Nicely</ENAMEX>

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> abruptly resigned, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Everyone expects
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> to win the presidency outright in the upcoming elections. But what kind
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>? His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> say he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in centralized
power, and a ruthless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> of the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. And what do his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> say? That each of these vices is really a virtue.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> point to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX>, calling him a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonist</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> was dubbed
"Stasi" (the name of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East German</ENAMEX> secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>) for wielding
behind-the-scenes power. Detractors use these terms to portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Warrior</ENAMEX> who can't be trusted with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s nukes. On television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">National Security Adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> lent credence to this theory by arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> has "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> strands": on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and on the other, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> as a "democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>"
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> reject the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-strands theory. They argue that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX>
experience actually reinforced his interest in economic liberalization. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> explained on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> worked in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>. That's a very positive point. … The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX>, in some way,
prepared perestroika … because they were very open and they knew the exact
situation in the economy, inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and what was happening outside."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anatoly Sobchak</ENAMEX>, told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , "He is a convinced supporter of the market economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">… He</ENAMEX>
knows the western <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> of economic and political life not as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> but
from the inside."

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterspin</ENAMEX> is already making headway. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> returned from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> service
"steeped in Western business knowledge," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . On This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Washington</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Oreskes</ENAMEX> noted that
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, he
learned a lot about Western business practices, and that may be exactly what he
needs to understand to solve" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economic problems.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
He's a socialist. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> worry that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> might wield too much
state power over the economy and society, thereby undermining both capitalism
and democracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>, however, sees the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX> of honest
capitalism and true democracy. "Any attempt to exceed the limits of the law and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> will be decisively crushed," he warned in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s
Eve message. "Freedom of speech, freedom of conscience, freedom of the press,
the right to private property--all these basic principles of a civilized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> will be reliably protected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, and even his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, agree that the chief threat to
freedom in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> today is too little power in the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, not too
much. But how can they make this case to the world's most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lender</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, in terms we can understand? By comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> to former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> has a wonderful opportunity to become for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roosevelts</ENAMEX> are for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sobchak</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . The
Times buys this analysis: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX> took on entrenched
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monopolies</ENAMEX>, helping small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to thrive and competition to flourish.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> reworked the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to aid the poor, improve
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> and create a less crash-prone financial system." Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> "amassed
state power over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and economy to shape the capitalistic system
that exists <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> "cruel," a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>," and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>" who might suspend civil liberties to whip <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> into shape. They're
particularly outraged by "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> says he's
"troubled" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> owes his popularity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chechen war</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> demand economic sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> for its "brutal" assaults
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> had
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> "dark-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who must be annihilated" and had
warned that "they will be found in latrines and killed." Furthermore, Russert
noted, "His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official visit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">…</ENAMEX> was to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechnya</ENAMEX> giving hunting knives to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military."

            To
make nice with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have begun to rephrase complaints about
the war. When asked about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> "atrocities," they express regret about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s "actions." But they also frame the war as an unfortunate expression of
a trait that could serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> well in other pursuits. When asked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s
vow to "annihilate" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> "very determined" and
"action-oriented." The media, too, have begun to use positive adjectives to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">describe Putin</ENAMEX>'s conduct of the war: "aggressive," "tough-minded,"
"determined," "decisive," "uncompromising," "no-nonsense."

            How,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, will these traits make him a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>?
First, he can halt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s slide into chaos. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> frames the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> war as a
struggle to rein in "terrorism" and "the breakup of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>," a rationale for
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> express sympathy. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, he can confront cronyism.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s pawn, installed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX> to safeguard their financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> and shield them from
prosecution for corruption. By underscoring his image as a fearless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> defies this critique. He began by "firing" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, eliciting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oohs</ENAMEX> and aahs from the world press, even though everyone expects her to stay on
as an informal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>. In view of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s endemic corruption, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are reconsidering whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman president</ENAMEX> is such a bad thing.
"Does he have the power and the will to take on the robber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX>?" asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> . "Will he tax them? Will he crack
down on them? Will he clean them up?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, a ruthlessly
efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> can win a ruthlessly efficient election and craft a ruthlessly
efficient economy. Arguing for a quick end to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chechen war</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> appeal not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s mercy but to his political interests. "He now
faces an election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX>. "If the costs become too high
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> … this could become an albatross around his neck in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>."
Never mind morality. When asked whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should oppose loans
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> because of the war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> replies, "It's a premature question …
because the predicate question is whether they get the economic reforms in
order," at which point "we'll have to look at what's in our national interest."
Here is an argument <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> can understand: We should judge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> the same way we judge ours. "The test for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX>, "is
the economy, stupid."

         
      
   
