
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad Credit</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Plan</ENAMEX> as Desegregator

            
               From:

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: Thu
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec 9</ENAMEX>

            I'm surprised that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Gottlieb</ENAMEX> is so troubled by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> quasi-affirmative action collegiate admissions
plans. If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> accepts the need for a corrective (or, depending on how <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> views
it, is willing to live with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a mere palliative</NUMEX>), why not design one that
operates in direct proportion to how segregated a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are?

            Of course, affirmative action has never been
intended as a corrective (or palliative) for segregation. Yet there is surely
some considerable connection between segregation, school quality, and student
performance. One could argue that, absent school segregation, any kind of
affirmative action admission plans are that much less necessary. Thus, three
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now have automatically self-adjusting policies. Surely that's not such a
terrible outcome.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> Plan <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Class</ENAMEX>, Not Race

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter L. Williams</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dec</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>

            In reality, it takes more work and more character
for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">X</ENAMEX>" to finish in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent of his or her public
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and obtain a mediocre <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> score than it does for rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>" to
finish in the bottom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of his private school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and score slightly higher
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>. Unlike affirmative action, high school quotas avoid giving an
advantage based on something other than merit in those situations where student
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">X</ENAMEX>" is white and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>" is a minority.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Connerly No Fan of Compromise</ENAMEX>

            
               From:

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Archer</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: Thu
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec 9</ENAMEX>

            It is not true that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> plans, which guarantee the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of each high school
graduating class admission to a state university, have been "heralded" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ward</ENAMEX>
Connerly, as reported in this article. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connerly</ENAMEX> strongly criticized Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> plan in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 18</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> op-ed
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, "Why I'm Still <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fighting Preferences</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>." "Part of me applauds
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for trying to reach a compromise on this issue," he wrote. "... But
some things can't be compromised, and equality under the law is one of them.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s initiative falls short in several areas." 
                  Slate
                should
correct this misrepresentation of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connerly</ENAMEX>'s views.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax-Cheat</ENAMEX> Helper

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Thomas</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec 8</ENAMEX>

            I am not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> but I can understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>
won't accept tax payments by credit card. If you fail to pay your taxes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
can seize your assets. But if a credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> pays your taxes and then
you don't pay the credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> what measures can the credit card company
take to get its money? I can't imagine that in court the debt you owe to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> is equivalent to the debt you owe your credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. This seems like
a real good deal for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> and a horrible idea for the credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
In effect, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> is using them as a collection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Measure</ENAMEX> of Subjectivity

            
               From:

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stevens</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nov</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>

            In the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everyday Economics</ENAMEX>" article of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg</ENAMEX> cites an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 18</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> editorial in
which I am quoted as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalist</ENAMEX> who is skeptical about the concept of
existence value because the "numbers might not add up in our favor." This
statement is then used to argue that I do not value intellectual consistency. I
would simply like to set the record straight. I was partially misquoted by the
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg's</ENAMEX> interpretation of my "statement" is not accurate.
My concern about existence value is that it is very hard to measure and one can
generate almost any number one wants to. So I am concerned that some groups
will attempt to measure existence value in such a way that they do, in fact,
come up with a number that is in their favor. This is my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, it is
not what I advocate. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> I make every attempt to
be objective. I value intellectual consistency highly. I am therefore quite sad
that the opposite impression is being conveyed. With respect to existence
value, the real problem is that its measurement often becomes subjective.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stevens</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of resource economics at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. ]

         
      
   
