
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fund-Raising McCain</ENAMEX>

            

                
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Airlines</ENAMEX> hijackers dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
demands. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> hijackers, who seized a jet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, are still
demanding that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> Kashmiri militants, but they are no longer
asking for the return of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>'s dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> or for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> in ransom.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> would be forced to leave
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> if a settlement is not reached soon. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> condemned
the hijacking (as did the 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
               ), and each accused the other of
plotting it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> differed as to whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concessions</ENAMEX> would make a
settlement more likely or increase the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>' determination to achieve
their remaining demand. But most agreed that the incident is "a huge
blow" to prospects for peace talks between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>.
(
                  Slate
               's "" rounds up overseas reactions to the
hijacking, and "" outlines the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> conflict.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourth-quarter</TIMEX> fund raising equaled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outpaced Gore</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, bringing him within <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> total.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 million</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> pulled in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX> in the same period. The

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
                said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> had
"translated their momentum in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> into a national money boost."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> asserted that he'd become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> camp said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
wouldn't survive nationally, pointing to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s lead in total fund
raising (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$66 million to $16 million</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was
in trouble : "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> were as popular as he should be,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wouldn't be writing checks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> countered that in any
other year his fund-raising performance would have set records.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> canceled its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX> celebration. It was expected
to draw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Space Needle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> said that while
there was no specific threat it was "impossible for federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to rule
out the area as a terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>." International law enforcement has also
begun a "roundup of the usual suspects ," detaining anyone with suspected ties
to terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> until the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX>. The spins, in order of increasing
gloominess: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authorities</ENAMEX> are taking necessary precautions ; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) they're making everyone more
nervous; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) they're discriminating against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> descent; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overreaction</ENAMEX> is helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> achieve their goals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> suggested
that the overkill of millennium hoopla was actually the greatest

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> composite index closed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">above 4,000</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. Its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX>
percent, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-month</TIMEX> gain is the largest ever by a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stock market index.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>'s technology focus helped it outpace the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX> industrials,
which were up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">S&P 500</ENAMEX>, up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX>. Reasons
to be pleased: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) this comes on the heels of an economic expansion, not a
recession, as previous large gains have; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) it underscores the
revolutionary potential of new technologies. Reasons to be discouraged: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) most
of the gains were generated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with little or no profit ; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the market is beginning to scrutinize
new stocks more closely; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> predict a sell-off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2000</TIMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> unload stocks they held for tax purposes.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> was denied bail. A federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> said his release
could compromise global security because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of the tapes onto which he had
copied <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> nuclear secrets remain unaccounted for . In the bail hearing, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> alleged
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee 1</ENAMEX>) stole nuclear secrets "sufficient to build a functional
thermonuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) stored this information on a computer network easily
accessible to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> that he "may have
accidentally" disclosed secrets to a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>'s lawyers
countered that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) there is no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> ever accessed the
information; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> took no steps to cover his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX>. Government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' spin: The evidence shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> was not arbitrarily singled out
for prosecution. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' spin: But the insinuations of spying are
based on "circumstantial
evidence, innuendo, or inference." Government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' counterspin: Even
so, the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> for security violations is airtight.

            
               Rap
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mogul Sean "Puffy</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Combs</ENAMEX> was arrested. He was charged with illegal
possession of a handgun after an associate allegedly shot and injured three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. Combs, who has signed and produced some of the
biggest "gangsta rap" acts of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>, denied the allegations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variously</ENAMEX> said the incident underscored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the imminent
decline of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Puff Daddy</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) Combs' futile attempts to gain "street
credibility"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the impossibility of blending the gangsta and corporate
cultures.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> rescued his coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. He
negotiated a budget deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shas</ENAMEX>, an ultra-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that controls a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>'s parliamentary seats, thereby averting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shas</ENAMEX>'
threatened withdrawal from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. International <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> termed it a
"potentially destabilizing political crisis" that could have
imperiled peace talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s spin: We reached a fair compromise.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>' spin: You were extorted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shas</ENAMEX>. The American spin: That's a small
price to pay for peace.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX> is recalling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pok√</ENAMEX>©mon toy cases. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toys</ENAMEX>, distributed in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kids Club</ENAMEX>" meals, are thought to be safe. But their round
cases have been linked to the suffocation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX>. It is the
largest toy
recall ever. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX>'s spin: We're putting safety <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Product Safety Commission</ENAMEX>'s spin: Only because we forced you to.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX>' spin: We always knew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pok√©mon</ENAMEX> was insidious.
(
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pok√©mon</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> proposed to expand low-income rental subsidies. The
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$690 million</NUMEX> increase would add <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7 million</NUMEX> currently
receiving the housing vouchers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said that expanding the program, which
covers <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 70 percent</NUMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s rent, would particularly help <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the
homeless; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) those moving from welfare to work; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that
presently live far from jobs in higher-rent areas. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> criticized the
proposal as costly and only
marginally effective . However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> doubted whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> could
defeat a program that has been a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the past.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vermont Supreme Court</ENAMEX> granted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> greater partnership
rights. The unanimous ruling held that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is constitutionally
required to extend to same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> the common benefits and protections that
flow from marriage under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> law." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> left it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> to
determine whether gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> will get these rights through marriage or
domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of gay rights called the decision a "deeply disturbing" blow to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of marriage, but they
promised to limit its effects to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>. Gay rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> deemed it a
triumph of "our common humanity" that paves the way for similar rights
nationally. (
                  Slate
               's "" outlines the legal status of
gay marriages.)

         
      
   
