
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoop Schemes</ENAMEX>

basketball game, we would be going into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, led
by the former bench-warmer from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman team</ENAMEX>, holding a slight
lead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX>, led by the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">All-American</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, hasn't
quite caught up, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> is complaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> isn't
playing fair.

            "I think we've reached the sad day when a sitting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> distorts a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>'s record because he thinks he can
score a cheap political point," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> said recently.

            This isn't just a runaway sport metaphor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
whining about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s tactics is, in fact, an essential aspect of his political
style and is surely derived from his style as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>.

            Not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s complaints aren't sometimes
justified. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s tiresome accusation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> favors <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> "vouchers"
seeks to link his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe subliminally</ENAMEX>, if irrationally, to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plans for
school vouchers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s effort to portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> as a latter-day
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> is unconvincing considering that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is frank about his
desire to spend a lot of tax dollars expanding the availability of federal
health insurance.

            But if anybody should
recognize why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is dishing out cheap shots, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted shooter</ENAMEX> with remarkable stamina, but he lacked the foot
speed and upper-body strength of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>. He compensated for his
liabilities with tactics, which, while not exactly cheating, were not quite
within the rules either.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Bullet</ENAMEX> forward
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Marin</ENAMEX>, spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every</TIMEX> game "trying to escape <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s vise-like hold on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shorts</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> recently reported.

            "He was one of the dirtiest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> I ever played
against," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . "He held and pushed and tugged. It was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irritating</ENAMEX>."

            A former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX> teammate was quoted as describing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s style as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwinistic</ENAMEX>." "Basketball is a contact sport," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Walters</ENAMEX>
said. "He was never a goody-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-shoes. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>, he would
have thrown brushback pitches. That's the game within the game."

            Now this competitive style seems to be a point of
pride. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ernestine</ENAMEX>, likes to tell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> about her first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">game</ENAMEX>, where she was amazed to discover that
her "gentle, totally open, inquisitive" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> threw elbows like a street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fighter</ENAMEX>. "Watch the elbows!" she warns to applause.

            But now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is
throwing elbows back in an effort to stave off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s gains, the
gentleman-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>-statesman is quick to take offense.

            
Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> complaining <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">to Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s insinuation that he might raise
the eligibility age for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>.

            

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: "The reality is that the only way this is going to be solved is if you
can prevent it from being a political <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>'s criticism of me for
voting to continue discussion on a variety of options at the same time; the
administration was considering the same discussion."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>"

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: "I mean, you know, if it's OK for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to discuss--"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>:
"No. Not raising the retirement age."

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: [getting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sarcastic</ENAMEX>] "Oh, you didn't discuss it in all of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security forums out there?"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I certainly didn't."

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: "No one ever did, right? No one ever did. Give me a break."

            

            For sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s bitching and moaning is less
than surprising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> who takes liberties when the refs aren't
looking is often the same one who wants special attention when they are.

            Sportswriters call it "working the refs," and it is
a subtle art. While a mediocre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>) often regards the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">referees</ENAMEX> as impartial arbiters to be respected, a superior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> (such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>) will treat them as fallible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> who can be manipulated into rendering
favorable decisions. In the political arena, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> are analogous
to refs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electoral</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, as well as athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, seek to appear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aggrieved</ENAMEX> rather than antagonistic. This appeals to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> (whose roar may
provoke a favorable call) without calling into question the judgment of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referees</ENAMEX>.

            The trick, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
demonstrated on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , is to bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s dirty deeds
into plain view.

            

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: "Whether it's my health-care plan or whatever, then you only have a
negative message."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, hold on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> here."

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: "I'm talking about positive messages."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>:
"Yeah."

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: "To talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> should go."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, you know, I haven't had to apologize yet."

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: "I know you haven't. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">…</ENAMEX>"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>:
"Nor have you called upon me to--"

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: "I call upon you now to apologize."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>:
"--because I haven't given you to cause to. But at the beginning of the
show--"

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do you apologize?</ENAMEX>"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>:
"No, I don't--"

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: "OK. Well, there it is. There it is."

            

            This is the political version of the basketball moment when
an exasperated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> turns to the ref and points out his opponent's alleged
foul. In sports the putative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> almost always shouts something like, "There
it is!" In this case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX> didn't blow his whistle and the game went on.

            The fact is that in politics, as in sports, bending
the rules isn't cheating if you get away with it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pitchers</ENAMEX> scuff the ball.
Defensive ends deliver late hits. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> seem to
have absorbed this point better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bills</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> who ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s ticket, has always
been too much of a rah-rah type to complain about political cheap shots. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
Bunning, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, was known during his major league
baseball career for throwing hard inside fastballs to keep batters off the
plate. But he hasn't complained about the tactics of his political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> reflex to call foul is probably too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ingrained for Bradley</ENAMEX> to completely abandon it. But somebody needs to remind
him that you don't win the game by working the refs. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You gotta score</ENAMEX> points on
your own. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, quit whining and play.

         
      
   
