
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lolita Lewinsky</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo</ENAMEX>-ni-ca,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lo-li-ta</ENAMEX>

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Solovay</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec</TIMEX>
15

            "In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masters</ENAMEX> said, she could think of only one
other word that featured such an exquisitely pleasing articulatory progression
in the mouth: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'Monica</NUMEX>.' " Let's not forget <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s exquisite progression in
the other direction: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tongue</ENAMEX> taking a trip of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> steps down the palate to
tap, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, on the teeth: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ta</ENAMEX>."

            
               (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">reply,</ENAMEX> click here .)
            

            
               Subject:

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanuts Metaphysics</ENAMEX>

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Anger</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tue Dec</ENAMEX>
14

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schulz</ENAMEX> need not fear death. He already has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immortality</ENAMEX>. My favorite strip was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> fell ill and sent Rerun to hold
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> stayed home. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rerun</ENAMEX> arrived home a short
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> later. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> screamed, "I've got to know. Did you pull away the football or
did you let him kick it"? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rerun</ENAMEX> smiled and said, "You'll never know!"

            
               (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">reply,</ENAMEX> click here .)
            

            
               Subject: What
Papers Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> Reading?

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Parsons</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: "

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thu Dec</ENAMEX>
16

            I just wanted to briefly contradict your
characterization regarding how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> supposedly ignored or
downplayed the story of the recent monetary settlement agreement for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> slave-labor and forced-labor programs. It was the lead story in every
paper I saw <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. It was the lead story in every national newscast I saw
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.

            The story touches on everything from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
most shameful chapter to the business <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s potential bottom lines.
Believe me, it has been one of the top stories here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last six months</TIMEX>.
And for the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, it has become a subject as inescapable as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
past itself.

            Witness the present controversy surrounding an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s idea to stage what looks like a really cool light show on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>. Everyone, from new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize winner Günter Grass to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, say the show must not go on. Why? Because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Speer</ENAMEX> staged lightshows. Say what you want about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> and their past; they are the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-most obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> on earth when
it comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> era as a story. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> are, of course,
numbers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and two</NUMEX>.)

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: What
Papers Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> Reading?

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Chancellor</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fri Dec</ENAMEX>
17

            My sincere apologies. I must assume the subject
dominated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> papers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day earlier</TIMEX> when I didn't see them.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
Was Present at the Creation

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James W. Brosnan</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec</TIMEX>
15

            I'd like to help set the record for

                  Slate
               . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> was:

            

               [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> proposes] the
expansion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>. I was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of that proposal. I
wrote that, so I say, welcome aboard. That is something for which I have been
the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.

            

            Clearly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was referring to a proposal to expand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 7, 1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reps.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Downey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lewis</ENAMEX>
introduced a bill to expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34 billion</NUMEX> by raising taxes on people
earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $200,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Much of that proposal was incorporated into
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> tax increase. I wrote a story about the tax proposal for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> Commercial Appeal .

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
Was Present at the Creation

            
               From: Jodie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fri Dec</ENAMEX>
17

            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brosnan</ENAMEX> has added
another small footnote to the long history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>. He notes that then-Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> co-sponsored one of many EITC expansion plans, though not one that made it
directly into law. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX>'s authoritative
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Green Book</ENAMEX>" notes, there were several expansions to the
EITC:

            

               The earned income credit
(<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">EIC Code</ENAMEX> sec. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>), enacted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, generally equals a specified percentage of
wages up to a maximum dollar amount. … The income ranges and percentages have
been revised several times since original enactment, expanding the credit (see
table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13-12</NUMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, the credit was indexed for inflation. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> and again
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacted substantial expansions of the credit. …

            

            So what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> might have accurately
said was, "I was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of numerous proposals to expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>,
though the one I co-sponsored wasn't the one that was enacted into law in that
period." That's not what he said.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: Not
Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance Reform</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cynical Politics</ENAMEX>

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mon Dec</ENAMEX>
20

            You are too quick to brush off the dubious motive
behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s offer to forgo radio and TV ads in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> had everything to gain and nothing to lose by the offer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> went on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">air</ENAMEX> with both TV and radio commercials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two months</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> did.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> saved his money and went on the air just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
has already bought up airtime to use during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several weeks</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caucuses</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary. To pull TV ads now only helps
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--he's already been on the air a lot longer than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has outspent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> by a wide margin and is close to hitting the spending caps.

            In terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s offer for debates twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>,
where was the offer back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>? There was no offer
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> ignored him. Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has made it a race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> wants to
dictate the pace of the campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> have now met <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and
will meet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is not a hypocrite on campaign finance
reform for refusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s grandstanding offer. TV and radio are a reality in
modern campaigns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has to build up his name recognition to beat a
sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s ads, which are paid for by "hard" dollars,
help get his name and message across to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are not familiar with him.
If you noticed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> didn't offer not to spend the money that would be saved by
not purchasing TV or radio ads. His campaign is in danger of running out of
money early in the primary season. By not paying for ads in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
primary, that would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to pay for ads in the period between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">primaries</ENAMEX> and the convention. Again, the offer benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> because his
earlier spending spree has backfired on him.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has grandstanded in the past and he will in
the future. If he was serious about the offer he wouldn't have sprung it on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> --he would have talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> about it behind the
scenes <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. To offer deals that only benefit you isn't campaign finance
reform--it's cynical politics.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">B2B Need</ENAMEX>
Not Equal B2C

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Huang</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tue Dec</ENAMEX>
14

            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surowiecki</ENAMEX> says that the success of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">business-to-business</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">B2B</NUMEX>) Internet sales depends on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> ultimately
buying the stuff (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">B2C</NUMEX>)--certainly a valid point. But Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surowiecki</ENAMEX> misses one
crucial point: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B2B</ENAMEX> can exist without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">B2C</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> can purchase
goods in the offline world.

            If you take most large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX>,
to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surowiecki</ENAMEX>'s example, are no exception), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> purchase a lot of
goods--on parity with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> in some industries (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX>), but also
in far greater quantities in others (energy, telecommunications, office supply
goods, construction goods, etc.). Furthermore, the economies of scale you get
by focusing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B2B</TIMEX> are enormous: To take the example of the automobile, while a
consumer may make a single purchase, amounting to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20K</NUMEX> in net revenue, when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>, etc.) makes a purchase for a fleet of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, it's a one-time sale amounting to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20K</NUMEX> * large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> = very
large number. As you can see, making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> sale is probably more
cost-effective than making the consumer sale. Take, for instance, the oil
industry: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marketplaces</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">petrochemicals</ENAMEX> can be established online between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, but it would be illogical for a Web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to try and sell
gasoline to a single consumer pumping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>.

            
               (To reply, click here .)
            

         
      
   
