
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">358</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Foto Fun</ENAMEX>"

            
               I give the
picture; you give the caption.
            

            
               Compose a
newspaper-style caption for the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> news photo shown
below.
            

             

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">357</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2, 4, 6, 8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Do We Indoctrinate?</ENAMEX>"
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal District</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon Oliver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> said it "had the effect of advancing religion through government-sponsored
religious indoctrination." What
did?
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusades</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie Driscoll</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Express <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> at highway toll plazas for those who know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> as their
personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> Frellick
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
plan to teach school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to cry 'Please God, no!' before being shot by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classmate</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "Did
you know that all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> who weren't Masons were assassinated?
That's indoctri-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">friggin</NUMEX>-nation for ya!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Cloutier</ENAMEX>
            

            "An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX>'s announcement, just prior to lunch, that 'Everyone can
go outside for recess. Except the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, who have to sit inside and watch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goliath</ENAMEX> over and over and over again.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">As many</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> asserted, ours is a very observant, very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, so
please be sensitive to the displays of religiosity that are so common this time
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, often with elaborate lighting. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> caution: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> get cross if you
swipe the baby <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> out of their nativity scene, even if you replace it with
something better, like a live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>. Ask any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> what he'd rather see,
illuminated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic figurines</ENAMEX> or monkeys, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> is going to say,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monkeys</ENAMEX>! Where's my present?" Sure, it's easy to decry the commercialization
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX>, like putting trousers on all the figures in the nativity scene,
adding a big electric sign that flashes: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Wore Khakis</ENAMEX>," and pocketing
some pretty sweet change from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX> are generally nonprofit, and
yet my damned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> have threatened to call the cops if I set <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> foot on â€¦
well, enough about me. Except that I'd like to take this opportunity to wish
you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all season</TIMEX>'s greetings. A little impersonal, I know. How I wish I could
visit each of your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, when nobody's home, and go through your stuff. But
the sentiment is no less heartfelt for all that. So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merry Christmas</ENAMEX>, everyone,
and have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> on me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popo</ENAMEX>!

            
               What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Would Jesusâ„</ENAMEX>¢
Answer:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> voucher program is
government-sponsored religious indoctrination.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX> ruled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
tax-financed vouchers to attend that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> violated the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>'s separation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">six percent</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> receiving vouchers attend parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, among them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX>'s, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> handbook lists its No. 1 objective of education: "to
communicate the gospel message of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesusâ„¢</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters Guide</ENAMEX>: As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> voted for school vouchers. During
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s TV debate, he weaseled out of that decision by calling it "an
experiment in terror" (except for the words "in terror"). "And besides, I was
so drunk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>, I never knew what the hell I was voting for," he did not
add.

            
               One More Inverted
Headlines Extra
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vermont Court Insists</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Disease</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.C.</ENAMEX>
Study <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Links 'Mad Cow' Strain to Gay Partner Rights</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Solovay</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Corporate
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> Ongoing Extra
            

            Nothing captures the
spirit of this blessed season like a mass mailing from a vast commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to devise holiday cards from any
well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>, along these lines:

            
               Outside:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> gasses up the sleigh at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ExxonMobil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>.

            

               Inside: Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> from our remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>!

            
               Outside:
His sack on his shoulder, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> tiptoes into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> past dozing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountie</ENAMEX> at
border <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>.

            
               Inside:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> passes out cartons of cigarettes to appreciative lumberjacks.

            

               The message: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax-Free Greetings From Your American Friends</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>.

            Replies to run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Wan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> under God.

         
      
   
