
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greene Mile</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Fiennes</ENAMEX> makes me
think of a line from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Midsummer Night's Dream :</ENAMEX> "That is hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and
wondrous strange snow." His piercing blue eyes signal anger or torment while
his manner stays glassy and querulous. This aloof, slightly inhuman mix of
traits somehow suited both the insubstantial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Quiz Show</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>)
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> sadist of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>). (In the latter, his deep
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX> sounded great with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> accent, at once oily and metallic.) But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiennes</ENAMEX> is truly in his odd element as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham Greene</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Jordan</ENAMEX>'s
fluid adaptation of 
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of the Affair</ENAMEX>
               . He plays
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Bendrix</ENAMEX>, a self-centered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> who embarks on an opportunistic but
increasingly incendiary romance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianne Moore</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a
bland civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Miles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Rea</ENAMEX>). This happens during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> blitzkrieg, and the German bombs both heighten the passion (all rules
are suspended) and underscore the hopelessness: As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX> becomes more
possessive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> begins the inexorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham Greene</ENAMEX>-ian drift into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-abnegating Catholicism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiennes</ENAMEX> is superb at jealousy, and even better
when he has to fulminate at something so intangible and yet (to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greene</ENAMEX>) so
irrefutable as the existence of God. He looks enraged at having reached the
limit of his spiritual resources, and his haggard self-doubt humanizes him.

            The movie doesn't
capture all aspects of the novel, but that hardly matters: It's middling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene</ENAMEX>. The author barely bothers to characterize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> under siege (he was
more evocative when his settings were farther from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, as they almost always
were); and the last <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>--in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">atheistic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX> has his face rubbed
in the rightness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>'s faith--feels like a denouement, not a climax. The
glory of the book--of most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greene</ENAMEX>'s books--is in the dialogue, in which all
that vague spiritual yearning coalesces into candor so biting that it still has
the power to shock. Wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> dismiss each other with compact fury, while
the fiercest insults are reserved for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of a God who has let
despair run riot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene</ENAMEX>'s dialogue is already close to great screenwriting,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> edits and orchestrates it with masterful cunning.

            More important, he distills from the novel a mournfully wry
fable on the all-consuming convolutions of jealousy. We meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
after his entanglement with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> has (abruptly) ended, but an encounter with
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>--forlorn and hatless in a deluge, convinced that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is holed
up somewhere with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>--brings the green-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> (as well as a host of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX>) back with a snap. It's the ex-paramour, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, who hires a
detective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to dog the mysteriously wayward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>, and--in one of those
ironies that feels delightfully postmodern--it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX> himself who ends up
being trailed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockney</ENAMEX> gumshoe, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parkis</ENAMEX> (an amusingly earnest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Hart</ENAMEX>),
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> reinitiates contact. The story touches on sex farce, but only
briefly: This is a tale in which every possessive human act ends up driving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine closer</ENAMEX>--both spiritually and literally--to God. The movie is a
religious conspiracy disguised as a romance.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s mysticism isn't
on the surface, the way it is in some of his other films, but in the recesses.
He and his cinematographer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Pratt</ENAMEX>, have loaded the screen with
shadows--not the hard-edged ones of film noir but a sort of existential
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>) smudginess. The textures are muddied, the palette damp. It's as if
the light has had to pass through layer upon layer of dust and fog, so that
only the faded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yellows</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX>, and the occasional green of some wallpaper
register amid the ashy grays. You can't make this world seem too welcoming or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> will lose the incentive to seek out a better one. That means
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">freezing rain</ENAMEX>, cheerlessly crabbed interiors, and lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX> who visibly
live lives of quiet desperation. The effect of so much misery isn't
narcotizing, however. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene</ENAMEX>, is too sensitive to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vexations</ENAMEX>--to their colorful spasms of pique. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> don't go mutely; their
souls scratch and kick.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianne Moore</ENAMEX> is especially raw<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Her whitish</ENAMEX>, faintly
freckled complexion affords her no protection from the elements, worldly or
otherwise. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX> questions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>'s love while bombs drop nearby, she
responds by screwing him harder, her bare breasts looming over him, imperious
yet vulnerable as the plaster dust <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> down. This is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s soft-hair
performances. I tend to prefer the straight-hair ones--the razor's-edge
hysterics of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Big Lebowski</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Myth of Fingerprints</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), and the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Magnolia</ENAMEX> --although her soft-haired repository
of environmental poison in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>) is probably her most amazing
work. I love everything she does, but I wish that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> hadn't left her so
exposed. He misdirects her in her big scene, in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> falls on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX>'s love <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX> and her response to his apparent death spells the end of
her earthly happiness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> internalizes the emotion a shade too much, and her
lack of urgency amid the rubble borders on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. It's a mark of her stature
that another potential camp moment doesn't bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down: the line "It's
only a cough"--never a happy portent in a love story.

            At first, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rea</ENAMEX>'s hangdog
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persona</ENAMEX> struck me as overly pitiable for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>: A more repressed, formal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Englishman</ENAMEX> would make his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s open disregard seem less cruel. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greene</ENAMEX>
intends an element of cruelty, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rea</ENAMEX>'s blurry bewilderment is finally moving.
You can see why even a cold fish like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiennes' Maurice</ENAMEX> would feel compelled to
take care of him. In a late scene, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> invades the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>' seaside
idyll, which is an impulse that might seem out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX> and that
isn't in the book. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> has lifted the idea from another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greene</ENAMEX> work. Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene</ENAMEX> would juggle the same motifs for the rest of his life--the triangles,
the bonds between cuckolds and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, the self-sacrificing renunciations, the
use of birthmarks to indicate spiritual blight, the insistent pull of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholicism</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s interpolation seems not an impertinence but the highest
form of respect. On their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> date, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX> takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> to see
an adaption of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his novels and has to shield his eyes from the coarseness
of it. I think if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene</ENAMEX> took a date to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End of the Affair</ENAMEX> he'd
say: "The bloody cheek! I didn't--oh--hmmm--that's very good. That's very good,
indeed."

            By contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Darabont</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-hour</TIMEX> adaptation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>'s serial novel 
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX>
                is superficially
respectful but ultimately cruel: He exposes the work as hooey. Actually, not
all of the movie is melodramatic, pseudo-mystical drivel--<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about two hours</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>.

            That leaves a stately <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> in which the texture of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX> life in the death-row <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> is richly evoked. The rhythms are leisurely but fraught--even
the most casual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> carry an awareness of the electric chair nearby. The
day before an execution, the condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is sent away and a surrogate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Stanton</ENAMEX>) does a dress rehearsal. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Walkin' the mile …</ENAMEX>," repeats the old man
as he and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> troop down the corridor--known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX> of the floor--to the chair, in which he's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elaborately</ENAMEX> strapped, offered
an opportunity to make a final statement (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Sorry</ENAMEX> for all the bad shit I done"),
and mock-dispatched. When the surrogate makes a sick joke and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> erupt
in laughter, the head <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Edgecomb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>), silences them
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worriedly</ENAMEX>. He says they shouldn't make jokes because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>, when a man
will actually die, they might remember the joke and not be able to stop from
cracking up. That rebuke is a wonderful piece of writing--it establishes both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edgecomb</ENAMEX>'s watchfulness and his decency. The movie is full of details like
that: Its attention to rituals that other films don't have time for gives it
surprising power. And its episodic construction--which mirrors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s novel--is
a relief from the beeline structure of most big-budget thrillers.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> he <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> also features a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>, mentally slow
"Negra" under sentence of execution. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coffey</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Clarke Duncan</ENAMEX>)--note
the initials--was found clutching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bloodied little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and wailing that he
"tried to take it back, but it was too late." <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">About an hour</NUMEX> into the picture he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grabs Edgecomb</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>, puts his hand against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s crotch, and
generates a mystical white light; he then exhales a swarm of evil-looking black
particles that dissipate into the ether. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edgecomb</ENAMEX>'s bladder infection vanishes.
Eventually, these kindly white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> death row <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> sneak their pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.C.</ENAMEX>
on all kinds of useful errands, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of a terminally-ill,
bedridden white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, over whom the black giant hovers in a miraculous
inversion of a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX> rape fantasy.

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have influences; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> has nothing
but influences. The gentle giant plays with a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>-- Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> . The stricken executioner gets blessed by his beatific
sacrifice-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Budd</ENAMEX> . You could add a score of prison movies, along
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.T.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starman</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>), and even some vigilante
pictures. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.C.</ENAMEX> evidently isn't opposed to capital punishment as long as it's
the evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get punished.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> isn't a cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>: He recycles
these elements as if he has true faith in the power of his fables to heal. But
I find his storytelling both morally easy and artistically promiscuous. The
Green <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mile</ENAMEX> is a fat old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whore</ENAMEX> who thinks appealing to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s most
self-congratulatory instincts--stroking it until it goes blind--is a public
service.

         
      
   
