
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain Knocks Himself</ENAMEX> Out 

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s report from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> debate.
            

            From
the opening bell of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> went hard after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s punches were awkwardly
thrown--in part because the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> crowded the ring, keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> apart--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> absorbed the blows with genial poise. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
performance was otherwise clumsy and lackluster, he won by playing rope-a-dope.
He let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> wear out himself and the patience of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>. Here's a scorecard
of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is asked whether he acted improperly by asking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX> to expedite its review of a transaction by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> tries to change the subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>:
"Our money is coming in very well, by the way. Not anywhere near <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$74 million</NUMEX>,
but it's coming along pretty good." The implicit message of this quip is, "If
you want to look at somebody's fund raising, look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> delivers
it with a grin that suggests he's just razzing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. The grin isn't designed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protect Bush</ENAMEX>. It's designed to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. You're not supposed to get angry
at him, and neither is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is just having fun, right? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
chuckles along, playing the good sport. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> leaves a bruise without looking
mean. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> point to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moderator Tim Russert</ENAMEX> invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>
story, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has addressed the story adequately. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticizes McCain</ENAMEX>'s campaign-reform plan, which he claims would "unilaterally
disarm" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> fires back: "What you're saying is that we should
continue what happened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. That's disgraceful. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> money, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
money came into the campaign. … Right now, a supporter of yours is running
attack ads morphing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s face into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>. And by the way, ask him to
get a better picture, will you?" Everyone laughs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> grins again, adding,
"And ask him at least to disclose where this money is coming from."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX>
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> manipulates the evidence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> opposes a particular campaign-reform
plan. From this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> infers that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> favors "disgraceful" fund-raising
practices. Meanwhile, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "supporter" is running ads against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. From
this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> infers that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> can tell this "supporter" what to do. And in case
anyone misses the implication that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is funding the ads in violation of
campaign-finance laws, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to ask his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> where the ad
campaign's "money is coming from." Another point to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> for landing a second
blow and leaving 'em laughing.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> repeats that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s plan "is bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX> tries to move on, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> interrupts and tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, "You've raised
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 million</NUMEX>, and I don't think you have an idea of how important
campaign-finance reform is to restore the confidence of young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> replies, "What you don't need to do is tell me what I
have an idea about or not." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> stares ahead; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> stares at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">McCain</ENAMEX>
doesn't let up. "I don't believe you have a good idea," he says. "Otherwise
you'd get on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> grins again, but only at the end. He has delivered
most of his blast with a scowl. His mask is slipping, and his criticism is
turning personal. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> point to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Halfway through the debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> how he
would shore up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> replies that there's a
surplus. Then he turns the question on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. "We don't want to spend it all in
tax cuts," he says. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> [that] we're awash in cash.
We've got a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.6 trillion</NUMEX> debt that we're saddling young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with. We
ought to pay down the debt." This shot at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, like the one about the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$74</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>," comes out of nowhere. To get from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX>'s question to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s tax
plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has twisted the topic completely out of shape. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> can get
away with reaching this far for a punch once, but not twice. Another point to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> tries to respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s criticism of his
tax-cut proposal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> barks, "Could I finish my answer? <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX> !"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is grinning, but the grin is becoming ghoulish, and his voice is rising
to a tightly wound pitch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> maintains an air of ease and good humor, as
though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> is friendly. Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> gets a word in. "No one is
suggesting we pass the entire surplus back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>," he says. "But
your plan does," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> interjects. "No, it doesn't," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. "Yes, it
does," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> blinks in amused disbelief and, when asked by Russert
to respond, jokes, "No it doesn't, yes it does, no it doesn't." Everyone
chuckles. Not only has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> lost his temper, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has bailed him out and
has come through smiling. Two more points to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. In his closing statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says, "I'm the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> up
here who's been elected to an executive position." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s turn comes, he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tells Bush</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, I've had executive experience. I was commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> of
the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squadron</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Navy</ENAMEX>. It was a great experience."
This doesn't contradict what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said--another wild swing by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>--but never
mind. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> just wants to point out that he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> didn't.
By now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s expression is utterly humorless.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The week</TIMEX> began with rumors
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was doing so well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was going to attack him. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
spends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. He lands few blows, and he wears out his own
image as a good-natured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX>. Round <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
