
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Miracle Mile</ENAMEX>

            
               Movies

            

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> render a
split verdict on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawshank Redemption</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Darabont</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-hour</TIMEX> adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>'s serial novel. The film chronicles the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> served on death row by a massive, simple, and saintly black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duncan</ENAMEX>) convicted of molesting and murdering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, as well as his
relationship with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">white jailer</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>. Some are moved by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s themes of redemption and spirituality; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> says it's full of
"vivid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, humor, outrage and emotional release" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). Less kind reviews note the "inadvertently racist overtones" of
the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duncan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ) and say the movie has the "suffocating deliberateness of a river of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">molasses</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> the
movie in 
                  Slate
               : "not all of the movie is melodramatic,
pseudo-mystical drivel--<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about two hours and 15 minutes</TIMEX>.")

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deuce Bigalow: Male Gigolo</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>).
Not surprisingly, a slew of bad reviews for this bottom-feeding comedy about a
fish tank cleaner who falls into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gigolo</ENAMEX> business by accident: "Among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> of comedy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deuce Bigalow</ENAMEX> is for the undemanding" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence Van</ENAMEX>
Gelder, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Some go so far as to insult the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>,
calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Schneider</ENAMEX> "a runty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> of no particular talent" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
Wloszczyna, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reviewer pipes up in the movie's defense,
calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deuce</ENAMEX> "an hour-and-a-half goof on kinky sex, bathroom humor and
inner happiness … a considerable cut above the crop of recent features by other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNL</ENAMEX> alums" (which is not saying much) and that it's "funnier than it
deserves to be, not to mention rather sweet in a sophomoric,
manwhore-with-a-heart-of-gold kind of way" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Schneider</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Choice</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Sheehy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s psychological biography of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> is deemed old news by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> ("compartmentalization, the need of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX> to please
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> the enabler, who feels closest to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> when she's saving him from
impending disaster") that will be of use only as a "compendium of all the
previous reporting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' marriage" for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been trapped
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Collins</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source"</ENAMEX> column has had a
field day pointing out factual errors in the book over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX>.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> has a weakness for writing about "how our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> feel, not
what they stand for or what might become of them or even what we should think
about the things they do," the book has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in its favor: It has the
irresistible pull of "good local gossip" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>,

                  Slate
               ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> and to read the rest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shulevitz</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               Death
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923-1999</TIMEX>). The author of Catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> died of a heart
attack <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. Best known for his absurdist treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heller</ENAMEX>
published <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> novels as well as plays, screenplays, and TV comedy. Although
Catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> received mixed reviews when first published, it eventually sold
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10 million</NUMEX> copies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and "enriched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
lexicon with its title slogan and its new definition of absurdity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Woo</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait of an Artist</ENAMEX>
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Man</ENAMEX> , was completed just before his death and will be published
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' special section on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX>, which includes the original reviews of his novels and plays,
interviews, and other information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
