
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Avedon</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the many arresting
images in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sixties</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Avedon</ENAMEX>'s latest collection of portraits,
is a famous photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, looking either terrified or
defiant, is peeling back a bandage to reveal the scars left by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> from
would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valerie Solanas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>. The picture, however many times you've
seen it, retains its creepy power. It also invokes a remarkably complex set of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">references</ENAMEX>, and so might stand as an emblem of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> and the
book--for a number of reasons. Apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX>'s own iconic status, his pose
recalls a notorious moment of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> political theater: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>'s display,
to a press corps as yet unaccustomed to familiarity with the intimate anatomy
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>, of his gall-bladder surgery scar, which illustrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Levine</ENAMEX>
later rendered as a map of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s book exposes a number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scars</ENAMEX>, both physical and spiritual: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">disfigured</ENAMEX> face of a napalmed
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, the sores on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leper</ENAMEX>'s fingerless hand, the bent, swollen
nose of a tired, defeated-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbie Hoffman</ENAMEX>. This was a time that left its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mark</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            Scars
are not all that's exposed: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flipping</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Sixties</ENAMEX> you'll catch
glimpses of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol superstar Viva</ENAMEX>'s pregnant belly and fashion model
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veruschka</ENAMEX>'s breasts, as well as (among others) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf Nureyev</ENAMEX>'s penis
(impressive, flaccid) and satirist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krassner</ENAMEX>'s (less so, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-erect). And
then there are the bellybuttons: On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> page <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman Capote</ENAMEX>, no longer the
slender, bow-tied manchild <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avedon</ENAMEX> had photographed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade earlier</TIMEX>, pulls open
his dark shirt to show his navel, a winking eye in an expanse of pale flesh. On
the next page the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fugs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Weaver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Sanders</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuli Kupferberg</ENAMEX>) in all
their hairy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie insouciance</ENAMEX>, mimic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capote</ENAMEX>'s pose. (The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX>, by the way,
were not an era of ripped abs.) Not that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s omphalic interests have been
confined to the famous. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American West</ENAMEX> , his controversial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>
exhibition at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amon Carter Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> (published as a
handsome coffee table volume by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX>), features the exposed midriffs and
naked torsos of drifters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>-stop waitresses, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rodeo cowboys</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bellybutton</ENAMEX> might be an apt metaphor for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s intimate, unsettling work.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who gaze at their own navels are called narcissists. What do you call
someone who makes his living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gazing</ENAMEX> at other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s? A voyeur? A sadist? A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> freak? Or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>?

            It says a great deal about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Avedon</ENAMEX>, and about the
civilization he has documented for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>, that he has
published a fat volume of pictures of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and called it An
Autobiography . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photography</ENAMEX> is a relentlessly objective art, ours is a
relentlessly subjective age, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX> has meticulously organized his art
around this paradox. He understands that self-exposure, an organizing principle
of our politics and our culture, is a defense mechanism: The selves we
shamelessly exhibit to the world are screens, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX> uses his camera to
penetrate them. He catches <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbie Hoffman</ENAMEX> acting out for the camera--tongue
protruding, middle finger in the air, "fuck" emblazoned on his forehead--but
when you look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>'s eyes you see no joy, no mirth, no childish glee at
pissing off the grown-ups. You see the calculation behind the anarchic
theatricality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Left</ENAMEX> and also the sheer dread. When you look into the
faces of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Kennedy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> you see souls emptied by the pursuit
of power. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American West</ENAMEX> lays open souls crushed by the lack of
it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX> has done much to
revive the portrait as a central genre of photographic art. His only serious
rival is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving Penn</ENAMEX>, and his epigones (whether they admit it or not) include
everyone from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mapplethorpe</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Leibovitz</ENAMEX>. Among his precursors are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Margaret Cameron</ENAMEX>, the great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> portraitist,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Sander</ENAMEX>, who set out to compile a comprehensive visual record of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> life between the world wars. But while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s portraits clearly
represent his bid for artistic immortality--a bid he has assiduously devoted
much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> to mounting--they represent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> facet of his work.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1940s</TIMEX>, when he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> to capture the revitalization of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> couture--a moment captured in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Donen</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX> film Funny
Face , for which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avedon</ENAMEX> served as visual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, and in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astaire</ENAMEX> plays a fey, charming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Avery</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avedon</ENAMEX> has
produced a staggering corpus of fashion and commercial photography. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bazaar</ENAMEX> , where he was a protégé of the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX> and her equally celebrated art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexey Brodovitch</ENAMEX>, and then at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogue</ENAMEX> , to which he defected, for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million-dollar</NUMEX> contract, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s covers and spreads defined the frothy, exuberant spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
fashion photography in what will likely be remembered as its golden age. Along
the way, he produced a staggering number of images that have remained lodged in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> memory and adorned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dorm</NUMEX>-room walls: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dovima</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nastassja Kinski</ENAMEX> and the snake, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garfunkel</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> (on the cover of their breakthrough album <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bookends</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra</ENAMEX>
Streisand chewing on a daffodil, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Baez</ENAMEX> blowin' in the wind. If you can
conjure a mental image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S. Burroughs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Zappa</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marianne Moore</ENAMEX>, chances are you're thinking of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX> photograph.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s ubiquity, the extraordinary variety of subjects
and styles, and his willingness to shoot album covers, posters, and
advertisements as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>-worthy black-bordered prints, have
occasionally offended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton Kramer</ENAMEX>, for instance, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> retrospective at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> (which produced a gorgeous book titled
Evidence: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1944-1994</ENAMEX> ) "the ultimate capitulation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, money and
fashion at the expense of art." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, money, and fashion have been, at
least since the age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medicis</ENAMEX>, part of the ambience in which art is
made--and also one of its favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. And anyway, to quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashbery</ENAMEX>,
"What need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX> when the demotic is built to last?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photography</ENAMEX>, in
other words, is an inherently compromised art form--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX>, ephemeral, and
easy. Anyone can do it.

            In sifting through the
profusion of images <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avedon</ENAMEX> has assembled over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, it's hard to keep the
categories distinct. And this may be the point. "Distinctions between
reportage, portraiture and fashion have always seemed arbitrary," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographer</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> "I'm one of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> who can address a camera towards anything that takes his
interest, and I'm interested in many things." There is remarkable continuity
among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s celebrity portraits, his fashion layouts, and documentary work
such as the pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sicilian</ENAMEX> street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> mental patients
he took in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>. And how would one classify the brilliant hoax Avedon
perpetrated in the pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bazaar</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>--a series of garish,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hectic</ENAMEX>, faux-tabloid shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX> and model <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suzy Parker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cavorting</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>? Is it photojournalism? A prank? A happening? A
mess?

            The most powerful work in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sixties</ENAMEX> also defies
easy categorization. The endlessly reproduced images of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that decade</TIMEX> tend to
come from television or photojournalism: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marchers</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Edmund Pettis Bridge</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> fleeing burning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> clubbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. And though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX> "covered" the civil rights movement, the war in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Seven</ENAMEX> conspiracy trial, the pictures he took are
deliberately decontextualized. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American West</ENAMEX> leaves out the most
striking fact about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>--its landscapes; similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> pictures
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sixties</ENAMEX> --taken during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saigon</ENAMEX>--contain no
lush jungles or crowded urban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hueys</ENAMEX> or hamlets or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice paddies</ENAMEX>.
Rather than record the drama of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX> invited his
subjects--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, and ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>--to re-enact it. A picture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American GIs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the latter decked out in minidresses, heels, and a whole lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hairspray</ENAMEX>, captures the shame, arrogance, and bizarre innocence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
involvement. A few pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, we see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Emerson</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographer Denis Cameron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interpreter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nguyen Ngoc Luong</ENAMEX> staging a movie
still. And then, on the next page, the napalm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s face stops us dead.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX> is often accused of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploiting</ENAMEX> and manipulating his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, and of course he does. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, he
exhibited a series of deathbed portraits of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> clothing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>, which struck many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>) as an act of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unchecked Oedipal</ENAMEX> hostility. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Whitney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> documentary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Avedon: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Darkness and Light</ENAMEX> , he is confronted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bennet</ENAMEX>, who was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
when he put her on the cover of In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American West</ENAMEX> in a halter top and
denim overalls. She politely tells him of her self-consciousness and discomfort
at seeing the picture, and he explains to her that, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> are in some ways <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX>, the power, the control, ultimately
belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> alone.

            At the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>'s film, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX> is heard musing
on his relationship to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>, a religion that regards graven images as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sinful</ENAMEX>. While he denies that he has ever been observant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avedon</ENAMEX> confesses to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vague</ENAMEX> spiritual leanings. His most recent work, a portfolio in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> (which hired him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> as its first staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX>) is called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revelations</ENAMEX>," and it consists of pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilgrims</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> lamas,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>. But these photographs, seen against the
backdrop of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>'s protean career, seem strangely cold and disembodied. His
is, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, a thoroughly secular imagination. The metaphysical confidence
of the sincerely religious gives him nothing to work with--no secrets to
unveil, no narcissism to refract. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX>, the camera is the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> of
immortality, which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> accept on his terms: at the cost of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avedon</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mephistopheles</ENAMEX> with a camera--an exemplary modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
