
   
   
      
         
            Hot, Dada, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Still Dead</ENAMEX>

            

               (Note: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life and Art</ENAMEX>" is an occasional column that compares fiction, in
various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, with the real-life facts on which it is ostensibly
based.)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX>, the comedian
who died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 35</TIMEX>, enjoyed making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wonder
whether his acts were real or not. He would sometimes deliberately "bomb" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clubs</ENAMEX>, telling bad jokes and letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> grow more and more uncomfortable.
He loved planting fake stories about himself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> .
And then there were his repeated turns as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Clifton</ENAMEX>," a noxious, heavily
made up and toupeed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> who did things like abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinah Shore</ENAMEX> on
her own show by cracking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and handing her the shells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> would
swear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> were not the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. Even after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifton</ENAMEX> gag
had worn thin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> would continue to perform it, as comfortable causing
anger as he was getting laughs.

            Given this pattern, it
seems appropriate that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milos Forman</ENAMEX>'s new biopic about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>, starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>, would take liberties with its subject's life. But
despite some inevitable streamlining, the film hits the major points--both high
and low--in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s career. The most obvious factual change seems designed to
uplift the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> rather than unsettle it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>, who preferred to call himself a "song and dance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," was first spotted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, where he did a faltering "foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic</ENAMEX> who could also imitate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> brilliantly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> imitation
came before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> died and well before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> imitators were legion. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>
reportedly liked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s imitation the best.) Appearing on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> stood awkwardly next to a
turntable as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mighty Mouse</ENAMEX> theme played, opening his mouth only to lip-sync
the lyrics "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here</ENAMEX> I come to save <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>." He parlayed his foreign<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-man</ENAMEX> schtick
into a job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latka</ENAMEX>, the lovable foreign mechanic on the soon-to-be-hit series
Taxi , which debuted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s contract stipulated occasional
appearances--on episodes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latka</ENAMEX> didn't appear in--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Clifton</ENAMEX>, who
proved so rude to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast members</ENAMEX> that he was thrown off the set
permanently.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s professional life took an unorthodox turn
when he started wrestling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">arenas</ENAMEX> and on television--this, too, before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wrestling</ENAMEX> took off. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestler</ENAMEX> would provoke <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience members</ENAMEX> into
fighting him by making sexist remarks. Eventually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lawler</ENAMEX> challenged
him to a wrestling match and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> ended up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman-Lawler</ENAMEX> feud was orchestrated by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from the beginning, though
many would be fooled). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> began to lose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in part because of the
obsessive wrestling. He got into a believable-looking fight with fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> knockoff show on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX> ,
giving the impression that he had lost control on air. Taxi was
canceled. And he was banished as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX>
itself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> (after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> voted in a call-in poll to kick him off the
show).

            The film skips over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s adolescence and
college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, in which he developed much of his comic material. (During
college he also got his then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> pregnant; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> was later given away
for adoption. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> never met his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, she has since become
friendly with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon</ENAMEX>
includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>'s girlfriends, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne Margulies</ENAMEX> (played by Courtney
Love). But the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Margulies</ENAMEX> character is a "composite of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> [that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> dated]," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Zehme</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost in the Funhouse:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> and Mind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX> . In the film, the two meet when he
wrestles her on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merv Griffin</ENAMEX> --they actually met during a film shoot.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> did, it should be noted, date a lot of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>.

            The film does a good job of capturing the contradictions in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s personality. A devotee of transcendental meditation, he was also
prone to temper tantrums, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage personae</ENAMEX>--particularly the sexist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wrestler</ENAMEX>--upset some fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> (in life, as in the movie, the TM
movement threw him out at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point). Even though he was earning good money at
Taxi , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> took a night job as a busboy. Always trying to purify
himself through meditation and a strict vegetarian diet, he was at the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> addicted to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX> and sex, and he often visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>.

            And while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> was
desperate for fame, he deeply resented the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> that were best equipped to
deliver him fame. As <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon correctly</ENAMEX> shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> hated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sitcoms</ENAMEX> and wasn't crazy about the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi</ENAMEX> job: He eventually felt trapped
by the "foreign" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> adored. He was far more excited about
the money <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> gave him to film his own special in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>. In the film, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> is
given the special as an incentive for starring on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi</ENAMEX> , whereas in life,
it was made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taxi</ENAMEX> went into production. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90-minute</TIMEX>
program included segments such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> chatting with his idol, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howdy Doody</ENAMEX>,
and renditions of songs such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's a Small World</ENAMEX>." As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s co-writer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Zmuda</ENAMEX> reports in his book <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman Revealed</ENAMEX>! , it also contained
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few seconds</TIMEX> in which the screen was made to deliberately roll. In life, as in
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon</ENAMEX>, apoplectic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> declined to air the special. (It
would finally be broadcast on the network <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> after it was made--and draw
better ratings than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight Show</ENAMEX> , a fact that isn't in the
movie.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> an on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> is right to portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> as a
frustrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> pitted against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who just didn't get it. But in setting
up a world-vs.-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> theme, the film exaggerates some of the lengths to which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> would go to maintain his artistic integrity. When a college audience
annoys him by clamoring for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latka</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mighty Mouse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrey</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> proceeds
to read all of The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Gatsby</ENAMEX> on stage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> did read from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatsby</ENAMEX> in his act, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zehme</ENAMEX>'s book, but rarely did he finish
the "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter anywhere, much less two pages." And the movie occasionally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downplays Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s part in bringing about his own professional decline. Man
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> does not indicate, for example, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> came up with the
idea for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live call-in</ENAMEX> vote, nor that he had numerous
chances to nix the whole thing.

            In its most marked
deviation from real life, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon</ENAMEX> provides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> with a kind
of feel-good comeback. Earlier in the film, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> Shapiro
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny DeVito</ENAMEX>), frustrated with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s self-indulgent performances, tells
him that he has to decide whether he's out to entertain the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> or
himself. (In life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shapiro</ENAMEX> was similarly frustrated.) After being diagnosed
with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> decides to do a show at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Hall</ENAMEX>. The event
is the definition of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> pleaser, replete with appearances by the
Rockettes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mormon Tabernacle Choir, and Santa Claus</ENAMEX> (the act isn't entirely
without bite; there's also a very funny moment involving a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX>). And
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the evening</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> takes the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> out for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>. This all happened in real life--although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockettes</ENAMEX> weren't the
real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rockettes</ENAMEX> and neither was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX>. But the performance took place in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, well before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> got sick.

            By time-shifting this feel-good scene forward, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> relieves the true story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s depressing decline. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>, for example, his wrestling days come to an abrupt end after he and Lawler
erupt into a brawl while appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Night With David Letterman</ENAMEX> .
But in life, the rematches would continue. As Lost in the Funhouse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> actually joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawler</ENAMEX> on the professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circuit</ENAMEX> and traveled
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in a kind of "touring carnival." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zehme</ENAMEX> writes, "Nobody paid
much attention." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had once come up with a "has-been corner" skit, in
which, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zmuda</ENAMEX> recalls, forgotten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> "would be sent out to flounder in
front of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> ... in an attempt to regain some of their vanished fame,"
was on his way to becoming a has-been himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tellingly</ENAMEX>, the "has-been corner"
routine is not in the movie.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>,
the film is true to the record when it suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't believe that
he was really sick with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> tells Zmuda the
news, he responds that they can really make something out of this gag. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>
was a nonsmoker, which naturally made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doubt him. (In the film, as in
life, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> to visit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healer</ENAMEX> who pretends to remove
diseased-looking entrails--actually, concealed animal parts--from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s
body. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> immediately understands the put-on and laughs. But as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne Margulies</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zehme</ENAMEX>, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>] actually seemed to be getting better at
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. He believed it was magic.")

            What the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neglects</ENAMEX> to mention is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> had
often talked about how he would like to pull off his own death. And there are
still those who believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>, like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>, is out there
somewhere. In the epilogue to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman Revealed</ENAMEX>! Zmuda
writes--perhaps in an effort to ratchet up the mystery factor--"I've often been
asked, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'Had</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> lived, what would he be doing?' The answer is obvious: I truly
believe he would have faked his death."

            The film's own mild flirtation with mystery comes
in the final scene: A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s funeral, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Clifton</ENAMEX> performs in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">club</ENAMEX>, doing a rather spirited rendition of--what else--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Will Survive</ENAMEX>." We're
expecting a trick, but we're also pretty sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zmuda</ENAMEX>, who
sometimes played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifton</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> was alive. However, the camera scans the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> until it lands on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zmuda</ENAMEX>, who's watching the spectacle along with everyone
else. This "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tony Clifton Live</ENAMEX>" performance did actually take place except Zmuda
was, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifton</ENAMEX>. And the occasion? A <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> benefit.

         
      
   
