
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint Boris</ENAMEX>

            "How
do you feel in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> was asked. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy</ENAMEX>," he replied.
According to Le
Figaro of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, which supplied this anecdote, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, who resigned on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>, totally eclipsed all the actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads of state</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX>, etc.--gathered in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> to celebrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and several black <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">limousines</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> noted that, despite reports of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
military setbacks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> "will finish with the
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chechen</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>." Earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, he had predicted a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX> victory in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>, but after a festive luncheon held in his honor
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezer Weizman</ENAMEX>, he halved the estimate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> had been stocked with a selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vodkas</ENAMEX>. When
asked to sign a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>'s book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin "</ENAMEX>spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few long minutes</TIMEX> writing
laboriously in the volume," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said. "But all he left for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">posterity</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> was his signature and the date." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> , meanwhile,
continued its campaign to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weizman</ENAMEX> to resign, after reports,
which he has not denied, that he received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $500,000</NUMEX> in gifts from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>.

            The
Independent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> reported allegations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>-block
bombings that ignited the latest war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> and propelled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>
into the presidency were the work not of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>, as claimed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, but of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> special services. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> correspondent
claimed to have seen a video in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> captured by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX> made the allegations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Identifying</ENAMEX> himself as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexei Galitin</ENAMEX> of the GRU
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military intelligence service), the bearded captive said that the
explosions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last September</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volgodonsk</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had been carried out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRU</ENAMEX> in collaboration with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSB</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> of defense dismissed the video
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> dirty trick. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> armed forces protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It is
impossible that they would attack their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> said.

            From
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Khrushchev</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikita</ENAMEX>
Khrushchev, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Times</ENAMEX> that he is "scared" by the transfer of power
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin to Putin</ENAMEX>. Khrushchev, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> who became
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX>, said he believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> launched the war in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> to mask the fact that he has no economic program for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> fronted what they called a snub to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, when it consecrated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> "patriotic" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
without his authorization. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> described the action as a severe blow to efforts to
normalize diplomatic relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> and said that "the
timing of the ceremony at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing cathedral</ENAMEX> appeared to be an open challenge
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just hours</TIMEX> before he was due to ordain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> from around
the world at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter's Basilica</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> are
a major obstacle to the restoration of diplomatic relations, the paper
said.

            The
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with a report
of an epic escape from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese Communist</ENAMEX> rule in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> by the teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> great sects of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan Buddhism</ENAMEX>. It said the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
karmapa, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, crossed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX> on foot with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>
before stumbling into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharamsala</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> seat in exile of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. He had traveled <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">900 miles</NUMEX> from his remote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> home, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 miles</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northwest</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lhasa</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX>
called his flight a "body blow" to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, which
recognized his enthronement as a living <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and was suspected of
wanting to manipulate him to drive a wedge between his sect and the dominant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gelugpa</ENAMEX> sect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, the karmapa
left behind a letter saying he was going abroad "to get the musical instruments
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> mass and the black hats that have been used by the previous
living <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhas</ENAMEX>." Playing down his defection, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New China News Agency</ENAMEX> said
that he "did not mean to betray the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>, or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>."

            For
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> ran an editorial
calling for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> to be made more accountable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
and the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Praising Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s record as he embarks on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> term
as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said, however, that "the concentration of so
much policymaking power in the hands of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> does not constitute
international best practice. Nor does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> win <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> prize for openness and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transparency</ENAMEX> in central banking." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> led its front page, as did the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , with the inquiry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> auditing profession
following revelations of rampant violations of share ownership regulations by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PricewaterhouseCoopers</ENAMEX>, the world's biggest accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> reported
"exclusively" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Zeta Jones</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Welsh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film star</ENAMEX>, has agreed
to sign a pre-nuptial agreement forgoing any claims on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Douglas</ENAMEX>' fortune
if their marriage fails. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> on his Web site that they
plan to marry sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeta Jones</ENAMEX> didn't want a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> wedding but hoped to marry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX> in a tiny chapel close to her
childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Wales</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
