
   
   
      
         
            Scam of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>

            After
weighing the relative merits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohandas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>, and other great figures, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> has named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX> the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>." How do you become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX>? There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> steps. First,
do something great. And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> in the punditocracy
to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> the contest in your favor by fiddling with the meaning and sequence of
the judging criteria.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Influence. At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, this seems the most obvious
criterion for choosing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX>. Trouble is, it's been a nasty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> world
wars, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> purges), so if you look for who did the most to
cause it, you'll end up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX> debate, this has become the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitler Problem</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Grunwald</ENAMEX> have identified the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FÃ</ENAMEX>¼hrer as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>'s most
influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's online poll (with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5 million</NUMEX> votes
cast), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> is in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> place for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX>, trailing only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> makes fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's deliberations about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>.
In a story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX> debate, the paper leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Isaacson</ENAMEX> saying, "You can't write off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>," since "many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" argue
"that he had the most influence on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> by far. To not consider him
would intellectually dishonest." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ends up crediting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> with all
similar evil, calling him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FÃ</ENAMEX>¼hrer of the fascist genocides and refugee floods
that plagued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>."

            So why
doesn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> win <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX>? Not for the obvious reason--that he was a really,
really bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--but because, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> puts it, "He lost." He wasn't
influential enough. If only he had won the war, he'd have bagged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> also offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> doesn't get the award:
First, he was derivative of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>, who sort of "begat" him. And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, if you
check the stats, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> actually killed more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            Then
there's the populist-elitist debate over what sort of influence counts most.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaacson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>, the "great theoretician," was originally going
to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>, but the magazine
dumped him for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Edison</ENAMEX>, who invented gizmos that "had more impact on our
lives." The populists have the upper hand in this debate, because the media
want to please their mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> by naming somebody whose contributions most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can relate to. That's why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> 's "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
Shapers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Era</ENAMEX>" features world-historical figures such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ball</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi Strauss</ENAMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Football League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rozelle</ENAMEX>.

            

               Time rigs the debate in favor of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> by defining influence to
include the spread of their ideas and sentiments. While conceding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>
failed to establish peace and justice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> argues that his
doctrine of nonviolent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> has overtaken the world. (Never mind that two
of his other big ideas, sexual and material abstinence, went nowhere.) And
while admitting that the New Deal was confused and failed to halt the
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Depression</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> "restored <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' faith and
hopes" and thereby "saved them from fear itself." (Never mind that a similarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">artful</ENAMEX> case could be made for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, but isn't.) In general, the
interpretation of influence as the dissemination of ideas improves the POC
chances of cultural figures. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley Jr.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nominated Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> as his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX> for "providing the special spiritual
animus that made all the difference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s and '80s</TIMEX> in overcoming the
greatest threat of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, which was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtue</ENAMEX>. You'd think this was the obvious criterion for
choosing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX> by something other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> count. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtue</ENAMEX> favors <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JP</ENAMEX> II. But since this factor confounds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's choice of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> (who was more brave and honest), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> makes it
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> game, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX> supplied the earnestness and
uncompromising principle her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> lacked. The spin job on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> is even
more egregious. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Kearns Goodwin</ENAMEX> argued that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s "courage," unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s brains, teaches a lesson. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s defense, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> turns his physics into philosophy, saying he
"taught the greatest humility of all: that we are but a speck in an
unfathomably large universe." Furthermore, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> believed
in "divine harmony" and "often invoked God."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the great tricks of the virtue debate is the reciprocal blurb. To prove that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> are worthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> quotes
them praising each other. What better way to validate a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> than to quote
another great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> calling him a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwin</ENAMEX> plays the same game between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>'s fatal mistake, it turns out, was giving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> a negative blurb. "He called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohandas Gandhi</ENAMEX> 'nauseating' and a
'half-naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fakir</ENAMEX>,' " sniffs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , crossing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> off its list.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Themes. This is the most convenient way to pick a POC: List
the top themes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, and then select <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> who "embody" them.
Time explicitly uses this method to pick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> (science and
technology), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> (the struggle against totalitarianism), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>
(liberation and justice). Others personify the theme with a composite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX> such
as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX>" (submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riveter</ENAMEX> (submitted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwin</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> (submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> ). Once you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">finalist</ENAMEX>
representing a theme, the trick is to elevate your theme. In principle, this is
how <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Einstein</ENAMEX> wins: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> gets the nod. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> puts it, "He serves as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> â€¦ who built upon his work." He gets credit for
the Big Bang, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, the PC, and above all, television.

            In
practice, it's more complicated. The ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX> represents all the big
themes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>. This triathlon kills <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>, who wins the
defeat-totalitarianism contest but flunks the liberation-and-justice contest.
"He bulldoggedly opposed the women's rights movement, other civil-rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crusades</ENAMEX> and decolonization," objects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> has better
crossover appeal, since, in addition to defeating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, he expanded economic
opportunity through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the New Deal</TIMEX> (and gets credit for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s contributions
to "feminism and social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>"). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> wins the triathlon because in
addition to acing the science test, he prodded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
points for defeating totalitarianism), fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and immigrated to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> more points for defeating totalitarianism and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberation</ENAMEX> and justice), and preached pacifism and praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> more
points for liberation and justice). "As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>'s greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>, as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> who fled from oppression to freedom, as a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX>, he best
embodies" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> .

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Causality</ENAMEX>. The debate over whether to pick a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, philosopher, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> often turns on which of these fields drives
the others. Those who think culture drives politics (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>) argue that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">overthrew</ENAMEX> tyranny. Those who think politics drives culture
(e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwin</ENAMEX>) argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> spawned the civil rights and feminist
movements by putting everyone to work regardless of race or gender.

            Those
who think politics determines the course of technology (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>)
argue that technology built <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s power and that brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> defeated
him. And while some, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwin</ENAMEX>, argue that the wars against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">totalitarianism</ENAMEX> made economic progress possible, others, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, argue that economic progress made possible the end of world
wars.

            

               Time seals the case for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> by arguing that science drives
everything. Not only did it promote freedom "more than any statesman or soldier
did" by creating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, faxes, and e-mail, but furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s theory of
"relativity paved the way for a new relativism in morality, arts and politics,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">influencing James Joyce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pablo Picasso</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Igor Stravinsky</ENAMEX>, and others. (The
press, of course, has its own causal theory: The press drives everything.
That's why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Douglass</ENAMEX> picked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johann Gutenberg</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of the printing press, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>: "The written
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">word â€¦</ENAMEX> enables us to preserve our laws.")

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indispensability</ENAMEX>. The best way to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> the debate in favor
of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> is to stipulate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX> should be someone whose
accomplishments would never have happened without him. Since art is infinitely
various and complex, it's particularly implausible that anyone else would have
written <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s plays. This is how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> justifies his selection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shakespeare</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>, while dismissing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> on
the grounds that "science has its own logic and is going to get where it's
going," regardless of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> gets there first. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> counter this
spin by arguing that the inexorable logic of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> makes it more
significant than art or politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> on this point:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics</ENAMEX> is for the moment. An equation is for eternity."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Timing. If your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> scored his achievements early
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, stress his long-term influence. By this standard, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s
timing was excellent, earning him credit for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">subsequent decades</TIMEX> of
technological progress. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, by contrast, showed up too late to
get much consideration.) If your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> showed up later, stress the immediacy
of his achievements, since most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can relate to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s breakthroughs and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gizmos</ENAMEX> and have forgotten those from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of the century</TIMEX>. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dynamic</ENAMEX> explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> picked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Watson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Crick</ENAMEX> (who discovered
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>) as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> picked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> as
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>, and why end-of-year movies score well in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
Awards. What has the POC done for us lately?

            If your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> showed up
too late for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s contest, don't worry. Nominate her for next time. If
she's worth it, she'll still be in the running <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years from now</TIMEX>. And if she's
not, you won't be around to explain your goof. By its nature, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POC</ENAMEX> debate is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retroactive</ENAMEX>. No wonder the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> love it.

         
      
   
