
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=630250921-01071999><ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Man Talking</ENAMEX></SPAN>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 2</TIMEX>
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lives They Lived</ENAMEX>" issue memorializes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>'s dead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gravano</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Puzo</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> life honorable with The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gravano</ENAMEX> says that he himself borrowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puzo</ENAMEX>'s lines for his own
mob work. ("I'm gonna make you an offer you can't refuse.") …
A piece celebrates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Trump</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>'s no-nonsense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who built a
real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> in the outer boroughs with hard work and no flash. He lacked
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s imagination and grandiosity. … <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week</TIMEX> before his
execution, a death-row inmate remembers his miserable life: "Been unhappy from
the time I was born." … Others honored include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank DeVol</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> of the Brady Bunch theme; stripper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lili St. Cyr; Gorilla</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monsoon</ENAMEX>, the first pro wrestling villain; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Hart</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traditionalist</ENAMEX> sculptor the art world stupidly ignored.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31</TIMEX>
            

            The
exhaustive fin-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-siècle issue elects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>," because he is "a symbol for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> defined by
scientific advance. The cover profile hails the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">German-born</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geniuses</ENAMEX>" for helping to resettle scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> and alerting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> to the
need for atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> research. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">… Stephen Hawking</ENAMEX> explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s theory of special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relativity</ENAMEX>--the speed of light is constant while time and motion are
relative--turned centuries of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newtonian</ENAMEX> physics on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">… President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> honors runner-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Delano Roosevelt</ENAMEX> for "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> decisive victories:
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> over economic depression and then over fascism." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohandas Gandhi</ENAMEX> is also
a runner-up. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">… A "Most Important People of the Millennium</ENAMEX>" section
exalts the greatest historical figures of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each century</TIMEX>, including:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mongol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conqueror</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genghis Khan</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th -century</ENAMEX>
printing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press innovator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johann Gutenberg</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th -century Queen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> I of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Edison</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 10</TIMEX>
            

            A
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook 2000</ENAMEX>" issue anticipates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st -century</TIMEX> innovations. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> focuses on the race to map the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX>: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> hopes to finish a genetic sequence by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>,
before a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> can. Whoever wins will hold the keys to
creating personalized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> and cures for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">killer diseases</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
… A profile of zoologist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy Dresser</ENAMEX> applauds her
efforts to create a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">21 st -century Noah's ark</ENAMEX>" of endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dresser</ENAMEX> hopes to clone a near-extinct <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>. She has already produced the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s first <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">test-tube gorilla</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 10 and 17</TIMEX>
            

            

               The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> goes glossy for its "alternative" retrospective of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>. Highlights of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>'s correspondence include a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX> letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX> complaining that the magazine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wrongly</ENAMEX> said he served a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-month</TIMEX> prison sentence when he actually served <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. ... The cover
story delivers excerpts from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> 's archives, focused
around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> central themes: continuing class struggles and the rise of
Americanized capitalism. … Among the excerpts from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> is a prediction that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Garvey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> movement would enduringly raise the racial consciousness of black
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. … In a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1960s</NUMEX> excerpt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Baldwin</ENAMEX> argues that "The law is meant to
be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> and not my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>, still less my torturer." … A
1980s editorial predicts: "Things will come flying through
the windows of glasnost that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of
radical reform in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> neither foresee nor completely control."

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 10</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story crowns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>." (Note the defiant "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.") "No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> was so clear-eyed about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>." While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> was "tragically unwary of the new
global menace from the left," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> spearheaded the opposition to the "twin
scourges" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nazism</ENAMEX> and communism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who gave the Iron
Curtain its name is the true "democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of our age." … An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> accuses the press of overlooking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s
domestic-policy gaffes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s media "cheering section" neglects its favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s lack of coherence on tax and health-care policy. The mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> do not cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> any slack. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> emerges as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will exploit his domestic weaknesses.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31</TIMEX>
            

            This is the "millennium of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>," concludes the special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> issue, which is by far the best of
the millennial mags. The greatest events and achievements of the past <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> are reviewed, including the miraculous growth of prosperity since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1750</TIMEX>,
the persistence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">emancipation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the rise of the law,
and the invention of limited liability (the key to the rise of equity
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>). … The top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> inventions include electrification,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contraceptives</ENAMEX>, gunpowder, and calculus. … The issue is packed with
remarkable historical tidbits: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> article traces the rise of total war to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>'s conquest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zaragoza</ENAMEX>. … A piece considers what would have
happened if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederacy</ENAMEX> had won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> (the ascendance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>).
… The obituary is for God.

         
      
   
