
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guess Who's Coming to Dinner</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>:
               
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About a month ago</TIMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> informed us--by
e-mail!--that he was planning to divorce my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and had contacted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
Now he tells us he's coming home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. At the same time, my mother
invited a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of hers for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> dinner because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> recently
discovered her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-long</TIMEX> affair and has no one to share the holiday
with.
            

            
               The problem is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> hasn't told her friend
about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> wanting a divorce. Although we all plan to be civilized about
it, if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> makes some offhand comment about the situation, it will be
awkward to say the least. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I feel our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> should discreetly
tell her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> what's going on, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is very proud and prefers to
pretend that everything is fine, especially since she's the one who encouraged
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> to dump her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>'s afraid that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> will encourage her
to go along with the divorce--which she doesn't want to do. Should my sister
and I quietly tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> what's up? Or should we ask our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> to stay
away from the topic of the divorce during dinner? We don't know what to do that
won't make the problem worse. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> dinner is shaping up to be a nightmare.
Help!
            

            
               Can it get any more
awkward than this?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Can:</ENAMEX>

            Probably ... but you
have a day or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to make your moves. Since the woman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>, and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> wishes to keep her marital situation under wraps
(strangely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks) you should not be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to spill the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>. And
since your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> wants to come to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> dinner (strangely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks)
the mechanistic thing to do to salvage <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> is to quietly tell your dad
that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> hasn't broken the news to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> ... so could he please
pretend things are "normal." Take heart that yours will be just one of
countless such dinners around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where the family dynamics are, shall
we say, unusual.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, delicately

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>:
               
            

            
               As a young woman
with serious curves on a trim frame, I, myself, have had to deal with the issue
of my gazongas and my pretty face in a professional manner. I wear non-push-up
bras with thin padding, often marketed as "T-shirt bras," and I only wear
tight-fitting sweaters if they are black, long-sleeved, and matte. Tailored
shirts work well, too. I find that having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Hepburn</ENAMEX> as my style icon
for work clothes is an ideal solution, even though I've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX>
body. The difficult part for who wrote will be requesting, in a tactful
fashion, that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> dress modestly. I recommend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Hepburn</ENAMEX>
metaphor as a gentle and flattering way to make this request.
            

            
               Best wishes,
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear E.</ENAMEX>:

            You are nice to weigh in
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>. The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> will probably have to be a little more explicit than
just mentioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>'s name, however, because her style of dressing
is most associated with slax and turtlenecks. Also, the wonderful Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hepburn</ENAMEX>
was never known for remarkable gazongas. Prudie guesses it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hepburn</ENAMEX> aura
you're going for, since, unlike you, there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX> body
underneath all those tailored clothes. Just as an aside, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX> cannot quite
understand your wearing the "T-shirt bra" with its thin padding. Wouldn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">padding</ENAMEX>--even thin--be gilding the lilies?

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, titularly

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>:
               
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> little addenda to your advice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junior</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exec</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) If he wishes to continue to advance his
career, he might want to refer to his well-endowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>," not a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>." If, however, she is under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>, then he has a completely different
problem.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He might want to establish the difference
between "plain" and "major pair of hooters." The opposite of "plain" is
actually "beautiful," and the opposite of "major hooters" is "flat as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pancake</ENAMEX>."
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) What exactly is
the problem he wants advice for? Is he actually suggesting that having a
bazoomba fetish might hamper his career? Wake up and smell the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Junior</ENAMEX>.
This is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>!
            

            

               Nitpicker, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Emmaus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PA.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Nit</ENAMEX>:

            Hmmm. Bazoomba fetish.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thanks you for the new word ... and for letting the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> have it
with both barrels. Prudie, for some reason, only used one.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, mammiferously

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>:
               
            

            
               Thanks for all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> advice. Here is my problem: My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> calls me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every few days</TIMEX> for a chat,
and she is in the habit of eating while talking on the phone. She is invariably
crunching an apple or snacking on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> jerky every time I talk to her. It's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgusting</ENAMEX>! I actually try to avoid her calls so that I won't have to listen to
those noises. I think this is so rude and inconsiderate of her, but I don't
know what to do about it. I have even tried doing it back to her, but she
didn't get the hint. Her grazing into the receiver is making me nuts. What
should I do?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.E.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear S.</ENAMEX>:

            Instead of chomping on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> jerky yourself, hoping
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grazers</ENAMEX> will get the hint, why not opt for a more direct
approach? Simply say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>, you know I love you, but the noise of your
eating while talking on the phone distracts me from what you're saying." You
might suggest that she separate the activities of eating and phoning. If you
feel she wouldn't respond well to your request, then avoid her calls when you
can, and when you can't, hold the phone far away from your ear. Of course you
won't know what she's saying, but life is choices, my dear.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has the reverse
situation by the way. When talking to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, if she's in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> it always seems like a good time to do whatever dishes are in the sink.
This invariably elicits from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>: "Are you running <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>?" Until
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explicitly</ENAMEX> asked to desist, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will continue. This is all by way of saying
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do what they're in the habit of doing, unless specifically asked to
cut it out.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, habitually

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>:
               
            

            
               Do you know about the latest craze in parking
spots? They are "pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>" spots at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> and
grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. My contention is that these are no different in theory than a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> only" parking spot, though of course, in practice, racial
discrimination beats reproductive discrimination hands down. The contention of
the pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is that I'm a bastard.
            

            
               Should I take the
gentlemanly way out and quit parking in the spaces reserved for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeders</ENAMEX> or
continue my lonesome fight?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Sid</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has not heard of
these new preferential parking spots. It would seem prudent (to use the
adjective named for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>) to forgo your "lonesome fight" in the name of
peace and quiet. Hang on, though. The way reproductive developments are going,
it shouldn't be too long before you can look a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> in the eye and say,
"Sir, I am entitled to this space. Though I do not show yet, I am due in the
spring."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
futuristically

         
      
   
