
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Critical Photo</ENAMEX> Op

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> complained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> about the lack of support
within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>'s peace
negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. He went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> "without a hearty send-off from
all his political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> represented in the government
temporarily joined the opposition, which refused to place its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> who promised that he would 'do everything to achieve the best
agreement possible for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.' " The editorial concluded, "If they don't trust
him enough to give him a hearty send-off, they don't belong in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's editorial criticized the desire of "considerable numbers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>" to negate the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli Arab</ENAMEX> votes in an eventual
referendum on the return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. "It is wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">…</ENAMEX> to
single out any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as somehow disqualified to influence decisions, even
critical ones, that are being decided democratically," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            In
another alarm about the peace negotiations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> predicted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> will step up terrorist activities around the world in order to foil a
settlement. This was the conclusion of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> intelligence assessment
delivered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset Foreign Affairs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Committee</ENAMEX>, it
said. The general tone of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> remained positive, however. An
analysis in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aluf Ben</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> regards
the public handshake between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farouk Shara</ENAMEX> as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> achievement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> summit. "The photo of them together
will become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rubicon</ENAMEX> from which there is no turning back," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> wrote. "That
was always the main card that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrians</ENAMEX> held closest to their chest in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> game of peace negotiations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">… Barak</ENAMEX> won his photo-opportunity, even at
the relatively low level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX>, on the basis of secret
understanding with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--and without having to announce
his withdrawal lines."

            In a
report
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> said there are problems deciding who
will benefit from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s agreement to disburse <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.1 billion</NUMEX> in compensation
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave laborers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 130,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> will be eligible to draw from the fund but that a distinction
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> and forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX> is "a sore point" with central and eastern
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. It quoted an unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> involved in the talks
as saying that while no one denies that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave laborers</ENAMEX>, who were in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, suffered more than the forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>, the latter "should
get compensation that is dignified." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said infighting among
different sets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> has already begun, and he dreads the talks on
allocating the funds. "I have heard things I really didn't want to hear," he
said. "The most unfortunate thing would be if it became a fight between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. But this approach--to set up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> sum--really asks
for it."

            The
deal received little play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX>--and seemingly none at all in the
Frankfurter Allgemeine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitung</ENAMEX> , which led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> closing
in on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX>. Also leading on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chechen war</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> reported, "The damage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechen</ENAMEX> campaign is wreaking on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
relations with the West was accentuated by criticism of the West by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Javier Solana</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> security
policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supremo</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX>, said publicly that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> was not in his right mind." His comment on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catalan TV</ENAMEX> was widely
noted across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> as the most outspoken yet by a western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
is not in possession of all his faculties," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solana</ENAMEX> said. "We've seen it on
television across the world, and nobody can hide it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> also led
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, but with an opinion poll showing that a majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want economic sanctions imposed on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of them
think its behavior in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> is much the same as that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>
Times reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Stalin</ENAMEX> is making a comeback in the
parliamentary elections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Sunday</TIMEX>. His name will be on the ballot, and his
picture is on posters and billboards all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, it said. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> called
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bloc</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX> is hoping to break through the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>
barrier that would give it <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX>. A recent opinion poll showed
that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> were alive, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would choose him as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal</ENAMEX> prepares to hand over its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> Macau to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> forecast a new area of disagreement between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. In a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that next
spring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> will redouble efforts to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to pass
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Macau Policy Act</ENAMEX>, which will formalize <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX>'s
freedoms, culture, and autonomy. But it quoted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> as saying, "We will brook no foreign intervention. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">…</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he issue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX> and the affairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX> will be purely <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s domestic affair."

            In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> said it was a pity that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Macau Policy Act</ENAMEX> wasn't passed before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas</TIMEX> recess, because that would
have ensured the continuance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s vital textile exports to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. It also warned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, when it reconvenes, not "to slant the
act too heavily on political issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has not intervened directly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>'s domestic affairs. There is reason to suppose it will pursue the same
policy with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX>. A non-confrontational approach is the best way to support
Macau as it moves into a new era." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> also reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> have finally
reached an understanding on establishing diplomatic ties. Quoting unidentified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, it said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> has agreed to break diplomatic relations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> as part of the deal.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
ran photographs of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatle Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> performing at the tiny Cavern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liverpool</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> began and where he last appeared 36 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. The event even made the front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liverpool</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart Beats</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mirror of London</ENAMEX> reported
that around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles fans</ENAMEX> tried to watch the concert on the
Internet, but many found it jammed.

         
      
   
