
   
   
      
         
            Read My Vote: No New Taxes

            In the cyberfuture, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middlemen</ENAMEX> will lose
their jobs. Or so goes the theory. Insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, music label <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>, and even university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> will be annihilated as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> turn directly to the infinitely efficient Web to buy and sell goods
and services. Such "disintermediation" is supposed to transform politics, too,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> cashier the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middlemen</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX>--who represent them. Once again, the theory is that the efficient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> will let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> cast their ballots directly on all the issues.

            Out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, where we already run
on Internet time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> decided that political disintermediation via the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> was taking too long, so they passed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Initiative 695</ENAMEX> by a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
percent landslide in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX> general election. I-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">695</NUMEX> came in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> cuts the much-loathed annual license fee on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.2 percent</NUMEX> of the
car's value to a flat fee of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>, putting a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> dent in state
and local revenues. (Some of the license fee goes to local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>; most of
it goes to a shared transportation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>.) The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-695</ENAMEX> achieved
disintermediation: It prevents any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> or local jurisdiction from raising
taxes or fees without a vote of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            So, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> wants to so much as boost late fees on library books, it has to ask the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. The same goes if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> wants to add <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> to
the price of a cheeseburger at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Husky Stadium</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s first response to the tax revolt was … a
bunch of new taxes. The measure doesn't take effect until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX>, so dozens of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">towns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> have increased service fees on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewer</ENAMEX>, utilities,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">garbage</ENAMEX>, business, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>. From "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Inevitability of Death and Taxes</ENAMEX>
Department" comes the news that some jurisdictions are raising the price on
cemetery plots. As a countermeasure to all the taxes, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> whose tags
expired after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election are playing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> with the cops,
hoping to postpone the purchase of new tags until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, when they can pay
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> fee. (The savings are real: It cost me <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450</NUMEX> to license my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.) Meanwhile, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>, the disintermediated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> are walking around like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zombies</ENAMEX>. Stripped of the power to increase
taxes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> have been reduced to ceremonial bodies.

            The roots of the current
tax revolt go back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a recession year</TIMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> narrowly approved
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> sanctioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Initiative 601</ENAMEX>. I-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">601</NUMEX> placed a spending limit
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>, based on inflation and population growth, but offered no
tax relief. Instead, it diverted all excess state revenues to a special, almost
untouchable reserve fund.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s economy improved, the reserve fund swelled
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>, creating a political opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-695</ENAMEX> mastermind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Eyman</ENAMEX>, who makes his living selling mail-order sorority wristwatches out of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mukilteo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyman</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compatriots</ENAMEX> collected a record-setting
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> signatures for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-695</ENAMEX>, arguing quite rightly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was flush
with cash. Every time the political establishment damned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-695</ENAMEX> as
reckless--warning of reduced police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, cut public health services,
dry-docked commuter ferries, abandoned bus routes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super</ENAMEX> congested
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team Eyman</ENAMEX> just pointed to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> surplus.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX>, campaigned vigorously against <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-695</ENAMEX>. But he
changed his tactics at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX> when he saw the measure was going to
pass. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> promised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> would reduce the car tax
if they voted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-695</ENAMEX> down. This only gave I-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">695</NUMEX> additional credence. See! The
state doesn't need the money! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>'s vacillation also reinforced <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-695</ENAMEX>'s
ideological point that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> can't be trusted with tax rates.

            One peculiar thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> tax revolt is that
taxes are relatively mild out here. There is no state income tax, property
taxes rank <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> (as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), and the average sales tax is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 7.5</NUMEX>
percent. So what started as a revolt against an unpopular tax turned into a
referendum on disingenuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>--and their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weyerhaeuser</ENAMEX>, labor, and virtually every editorial page in the state opposed
I-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">695</NUMEX>, portraying it in hyperbolic, apocalyptic colors. The political,
corporate, and union <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> put their money where their mouths were,
too, dropping <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.1 million</NUMEX> to fight the measure, outspending the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-to-1</NUMEX>.

            The vote cut along class
lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Opposing I-695</ENAMEX> were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthy</ENAMEX> who live in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' waterfront
village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medina</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">750-618</ENAMEX> against). Embracing it were the working-class
residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tukwila</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Renton</ENAMEX>, who passed it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,065</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,378 and 7,103</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,190</NUMEX>,
respectively. The turnout was high (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57.7 percent</NUMEX>) for an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">off-year</TIMEX> election,
making the whole drama unspool like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Capra</ENAMEX> movie: The little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> beat
the fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, only the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> instead of good
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. The biggest applause line on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> came when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eyman</ENAMEX> screamed, "From now on, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are going to have to ask your
permission to take your money."

            Most"yes" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> dismissed the predictions of doom as
exaggeration, according to polls conducted on either side of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX>. They
suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of wanting to punish them for approving the measure. And
they also doubted that the political establishment--which helped pass new taxes
to build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new pro <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> for multimillionaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>--would
ever ease the irksome car tax. This confluence of a bad tax, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reserve</ENAMEX>, a botched opposition campaign, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> willing to call a bluff
resulted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-695</ENAMEX> victory. The unintended side effect is radical, direct
democracy: In what other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> set the tax rates?

            The inevitable legal
challenges have arrived, but they're all piecemeal, failing to address sweeping
constitutional questions. Given that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
are elected, legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> say it's more likely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> will narrow
I-695 than overturn it. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> has proposed spending <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reserve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> to bail out local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>--perhaps because he doesn't want to
be outflanked by the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> who has positioned himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>
who can make <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-695</ENAMEX> work (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> wants a financial review of all state
programs). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, predictably, want to preserve the surplus, which
they call the "rainy-day fund," by outsourcing government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> and cutting
budgetary "fat."

            The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> cushion averts the apocalypse for now. But
when the cushion is spent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX>, or when the next recession arrives,
the disintermediating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will find themselves playing the roles of budget
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and tax wonks. What and who will they tax? Will they tax themselves to
build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> and create new bus lines? Or will they stay the course and ask
government to do more with less?

            Instead of waiting for judgment day, watch-salesman
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyman</ENAMEX> is hastening it with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">695</NUMEX>." This tax-cutting initiative, which he
is readying for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX> election, will cap <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> property-tax
appraisals at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> and exempt <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> from the property tax (on the long
shot that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> might start taxing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> as property). And in a final
act of disintermediation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">695</NUMEX> retaliates against all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> and
council <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who thought they got the drop on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyman</ENAMEX>: It will roll back all
taxes and fees increased since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX>, when I-695 qualified for the
ballot.

         
      
   
