
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 10, 2000</TIMEX>

            We
landed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles de Gaulle Airport</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. One <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> books on how to get along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> pieces of
luggage, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of which had already gone missing. We drove for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90 minutes</TIMEX> in
heavy traffic, the baby howling, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> attempting to hide her exposed
nursing bosom from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>, and the dog scratching her bottom across the
floor of the minivan. At length we arrived at our new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Left Bank</ENAMEX>,
which we'd never actually seen, except in photographs. It was a small cluster
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>-size <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in a tiny garden tucked away at the back of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> of
an old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment building</ENAMEX>. We piled out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and rushed to the front
door, a small teeming peristaltic bundle of needs and hopes and anticipations.
The door failed to open. The key mailed to us by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> did not fit the
lock.

            For
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next 30 minutes</TIMEX>, we sat in the cold, dark <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> and waited,
mainly because we couldn't think what else to do. We were being punished for
our sins; we had wanted to dance, now we were paying the fiddler. It had been
fun, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> asked us where we lived, to say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, that's hard to say,
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end of the year</TIMEX> we're moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>." They were all envious, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretended</ENAMEX> to be, which was just as gratifying. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six months</TIMEX> we had
been playing our new role: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">People Who Are About To Live</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> . Now
here we were, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> itself. We knew no one. We spoke so little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> that
it was better to claim we spoke none. We had no purpose. And that, I should
have reminded myself, was the point.

            About
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months ago</TIMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tabitha</ENAMEX>, and I were on an airplane when I began to
complain about adulthood. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the many things I dislike about being a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grown-up</ENAMEX> is the compulsion to have a purpose in life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are forever asking
why you are doing whatever you happen to be doing and before long you succumb
to the need to supply an answer. The least naturally ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can have
ambition thrust upon them in this way. Once you've established yourself as a
more or less properly functioning adult, it is nearly impossible to just go
somewhere and screw off.

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> pregnant with our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabitha</ENAMEX> pointed out that the feeling of
being weighed down by adulthood wasn't likely to improve anytime soon.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parenthood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">loomed</ENAMEX>. There was a time when I suspected this wouldn't have much
effect on me. I figured that the chemical rush that attended new motherhood
might get me off the hook--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tabitha</ENAMEX> would happily embrace all the new
unpleasant chores and I'd stop in from time to time to offer advice. She'd do
the play by play; I'd do the color commentary. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five months</TIMEX> into the pregnancy
that illusion had been pretty well shattered by the anecdotal evidence. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> with a truly amazing gift for getting out of things he did not want to
do wrote to describe his own experience of fatherhood. "Remember that life you
thought you had?" he wrote. "Guess what. It's not yours anymore."

            At any
rate, since a door in our lives seemed to be closing, we went looking for a
window. As we sat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, one thing led to another, and before long we
had spread out on our laps the map of the world at the back of the in-flight
magazine. We had no idea where we would wind up; we just knew we were going
someplace foreign. My vague desire to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> got swapped, unfairly I
felt, for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s even vaguer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. Whole continents vanished
from our future in an instant. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 minutes</TIMEX> we had shrunk the world to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days later</TIMEX> we were at a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> across the table, an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, mentioned that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> had this old,
charming place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> occupied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> she couldn't stand. There it was:
Our bluff was being called. We agreed to rent the place, sight unseen.

            Now we
are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, in the cold and the dark, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> and friendless and
tongue-tied. Unbelievably, I hear myself asking: Why on earth did we come? Just
then an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> hobbles into the cobblestone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> and makes for the
door nearest ours. Our new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>! A distant memory lifts my
spirits.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, when I arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, to live outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in my life, I was fitting the key into my new front door
when an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> called to me from the neighboring garden. "My name is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Martin</ENAMEX>," she said in an ancient voice, "and I'll be your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> if
you'll have me." Just like that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Martin</ENAMEX> had taken me into her life; I
had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. She'd turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 that year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> had sent her a telegram to
congratulate her. When you know someone with that kind of standing in society,
you somehow feel you belong, too. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assimilation</ENAMEX> is just another word for
acquiring a bit of the local status.

            I eye
our new old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> with longing. And even though I know that the
moment history looks as if it is repeating itself is exactly the moment it is
not, I feel a little leap in my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spirits</ENAMEX>. I walk over, open a door for her, and
say bonjour . She doesn't even look up, just keeps tap-tapping on by with
her head down and right into her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. As she closes her door, the odor of
stove gas wafts into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>. A voice behind me says, "She so old she
forgets to turn off her gas burners when she goes out." I turn around. There
stands a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> wearing a black stocking cap, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">navy pea</ENAMEX> coat, and a grim
expression. He looks like something dreamed up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dostoevski</ENAMEX>, yet he sounds
perfectly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>. He motions to the door closing behind the elderly French
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>: "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> she'll come back here, light a match, and this whole building
will be a crater."

            He
puts his hand in the pocket of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pea coat</ENAMEX>. "I have your key," he says.

         
      
   
