
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Military</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> army
saved the world from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazism</ENAMEX> by holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stalingrad</ENAMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> pounded it
to rubble. Today, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s delinquent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepchild</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, is
fighting a city battle of its own. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> are pounding their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>,
Grozny, to rubble and are murdering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> in the process. Their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conquest of Grozny</ENAMEX>, which should conclude by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of January</TIMEX>, will complete
a methodical campaign of brutality. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> have inched through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, leveling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> with low-precision
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">artillery</ENAMEX> and dumb bombs. This "pacification" has killed many Chechen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and has turned most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>.
"In its indiscriminate use of firepower against civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, it is as bad
as anything since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lani Kass</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of military
strategy at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National War College</ENAMEX>.

            No matter. The war against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX>, who are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">despised</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">slavic</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, is wildly popular, proof that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military power is returning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> is payback for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, for
the first humiliating <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chechen war</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994-96</TIMEX>, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s triumph will ensure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>'s election as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>.
It has already restored the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s prestige and budget.

            But the notion that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>'s rape represents a return of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military glory is preposterous.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is turtling through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> partly because it doesn't have enough
competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to fight more quickly. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> can rely on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 20,000</NUMEX>
skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> could
muster "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX>" decent army <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> out of a paper strength of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>
divisions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s military is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lumpen -army</ENAMEX>, the dregs of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dregs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conscription</ENAMEX> remains mandatory, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 80 percent</NUMEX> of young
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> avoid it. The enlisted ranks fill with the stupid, the sick, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are little better than cannon <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fodder</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> makes no
serious effort to train them, because it doesn't have qualified noncommissioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> can't control the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conscripts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazing</ENAMEX> is unbelievably
brutal: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are murdered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> by their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brothers</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 500</NUMEX> kill themselves because of the horrific
conditions.

            Pay is laughably small
and usually in arrears. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has shelved its longstanding plan to switch to a
volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> because it can't pay enough to recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> spends <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one-sixth</NUMEX> as much on the military as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> did during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>. Clothing and rations are scarce: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> servicemen
have starved to death. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alcoholism</ENAMEX> is rampant, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> drink everything they
can get their hands on. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mig-25</ENAMEX> was nicknamed the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flying</ENAMEX>
Restaurant" because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> would drain and drink its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-based hydraulic
fluid.) <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hepatitis flourishes</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> don't know how to dig latrines. The
army is "a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of darkness," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army War College</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
Blank.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> can't afford to equip its so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. Only a
tiny fraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> materiel is equal to modern Western equipment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
lacks up-to-date communications, computers, and precision munitions. Much
hardware remains from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> buildup, but most of it doesn't work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX>
cannibalize spare parts to keep a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> working. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pilots</ENAMEX> lack the fuel
and equipment to fly training missions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX> arms <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> still produce
excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> for export (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti</ENAMEX>-ship <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, for example), but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
military can't afford to buy any of them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> conventional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> have grown so flaccid that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has altered its nuclear policy. It
used to abjure <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-use of nukes. Now <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-use is an essential part of
military doctrine, because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> knows it can't defend itself conventionally.
(The only good news about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is that it has regained secure control
over its active nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>--though not over discarded nuclear material.)
Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, which has long featherbedded its budget by inflating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> threat, has largely stopped pretending that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> can endanger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military interests. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> is no longer the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bear</ENAMEX> but a
"rather vicious ferret," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Galeotti</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keele University</ENAMEX>.

            This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> has decayed immeasurably since the glory days
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mighty Red Army</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> broke <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX>'s words, "tore the guts" out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
certainly exaggerated the competence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> military during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War, but it was still a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3-to-1</NUMEX> tank
advantage, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2-to-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> advantage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Army</ENAMEX> was the only institution
that matched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> in prestige. The best and brightest joined the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer corps</ENAMEX>. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> for every slot at some military
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. The state pampered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> with special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, chauffeured <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dachas</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Czarist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> were not artful, but they were often effective: weak on offense, strong
on defense. They performed poorly in far-flung adventures (the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>
War, for example) but savaged invaders when the Motherland was under attack.
They mastered brute-force warfare, throwing huge numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>, and
shells at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX> won <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> by losing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> invasion vanquished the myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">invincibility</ENAMEX> and aroused the popular mistrust of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> that
persists <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The breakup of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX> shattered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> pieces,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> lost nukes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>, and many of its best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to newly
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX>. In the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> chaos, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> found more ways to
duck conscription, and the quality of the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> plummeted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, who didn't trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, further damaged it by elevating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX>--with its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>--as a separate,
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of military power. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chechen war</ENAMEX> dealt the final
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgrace</ENAMEX>. The hardened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> slaughtered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s ill-prepared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, ambushing
them by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, pulled
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> off the front lines, and brought them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> essentially ginned up the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> war as a confidence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builder</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has reason to invade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>: The rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agitating</ENAMEX> to form a separate, antagonistic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> was itching
for an excuse to attack. When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechens</ENAMEX> raided the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> territory of
Dagestan, and bombs wrecked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> seized the
opportunity. (Many suspect that the bombings were staged to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshal</ENAMEX> support for
war.) Because it is a win-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-costs war to restore military prestige,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> have shown utter indifference to civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> and a
willingness to lie to retain popular support. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, for example,
consistently undercounts its war dead.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> tolerates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s atrocities
because it has no choice and because it is better for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to take out its
aggression on its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> than to go adventuring abroad.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman</ENAMEX>'s march through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> is not just boosting
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military pride. It is also increasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s political clout.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military has long been politically quiescent because a tradition of
professionalism pervades the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer corps</ENAMEX>. But the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> insisted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> grant them total freedom to prosecute the war. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>, who wants a victory
to boost his own prospects, granted it, essentially castrating the civilian
defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> and subordinating the interior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX>. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> now
fear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> are using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> to reassert control over national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> and foreign policy. Their militarism and nationalism bode ill for
future relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and the West. The general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, for instance,
has essentially forbidden <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> from talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>.

            As for the victory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, it's a mirage. For
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, victory simply means flying the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> flag
in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX> are fighting a guerrilla war. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
will shell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Grozny</ENAMEX> to its foundations and fly their flags, but they won't engage
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-to-street fighting: It's too bloody. So the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> can melt away and
join their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>'s southern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> has been
fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">217 years</TIMEX> and hasn't surrendered yet. It won't stop now.
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> continues south, it will find itself in another mountain
war--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, this time against a tougher and better-organized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX> will gradually bleed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garrison</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car bomb</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>, one mortar at a time--until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> withdraw in frustration. But
for now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> will get their victory --a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potemkin</ENAMEX> triumph for
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Potemkin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
