
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Banner Year</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the events we political Web-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> were waiting for has arrived: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serious</ENAMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have begun advertising on the Internet. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s campaign is now running several different interactive banner ads
targeted to Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> in early primary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> that allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to calculate how much they would save under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s tax plan. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to see the tax-savings banner.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> ran
banners soliciting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> to circulate ballot petitions for him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. (To see these ads, click here.) Today
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> announced another Internet ad campaign touting his support for a
permanent moratorium on Internet taxation.

             

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaigns are likely to follow suit with banner ads of their
own. But before these ads become as commonplace as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> TV spots, it's
worth considering a few of the issues they raise.

            

               Privacy: Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s banner ads were developed by
Aristotle
Publishing , a political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that maintains up-to-date voter lists and
sells them to campaigns for use in various kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> targeting, from
direct mail to door-to-door <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">canvassing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle</ENAMEX> has recently developed an
Internet application. It cross-references its voter information with data
collected by portals, Web sites, and Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. By sifting
such information together, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> believes it can surgically target
clusters of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of special interest to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--such as, say, married
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">30s</NUMEX> who are registered as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> have been using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle</ENAMEX>'s method of targeting banners for
their pilot Internet ads.

            But
this sort of targeting raises an ethical question: Should a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, by virtue
of registering to use a certain Web site, become the involuntary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> of
political propaganda? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay McAniff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aristotle</ENAMEX> says his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> relies on what is
known as "permission-based marketing"--that is, it only uses information
offered voluntarily, not the kind gained passively on the basis of "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>"
(click  for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s explanation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>). And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
campaigns both say they won't resell or otherwise use the information collected
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who click on their ads.

             

            But
even if all are scrupulous about what they do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> data, there's something
Big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother-ish</ENAMEX> about being bombarded with ads based on information you've
given for another purpose. Imagine if your television was able to gather
details about your viewing habits and your personal life and then transmit that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that wanted to use it to sell you things. You might find it
pretty creepy. With e-mail spam or old-fashioned direct mail, at least the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recipient</ENAMEX> knows that someone is marketing something to him with the help of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> that someone else sold. With banner ads, targeting can be invisible.

            

               Disclosure and Fairness: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott McClellan</ENAMEX> told
me that the campaign's banner ads have run on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 1,500</NUMEX> Web sites, including
Yahoo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excite</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClellan</ENAMEX> declined to give any more specific
information about the ad buy for "strategic reasons." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s campaign
couldn't provide the names of any of the Web sites where it was advertising.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle Publishing</ENAMEX> isn't even willing to divulge the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
actually places its banner ads on Web sites.

            If we
were talking about conventional TV or radio advertising, all such information
would be a matter of public record. According to federal law, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> have to
maintain open books showing who spent how much on political advertising. This
assures compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX> rules designed to
secure equal access to public airwaves. Mandatory disclosure means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WMUR</ENAMEX>,
the leading TV station in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, can't give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> a volume
discount without offering the same deal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>. But these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> rules
haven't yet been applied to the Internet, and it's not clear they can be.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISPs</ENAMEX> don't use the public airwaves, and they don't need
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">broadcasting</ENAMEX> licenses.

            
There's a widespread and largely sensible aversion to the mechanistic
application of existing campaign-finance regulations to the rapidly evolving
medium of the Internet. But the TV-Internet disclosure disparity is hard to
justify in principle and points to potential abuses down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. As it is
now, Web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> not only have the ability to provide diabolically precise
demographic targeting to political campaigns, they can also make such offers
exclusively. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> could theoretically offer its entire inventory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> campaign at a premium price.
This would be unfair to the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--and if done on television or
radio, entirely illegal. But a campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> I spoke to for this story said
he couldn't see what would prevent it on the Internet, so long as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> charged
at least the going rate for the ads.

            

               Effectiveness: Of course, we'll only need to worry about
issues of fairness and privacy if banner ads are seen by political campaigns as
working. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say the results of their effort aren't in yet, but
they're optimistic and expect to stick with Internet advertising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
campaign has more specific evidence of success. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
Schnur, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">192</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people clicked</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia</ENAMEX> banner ads, some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> of
those who viewed the banners. This isn't a bad response rate, though it means
the overall campaign was tiny--just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">impressions</ENAMEX>. But of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">192</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who clicked, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schnur</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> followed through by circulating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">petitions for McCain</ENAMEX>. An ad buy that probably cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $1,000</NUMEX> prompting
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to volunteer in person--that's true interactivity.

         
      
   
