
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">365</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Urge To Merge</ENAMEX>"

            
               Fill in the blank
as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven M. Case</ENAMEX> evaluates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> properties he's
just acquired: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional</ENAMEX> media assets have a vibrant future if they can
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">________________</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">364</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top 20":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  In his autobiography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> called it "the longest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of my tenure as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>." What was he doing?
               
            

            
"Writing his autobiography."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Deciding who to smoke <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>--the retard or the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
part where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest</ENAMEX> just keeps on running."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gus Robertson</ENAMEX>
            

            "Those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the karaoke bar just wouldn't let him sit down until he did two
encores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Clapton</ENAMEX>'s 'Cocaine.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            "Oh,
meeting with some visiting dignitary. From some other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Wore a rag on
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. Or was it a sombrero? Anyway, it was all, 'my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>' this, and 'my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>' that. Took forever."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            This was the toe shoe on
which many responses pirouetted: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is stupid. No argument here.
But how to explain why being caricatured as The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumb Guy</ENAMEX> sank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>, yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.W.</ENAMEX> is surprisingly buoyant? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possibility: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.W.</ENAMEX> is rich, and that seems to
be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> card in any conversation, at least with a fashion model. And
aren't we all? Another angle: He's quiet, leaving it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>, for example, to decide if there should be a big banner of a lynching
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluttering</ENAMEX> above their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Capitol building</ENAMEX>. It is hard to punch fog. Possibility
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: He's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, he's a logo. We don't expect badinage from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillsbury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doughboy</ENAMEX> or banter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Crocker</ENAMEX>. We know them to be the artificial
personification of a particular set of values--cut taxes for the rich, roll
back the civil rights movement, build an anti-missile system. (That doughboy
has always been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> for shiny yet unworkable military hardware.)
Possibility the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>: We the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are like terrified rabbits frozen in the
glare of the onrushing headlights of the great big truck that is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">G.W.</ENAMEX> That is,
we're paralyzed by the repeated idea that his election is inevitable. Which
brings us to possibility No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>: His election is inevitable. The fix is in.
Sufficient money and party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulars</ENAMEX> and money have been assembled to make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">primaries</ENAMEX> and indeed the general election even more than usually irrelevant. I
do feel like a rabbit. In toe shoes. And I've never looked lovelier.

            
               Hang 'Em High
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was loafing around with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX>, waiting
to execute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karla Faye Tucker</ENAMEX>. He was so distraught, he couldn't eat for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>.
No, wait, sorry, there is no record of his missing so much as a meal. And a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year later</TIMEX>, he was sufficiently recovered to mock the late Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> in
Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. That's resilience. Or something.

            In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> presided over the executions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, more than
any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> in any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> revived the death
penalty in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, a record his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb</ENAMEX> can only envy. No, wait, sorry--he
can also attempt to emulate it by persuading the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> to
"reform" its death penalty statutes so they can kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> as fast as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX>
do. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> needs a dream.

            
               Putting It All
Into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perspective Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s fellow
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> referred to "the hardest thing I've ever
done." What was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>'s greatest test?

            A: Breaking up with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melania Knauss</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slovenian</ENAMEX> professional beauty. On the plus
side, no lethal injection was required.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX>
Augmented Quotations
            

            Below, comments on the biggest merger in history.
Each final sentence added by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.

            

               "When I cast my vote for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100 million</NUMEX> shares, I did it with as much
excitement as I felt the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I made love <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 42 years ago</TIMEX>. And I was
just as drunk."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>
               

               "There has always existed the import of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> culture. It has been the case
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in film and television shows. They have content that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are very attuned to. Except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>, which just makes us all
sick."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Therese Torris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> Internet commerce, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forrester</ENAMEX>
Research, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX>
               

               "The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> element is connectivity, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> element is content, and the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> element is scale. No, wait, sorry--I was thinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> buying a new
supermodel, but it probably holds for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> thing."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Dixon</ENAMEX>, Paine
Webber
               

               "We had very few resources so we were forced to figure out how to get other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to carry our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Now we can carry it ourselves in a solid gold
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bucket</ENAMEX>, we're so stinking rich!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Kimsey</ENAMEX> , AOL
co-founder
               

               "I accept that something profound is happening in the Internet space; I
believe that. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, you can download pictures of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX> made love <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42 years ago</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald M. Levin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
               

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> is stupid.

         
      
   
