
   
   
      
         
            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> the Plagiarist

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Decoder Ring</ENAMEX>
Chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> has been almost completely decoded by an
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>. As reported in a recent issue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> , the very first sequenced chromosome may offer new insights into
many human diseases, including <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>. (The human species has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> pairs
of chromosomes.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, who hail from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zealand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, discovered that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chromosome 22</ENAMEX> contains
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33.4 million</NUMEX> different letters of genetic code and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 545</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. Thanks
to the Internet, the data has reached other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> around the world, many
of whom are using it in their own studies.

            
               Milestones in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of mass communication, advertising, and public
relations at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> stepped down from his administrative post after being accused of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plagiarism</ENAMEX>. In a lecture delivered to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> undergraduates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Schulz</ENAMEX> used a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>-word sentence from a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Stille</ENAMEX>
without attribution. The line was identified by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, who publicized the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transgression</ENAMEX> in an Internet chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and sent a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> says that he
didn't give the proper citation for the quote because he was pressed for time.
Still, he insists that his "ethical lapse" must be punished.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">…</ENAMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two-Year</TIMEX>
Supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheese</ENAMEX>
            

            Did
Lakeshore
Technical College in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>, over-prepare for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX>? The public
school's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130,000</NUMEX> general disaster-recovery plan, in the works for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>,
provides enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>-oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>, and electrical generators to
sustain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeshore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis J. Ladwig</ENAMEX> insists
that the program was designed for other contingencies, such as bad weather. But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milwaukee Journal</ENAMEX> Sentinel disputed this, publishing a story headlined "College preparing for worst from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Jauch</ENAMEX> denounced the planning as "nutty behavior that isn't
fitting of a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Meets</ENAMEX>
West
            

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> debated the value of studying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> cultures instead
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> ones when a call was made to establish a new curricular
concentration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> , a
conservative campus periodical, avowed that Western values are "superior to the
values of a primitive, impoverished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>." Now that the academic
concentration has been approved, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anand Shah</ENAMEX>, co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asian</ENAMEX>
student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh News and Observer</ENAMEX> , "I don't
foresee further debate about the issue." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Strader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>

               Review complained, "This is another example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke administrators</ENAMEX>
bowing to the interests of special-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>."

            
               Buying the
Court
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University School</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>--a k a "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Law School</ENAMEX>"--is supplying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Court of Justice</ENAMEX>
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX> with its very first batch of law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>. The intern program, which
will send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, is fully funded by money
raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> from (as yet) anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
Schwebel, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who once taught at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins</ENAMEX>, told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX>'s assistance was appreciated because
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> is in poor financial shape."

            
               But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will He Bring</ENAMEX>
Back the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Football Team</ENAMEX>?
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>
has chosen a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--but the debate over the ongoing shake-up at the
school continues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Michael Randel</ENAMEX>, currently <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">provost</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell University</ENAMEX>,
has been selected to succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Sonnenschein</ENAMEX>, who stepped down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sonnenschein</ENAMEX> had --increasing enrollment, scaling back the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Books" core curriculum, reducing overall stuffiness--changes that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faculty</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> feared would compromise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s identity. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicologist</ENAMEX> is expected to continue
with the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s plans, though in a more harmonious manner.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UC Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> To
Make the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grades</ENAMEX>?
            

            For
the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> have been able to ask their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> for written
evaluations instead of the standard grades. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 170</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> members
asked the academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> to adopt a more conventional grading system. A vote
on the proposal by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">588</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> was postponed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early December</TIMEX> after
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 1,000</NUMEX> grade-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> showed up to protest the change, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>.

            
               They Shoot
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>, Don't They?
            

            In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early December</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> complained in an Internet discussion
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX> that his religion thesis prep class was a waste of time, adding that one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> agreed with him. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaun E. Marmon</ENAMEX>, the professor
in question, says that she never agreed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and proceeded to post
a message suggesting that complaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were lucky not to be in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> and quipped that it was true that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> "do not shoot people
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX> anymore." The chair of the religion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of
Higher Education that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were "a little agitated" by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s message but added that no disciplinary action would be taken.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LegalEducation</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concord University</ENAMEX>
Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">School</ENAMEX>, which is located in cyberspace, is probably the only law school
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>,
and whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> attend class in their bathrobes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bader Ginsburg</ENAMEX> put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> into the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> when she expressed her
dismay about online legal education to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Jose Mercury News</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> decried the lack of "face-to-face interaction," to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concord</ENAMEX>
student <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Boletta</ENAMEX> responded, "I suggest that she might want to take a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tylenol</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and get ready for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21 st century</TIMEX>."

            
               More <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> Than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>
            

Conference of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Bishops</ENAMEX> approved a controversial set of guidelines
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">230</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of higher learning in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. The guidelines (click here to read
them) call for a majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trustees</ENAMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, for
new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> to publicize their commitment to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> of theology to receive a general approval from their
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX>. In the pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clara University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Locatelli</ENAMEX> warned that if the
guidelines are "interpreted too rigidly, we could look like seminaries and not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>."

            
               Preschool for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Freshmen</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regents</ENAMEX>
have tightened admissions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City University of New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>. Incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who test poorly on math and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> placement tests
will no longer be allowed to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CUNY</ENAMEX> while taking remedial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> to
improve their skills. Instead, they'll be redirected to other institutions to
prepare them for college-level work. The measure will affect <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> say the move will improve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CUNY</ENAMEX>'s standing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> worry
that it will discourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from applying to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
