
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabloids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1999 Secrets Exposed</ENAMEX>!

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, Keeping Tabs
has been eagerly awaiting the last few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. With every publication
known to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> kicking out special issues, she was certain the tabs would
follow suit and deliver some juicy, best-of-the-year/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>/millennium
packages. She could even see the headlines: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Machiavelli</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Health</ENAMEX>
Crisis!" "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther Packs</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pounds</ENAMEX>!" "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Nest With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'Gal Pal</ENAMEX>!' "

            But much to her chagrin, the tabs have hardly
mentioned the dawning of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX> (aside from a few New
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s predictions from their astrologers). Keeping Tabs couldn't help but
wonder if the tabs' reluctance to reflect might have something to do with their
track records. Would the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> want to be reminded, for example, that
its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4</TIMEX> issue announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX> was "about to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>"? (At press time, she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> are neither married
nor expecting.) What about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 21</TIMEX> issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> that
explained "why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce Brosnan</ENAMEX> will NEVER marry sexy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keely Shaye Smith</ENAMEX>?
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> became happily engaged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next month</TIMEX>, prompting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> to
claim that its story forced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brosnan</ENAMEX>'s hand.

            Would the Star care to recall the fact that
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX>'s engagement to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Sklar</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> was
reportedly "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> over heels" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>? Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>
still stand by its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> prediction that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camilla Parker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowles</ENAMEX> would publicly announce their secret engagement "at the end of this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>," with a wedding to "follow soon after"?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Nuf</ENAMEX> said. Since the
tabloids aren't interested in remembering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that was, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> has
assembled her favorite tabloid moments of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> ost hyperbolic story: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX> cover
story on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Surprising Hush-Hush Romance</ENAMEX>" between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prince William</ENAMEX> and teen pop
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">star Britney Spears</ENAMEX>. While the tabs are notorious for speeding up celeb
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>' romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">timetables</ENAMEX>, this romance is so hush-hush that, well, the two
have yet to meet. But that doesn't stop a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star source</ENAMEX> from speculating
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spears</ENAMEX> might consider marriage if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> were to ask.

            
               Most creative use of a prepared statement: A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5</TIMEX> story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> wire reported that comedienne <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeline Kahn</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hansbury</ENAMEX>, announced her death outside a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. "We
all suffered a great loss <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansbury</ENAMEX> told the assembled media. "While we
mourn her passing, we celebrate a full and wonderful life." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following week</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansbury</ENAMEX> "sobbing" those exact words "to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>." 


            
               Most overused
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cliché</ENAMEX> : Celebs dying alone and heartbroken. See, for example, the
Star on the "sad, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of What's Happening</ENAMEX>!! 's <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shirley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemphill</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> on the "sad, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Corby</ENAMEX> of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waltons</ENAMEX> ; or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> on the "sad, tormented life" of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> ost dubious proof of pregnancy: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aforementioned Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX> story, in which one of the "strong hints" that
Aniston was "in a family way" was the fact that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> come to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> set, she is always "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to rush over and ask if she can
hold the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tot</ENAMEX>." (Keeping Tabs is sure that with that in mind, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
just skipped the pregnancy tests and started painting that nursery.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trend Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> would like to go on
record as vehemently opposing: The kinder, gentler National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , which is apparently modeling itself after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> is now filled with headlines such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cat's Incredible:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Kitty</ENAMEX> walks <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2000 miles</NUMEX> back home" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millionaire Businessman Learns to Read</ENAMEX>
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>!" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> has also taken to running "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Helpful Household Hints</ENAMEX>"
and paying for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' contributions: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Thoughts"</ENAMEX> (Sample entry:
"To me, happiness is finding that your flashlight works after the lights go
out.") and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> for "Why I love my pet."

            
               Secret tabloid
technique debunked!: The tabs' habit of crediting "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>"
with information gleaned from talk-show interviews. To wit: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's story on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sopranos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edie Falco</ENAMEX>--cribbed entirely
from her appearance on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Show With David Letterman</ENAMEX> --and this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>'s "secret passion" for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>
sales. Keeping Tabs now considers herself an "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX>," given that she knew all
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s "secret" passion after watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> discuss it at length
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Donnell Show</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> ost ironic tribute: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> salutes all
the "much loved" public figures who passed away in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, most notably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Bessette Kennedy</ENAMEX>. "Our hearts are particularly heavy
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> as we look back at those we've lost," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> writes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lovingly</ENAMEX>. "May they all rest in peace." Apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> subscribes
to the theory that incessant posthumous prying ("They hadn't slept together for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX>" screamed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX> cover) is just the thing for
those trying to rest in peace.

            
               Most tedious "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World Exclusive": The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-page spread on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanya Tucker</ENAMEX> and her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-week-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>,
Layla, which basically consisted of frame after frame of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in
varying proximity to the sleeping newborn.

            
               Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> clichés
in a single story: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> piece about convicted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">murderer Susan Smith</ENAMEX>, who is said to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) taken a lesbian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60 pounds</NUMEX> from bulimia; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) become desperate to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>.

            A nd finally, the best tabloid headlines of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>--oh,
what the hell, of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>: Both were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> . In second
place: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Made Love to Potsie in Hot Tub While His Wife Went Shopping</ENAMEX>." And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> prize goes to (drumroll please), "I thought my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was cheating with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX>--but I found her with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>."

            Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>. May you
stay out of the pages of the tabs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. 

         
      
   
