
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masked</ENAMEX> and the Unmasked

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Thomas Anderson</ENAMEX>'s

                  Magnolia
                takes place on a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dark night</TIMEX> of the soul in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> is dying. No, hold on, this is a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-hour</TIMEX> movie:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarchs</ENAMEX> are dying. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich geezer Jason Robards</ENAMEX> is slipping in and out of a
coma on a bed with an oxygen tube up his nose while his minky young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianne Moore</ENAMEX>) acts out her despair at losing an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> she thought she'd
married for his money. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">geezer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Seymour Hoffman</ENAMEX>) listens to
his semi-coherent monologues then decides to get in touch with the dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX>), who gives inspirational lectures in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exhorted</ENAMEX> to "turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> receptacles" and to leave behind their
"unmanly" pasts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> gets a double dose of his unmanly past <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this night</TIMEX>,
since a female TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">April Grace</ENAMEX>) has uncovered the history he has
determinedly concealed and is eating through his mask of machismo on camera.
"We may be through with the past," says someone, "but the past isn't through
with us."

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> dying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paterfamilias</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Baker Hall</ENAMEX> as the host of a quiz show for bright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
He bursts in on his estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melora Walters</ENAMEX>) with news of his
imminent demise, but the addled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> for some reason (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three guesses</NUMEX>) won't have
anything to do with him. His visit sends her into a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>-snorting frenzy,
which is interrupted by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John C. Reilly</ENAMEX>) checking out her deafening
stereo: "You've been doing some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?" After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX>, it isn't clear
whether this dweebish flatfoot is interrogating her or trying to ask for a
date--or whether he even knows. Meanwhile ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> could have been
titled Meanwhile ), an aging ex-quiz-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid celebrity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William H. Macy</ENAMEX>) gets
fired from his job and goes looking for the love he never had, while a
contemporary quiz-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid celebrity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Blackman</ENAMEX>) tries to make his father
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bowen</ENAMEX>) understand that he wants to be loved for himself and not his TV
achievements--even if that means peeing in his pants on-camera.

            What's the connection among these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>? Some of the links
are familial, others merely circumstantial. But everyone and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> are
having a really lousy day. At the peak of their collective loneliness, the
cokehead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> puts on a plaintive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aimee Mann song</ENAMEX>, the chorus of which
goes: "It's not going to stop/ It's not going to stop/ It's not going to stop/
Till you wise up." She moves her lips and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> cuts to all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in all the movie's other strands as they all move their lips to the
same universal refrain: "It's not going to stop …" The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> sings.
The aging quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> on the barstool sings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> searching for his lost gun
sings. I thought, "Please don't make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coma</ENAMEX> sing, or I'm going to
be hysterical"--but yup, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the coma sings, too. At that point, I had
an interesting reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> : I laughed at it and forgave it
almost everything.

            OK, you could spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> snickering at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What the World Needs Now Is Aimee Mann</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metaphysic</ENAMEX>. But his vision cuts deeper than a lot of folky bathos. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have been screwed up by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, so when he turns around and
makes a case for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> as the ultimate salvation, he doesn't seem
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simple-minded</ENAMEX>. He's saying the diaspora is understandable--but that it's also
killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. At the point where these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could actually start dying of
aloneness, he goes metaphorical. He goes biblical. He goes nuts. He has sort of
prepared us with weather reports and the recurrence of numerals suggesting an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Testament</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> and verse. But nothing could prepare us for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">full-scale</ENAMEX>, surreal, gross-out deluge that's the picture's splattery climax.
For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time, he dynamites his own movie. And for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time I
forgave him almost everything.

            What clinches <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s case for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is how beautifully
he works with his surrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> show up from his Hard
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eight</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), and he's so eager to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> into the film, despite the lack of a role, that he makes him a game-show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX> named "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Guzman</ENAMEX>." He's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> who can't stop adopting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> knows what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> live to do: fall apart. He puts their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' backs against the wall, then gives them speeches full of free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freudian</ENAMEX> slips, so that they're suddenly exposed--and
terrified by their nakedness. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the first hour</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> ,
the whole cast is unraveling. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the second</TIMEX>, they've unraveled so
much that they've burst into song. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> must have needed that bonkers
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-hour</TIMEX> climax because there was nowhere to go short of spontaneous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">combustion</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>--all of them. It seems unfair to single anyone out, but I loved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reilly</ENAMEX>'s
unsettling combination of sweetness and prudery--unsettling because he's just
the kind of earnest, by-the-book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> whose wheels move too slowly in a crisis.
Between tantrums, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianne Moore</ENAMEX> opens and closes her mouth like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> that's
slowly suffocating at the bottom of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>. And who would have expected a real
performance from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> takes everything fake in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruise</ENAMEX>'s
acting--the face-pulling, the too-quick smile--and turns it into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s own shtick, so that when the mask is pulled off you get a startling
glimpse of the rage and fear under the pose. Elsewhere, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anderson</ENAMEX> uses Mamet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamety</ENAMEX> diction, but he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Anti-Mamet</ENAMEX>. He makes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> feel so
safe--so loved--that they seem to be competing to see who can shed the most
skin.

            The title card of 
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talented Mr.</ENAMEX>
Ripley
                is a stroke of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adjectives</ENAMEX> flash before the words
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ripley</ENAMEX> , with "talented" an imperfect substitute for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 30</NUMEX> other
possibilities, including "confused." Actually, I think confused (or vulnerable
or desperate) would have been a more appropriate choice. As played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> is for licking his lips and looking clammily
out of place. Dispatched to the south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenleaf</ENAMEX>
seeking the return of his wastrel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jude Law</ENAMEX>), the working-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX> has to pretend he's an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX>. But nothing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>'s
demeanor remotely suggests the Ivy League. Beside the smooth, caramel-colored
Law, even his pale little muscles seem like poseurs.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Minghella</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The English Patient</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>)
has adapted <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Talented Mr. Ripley</ENAMEX> from a thriller by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>
Highsmith, and it's a gorgeously creepy piece of movie-making. The Old World
luxury--even the Old World rot--is double-edged, subtly mocking its
bantamweight New World <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>. The light that bronzes everyone else burns
poor, pasty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX>. We watch him having the time of his life, but there's no
question of his ever fitting in with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickie</ENAMEX>, his willowy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marge</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>), or even their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX>, to-the-manner-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freddie Miles</ENAMEX> (a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hilarious Philip Seymour Hoffman</ENAMEX>)--he's too tense, too hungry, too incomplete.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ripley</ENAMEX> is by himself onscreen, there's nothing going on.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minghella</ENAMEX> is a thoughtful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a snazzy craftsman, but by the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX> , I wasn't sure what
had attracted him to this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. What does a vaguely masochistic humanist
see in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Highsmith</ENAMEX>? The novel's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ripley</ENAMEX> (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley of René Clément</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1960 Purple Noon</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alain Delon</ENAMEX>) isn't so palpably out of his depth. With
a bit of polish he can pass for a playboy, and the bad fun is watching him do
anything to keep from accepting the swinish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickie</ENAMEX>'s view of him as an eternal
loser. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX> is an eternal loser, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-chameleon</ENAMEX>, and so
conscientiously dreary that he lets <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Jude Law</ENAMEX> act him off the screen. He isn't
allowed to feel a moment's glee at seizing what these rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boobs</ENAMEX> have denied
him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minghella</ENAMEX> comes up with a bleakly sincere ending that's the opposite of
what this ironic little melodrama needs. He's trying to inflate it into
tragedy, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highsmith</ENAMEX>'s setups are too cold and shallow to be tragic. The
old biddy herself would have thought this ending stinks.

            Along with many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> caught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight Show</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'70s</TIMEX>. He sat next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Carson</ENAMEX> and in
his helium-pitched "foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" voice told jokes without punch lines (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Her</ENAMEX>
cooking ees so bad--ees terrible") and did non-impressionistic impressions;
then he got up and launched into the most electrifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> takeoff
I've ever seen. Without that final flourish of virtuosity, the shtick would
have been just weird. With it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> signaled that his comedy was about more
than untranscendent ineptitude: It was about wondrously fucking with your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            That whole act is
reproduced in the funny, frustrating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> biopic 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> on the
Moon
               , but not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight Show</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>)
does it onstage at a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. We don't know where it came from or what the
thinking was behind it. He brings down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> (lots of shots of people
smiling and laughing), then goes out for a drink with a potential manager
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny DeVito</ENAMEX>), who tells him, "You're insane--but you might also be
brilliant." That's about as close to analysis as the picture gets.

            As in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Wood</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>) and The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Alexander</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Karaszewski</ENAMEX>
take marginal or plain cruddy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and stick them in the middle of
breezily wide-eyed biopics. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Horatio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger</ENAMEX> tone is the joke, but it's not
a joke that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milos Forman</ENAMEX> seems to be in on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forman</ENAMEX> tells one, deadly
serious story: A reckless individualist is slowly crushed by society. It meshed
with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">McMurphy in One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>) but seemed odd
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amadeus</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>) and disastrous with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valmont</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valmont</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>). With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX>, it seems not so much wrong as beside the point. Where
did the rage in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> come from, and at what point did it kill the comedy?
More important: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Did Kaufman</ENAMEX> himself consider some of his experiments failures,
or had his aesthetic finally become so punk/pro-wrestling that he thought
driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> crazy was enough? As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jared Hohlt</ENAMEX>  in 
                  Slate
               , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comedian</ENAMEX> got sick at the point where he needed to reinvent himself to keep from
sinking into obscurity. The filmmakers reverse the trajectory (and the actual
chronology of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s career), so that he seems to achieve a magical
synthesis of warmth and aggression--and then gets cut down at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime</ENAMEX>. That's
not just bogus; it's false to the conflicts that ate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> alive.

            The reason to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX>
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>. It's not just that he does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> routines
with the kind of hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gleam</ENAMEX> that makes you think he's "channeling" the dead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX>. It's that he knows what it's like to walk the high wire and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. He
knows what it's like to lose control of his aggression: It happened to him in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable Guy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), maybe his real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX> film. I bet
that what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrey</ENAMEX> saw from inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> would be more illuminating than
anything in the movie. He's not just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the moon: He generates his own
light.

            Anyone who reads 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>'s Ashes
                is
torn down the middle--appalled by the misery and deaths of small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
yet exhilarated, even turned on, by the cadences of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank McCourt</ENAMEX>. His
alcoholic father starved him of real food but filled his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with the kind of
stories that nourished his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>'s instincts. I worried that the movie, directed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Parker</ENAMEX>, would miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCourt</ENAMEX>'s voice and dwell too much on the tragic
details. But what happens is the opposite: McCourt narrates the film, and it
turns into a lifeless slide show. There's no flow, no connective tissue between
episodes. After the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 th</NUMEX> teensy scene goes by, you realize the movie
isn't just botched: It doesn't even exist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Watson</ENAMEX> suffers prettily, but
whatever she's thinking stays in her head, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Carlyle</ENAMEX> is so mopily
present that you don't have a clue why such an earnest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> would drink so
many lives away. (The horror of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCourt</ENAMEX> describes is that he's not
at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> on planet <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> says his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was a helluva <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">storyteller</ENAMEX>,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on screen doesn't say so much as "Once upon a time …" Has anyone
involved in this disaster ever heard a real story?

         
      
   
