
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franjo Tudjman</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franjo Tudjman</ENAMEX> dies, as he is expected to any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> will surely write him an epitaph full of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandiosity Tudjman</ENAMEX> adored so much in life. Something like: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franjo Tudjman</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warrior</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dissident, Man of Letters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statesman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberator</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> of the
Free, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic Nation of Croatia</ENAMEX> ." History will remember
him more accurately: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franjo Tudjman</ENAMEX>: Not Quite as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> ."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX>'s good fortune
is that he has never been quite as nasty, stupid, and uncivilized as his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>-in-crime, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> shares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s eliminationist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nationalism</ENAMEX>, and he implemented it with similar brutality, using murder, war,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exile</ENAMEX>, and judicial terrorism to empty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croatia</ENAMEX> of non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Croatians</ENAMEX>. But the
untrammeled brutality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> overshadowed
the trammeled brutality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman's Croats</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s colorful crudeness
appeared more wicked than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX>'s schoolmarm prissiness. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> is thuggish, but he also craves the respect of the world," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivo Banac</ENAMEX>, who studies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> is a true believer, but he has not always believed
the same thing. Born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>, he enlisted with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX>
during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joining Tito</ENAMEX> was the only honorable course for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Croat</ENAMEX>:
The other choice was supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX>'s home-grown fascist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evil</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ustasha</ENAMEX>, which slaughtered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>. Tudjman
was a fervent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red</ENAMEX>, and after the war he rose through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> and party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranks</ENAMEX>,
eventually becoming the general in charge of party discipline. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>, at the
height of his career, he quit to immerse himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Croat</ENAMEX> history. Soon he was
a dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, and he served a term in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opposing Tito</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX>'s brave stand against communism would be
admirable except that he offered an equally bad ideology in its place: ruthless
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Croat</ENAMEX> nationalism. Though he had fought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ustasha</ENAMEX>, he began to excuse their
behavior, arguing that they had killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> claimed. He also
made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Serb</ENAMEX> statements and insisted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croatia</ENAMEX> was only
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croats</ENAMEX>. (The ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tudjman</ENAMEX> contrasts sharply with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. Tudjman
became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX> before it was fashionable; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> stumbled into
nationalism in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '80s</TIMEX> when it was convenient.)

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '80s</TIMEX>, Tudjman
used money raised from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Croat</ENAMEX> émigrés in the West to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist party</ENAMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> began to fragment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croats</ENAMEX> an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> and a convenient replacement ideology. They embraced him. He came
to power in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croatia</ENAMEX>'s independence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, was elected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, and was re-elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.

            Tudjman awakened and fanned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croats</ENAMEX>' sense of aggrievement.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croats</ENAMEX>, like everyone else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>, are aggrieved.) He hearkened back
to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 th century</TIMEX>, the only period when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croatia</ENAMEX> was independent.
He reminded his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> majority treated Croats like
second-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. He blatantly appealed to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Croat</ENAMEX> prejudice, emphasizing
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croats</ENAMEX> needed to unshackle themselves from the dirty, dark <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to their south and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> and join their real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. (Fundamentally,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjmanism</ENAMEX> is snobbery.) He resurrected Ustasha symbols, including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chessboard</ENAMEX> flag and kuna currency.

            Conventional wisdom
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> conflicts holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> is
an inflexible ideologue. But the history of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> suggests the
reverse: It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tudjman</ENAMEX> who has been flexible enough to triumph, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
who has been imprisoned by ideology. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> has employed roughly the same
tactics as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> but has always pulled back before irrevocably damaging
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX>'s standing.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were made for each other. For most of the
'90s, each used the other to reinforce nationalism at home. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tudjman</ENAMEX>
rewrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian Constitution</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> to undermine the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> used this as a pretext to invade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX>, capturing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-quarter</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX> inhabited by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> took advantage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s brutality
to ingratiate himself with the West. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> invaded, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> had
schemed with him to divide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> between them and throw out the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. But
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> double-crossed him, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> brought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX> into the Bosnian
war on the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, when he thought he could build a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Croat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tudjman</ENAMEX> turned on his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>. Bosnian <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Croat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militias</ENAMEX>--directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zagreb</ENAMEX>--imprisoned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of Bosnian
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> in concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, shelled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, and barred
humanitarian relief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convoys</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croats</ENAMEX> laid siege to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mostar</ENAMEX>, penning 50,000
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> inside, cut off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and launched an artillery
bombardment.

            Once Western pressure
became too great, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tudjman</ENAMEX>, displaying exactly the pragmatism <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> lacked,
stopped the assault and changed sides again. Tudjman silenced most outside
criticism by pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian Croats</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">federation</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. Tudjman
retained enough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> support that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> even allowed retired
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to train the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian</ENAMEX> military, despite an arms
embargo.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> again showed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> for limiting his
brutality just enough to get away with it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That summer</TIMEX>, he invaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krajina</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> area captured by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> fled to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> rather than fight. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Tudjman</ENAMEX> punctuated the arguably justified invasion
with a vicious exclamation point. He had his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> burn down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, passed laws to confiscate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> property, and allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Croat thugs</ENAMEX> to murder the few elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> who remained. "What he did after
the invasion was inexcusable," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Galbraith</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX>.

            Even so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> again
restored himself to the West's (semi-) good graces by signing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton Peace</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accords</ENAMEX> and agreeing to let <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> return to their burned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. But he has not
allowed them to return in fact. Only a handful of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> have come
back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krajina</ENAMEX>. (He has also refused to extradite the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Croats</ENAMEX> indicted for
war crimes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX>, perhaps fearing they would implicate him.)

            Domestically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> has displayed a similar gift for
conceding just enough to seem reasonable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX> is ostensibly a democracy,
but it has functioned under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tudjman</ENAMEX> like a semi-fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>. Tudjman,
who is fond of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Il Duce</ENAMEX>-type uniforms, rigged the parliamentary elections so
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist party</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDZ</ENAMEX>, could not lose. (For example, he guaranteed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosnian Croats</ENAMEX>, who are wildly nationalistic, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> seats in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>--even
though they don't live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Croatia.</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> has suppressed independent media
and used his control of state television like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. During the last
presidential campaign, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> times as
much TV time as his opponent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> has putatively supported capitalism, but
his idea of free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> is to privatize industries and give them to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian</ENAMEX> economy, which ought to be thriving from beach tourism
and low-wage manufacturing, is a mess.)

            This corruption and authoritarianism have irked
democracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, but it has not been enough to fully discredit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> dropped its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> embargo. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, albeit reluctantly, admitted Croatia
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Europe</ENAMEX>. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tudjman</ENAMEX> dies, a more democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croatia</ENAMEX> is
likely to be admitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>. Almost everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tudjman</ENAMEX> wished
for has come true. He has built an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Croatia</ENAMEX>, driven virtually all
its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> into exile, and won <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croats</ENAMEX> semi-autonomy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. He
is, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> put it, the "efficient ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleanser</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, has turned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah state</ENAMEX>, its economy destroyed,
its ambitions for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Serbia</ENAMEX> quashed.

            Even in dying, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> is proving his gift for
pragmatic villainy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> is reportedly suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stomach cancer</ENAMEX> that
has metastasized. According to most reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zagreb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> is brain dead
and has been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some weeks</TIMEX>. Croatia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> surmise that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDZ</ENAMEX> is keeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tudjman</ENAMEX> alive as a campaign strategy. Parliamentary elections are scheduled for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early January</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDZ</ENAMEX> is trailing the less nationalistic opposition in the
polls. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDZ</ENAMEX> seems to be trying to time his death for maximal electoral benefit,
hoping to generate a swell of patriotic sympathy that will help the party on
election day. Tudjman, who built his career on such <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold</ENAMEX>, grotesque, and highly
effective sleaziness, would surely appreciate the compliment.

         
      
   
