
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five-Minute Activist</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has raked in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 million</NUMEX> from his Web site. That sounds pretty
good until you consider that it's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 5 percent</NUMEX> of what he has raised
overall. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Elliott Brown</ENAMEX>, a novice <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>,
has raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $215,000</NUMEX> for her challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Foley</ENAMEX>. But she has
collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> of it--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 40 percent</NUMEX>--online.

            Brown
has done this with the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moveon</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX> , an online, grass-roots <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moveon</ENAMEX> first made
headlines in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1998</TIMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Censure and Move On</ENAMEX>." Launched by
husband-and-wife software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Boyd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Blades</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> they founded, is most famous for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Flying Toasters</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">screensaver</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Censure</ENAMEX> and Move On was an online petition campaign urging
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to call off impeachment proceedings, censure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and
get down to more important business.

            Every
online enterprise strives for viral marketing; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Censure</ENAMEX> and Move On was Typhoid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>. It signed up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months</TIMEX>.
The campaign delivered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of petitions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>,
swamped congressional switchboards with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX> calls, and won meetings with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>--all through what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blades call</ENAMEX> "word of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>." Originally, this was all intended to be part of a "flash campaign" that
would end with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blades</ENAMEX> were outraged when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> impeached <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> after the election, so they converted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Censure</ENAMEX> and
Move On into a "we will remember" campaign. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between December</TIMEX> and the end of the
trial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the site pledged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">volunteer hours</TIMEX> to oppose pro-impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            Things
were quiet for a while. Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moveon</ENAMEX> re-emerged as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blades</ENAMEX>,
and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> endorsed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. In addition to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moveon</ENAMEX> volunteer and public relations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>, the others
are: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Schiff</ENAMEX>, who's running against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Manager</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Rogan</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Keenan</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montanan</ENAMEX> seeking the seat of extremely
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Hill</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Carnahan</ENAMEX>, who's challenging Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashcroft</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Holt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pappas</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> who had gleefully caroled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twinkle</ENAMEX>, twinkle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor.

            Moveon
e-mailed solicitations to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who had pledged, as well as to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275,000</NUMEX> others on its mailing list. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Donors</ENAMEX> contribute online through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moveon</ENAMEX>'s
Web site; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> then delivers the cash to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. This
"Internet bundling" is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of its kind: It is modeled on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX>-mail
bundling practiced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily</ENAMEX>'s List. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moveon</ENAMEX> raised
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> and has harvested <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">another $240,000</NUMEX> since, without any
further solicitation. (The contributions are tiny--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92 percent</NUMEX> of them are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>
or less--but there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 13,000</NUMEX> of them.) This kind of cash can't replace
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> who are the backbone of every campaign, but it's enough to
matter in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> races. "We thought it might be interesting but
probably not really worth more than the time," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carnahan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX>. "It has way exceeded our expectations." For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schiff</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keenan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moveon</ENAMEX> money comprises <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent to 20 percent</NUMEX> of total fund
raising.

            Moveon
money made the biggest difference for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, turning her from a no-chance
challenger of a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> into a credible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moveon</ENAMEX> infusion
allowed her to report <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $100,000</NUMEX> in contributions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX> filing deadline. Now, she says, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily</ENAMEX>'s List
her, which they would never have done without the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moveon</ENAMEX> money. "For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moveon</ENAMEX> is far more important than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Democratic Party</ENAMEX>
or any interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Noble</ENAMEX>, who runs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PoliticsOnline</ENAMEX>. The only real
catch is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moveon</ENAMEX> money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exposes candidates</ENAMEX> to the charge that they are
bought by out-of-state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogan</ENAMEX>
are using their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moveon</ENAMEX> endorsement to help fund-raise from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>.

            
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blades</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moveon</ENAMEX> will also add more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to its roster this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">winter</ENAMEX> and will begin trying to direct those who volunteered time to campaigns.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blades</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> will ask for campaign contributions every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month from now</TIMEX> till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX>, in hopes of reaping the entire <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX>
promised. But even if it never collects <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $1 million</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moveon</ENAMEX> will be a
landmark: the first empirical evidence of the power of grass-roots Internet
politics. Its success all but guarantees that other political movements will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imitate Moveon</ENAMEX>'s style of flash campaign, which far outstrips the sluggardly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pace</ENAMEX> of direct mail. It is easy to imagine that an Internet movement could
spring up to oppose, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>'s gay-marriage ruling: A drive
targeted at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> could collect <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of electronic petitions in no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> and solicit contributions for anti-gay marriage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. Over time,
some of these flash campaigns may begin to evolve into new kinds of political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quasi-parties</ENAMEX>.

            "Five<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX> activism,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd</ENAMEX> calls this. It may become the fastest, fieriest method ever devised for
channeling citizen outrage.

         
      
   
