
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">355</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top 11 List</ENAMEX>"

            
               "It suspiciously
tracks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Falk</ENAMEX> about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> rules
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scott County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> intends to post in every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>.
Name one of these "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Common Precepts to Promote a Virtuous</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil School</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 354</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You're a Dead Man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX>"
            

            

               
                  After drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 50 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX> and ailing, is putting down his pen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to
describe his final strip. (Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delfin</ENAMEX>.)
                  
               
            

            "Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peppermint Patty</ENAMEX> come out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> admits his
'don't ask, don't tell' policy was a failure."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
cavalcade of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest 'Farewell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX>' appearances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Doonesbury</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dilbert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beetle Bailey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blondie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dagwood</ENAMEX>, and the inevitable Regis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philbin</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Frazier</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> bands together and kicks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garfield</ENAMEX>'s sorry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ass</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX> is wheeled into surgery at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sloan-Kettering</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Snoopy muses</ENAMEX> on what
life will be like without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> with the crooked smile. Back in the surgical
unit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> prepare to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX> his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemotherapy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> comes running in, and kicks the needle out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>'
hands."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX> wakes up in bed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne Pleshette</ENAMEX> and discovers it's all
been a horrible dream. Either that or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASPCA</ENAMEX> euthanizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Snoopy</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotchkiss</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            I liked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> .
(It is difficult to be funny in praise of anything, so if you want your little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laughs</ENAMEX>, leave off here and go peruse those newly released medical records with
their vivid--a little too vivid--description of the polyps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> doesn't have
in his colon. I'll meet you there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>. I'll bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX>.) For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, with impressive economy of line and language, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> avoided the
dimwitted rhythm of setup/lackluster punch line that defined comic strips and
would soon dominate TV sitcoms. Unlike most strips, his was about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>,
albeit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> depicted as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. And still more unusual, he was not
concerned with the follies and foibles of everyday life, that least interesting
comic subject, but something deeper, darker, and less ephemeral. Along with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, he provided comedy to my suburban boyhood--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> the
philosophical and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad the topical</ENAMEX>--at just the right intellectual level
for a suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. And if he sometimes wandered into whimsy--that alluring
comic swamp--and even farther, into mawkish sentimentality with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happiness Is a</ENAMEX>
Warm <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Puppy</ENAMEX>," he more often executed that most difficult comic turn, being
simultaneously funny and sweet. Few can. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX> come to mind. But not many more. I'll miss the strip.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happiness Is a</ENAMEX>
Warm Answer
            

            We can, of course, only speculate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> works
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six weeks ahead</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the final daily</TIMEX> installment will run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 3</TIMEX>; the last
new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> will be published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX>.

            The first <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX>
appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct., 2, 1950</TIMEX>. It now runs in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, reaching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 355</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            
               Fun With Subjects
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Predicates Ongoing Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Simply by swapping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> from a pair of actual headlines, you can eliminate the bad
news that fills our front pages, and create a happier world, as in these
examples using headlines from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Excite</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crystal To Host</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen Capital</ENAMEX>

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russian Troops Pound Oscars</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials Warn</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> Skit

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protest Forces NBC To Shelve West Nile Virus Return</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polanski Bad</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Elderly</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health-Study</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Water</ENAMEX>
Feted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Academie

            

            And, while it deviates
entirely from the form, there is this holiday cheer:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Garth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks May Retire Next</ENAMEX> Year

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited
to submit similar mix 'n' match pairs using headlines from any news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.
Results to run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peppermint Patty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcie</ENAMEX>: gay.

         
      
   
