
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">351</NUMEX>: "$$$"

            
               "I wonder if she
understands how much her life has changed this day. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itchy Pants</ENAMEX> has the
potential to make her a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>." Who said this about what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 350</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">USP Si</ENAMEX> ! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISP</ENAMEX> No!":
            

            

               
                  
                     On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> announced that it's
done something for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth consecutive year</TIMEX>.
What?
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Airbrushed Mary</ENAMEX>'s cigarette from its annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> and child <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
stamp."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secretly euthanized Donner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prancer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blitzen</ENAMEX>, so that some lucky mailman
can look like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> when he offers to 'help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> deliver those packages.'
"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Gavaghan</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Captured a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> before it got to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Hastings</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Sponsored a kick-ass bicycling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. So stop your bellyaching about the long
lines and homicidal postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, already."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Narver</ENAMEX>
            

            "For
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> consecutive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, it's going to let pretty girls ship everything book
rate."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            For <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33 cents</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33 cents</NUMEX>!
Less than the cost of a small caliber <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX>!--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> will
pick up a letter from anywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and deliver it to any place else in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>--any place! even some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> place way the hell out in the stupid
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of miles</NUMEX> away, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>!--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three days</TIMEX>! <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>! Why isn't that great? A bargain! A marvel! Why all the damn whining?
Could <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>? Could (as many of you noted) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shining Path,</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
               's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fiercely Maoist</ENAMEX> yet unreliable Internet service? Not likely! And now--licking
optional! If you want to lick, lick. If not, not. No way you'll get that kind
of freedom of choice from, say, those bastards at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil Exxon</ENAMEX>! There's your
precious private industry. I'd say some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> owe some
quasi-autonomous but government-regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> a letter of apology. Oh yes,
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, a letter.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next-Day</TIMEX> Delivery
Answer
            

            Once again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> is in the black. Its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$363 million</NUMEX> profit for Fiscal 1999, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$163</NUMEX>
more than expected, means that rates will remain unchanged until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s
Threat List Extra
            

            Speaking aboard the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.S. Intrepid</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> named
"potential threats" facing our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Which of the following are from his list
and which are mere fabrications likely to make him go nuts and start screaming
at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, what with that terrible temper of his?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Political and economic chaos in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s growing economic and military
threat.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Evil monkeys</ENAMEX> that might crawl up our trouser
legs and bite us on the ass.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Violent expressions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX> and ethnic
rivalry.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cats</ENAMEX> that read our minds.

to rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. The control of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction by a
really dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. You know--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orgejay Ushbay</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Information warfare such as an attack on our
private sector's computer grids.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crips</ENAMEX> and Bloods merging into supergang, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blips</ENAMEX>.
Or Cruds. Either way, bad news! Even worse than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and monkeys!

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Terrorism.

            
               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2, 4, 6, 8</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
made the list; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3, 5, 7</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9</ENAMEX> did not.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Least-Believable</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assertions Ongoing Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: We'll be together as much as we
can.

            (At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s press conference he claimed that,
although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> would be campaigning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> man
would be stuck in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, what they really wanted was to be together.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited
to submit similar credulity-straining claims--fact or fiction, actual or
invented, drunk or disorderly. Replies to run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, natch.

         
      
   
