
   
   
      
         

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Naturalization Service</ENAMEX> ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli√°n Gonz√</ENAMEX>°lez
should be reunited with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonz√°lez</ENAMEX>'s Cuban-American
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> had argued that he should remain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> after he was
rescued from a shipwreck in which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> died. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Protesters</ENAMEX> blocked
traffic in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonz√°lez</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> promised to appeal the ruling,
charging that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> was giving into blackmail by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> supporters
countered that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the ruling was based solely on legal concerns ; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the only blackmail was
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' threats of political retribution against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>'s spin: He's being reunited with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' spin: He's being denied a better life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> debated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. In their
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>, they clashed over health care and gun control and
agreed on support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> . But most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> said personality and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> --not policy issues--were
the true points of contention: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> deemed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> "too intellectually removed"
to deal with real-world problems; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> charged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was not removed
enough from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington bunker</ENAMEX>" to generate creative solutions. The rosy
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> spin: The frequent debates help both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates practice</ENAMEX> "crisper critiques of one
another and more polished defenses of their positions." The gloomy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
spin: The constant sparring over character issues makes them both less likable.
(
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> offers his assessment of the
debate in "," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> offers another take in ".")

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stock markets plunged. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s declines were the most
and the tech-heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.5 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> markets
followed suit. The apparent cause: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> waited for the new tax year to
reap profits from recent stock gains. The counterintuitive causes: Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">darling Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> was nominated for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> term as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> economic disruptions never surfaced--both of which increase
the likelihood that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> will raise interest rates. Wall Street shrugged off
the decline as a "necessary and expected" correction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> termed it an
indication that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are "even more confused than usual about what stocks
are really worth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX> explains why an interest-rate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hike</ENAMEX> would bad news for stocks in this "."

            

               Y2K came and went without terrorism or technological snafus.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airplanes</ENAMEX> stayed airborne and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATMs</ENAMEX> dispensed cash as usual. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX> said the
Y2K bug's threat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) was averted thanks to diligent preparation; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) had been
exaggerated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy programmers</ENAMEX> so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> would commission expensive
repairs; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) won't pass until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have used their
"backroom systems," which were not repaired as thoroughly as critical programs. ("" sums up
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX> coverage from around the globe.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> began peace talks. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> wants to regain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> captured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> wants
security guarantees and the restoration of normal diplomatic relations. The
initial discussions were deemed "rocky," with each side claiming that the other
was not following the agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> called the impasse a "crisis"
that threatened to derail the entire peace process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> charged it was
manufactured to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> that
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> bargained hard. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> downplayed the
dispute, saying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) no one expected a breakthrough in the talks' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round;
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the difficulties show that "the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> [are] getting into the knotty
issues." Separately, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> agreed to a plan for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> troop withdrawls from parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State</ENAMEX> won college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>'s national title. With a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46-29</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sugar Bowl</ENAMEX> victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 2 Virginia Tech</ENAMEX>, the undefeated Seminoles
became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to hold a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.1 Associate Press</ENAMEX> ranking throughout the
entire season. Sportswriters were happy for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State</ENAMEX> receiver
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Warrick</ENAMEX> , the undisputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of the game, who
"redeemed" himself after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s arrest and suspension for theft; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Bowden</ENAMEX>, who got his first undefeated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> national championship in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> of coaching; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Tech</ENAMEX> players , who "put <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>-long criticism
of their toughness to rest" with a valiant comeback attempt.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. In her long-expected
announcement , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> likened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> and said he would
repair the presidency's tarnished image. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> called it a win for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>,
who gains support from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women voters</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, who increases her chances of
nabbing the vice presidential nomination; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, who can again
cast "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> as the charmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX> and [himself] as the scrappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> resigned. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and is expected to win the presidency by a wide margin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
elections. In his surprise resignation speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> admitted his failings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundits</ENAMEX> agreed he had botched much of his job but also noted his shrewdness in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) capturing the world's attention on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) cutting his losses
before his communism-busting legacy was further tainted by a money-laundering
scandal or the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) designating his likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, who
has immunized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> from prosecution.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ni√±a</ENAMEX> is altering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> weather. The effects of the cooler-than-normal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> currents include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) balmy temperatures on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
tornadoes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) cool weather in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwesterners</ENAMEX> ran for cover. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Easterners</ENAMEX> celebrated with "giddiness usually reserved for the first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days of spring</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pessimists</ENAMEX> called the weather a "spooky "
reminder of Mother Nature's power and predicted further climatic changes from
the greenhouse effect.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> hijacking crisis was resolved. The still-unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrorists</ENAMEX> released their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">155</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> agreed to free <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of
their jailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX>. The hijackers were given <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 hours</TIMEX> to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>
and have presumably vanished into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> of backing
the hijacking and giving shelter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> of
playing politics with the hijacking. The rest of the world again worried about
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
                denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
for "trying to have it both ways on terrorism. They play host to terrorist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, yet wax indignant when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> hijack an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>."
(
                  Slate
               's "" rounds up overseas reactions to the
hijacking, and "" outlines the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> conflict.)

         
      
   
