
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emporium Strikes Back</ENAMEX>

            Every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, news stories about online <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas shopping</TIMEX> become more pervasive and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">effusive</ENAMEX>: It's fast, it's cheap, it's sweeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have taken their campaign into enemy territory. They have sent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emissaries</ENAMEX> to shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> with signs advising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to flee the chaos of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> of their PCs. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> are fighting back.
They're colonizing cyberspace with Web sites that invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> to log off and
hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Here's their pitch:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. We're fun. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> prefer in-store shopping because
they want to see and feel what they're buying. But while the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> do advertise
sensory advantages, they talk less about merchandise than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about</TIMEX> entertainment:
live music, fashion shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby pageants</ENAMEX>, carousels, and miniature <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> are maestros of counterspin. Whereas online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> promise to liberate
you from the congestion of shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> invite you to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-watch " in their food courtyards. And while e-shopping
spares you the trouble of dragging your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> around, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> promise to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entertain</ENAMEX> and "educate" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> through activities healthier than sitting at a
computer, such as art projects and puppet shows. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota's Mall of America</ENAMEX>
has <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pokémon "trainers</ENAMEX>" and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lego</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imagination Center</ENAMEX> ." <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Carolina Place Mall</ENAMEX> offers a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Science Show</ENAMEX>" and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story Time</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> ."

            To
lure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> promise tree <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lightings</ENAMEX> and other "sights and
sounds of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX>." The big draw is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> play it both ways:
They use <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>'s physical presence to lure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of all ages can have
their photos taken with Jolly Old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick"</ENAMEX>) and then offer, for an additional
fee, to put the pictures on Web sites or CD-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROMs</ENAMEX> so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> "can send [the images] to their loved ones over the
Internet ." <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tysons Corner Center</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, brags
about its "real-bearded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>" and "his authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> autograph." Tysons
Corner then spills the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> capable of reading the
rest of the page: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> is really <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Graham</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> and construction
company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. We're hassle-free. Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> point out that you
don't have to drive, walk, or lug packages and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> around when you shop
online. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> try to neutralize these annoyances. They offer valet parking,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> strollers, and free checking services for coats and packages. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gurnee Mills Mall</ENAMEX> boasts of its "baby changing
tables and nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> ." For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> who think of the Internet as
a labor-saving device, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tysons Corner</ENAMEX> promotes an even simpler option: "Our
Personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shoppers</ENAMEX> will, for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hourly</TIMEX> fee, take your requests
and return with terrific gifts."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. We're good exercise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> can't dispute that you'll
have to walk a lot, so they spin it as a virtue. "Lace up your walking shoes,
stride out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> Place and join us in a form of exercise everyone can
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">enjoy … Mall</ENAMEX> Walking," says shopcarolinaplace.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> (which points out that its concourses
are "climate controlled and barrier free"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallofamerica</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> advertises a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frequent Walker</ENAMEX> Rewards Program " featuring an "introductory
walking for fitness session" with a "professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">walker</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ontario Mills</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, promises that your "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>-mileage" will earn prizes--as long as
you "record your walk " during each visit.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ontario Mills</ENAMEX> is particularly duplicitous. On a page for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>, the mall
says it plays "motivational music on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mills TV</ENAMEX>, so you can treat your mind
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to an enjoyable, healthy and rewarding exercise program." But a page
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> reveals the truth: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mills TV</ENAMEX> is a state-of-the-art,
closed-circuit television network that saturates the common areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mills</ENAMEX> with commercial messages. … With a series of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
overhead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX>" large screen televisions spread throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario Mills</ENAMEX>,
there is
no escaping  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mills TV</ENAMEX> message. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">… Mills</ENAMEX> TV keeps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> longer,
creates a lasting impression of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, and most importantly, activates
the consumer's impulse to buy."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. We're good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> advertise the
capitalist advantages of not being anchored: easy access, low overhead, and
minimal transaction costs. Malls advertise the civic virtue of being anchored:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> service. They invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> to participate in food drives,
scholarship programs, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>-sponsored aid to "our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>" in "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>." They also boast of providing venues for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and school choral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tysons Corner</ENAMEX> is hosting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Child</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorus</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annandale United Methodist Church Choir</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax Baptist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Academy</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. We save you money. Before the Internet, you went to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">mall</ENAMEX> because it was cheaper than mom-and-pop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and you went from one mall
store to the next because you were already there. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> offered a volume
discount on your money and, in effect, on your time. Now that the Internet
saves you more money and time than the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> does, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> have invented new
volume discounts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gurnee Mills</ENAMEX> offers a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>-wide coupon
book . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mall of America</ENAMEX> advertises a frequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">buyer</ENAMEX> program. There's also a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mall V.I.P."</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> card " that earns discounts at "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
participating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. We offer more choices. Web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> promise a bigger
selection of merchandise than you can find in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Malls</ENAMEX> are outflanking
this pitch by pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>-wide gift certificates. The rationale for buying a
mall gift certificate instead of a gift certificate at an online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> is
complex in theory but simple in practice. Yes, each online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> has a wider
selection of goods than each mall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> does. And yes, cyberspace has a
wider selection of goods than any <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> does. But nobody has the time or mental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bandwidth</ENAMEX> to search all of cyberspace, and given a choice between a single
online store and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, you can probably find a wider selection at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> certificates, such as those advertised by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt Field</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mall</ENAMEX> , are good at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. We're user-friendly. Rather than ignore or disparage the
Internet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> exploit it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gurnee Mills</ENAMEX> instructs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to fill out an
online
form to get coupon-book vouchers via e-mail. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tysons Corner</ENAMEX> touts the
advantages of buying gift certificates online--you can "save time" and purchase
them "from the comfort of your PC"--and it even advertises "special
benefits that can only be received with online orders," such as
"special shipping rates." Far from suggesting that e-commerce is a security
hazard for credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>--a common reason why many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> refuse to shop
online--<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> go out of their way to dispel such concerns. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Holyoke Mall</ENAMEX>
encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> to buy "gift certificates online with our secure ordering
service." Tysons Corner assures <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> that it "employs
sophisticated technology to safeguard online transactions . ... The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> card and personal data you transmit is encrypted (scrambled) and sent to
a secure server."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. We're still your portal. Malls conquered the retail economy
by providing a selection of goods broad enough and cheap enough to gain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> and thereby control their options. When you wanted to shop,
you went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> and confined your search to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> you found there.
The Internet has simply transferred this principle to cyberspace. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> who
used to look for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> now look for portals, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> intend to become those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">portals</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RooseveltField</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> brings the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> to you, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any time day or night</TIMEX>,
when YOU have the time to shop," says that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>'s Web site. "Here you can
browse upcoming events, locate your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in our store directory,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> online or find products before coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>."

            By consolidating options
and information on their Web sites, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> command your attention and direct
you to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Need a gift idea? Tysons
Corner has all the answers . Wondering what's on sale? Scouring each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s Web site could take forever, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gurnee Mills</ENAMEX> puts
all the information on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> page . And while most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> let you click
on links to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, the links usually take you not to the national Web
sites of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> but to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummy</ENAMEX> pages on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>'s site that tell you
only about that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>. In the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, like the old
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, there is no escape.

         
      
   
