
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">363</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Edgy and Explosive</ENAMEX>"

            
               The list includes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">daggers</ENAMEX>, pipe bombs, spears, and bows and arrows. List of what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 362</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judge Mental":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shira</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheindlin</ENAMEX> ruled that because there was a "top hat" but no "bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>," something
must be done. What?
               
            

            "The
government must release <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Astaire</ENAMEX>'s censored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skinflicks</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
classified ad must be taken out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Arno</ENAMEX> cartoons must be redrawn so as to better represent the
diversity of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Cornog</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Make</ENAMEX>
sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chippendale</ENAMEX>'s delivers satisfaction."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Glassenberg</ENAMEX> had a similar answer, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S&M</ENAMEX>.)

            
"Apparently, they're making the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Monopoly</ENAMEX> tokens more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gay</ENAMEX>-friendly."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> treated the top hat as a self-consciously anachronistic symbol of
the rich. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, not the hat, are self-conscious; although I'd wear
my hat more often if it were a little more self-aware.) But while the silk hat
no longer invokes uptown swells, no other headgear has replaced it in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metonymy</ENAMEX>. Indeed, compared to the prewar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthy</ENAMEX>, the contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich</ENAMEX> have no
apparent class markers. It is not just hats but entire wardrobes that fail to
denote magnificent excess: The modern rich dress like business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and like pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, if indeed anyone is wearing
anything other than sneakers and jeans. The opera <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>--natural habitat of the
top hat (i.e., the opera hat)--is no longer the preserve of the rich; it is, if
anything, a cathedral of gay culture. Nor have the rich maintained that audible
indicator, that quasi-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, quasi-lockjawed accent that the swells all had
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX> movies. The rich now talk like everyone else, except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>, who speaks as if taught by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Fosse</ENAMEX>. Not even the long limousine
inspires a class-conscious hooligan to hurl a paving stone; the wise ragamuffin
knows he's likely not seeing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> on the way to
their prom. In an ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tux</ENAMEX>. And entirely hatless. But he throws it anyway.

            
               Stealing From the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poor Box Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of America</ENAMEX> must pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Aramony</ENAMEX>,
its imprisoned former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.2 million</NUMEX> in deferred compensation.

            Aramony, jailed for
fraud and embezzlement after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of stealing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>, had a "top
hat " pension plan, a grotesquely lavish package of benefits far richer than
those offered to ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Because his contract did not include a
"bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> "clause that would have revoked his benefits if he
committed a felony, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheindlin</ENAMEX> ruled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> must pay up.

            
               You Are What You
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perq Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            This actual e-mail was
sent to everyone at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX>. I intended to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to devise
similar but imaginary perqs that perfectly captured the ethos of other media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, but then I couldn't shake the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ved Mehta</ENAMEX> in spandex, so I
think I'd better go lie down and put a cold compress on my forehead. Or down my
pants. However, other examples of actual character-revealing corporate perqs
would be most welcome.

            
               To: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Square</ENAMEX> 5

            

               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">2000 Glamour Swimsuit Try-On</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swimsuit</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> will soon be upon us and once again
Glamour will be hosting its annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Swimsuit</ENAMEX> Try-On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 11th & 12th</TIMEX>.

            Often <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't realize that the suit they've
been wearing doesn't complement their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> type. So, for those who wish to
participate, we are offering a free <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> consultation to identify the
best suit for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>.

            To test drive these
swimsuits, please e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle DeShields</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 7th</TIMEX> and be sure to
include your size and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> type.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Monopoly guy</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
