
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raising McCain</ENAMEX>

            Every
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who does well enough to attract media scrutiny is doomed
to have a bad story written about him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>? A phony career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>? A do-nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lecturer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>? A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonesque playboy</ENAMEX>. Now
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> faces the same ritual. Rather than resist it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has turned it
to his advantage. He has chosen his own bad story: He's an angry <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>. It's an ingenious choice, a good story disguised as a bad one. It
advances <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s campaign themes--integrity and fearless independence--while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sating</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who imagine that their questions about his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">temper</ENAMEX>" amount to
tough-minded scrutiny.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s anger is supposed to be bad because he can't control it--and therefore
can't work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and can't be trusted with nuclear weapons. To refute
this charge, all he has to do is restrain his temper in a few highly visible
situations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> unwittingly oblige him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bent</ENAMEX> on making news, they
bombard him with questions designed to provoke an explosion. "Why is it that
those who know you best seem to like you the least?" debate co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> asked him at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. Responding to such
questions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> always smiles, thanks his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interrogators</ENAMEX>, praises his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, and deflects the challenge with a self-mocking joke. "A comment like
that really makes me mad ," he quipped during the debate.

            But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> understands that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who can control his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temper</ENAMEX>, they also want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with a sense of outrage. He flaunts his anger at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>, trial lawyers, agribusiness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX>, and defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> who
feed on "corporate welfare." "It's important to have passion and to get angry
when you see injustice," he argued on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Live</ENAMEX> . On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , he boasted, "Sure, I get angry. I get angry at this last bill that
we just passed that [is] an outrageous waste of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money." In the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> vowed, "From time to time, those of us … who stand in
an independent fashion are going to break some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX>. … It is very clear to all
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and the special influence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that run <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> now that if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, things are going to be a lot
different."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> make this spin an easy sell. Who's spreading the rumor that
he's too volatile to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
supplies their motive--"Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> despise [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>] … for his crusade in
favor of campaign-finance reform"--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> affirms that
they're out to stop him because "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s shaken up the establishment by talking
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> strong conservative reform." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borger</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, "The entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> [is] against you. … Is there
a sense, perhaps, that you are too much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX> to really become
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and govern?" Too much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX>? The question was practically a
campaign contribution.

            In
particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> asserts his anger on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. This combines two
good stories: his principled outrage and his war record. "Do I feel
passionately about issues? Absolutely," he conceded in the debate. "When I see
… wasteful pork-barrel spending [while] we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>--brave
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--on food stamps, yeah, I get angry." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> defended a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> shouting match with a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> over the fate of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam POWs</ENAMEX>. "I took strong exception to his allegations that somehow I was
ignoring important evidence," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> explained. "We're talking about an issue
of literally life and death." Such patriotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outbursts</ENAMEX> have captivated the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain "</ENAMEX>is best when he is angry," swoons <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . "He blazes with
indignation that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are on food stamps."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s cleverest strategy has been to associate the anger story with his POW
ordeal. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, citing nasty rumors that his torture and imprisonment in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> had left him emotionally unbalanced, his campaign released medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> indicating that he had never been mentally ill. The records did more
than kill a bad story. They revived a good one. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> got to tour the TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> retelling his heroic saga. In every interview, he alluded to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wounds</ENAMEX>, calling his medical records "an orthopedic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>'s dream." The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> discussed his "major fractures" and "solitary confinement." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> recalled his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> testimony that he had survived through
"faith in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and God." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bloom</ENAMEX>, recounting
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> had been "brutally and repeatedly tortured," quoted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> who
said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, "There was no tougher resister among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POWs</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> angle doesn't just help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. It hurts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. When stories about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">temper first</NUMEX> began to circulate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> told reporters, "I guess the
memo from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> has come out to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has
since backed away grudgingly from that allegation ("I was speaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">metaphorically</ENAMEX>," he says), but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> have kept it alive by publicly urging
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> to make sure its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> aren't spreading the rumors. By
framing these rumors in the context of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s surrogates create the
impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, who joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> to avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, is using
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s war record against him.

            
There's no evidence to support this insinuation, but since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> can't prove the
negative--that no one associated with his campaign has ever said any such
thing--the insinuation sticks. Front pages and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> political shows continue
to discuss the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> "whisper campaign," a phrase concocted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>. "It's going to be next to impossible to finger anyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
campaign for fomenting anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> sentiment," lamented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> called the trauma rumors "disgraceful." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX>
called them "disgusting" and "despicable." A POW <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> that those who
were spreading the rumors had "spit in the face of every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>."

            Now
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is being asked whether he's angry about the rumors about his anger.
Again, he gets to impress everyone by turning the other cheek. "It doesn't
matter to me," he shrugged on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . "We need to move forward."
When asked about reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> had circulated
the rumors, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> defended him: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> has been a personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine
for many, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has won the fight the best way--invisibly--by
framing the orientation of the questions. Everyone asks him about the "whisper
campaign" against him. No one asks him about the pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> whisper campaign
about the "whisper campaign." Everyone expects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to halt the
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> whispers. No one expects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> to halt the whispers that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is
behind the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> whispers.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> can't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and exploit rumors about his anger.
"Even if you handle it right, you still don't want this kind of thing out
there," argued <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> . "There's some people
who only hear a piece of it and say to themselves, is something wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estrich</ENAMEX> misses the point. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> are already asking whether
something is wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. They approach a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> the way
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> approaches a date. First, they want to know what's attractive about
him. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, if he passes that test, they want to know what's wrong with him.
They won't be satisfied--and won't relax--until they've identified his flaws.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, they want to observe those flaws, examine them, discuss them, and figure
out whether they're manageable. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has many flaws, some of which
are worse than others. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s best strategy, therefore, is to show the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> his most manageable flaw in the hope that they will focus
on that flaw and stop looking for others.

            This
is precisely what the anger story has accomplished. By consuming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, it
has overshadowed and smothered more dangerous anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> stories. With few
exceptions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> aren't pressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> about his role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keating</ENAMEX> Five
campaign-finance scandal. They aren't asking him to explain to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> how his crusades for campaign-finance restrictions and a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion-dollar</NUMEX> tobacco tax <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> with conservative principles. They
aren't asking him to explain to independents why he opposes the Brady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> aren't trying to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>; they just think
his mental stability is a more damaging issue. It "goes beyond accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
of hypocrisy" on campaign finance, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, this
illusion is felicitous. The anger story has distracted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> because it
looks so much worse than it is.

            Above
all, the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s anger has obscured what his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarrels</ENAMEX> have been
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. By focusing attention on tone, it has deflected attention from content.
When reports about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s bad temper <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> emerged out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>,
they indicated that he had muscled, rebuked, punished, and cowed fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in order to squelch dissent. Those reports could have generated
discussion about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s tirades against entrenched power in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> are hypocritical. Instead, they have been reduced to discussion
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> whether he is prone to tirades.

            
Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch McConnell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, has tried to focus scrutiny on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tobacco</ENAMEX> and campaign-finance crusades. "I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s personality
is the issue," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McConnell</ENAMEX> pleaded on television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>. "For me, it's
been a policy difference" over "big taxes and [putting] the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in
charge of everybody's political speech." But the anger story has overwhelmed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McConnell</ENAMEX>'s critique. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> aren't interested in the clash of ideas.
They're interested in the clash of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX>.

            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> too crazy
to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? The question answers itself. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who can use that issue to
obscure his more serious weaknesses, underscore his strengths, and besmirch his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> can't be accused of showing too little rationality and discipline. The
better question is whether he has shown too much.

         
      
   
