
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">359</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peril</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Us?</ENAMEX>"

            
               Government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have begun to caution <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> about "speed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">creep</ENAMEX>"--meaning?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 358</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Foto Fun":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Compose a caption for this .
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sparkles</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elf</ENAMEX> in happier times, before the sexual harassment
suit."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dressed as Santa Claus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX> relief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rocker</ENAMEX> brings
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> cheer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX>, teaching them the effectiveness of a
baseball bat in greeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Gavaghan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Whealon</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "Just
pretend it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Mason</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Stern</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
preps pint-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hubble</ENAMEX> repair techniques."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
delivers to wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, returns to take it back."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Jacobsson</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Once all the world
smiled benignly when an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> took an interest in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>: scoutmaster and
troop, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> and altar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>--what could be more wholesome? Now, all--or at any
rate, quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> all--smirk knowingly at the dark desires implicit in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo of Santa</ENAMEX> embracing a comely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lad</ENAMEX>, embellished with the most potent of
pederast symbols, baseball paraphernalia. How does one tell foresight from
fear? Today, some wary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> are reluctant to lift a thirsty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tot</ENAMEX> to a
playground drinking fountain, lest they be viewed with alarm. Others tow all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> within a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one-mile</NUMEX> radius, weld closed all manhole covers, remove all trash
cans, lock all mailboxes, and assign <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX> cops to the scene, while denying the
existence of any specific threat. Is this reasonable caution or self-important
delight in martial law? Is it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> screed or an actual comment on the question
at hand? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>? Either way, I won't be taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> boy
to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.

            
               Captious Answer
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian Gonzalez</ENAMEX> gets
some batting tips from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> in the front yard of his great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>'s home
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. The bat and ball were an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubas</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-year-old</TIMEX> has been living with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> after being picked
up at sea <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 25</TIMEX> while trying to escape <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and others
who died when their boat capsized." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cooke</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>)

            
               Anarchy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Streets</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela</ENAMEX> is the family
rebel," Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisman</ENAMEX> said. "Everybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX> family has to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela</ENAMEX> actually applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>. She ended up gong to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, but
..."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--"Vows</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cards</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> were invited to devise mass-mailed
corporate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cards, and a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> managed to keep off the eggnog long
enough to do just that, and delightfully so.

            

               Outside: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> driving off into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sunset</ENAMEX> aboard a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>-propelled sleigh.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Arches</ENAMEX> loom in the background.
Inside: McBlitzer: for those who really like reindeer.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon</ENAMEX>
Deegan
               

               Outside: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> drinking a glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> left by the chimney.
Inside: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> laughingly refusing chemotherapy treatment.
Message: Don't worry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> will probably be fine! Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX>.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
               

               Outside: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX> pass out <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy canes</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sweatshop</ENAMEX>.
Inside: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Season</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greetings</ENAMEX> from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
Vehrs
               

               Outside: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Balmer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> in front of a roaring fire.
Inside: Our chestnuts are roasting over an open fire.
Thanks to a non-techie in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s robe.
We'll still be here as your stock climbs Higher and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher</ENAMEX>.
He'll be off the bench when our election donations take hold.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happy Holidays</ENAMEX> to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.
P.S.: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the world is subjective, so no money has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">enclosed.</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Kenow</ENAMEX>
               

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Family values, shmamily values: We will bury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli√</ENAMEX>°n
Gonz√°lez beneath a mountain of toys before we reunite him with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who
lives in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> we disapprove of.

         
      
   
