
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">352</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pro and Context</ENAMEX>"

            
               Some key words in
a story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> were: jumping jack; youngest; "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catchers</ENAMEX>;" dreamy, romantic, and elegant; a flip, a toe loop, and a salchow.
What was the story about?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 351</ENAMEX>)--"$$$":
            

            

               "I wonder if she understands how much her life has changed this day.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itchy Pants</ENAMEX> has the potential to make her a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>." Who said this
about what?
            

            "This
is the endless tape-loop running in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s brain."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>
Cornog
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX>, upon hearing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Barkin</ENAMEX> had signed a prenup with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perelman</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callie Joseph</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David L. Duncan</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            "At
last! A cure for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock itch</ENAMEX>--and wouldn't you know, it was a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>
who came up with it. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> product name, by the way.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann</ENAMEX>
Gavaghan
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>, about the guttersnipe he picked up selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> in Covent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garden</ENAMEX>, whom he intends to turn into the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Playmate of the Year</ENAMEX>. Said the
guttersnipe: ' 'oward, me himplants 'urt!' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gurley Brown</ENAMEX>, about the many plus sides to sexual harassment."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            The popular portrayal of
bloated plutocrats has changed enormously in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 150 years</TIMEX>, devolving from
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>'s ferocious robber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX>, to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on the
Monopoly box who was always chasing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> around his desk in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> cartoons, to the addled and ineffectual potbellies of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screwball</ENAMEX> comedy. And now, judging by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> responses, these wan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX> are
barely portrayed at all. Unless he makes his money in show business, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billionaire</ENAMEX> is a sexless and unattractive sap who lacks the vigor and vanity to
crush his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> and build towering monuments to his ego, although he may have
a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. He is a tedious corporate drone, as innocuous as the lackluster
buildings erected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>. The fabulously <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthy</ENAMEX> are failing us as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> type; indeed, they are not fabulous--not excessively decadent, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imaginatively Sybaritic</ENAMEX>. They are, at most, dull on the grand scale. We live in
tepid times.

            
               Inventive
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonnie Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Soaker</ENAMEX> water
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gun</ENAMEX>, said this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 11-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nadia Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of the Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itchy Pants</ENAMEX>
doll, the winning entry in a toy invention contest for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            The contest was sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and
company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bezos</ENAMEX> was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>; skater
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katerina Witt</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Levey</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furby</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Edison</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sloane Jr.</ENAMEX>, a toy-industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nadia</ENAMEX> will receive a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> college savings bond. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itchy Pants</ENAMEX> will be manufactured and sold
online at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, and a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> royalty will be paid into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nadia Smith</ENAMEX>'s
college fund.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>
Bulletin Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liza Minnelli</ENAMEX>'s new
show, a tribute to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnelli on Minnelli</ENAMEX> , has been
panned-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reviewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> didn't even like her chorus
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>--so the odds of a long run seem limited. But my "backdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>" tell me
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liza</ENAMEX> is already planning another show, an homage to her past called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnelli</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methadone</ENAMEX> .

            
               Least Believable
Assertions Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> were invited to submit actual or
invented credulity-straining claims.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>: "I am reading a book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Hitt</ENAMEX>
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>: "I plan to have that swastika tattoo on my ass
removed."-- (But what a photo-op it would be, huh?) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eBay shopper</ENAMEX>: "You know, I've gotten so much use out of my fruit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dehydrator</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, really! I swear!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Fee Donald Trump</ENAMEX>:
"I care about ... something."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX>: "So I say to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi</ENAMEX>, you weren't kidding about what those
cowboy boots would do!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Vehrs</ENAMEX>
               

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium" Issue Corner</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Diller</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium</ENAMEX>" issue: "Thinking
that being in your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50s</TIMEX> would be this much great good fun."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Geffen</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium</ENAMEX>" issue: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crosby</ENAMEX>,
Stills, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX> records will be listened to for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Maher</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium</ENAMEX>" issue: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> and I couldn't get a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to go out with me, and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> I can."

            

            In fact, everything
everyone asserts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium</ENAMEX>" issue, except
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princess Mononoke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayao Miyazaki</ENAMEX>'s assertion that his biggest
influence is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Philbin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
