
   
   
      
         
            Wiesel Words

            
               Movies

            

            

               
                  Magnolia
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). Rave after rave for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>-director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Thomas Anderson</ENAMEX>'s ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>-filled film about a series
of interconnected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Fernando Valley</ENAMEX>: "A wildly funny, truly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wise</ENAMEX> and subversively sincere film about pain, forgiveness and the possibility
of healing" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). The cast
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">includes Julianne Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William H. Macy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Robards</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Seymour</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> (who receives over-the-top praise for his performance
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> do express some reservations, mainly about
the movie's length and overwrought emotion--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> writes, the film is
"operatic in its ambition," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> should "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">l</ENAMEX>]eave logic at the door. Do
not expect subdued taste and restraint" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). A few
feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> doesn't pull it off: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> , a "big, showy flower
of a movie, unfurls brilliantly, each plot petal a thing of exquisite design.
Then it ripens. Then it disintegrates, leaving a mess of color and a faint
whiff of rot" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). (The official
site includes
several <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX> and stills from the film.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow Falling</ENAMEX> on Cedars
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). "Inert," "hollow,"
"anesthetized," and other deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">adjectives</ENAMEX> fill the reviews for the screen
adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Guterson</ENAMEX>'s best-selling novel about the lingering effects
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> internment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Hicks</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shine</ENAMEX> ) takes a few knocks: "If ever there was an example of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s getting in the way of a story, this is it" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Strangely enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Hawke</ENAMEX>--the film's biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>--gets
almost no mention. The cinematography is alternately praised as stunning and
condemned as boring, but the response to the story line is unanimous: It's a
"liberal soap opera" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) that consists of a
"self-congratulatory anti-prejudice message, fleshed out with painstaking
topographic detail" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Lim</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> stand
up for the film, calling it a "thoughtful, evocative thriller" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (Find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawke</ENAMEX> here.)

            
               Books

            

            

               
                  And the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sea Is Never Full</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elie Wiesel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). After heaping
praise on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiesel</ENAMEX>'s work on behalf of countless <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> causes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>
reluctantly detail their problems with this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> volume of his memoirs. On
the positive side: It's a compelling document "of a life marked by high
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seriousness</ENAMEX>, good conscience and an utter refusal to submit to evil and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oppression"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Groner</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Book World</ENAMEX> ), and upon
reading it you "become persuaded that something about his combination of
seeming innocence and moral honesty has the power to move if not mountains then
those who have the most power" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lehmann-Haupt</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). But complaints against the book are uniform: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) This volume "feels
anti-climactic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duane Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Rocky Mountain News</ENAMEX> ) when compared
with his first because it lacks the kind of compelling events that shaped his
early life. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The book "is patchwork, a grab bag of speeches he gave, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> and the near-great he met, causes he could not refuse to get involved in,
conferences he helped to organize, ideological battles he fought" instead of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linear</ENAMEX> narrative (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehmann-Haupt</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
to read an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiesel</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edna O'Brien</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking Penguin</ENAMEX>). This latest
installment of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Penguin Lives</ENAMEX>" series is well received, even though it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trails Richard Ellman</ENAMEX>'s definitive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX>-page <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce tome</ENAMEX>, which was deemed
"probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>'s best biography of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kippen</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> ). Undaunted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien</ENAMEX> attempts something
entirely different: She gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">179</NUMEX> pages of "hardheaded hagiography in which she
spends a lot of time knocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> around" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Sullivan</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Review</ENAMEX> ). It's notable not for its wide net, but for its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">precision</ENAMEX>, economy, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>: "a first-rate appraisal of a master … a model
of pristine brevity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Robert Taylor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> complaint:
The book contains an "impressive number of inaccuracies of a factual nature,"
such as misidentifying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX> of Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> and misquoting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">critic Walter Pater</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Flannagan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (This <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> site has essays,
links, and message <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Fasting, Feasting
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Desai</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX>). Nominated
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Booker Prize</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desai</ENAMEX>'s novel of a small-town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
is deemed "splendid" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriella Stern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
parts of the title refer to the internal structure of the book, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first half</TIMEX>
following the life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s plain and somewhat dim older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, who
after failing to marry is consigned to the life of a glorified house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> follows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> as he travels to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> for
his education. A "wry, touching and understated novel" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francine Prose</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desai</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sick Puppy</ENAMEX>
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Hiaasen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Excellent reviews for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami Herald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>'s latest thriller excoriating the excesses of his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. "He
shows himself to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic writer</ENAMEX> at the peak of his powers" and "once again
produces a devilishly funny caper revolving around ... environmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploitation"</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The tale follows a slightly
psychotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalist</ENAMEX> who decides to enact personal revenge on a local
real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bigwig</ENAMEX> who happens to be an incurable litterbug. The only
criticism: Hiaasen "walks a fine line between satire and outrage, as well as
another between the conventions of the thriller and the conventions of
slapstick, and … toward the end matters get so frenetic that credulity is
strained well past the snapping point" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). (Read an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hiaasen</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
