
   
   
      
         
            Shooting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moon</ENAMEX>

            
               Movies

            

            

               
                  The Talented Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ripley</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are seduced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Minghella</ENAMEX>'s first work since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patient</ENAMEX> ; a few are left cold. Adapted from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Highsmith</ENAMEX>'s novel, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Ripley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX>), a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loner</ENAMEX> who usurps the identity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickie Greenleaf</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jude Law</ENAMEX>), a rich playboy loafing around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> in the late
'50s. The "hypnotic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensually</ENAMEX> charged <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adaptation …</ENAMEX> has the same kind of
complex allure that made <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The English Patient</ENAMEX> so mesmerizing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">…</ENAMEX> [It]
offers diabolically smart surprises wherever you care to look" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The wild measures <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ripley</ENAMEX> takes to maintain the
charade cause some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> to lose interest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> of the film:
"When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>'s aberrant qualities become more dangerous, the movie loses its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moorings</ENAMEX> and drifts into a sort of highly polished, implausible melodrama"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the official
site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). Lukewarm
reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milos Forman</ENAMEX>'s biopic about offbeat 1970s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX>;
tremendous reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX> in the lead role. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who can't
stand the film are impressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrey</ENAMEX>: "His performance is a brilliant, almost
terrifying impersonation" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' main bone of contention is that the film makes no attempt to explain
the source of his eccentricity: "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forman</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> present the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> mystery as if they thought it was utterly impenetrable" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
Morgenstern, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ), or as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> writes in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , "what is missing here, though it might have been the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thing expected from an ostensible film biography, is an answer to the
simplest question: Who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX>, and how did he get that way?" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX>

                  Slate
               's "" to see how the film compares with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s real
life.)

            

               
                  Any Given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX> directs
a flashy, high-speed football film. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are amused but not impressed: It's
an "energetic and diverting sports soap opera" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Pacino</ENAMEX> plays an aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> whose balance is upset when
his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> get injured and he's forced to put in the untried
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Foxx</ENAMEX>--in a "standout performance" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). From
here the film "develops into a kind of mega- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) complete with crucial last-minute plays. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>-style
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">editing</ENAMEX> leaves some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> dizzy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> complain that once again <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> is
peddling "conventional wisdom disguised as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manically</ENAMEX> charged, cutting-edge
consciousness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the official
site.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Home <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comforts: The Art and Science of Keeping House</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Mendelson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scribner</ENAMEX>). This compendium of information on proper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">housekeeping</ENAMEX> gets a tongue-bath from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>: "It's an extraordinary
achievement that has no peer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> and may well have none in the
next" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Shapiro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> with a Ph.D. in
philosophy, is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heloise</ENAMEX>. Her writing is "crisply entertaining" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia</ENAMEX>
Crossen, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ), her ideas are "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">revolutionary … a</ENAMEX>
manifesto in praise and defense of the home" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susannah Herbert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ), and the information is indispensable: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home Comforts</ENAMEX> is
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy of Cooking</ENAMEX> is to food" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katy Kelly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> ). The only negative comment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> can come up with is that on
occasion "a schoolmarmish, admonitory tone creeps in" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corby Kummer</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to buy the book.)

            

               Opera
            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gatsby</ENAMEX>
                (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>). After much buildup, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>'s last commissioned work of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, an opera based on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Scott Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>'s novel, draws weak reviews overall, with a few raves here
and there. Complaints: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatsby</ENAMEX> (sung by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Hadley</ENAMEX>) lacks "the vocal
flexibility or top notes to capture <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatsby</ENAMEX>'s sentimental underbelly and heroic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decency"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Kennicott</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) it's slow (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatsby</ENAMEX>
takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 minutes</TIMEX> to show up). On the positive side, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> includes a few
standout <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>, and the set and costumes are stunning. The few who find
the production enchanting claim, "It is hard to think of another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> opera
composed with a comparable degree of musical sophistication and sheer virtuoso
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositional chops</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dyer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). Even the negative
reviews give grudging respect to the opera, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Holland</ENAMEX> admitting that it "may also be the victim of the inflated
expectations surrounding it." (Find
out more about the production on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>'s Web page.)

         
      
   
