
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bucket of Cold Water</ENAMEX>

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> found encouragement in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farouk Shara</ENAMEX>'s speech at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, despite his frostiness and
his unexpected refusal to shake the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s hand. What the
world saw, it said, was "a continuation of the coldest shoulder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>, that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>." But his words revealed welcome changes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s approach to peace. The most significant of these was his statement that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> conflict was about borders and not about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s right to
exist. "The words 'border conflict,' combined with the concept of peace based
upon 'international legitimacy'--a phrase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shara</ENAMEX> used twice--signifies a shift
in conception that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has been seeking since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of its birth," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shara</ENAMEX> also implied that a peace settlement might be a boon,
as opposed to a setback, for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> unity, and he gave a broader than expected
description of what peace might be like. He spoke of a peace that would "open
new horizons for totally new relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>" and of "honorable
competition in various domains--the political, cultural, scientific, and
economic." This, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said, suggested "a peace much broader and
deeper than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassadors</ENAMEX> and other formalities."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> 's lead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was a reported promise by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shara</ENAMEX> not to allow
"any element in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> to disrupt the peace process," which was described by a
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> as the first clear indication that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> is willing to
rein in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. In its main
story from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>
said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> has called on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> immediately from its
list of regimes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> terrorism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is demanding that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> take action against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hezbollah</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, "there are
signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> crackdowns on terror <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> currently based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, as well
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX>." It also reported that, if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is satisfied with the progress
of the peace negotiations due to begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 3</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> would become involved in the lobbying effort to get <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> removed from the
list, clearing the way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX>-backed aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX>."

            In an
editorial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said it is "clear that the
negotiations have already reached an advanced stage" and that "[w]ith good will
on both sides everything is resolvable." But it said there is still the problem
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> would return to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> in a peace settlement. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golan</ENAMEX> were sent to build
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> opposite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> with the concurrence of every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>,
and the roots they struck in the basalt soil are deeper than those of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Judea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Samaria</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. But it concluded that they will
have to go, because "peace under reasonable conditions is more important than
the desire to ease the pain of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> who are evacuated from their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>." Another article in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> called for understanding
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s difficult task of preparing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> public opinion
for peace with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. If the settlement goes ahead, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> "will be required
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to present the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> with new facts completely contrary
to the ideology preached to them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>," it said.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Baath</ENAMEX> , the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s ruling party, said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> wouldn't give up "a grain of its soil or a drop of its water" in its
negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> fought honorably and it is now negotiating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honorably</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "It is doing all it can to attain an honorable
peace which safeguards rights, dignity, and sovereignty. That is the only peace
acceptable to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and that is the peace that will prove viable and
stand the test of time." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>
to consider the implications of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shara</ENAMEX>'s vision of scientific, economic, and
cultural competition with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> cannot engage in this competition
without swiftly adopting and applying its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, starting with democracy, freedom
to engage in political activity, freedom of expression, and economic
liberalization," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> cannot compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in
technology when access to the Internet is restricted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, and the use of a mobile phone must be cleared by the intelligence
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> was one of several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> papers skeptical about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> rapprochement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disputing Shara</ENAMEX>'s statement that a peace
agreement would mean "the end of a history of wars and conflicts," it noted
that he failed to say a word about the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, and it added: "An end to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of war between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> does not mean an end to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of war between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. This is because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> signing
up to peace were not democratically elected, nor did they conduct referendums
on their peace moves."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Hayat</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> had been wrong to believe that they could
negotiate on their own with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. They had only themselves to blame for the
fact that their peace negotiations were stalled, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s were picking up
again. The semi-official <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Ahram</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s coup in getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> together was "a cruel blow
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>--fighting to succeed him."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wanted "to pour a bucket of freezing cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>" on the hopes of his
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, who both want him to fail.
"They want the kudos for themselves, especially since they have both already
made promises in advance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> in order
to secure support in the presidential election."

         
      
   
