
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark of McCain</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of war
positioned him to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>." His
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> ordeal, it was said, made him candid, brave, inner-directed. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
is running from the character issue: His <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> ordeal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">allege</ENAMEX>, left him irascible, unstable, unfit for the presidency. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has now
released <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> pages of medical records to provide what the New York
Times has called "the broadest look ever given the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> at the
psychological profile of a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>." Presidential "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>"
has returned as a public and media obsession.

            To be sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> has always
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mattered</ENAMEX>. Whether charging that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> took a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>
or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Cleveland</ENAMEX> fathered an illegitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> have long
assailed the morals of presidential aspirants. But in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> such mudslinging never amounted to a full-scale attempt to assess a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s psychological profile. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Quincy Adams</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> all probably suffered from "melancholy"--or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>--but their
mental health didn't enter the public debate. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't even know
about their conditions.

            Only with the rise of
Freudian theory--specifically, the idea that not only the "ill" but also
well-functioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are captive to unconscious motives--did anyone think to
psychoanalyze a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Allen Renshon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invaluable</ENAMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Psychological Assessment of Presidential</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates</ENAMEX> ), the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such effort appeared in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> article titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Roosevelt as Analyzed by the New Psychology</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> tried to explain inconsistent comments that former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> had made about supporting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Taft</ENAMEX>, by postulating
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX> harbored an unresolved, repressed wish to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> again
himself. Though hardly controversial by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s standards (not least because we
know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX> did choose to run in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>), the story provoked an outcry,
including a denunciation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> himself.

            Just as the spread of psychoanalysis made putting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> acceptable, the advent of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> made
"stability" the watchword not only in geopolitics but also in psychopolitics.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1956</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> seized on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Lerner</ENAMEX>
called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Triple Issue</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>'s frail physical health (he'd
had a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1955</TIMEX>), nukes (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> built a hydrogen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1955</TIMEX>), and, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lerner</ENAMEX>'s phrase, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> viewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, as bellicose and ruthless).
In an election-eve speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai Stevenson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">standard-bearer</ENAMEX>,
said that "As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> more than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> ... I recoil at the prospect of
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> as custodian of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s future, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guardian</ENAMEX> of the hydrogen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX> ... as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> armed forces." Close aides
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disapproved</ENAMEX>, feeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> had gone too far.

            Yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> reprised the issue in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Goldwater</ENAMEX>'s slogan "In your
heart you know he's right," <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> countered: "In your guts you know he's
nuts." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>'s camp portrayed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> as a
trigger-happy Strangelove likely to blow up the world. The now-defunct magazine
FACT , published by the eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ginzburg</ENAMEX>, polled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,356</NUMEX> members
conclude that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> considered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX> paranoid. While plenty of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> did question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX>'s temperament and judgment, the study's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">methodology</ENAMEX> was so egregiously flawed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX> won a libel suit against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. --though, significantly, it also allowed that more "reliable"
psychological assessments of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> might reasonably inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>'
decisions.

            Ironically, it was the victors of those races, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, who would further elevate the question of psychological fitness for the
presidency. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, the issue surfaced when muckraker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Pearson</ENAMEX> told a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Press Club</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, just after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> election, that as vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had consulted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Hutschnecker</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> physician
specializing in psychosomatic illnesses. To his death, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> maintained he had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consulted Hutschnecker</ENAMEX> only as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> and not for psychotherapy, though
skeptics wondered why he would travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> for a checkup. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One unproven</ENAMEX>
claim was impotence.) When in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX> appeared before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> panel
to be confirmed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, he had to explain his own visits to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hutschnecker</ENAMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Question Marks Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hearing</ENAMEX>," read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
headline over the story about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s testimony. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s explanation: He had
visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s urging, but only socially.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hutschnecker</ENAMEX> episode
introduced a new aspect of the character issue: the stigma of seeing a shrink.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutschnecker</ENAMEX> argued that seeking help to secure
one's "emotional stability" denoted "not weakness but courage" and should not
be stigmatized. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> agreed. Hovering behind this debate, of
course, was the lingering memory of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> campaign, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Eagleton</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> after being chosen as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McGovern</ENAMEX>'s running mate,
resigned from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> ticket after revealing that he had undergone
hospitalization and electroshock therapy for depression. That story quickly
(and somewhat inaccurately) came to be portrayed as an illustration of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public's</ENAMEX> .

            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> question was morphing from the
matter of mental stability into the larger issue of what kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> would make. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watching Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> visit their private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> made the public correctly curious about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' hidden selves.
Academicians, most notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James David Barber</ENAMEX> in his
influential <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presidential Character</ENAMEX> , explored how to predict a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s performance based on a systematic study of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.
Meanwhile, the decline of the major political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> was creating a new
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>-centered" politics, which emphasized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and further
spotlighted his psychic makeup.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these years</TIMEX>, however,
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> meant by "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>" became increasingly confused. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> stressed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, by which he meant his (alleged) honesty. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, the press expanded the issue to include questions of marital infidelity,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX>, and narcissism, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> learned the hard way. By the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> question was reduced to a checklist of intrusive inquiries
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about</NUMEX> past infidelity, military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use--and, if evasive or
dishonest answers were given, also about honesty and integrity.

            What we mean--and should mean--by "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>" needs to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disentangled</ENAMEX>. First, there's no question that seeking psychological help needs
to be destigmatized. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX> have helped by saying they've each had
"counseling" but, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX> has noted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper</ENAMEX>'s use of such euphemisms and
the avoidance a "professional title [that] might include the prefix 'psych-'
... sent the signal, consciously or not, that she wasn't entirely free of shame
herself." When, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> chose not to see a
real clinician but a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>, he sent the same message.

            Yet removing the stigma of therapy doesn't mean
rejecting consideration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. Obviously, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s ambition,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX>, temperament, integrity, and ways of relating with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (among
other psychological qualities) bear greatly on how he will govern--at least as
greatly as whatever election-year stands he stakes out on "the issues" of
policy. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidencies</ENAMEX> are only the most salient examples
of this truth. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> exist, too. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> has argued cogently that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvin Coolidge</ENAMEX>'s psychological problems helped .)

            The real question, then, is how to assess
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. Clearly, the press has done a lousy job with its focus on behavior
such as infidelity or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't care about.
Alternatively, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychotherapists</ENAMEX> have argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> alone
should do the evaluating. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Hutschnecker</ENAMEX>, reveling in his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of fame, proposed establishing an official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> to
screen all presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.) Not surprisingly, the push for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shrinkocracy</ENAMEX> has gained little support.

            Yet just because we've failed to think clearly
about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> involves doesn't mean we should cease to think about it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> can also do a poor job analyzing policy issues--what was the last
really illuminating story you read about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> trust fund?--but
no one argues it should abandon the enterprise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> is right to focus on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. Now it needs to think more rigorously about how to do so.

         
      
   
