
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basqueing</ENAMEX> in That <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo Attitude</ENAMEX>?

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basque</ENAMEX> separatist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETA</ENAMEX> called off its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-month</TIMEX> cease-fire last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, prompting public outrage. The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Pa√≠s</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jos√© Mar√</ENAMEX>≠a
Aznar, told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basque</ENAMEX> separatist political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> "are closer to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, which represents exclusion and ethnic cleansing, than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> of the euro, which represents integration and pluralism." The mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basque Nationalist Party</ENAMEX> (PNV) recently formed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> with extreme
separatist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, prompting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aznar</ENAMEX> to compare the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s attitude with that
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>, who tried, unsuccessfully,
to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> with [territorial] concessions to avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II."

            An
editorial in the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> supported the invocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, damning the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX>' focus on "ethnicity, linguistic imposition, collusion with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETA</ENAMEX>
terrorism, dishonest rewriting of history, and social exclusion." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Catalonia</ENAMEX>,
another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> region with separatist ambitions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Vanguardia</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX>
decried the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PNV</ENAMEX>, using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basque</ENAMEX> term "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Euskadi</ENAMEX>" for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> equivalent.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>

               Correo , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Basque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bilbao</ENAMEX>, condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aznar</ENAMEX>'s pronouncements, warning that the growing
chasm between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Basque</ENAMEX> public opinion and that of the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> could
generate "a verbal escalation whose final objective couldn't be other than to
deepen the abyss" between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "likely to take <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Basque</ENAMEX> nationalism to the
ballot box and those who would like to prevent a sovereignty debate."
Surprisingly, none of the editorials connected the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s attack on PNV
with his announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> that a general election will be held in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX>.

            A
leader
in the Financial Times
responded to the findings of an investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> that linked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> bank accounts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> persecution and concluded that some
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> made "deliberately misleading statements" to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who
sought family assets lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> must
come to terms with this uncomfortable past. It was not alone among neutral
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in profiting from the war, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> persecutions. There is clearly
resentment amongst <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> at their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> being singled out for special
attention by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. That was one factor in the recent electoral success
of the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss People's Party</ENAMEX>. ‚Ä¶ As far as humanly possible, it must
be righted."

            A
commentary in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> reveals that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are obsessed with "the legacy thing." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is putting
the finishing touches on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">multi-volume Selected Works</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> ,
which will "lay the theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> for Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s status as the equal
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s track record will be "marred by serious flaws,"
specifically his refusal to "heal the wounds" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> and his "singularly inept" handling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> sect. The piece
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu Rongji</ENAMEX>'s "quest for a place in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pantheon</ENAMEX> is informed with a poignant urgency. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71</NUMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a hurry." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu</ENAMEX>, too, is judged harshly, since most of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> reform pledges have remained unfulfilled, but the economy is on an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">upswing</ENAMEX>, and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> breakthrough" is a boost to his hopes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu</ENAMEX> has said that
when he leaves office he will write a study "on how to make a go of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">'Chinese</ENAMEX>-style socialist market economy.' " The piece concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu</ENAMEX> "will
have more than kept faith with his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> forebears if he can leave
for posterity tips for the near-impossible task of reconciling market reforms
with a one-party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>."

            The silent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Polar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lander</ENAMEX> led to a rather <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch leader</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
Enumerating the long list of failed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> missions--and a few "spectacular
successes"--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> concluded, "It now seems that not everything was
fully tested before the mission started. But this is surely what comes of
cutting costs. ‚Ä¶ The chances of failure are, alas, much greater, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in a
row look like carelessness." By contrast, an editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, said that the likelihood of disappointment with such
ambitious efforts "is not sufficient reason not to take the risk. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have a better understanding of what they are doing in exploring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than ‚Ä¶</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> had when he sailed westwards to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Indies</ENAMEX> and
stumbled on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX>. There were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> who thought
his voyages a waste of money. But, despite all the subsequent suffering of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">indigenous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>, who now wishes he had not made them?"

         
      
   
