
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Opposites Day</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-graders</ENAMEX> have long known of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opposites Day</ENAMEX>,"
the fictional day once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> when everything means its opposite. But it took
the deeper wisdom of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to use this notion as a way of ending the bilious
debate over affirmative action. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>--have implemented a solution that has been heralded by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . The key to
agreement over affirmative action, it turns out, is for everyone to say the
opposite of what they mean.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connerly</ENAMEX> led the successful
referendum campaign against affirmative action. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Govs. Jeb Bush</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who have campaigned against minority
preferences. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now forbid traditional affirmative action in
admissions to state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. Instead, they use versions of what I'll call
a "high-school quota" plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> guarantees admission to any senior graduating
in the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of his or her high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, it's anyone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graduating</ENAMEX> in the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, it's the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times explains that this is "a sensible way to increase minority
enrollments without relying on a strategy that takes race into account."
Guaranteed admission has restored minority enrollments at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> campus,
for example, to levels not seen since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, when a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> struck down
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s affirmative action program. As , this whole scheme only works
because, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown vs. Board of Education</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are still severely segregated. If high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX>, taking the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> from each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> would produce the
same racial mix as taking the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of state high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> as
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a whole</TIMEX>. Since most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> attend overwhelmingly black high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, the result
is much closer to that of taking the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of each race.

            It's doubly crazy to argue on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> besides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opposites Day</ENAMEX>
that the high-school quota system has nothing to do with race. First, the
purpose is explicitly racial. The whole point is to increase minority
enrollment. That is why it was invented, and that is why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> brag
about its success. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the mechanism--piggybacking on a racially skewed
arrangement (high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>)--would never pass muster with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> not desperately eager to look the other way.

            Most of the civil rights
litigation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few decades</TIMEX>, in fact, is about this kind of piggybacking
discrimination rather than the explicit kind. When do traditional job
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">qualifications</ENAMEX>, such as a test or membership in a guild, amount to racial
discrimination? That sort of thing. You only have to imagine a state policy
applying the high-school quota system to, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> scholarships--and
explicitly being praised by state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> as a way to increase the number of
white <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>--to realize how empty the claims are that this
arrangement avoids the alleged evil of racial preference.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> have always claimed to want admissions
decisions based solely on so-called "merit-based" criteria such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores.
They think it immoral to give college places to minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who wouldn't
be admitted under a merit-based policy, since this means taking away those
places from white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with higher grades and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX>. But admitting black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who wouldn't be admitted under a merit-based policy is precisely what
high-school quotas do. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> had a fully "merit"-based admissions policy
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1996 and 1998</TIMEX>. Sadly, very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> were admitted. Along came
high-school quotas and minority admissions returned to pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> levels. Meaning
that the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> who were denied places they deserved on "merit" also
returned to the same level anti-preference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> had been complaining
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX> of high-school
quotas might argue that I'm missing the point. That this system, unlike
traditional minority preferences, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s performance in context.
It compares achievements with the environment in which they were achieved.
Moreover, it ensures that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from all backgrounds have an equal bite of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple</ENAMEX>. All are reasonable arguments. But weren't these the arguments for
affirmative action in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place? That is, one idea behind affirmative
action was always that "merit" must be judged relative to environment, so as to
combat persistent historical inequalities.

            Put differently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> were goaded
into action by the obvious unfairness of a state-subsidized university system
that more or less denies access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>. Naturally enough,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> dare not make this dangerous idea too explicit. They cannot
afford to admit that they don't really want the results they fought for during
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California Regents</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bakke</ENAMEX> . But at
heart, I suspect a large percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> share the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>'
discomfort with an all-white educational system paid for by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. In other
words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> aren't unaware of what they're doing,
namely fighting--gasp!--for racial justice. They just can't admit it.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> agree to pretend that
affirmative action is dead, and that this marvelous new discovery--high-school
quotas--doesn't amount to the same thing. And they lived happily ever after.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Opposites Day</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
