
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">353</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad-Ass Query</ENAMEX>" 

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>
made an announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important words, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hyphenated,
unlikely to show up in any of its forthcoming TV commercials. Which two
words?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">352</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pro and Context":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Some key words in a story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> were:
jumping jack; youngest; "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream Catchers"</ENAMEX>; dreamy, romantic, and elegant; a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flip</ENAMEX>, a toe loop, and a salchow. What was the story about?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX>'s sex life."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
think the campaign to rehabilitate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph McCarthy</ENAMEX> has gotten a little out
of hand."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
don't care how 'zesty, light, and delectable' it is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly O'Neill</ENAMEX>'s recipe for
almond <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter tart</ENAMEX> is just too damn difficult."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "A new
breakout of that flesh-eating virus. But they tried to kind of, you know,
lighten it up."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Whatever it was, at least we can delight in the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Rosenthal</ENAMEX> didn't
write it."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ballard</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            The pose and the prose
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have changed since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Hecht</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Front</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> . Indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hecht</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> would have balked at being called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>." Whether the
shift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hildy Johnson</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Rosenthal</ENAMEX> was a good or bad thing, it must be
noted that not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX>'s most passionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> have ever accused
him of being a fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> or of writing a sentence like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crushing</ENAMEX> all
Chechen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> made their dreamy, romantic, and elegant way
to the outskirts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX>." Although there are certainly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> who'd pay to see him perform a flip, a toe loop, and a salchow,
whatever they are, on a rocket-powered hell-cycle leaping a wall of fire. Or
failing to leap a wall of fire. Like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> when ‚Ä¶ oh, who
are we kidding? We miss him, damn it!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Low Coefficient</ENAMEX> of
Friction and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wit Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            The story was about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-skating.

            By winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife World Professional</ENAMEX> Figure
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Skating Championship</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tara Lipinski</ENAMEX> became the youngest
professional figure skating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> ever, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> or female.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tara Lipinski</ENAMEX> is unambiguously female. But neither
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> nor a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> ever won a professional championship at a younger age than
she. As you all no doubt understood all along. I'm going to stop
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-explaining now. No, now.

            According to
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Litsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipinski</ENAMEX> is a jumping jack. The music she
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skated</ENAMEX> to is called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Dream Catchers</ENAMEX>." Both the skating and the title song were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dreamy</ENAMEX>, romantic, and elegant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flip</ENAMEX>, loop, and salchow are the names of the
triple jumps she performed, although--and I don't claim to know anything about
figure skating--they'd also make good names for cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squirrels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> or
female.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xmas Xcess Xtra</ENAMEX>
            

            You can infer as much about a publication's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
from its ads as from its articles: That's the wacky premise behind this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel</ENAMEX>
extra. Which of the following were promoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and
which in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> ?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chanel 2000</ENAMEX> gift card--available in increments of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tourneau</ENAMEX> watch--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,600</NUMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartier</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pav√</ENAMEX>© diamond heart on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,700</NUMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Cleef</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arpel</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>--from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,500</NUMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergdorf</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rovert Lee Morris</ENAMEX> ring--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34,000</NUMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saks chinchilla</ENAMEX> jacket--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saks</ENAMEX> necklace--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$240,000</NUMEX>

            

            
               Answer
            

            All were advertised on
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pages 2-4</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . But, benefit of the doubt,
presumably some of the ads are not intended to sell products so much as to
instill a frisson of imaginary consumption, the sort of shopping
pornography that makes all of us so moist each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ice</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
