
   
   
      
         
            Flash! Net <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ignores Steamy Rumor</ENAMEX>!

            Has
the Internet abandoned its role as the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> of political
rumor?

            
Judging from the Net's nonchalant treatment of a steamy story alleging recent
infidelity by a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, the answer could be yes.

            In its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 4, 2000</TIMEX>, issue, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> has a story about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
claims to have had an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-month</TIMEX> affair with one of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX>.
(Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> named both names,

                  Slate
                will not do so. We want to be able to tell the
story of the story without being accused--reasonably--of just using that as an
excuse for telling the story itself.) Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X</ENAMEX>, described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>
as a "stunning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> model," claims to have had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> sexual
encounters with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1997</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1999</TIMEX>.

            Ms.
X's story has little apparent credibility. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> itself
concludes--19 paragraphs into its story--that "while her story may have the
appearance of truth, it's false--although [she] vehemently defends it."

            Rarely
has the falsity or unverifiability of a spicy political rumor been an
impediment to its widespread distribution on the Web. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> has taken
very little interest in the tale of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s alleged affair. And it's
next to impossible to find Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X</ENAMEX>'s story mentioned anywhere on the Net. Even
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> devoted to full-time bashing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> have thus far been
silent about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> story.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> anxieties of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> has been that the
unchecked proliferation of political rumor on the Internet would force
mainstream media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> to cover stories that were unchecked, or even
irresponsible. For example, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and
other venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> outposts ran stories on mere allegations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> use
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>--without any corroboration--largely because the stories had
become so widespread on the Internet.

            And
it's not hard to imagine Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X</ENAMEX>'s story being picked up by, say, the Drudge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>, and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> --a
time-tested spin cycle for dirty political rumors, particularly when they are
damaging to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            So
far, though, there's been silence. One minimizing factor might be the fact that
the story appeared in the publicity netherworld between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and New
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s. And Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X</ENAMEX>'s story seems to have less supporting evidence than, say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> tale about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, which was backed, however sketchily,
by tape-recorded telephone conversations (a technology that would later revisit
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency).

            But
clearly some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s indifference to the Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X</ENAMEX> story is attributable to
the gulf between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> and the tabloids. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's Web site
has posted the cover of the issue containing Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X</ENAMEX>'s allegations, with a big
coverline hyping the "smear," but the Web site doesn't offer a click-through to
the story itself.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's print circulation is a little over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 million</NUMEX>; it is part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Media</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid chain</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> revenues of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1999</TIMEX> it was bought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> Evercore
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Partners</ENAMEX>.

            
Although both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> and its sister <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX> have Web sites,
they do not use them to push their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>. That's probably because tabloid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most wired demographic; regardless, if the
tabloids don't post their stories in a timely fashion, would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> publicists
have nothing to link to.

            For a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> straddled the divide between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> and checkout-line cultures,
making the national press corps regularly scramble to cover a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> item. But
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> passes on a particular story, there are few other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>--in
print or on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>--who have the inclination and audience to break a tabloid
tale out to mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> 's "Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>"
gossip column ran a lead item on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> story on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
Day.)

            Some
might argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>--whose politics, while difficult to define, are
generally right of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>--is pulling punches to favor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> was
out front <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> reproducing stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s property having a
racially restrictive lease, a tale that received wide Net play but little
mainstream attention.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>'s relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> has lately soured a bit. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> trumpeted the details of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> investigation into a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>--a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>--claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. But that investigation, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>'s serial hype, determined
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s claims to be false. Since then, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid publishers</ENAMEX> have come
to see Web gossip sites as both nuisance and competition.

            It may
be, too, that Internet rumor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are a highly precise barometer of public
opinion. That is, they are ignoring the notion of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>
because, in the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> political climate, few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> believe that, even
if true, the allegations have any political significance.

         
      
   
