
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Case's Best Scenario</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX> is buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$166 billion</NUMEX> deal is
the biggest corporate merger ever and would create the world's largest media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $350 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> hailed the marriage because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> will be able to market its movies, music, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> will be able to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s massive cable
network to deliver high-speed Internet access. Reporters tripped over
themselves to describe the importance of the deal, saying, in order of
increasing excitement: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) it signals "convergence between old media content and
the new medium of the Net"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) it presages more megamergers, as other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
struggle to keep pace; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) it "marks the passage of the Internet from an exotic technology
into a mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> industry"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) it represents "the triumph of the Internet as the irresistible force in
business." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Customers</ENAMEX> were tepid, wondering whether the mammoth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would
improve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>' access to products or increase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' access to profits.
("" asks if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> paid too much for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, and "" wonders if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX>
brokered the deal.)

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stowaways</ENAMEX> died on their way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> were discovered, along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>, inside
a metal shipping container unloaded in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> have been arrested in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX>--almost
all on container <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. Unless the stowaways can prove they were
persecuted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, they will be sent home. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> were incensed by: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the
greed of the smugglers, who charge <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $60,000</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the complicity
of the shipping lines; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the negligence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. The
gloomy spin: This shows the desperate measures <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will take to escape
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
oppression . The rosier spin: This shows the desperate measures people
will take to gain <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> freedom .

            

               A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> granted temporary custody of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli√°n Gonz√</ENAMEX>°lez to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. The state judge ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonz√</ENAMEX>°lez to remain in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> until a hearing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naturalization Service</ENAMEX> ruled that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 year-old</TIMEX> should be reunited with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> could overrule the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s decision but has hinted that
it won't. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonz√°lez</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> said he was gaining a chance at due process and a better life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Most
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> said the chance would be short-lived, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are
almost certain to grant permanent custody to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s cynical spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> caved to political pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s
cynical spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX> caved to political pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exiles</ENAMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> wants to raise prices. If approved by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>, stamps for letters and postcards would each increase by
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2001</TIMEX>, to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">34 and 21 cents</NUMEX>, respectively. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
spun the rate hike as a competitive necessity that would allow it to maintain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> service, improve technology, and cover rising costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> charged
that it would hinder <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and nonprofits that rely on direct mail; and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> itself, by providing even greater incentive to use
alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shippers</ENAMEX>.

            

               Peace talks between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> wound down. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farouk Shara</ENAMEX> are returning home
without an agreement on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s withdrawal from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s
guarantees of security. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegations</ENAMEX> will continue to negotiate, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> will likely meet again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late January</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
deemed the talks a success, saying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) no one expected a breakthrough in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the
unprecedented discussion of substantive issues 
                  was a breakthrough
               . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> said the progress was
minimal and questioned whether the "well-rehearsed technique of locking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX> in a negotiating arena, cut off from other distractions,
still works as well as it once did."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> reiterated their support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in the
military. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said he would insist that potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX> support allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> to serve openly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> said he
would require his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> to carry out such a policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> later asserted
that he meant what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> said. Military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">candidates</ENAMEX> blasted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for crossing "a boundary between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> politics and military policy." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> variously said the hubbub
revealed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are increasingly important to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are
willing to sacrifice popular support in order to court them; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is
better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> at doing so.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> is hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Flu season arrived
earlier than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">previous years</TIMEX>, and the number and severity of infections are higher than average.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> are delaying elective procedures to deal with the influx of flu
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. The good news: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The most widespread flu <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> are covered by the
current <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> are effective if taken immediately
after symptoms appear. The bad news: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Fewer than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) it may be too late to get vaccinated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) people
usually react too slowly to flu symptoms for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> to be
effective.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. In her long-expected
announcement , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> likened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> and said he would
repair the presidency's tarnished image. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> called it a win for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>,
who gains support from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women voters</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, who increases her chances of
nabbing the vice presidential nomination; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, who can again
cast "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> as the charmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX> and [himself] as the scrappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ni√±a</ENAMEX> is altering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> weather. The effects of the cooler-than-normal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> currents include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) balmy temperatures on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
tornadoes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) cool weather in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwesterners</ENAMEX> ran for cover. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Easterners</ENAMEX> celebrated with "giddiness usually reserved for the first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days of spring</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pessimists</ENAMEX> called the weather a "spooky" reminder of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX>'s power and predicted further climatic changes from the greenhouse
effect.

            

               Y2K came and went without terrorism or technological snafus.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airplanes</ENAMEX> stayed airborne and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATMs</ENAMEX> dispensed cash as usual. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX> said the
Y2K bug's threat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) was averted thanks to diligent preparation; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) had been
exaggerated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy programmers</ENAMEX> so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> would commission expensive
repairs; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) won't pass until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have used their
"backroom systems," which were not repaired as thoroughly as critical programs. ("" sums up
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX> coverage from around the globe, and "" examines whether the Y2K
preparations were a waste.)

         
      
   
