
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX>: "USP <EM>S&<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#237</NUMEX>;</EM>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISP</ENAMEX> No!"

            
               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> announced that it's done something for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">consecutive year</TIMEX>. What?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 349</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whose Deal?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX> free online holiday greeting cards have
been sent via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bluemountain</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About a million</NUMEX> of them have something in
common. What?
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swastika</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Cornog</ENAMEX>
            

            "Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Registered Voter</ENAMEX>, As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> ..."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
cuss word is written on the knob of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Ripken</ENAMEX>'s baseball bat."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million Bluemountain</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> opted for the young, skinny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, but around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> went for the 'fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
goddamned hamster dance."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Heimer</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
scorn not just electronic greeting cards, but all greeting cards as prepackaged
expressions of sentiment for the emotionally illiterate. But isn't that a good
thing, meeting a real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> need, much as do village <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scribes</ENAMEX> in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>?
No. Not to orthodox quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, for whom greeting cards are to genuine
manifestations of feeling what Big Macs are to real <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX>, with some sort
of joke about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hallmark</ENAMEX> and bulimia--and an ugly image that would be, if only I
had the wit to express it. (Why isn't there a card!) Perhaps the crime isn't
that cards are prepackaged but that they are false--the impersonal disguised as
the personal, a mere pretense of affection, like corporate gift-giving,
particularly when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> passes out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> who, I'm told by corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>, only pretend to like you. (And which will not be offered after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil Exxon</ENAMEX> merger. At least not to gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>: Nothing judgmental, it's a
cost-cutting thing.) Or perhaps it's merely a matter of quality. No one seems
to mind a nice pre-written <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> sonnet, and that's why I'm going to send
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out just for you. Because I--wadda ya call it--love you. Happy
holidays.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Personal
Apology to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Mannella</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>
            

            "Never
mind your question. Here's my question: if 'Michael <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manella Speaks for Us All</ENAMEX>,'
why the hell can't we spell his name right? You're upsetting my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-A-N-N-E-L-L-A</ENAMEX>" Mannella
            

            
               iChristian, iJew,
iCaramba Answer
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About a million</NUMEX> of these electronic cards feature
an interfaith greeting, mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Judeo-Christian</ENAMEX> holiday cheer--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> in a
yarmulke, a reindeer with menorah antlers, that sort of nonsense.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Purists demurred</ENAMEX>, acting out their predictable
roles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> drama. "It is mistaken and misguided to synthesize the
distinct symbols of our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> traditions," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Leighton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guessing</ENAMEX>, not a medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who appreciates an honorific.

            "It is a terrible sign of intellectual and
religious confusion," carped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Faith or Fear: How</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jews Can Survive in a Christian America</ENAMEX> . "Each of these religions must
remain an immutable hodgepodge of customs, superstitions, and prejudices," he
did not add.

            Also available, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Christmas-tree</ENAMEX> ornaments--a
dreidel, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mogen David</ENAMEX>--none of which includes the cheery holiday message: "I'm
hedging my bets with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>."

            Also unavailable, a card showing a couple of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macabees</ENAMEX> beating the hell out of a yeshiva boy, just like real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About half</NUMEX> of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX> intermarry, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. "And they're all going to
hell," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX> did not declaim, "to the extent that we real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> have a hell,
which isn't much. Not like I'm jealous of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> or anything. They've
got hell, but we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>'
Heard at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joey Adams</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Funeral Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gee</ENAMEX>, I guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Baylos</ENAMEX>'ll have to drool on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX>, now."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poor Cindy Adams</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> she's buried. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First John Quincy</ENAMEX>, and now
this."

               "Thank God the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> still has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Peyser</ENAMEX>!"

               "Of course he's in hell--he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friar</ENAMEX>."

               "Only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Hebron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Hebron</ENAMEX>."

            

            
               Superfluous
Extra
            

            Mix and match. Below, a list of things <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>
says are unnecessary for our national defense, and a list of things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin R. Weissberg</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Supreme Court</ENAMEX> says are unnecessary for
the emotional well-being of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. But which is which?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-130</ENAMEX> cargo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Seawolf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>, yachts,
obsequious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX>, pandering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>.

            
               Answer
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Unnecessary for national defense.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Unnecessary for
emotional well-being of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Least-Believable</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assertions Ongoing Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX>: This has never been about money.

            (Or so the petulant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">divorcée</ENAMEX> claimed when <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weissberg</ENAMEX> rejected her request for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> child-support payments of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$132,000</NUMEX>
from former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelman</ENAMEX>, ordering her to scrimp by on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,825</NUMEX> a month
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their 4-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caleigh</ENAMEX>. His income is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $40 million</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>; hers is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2.4 million</NUMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited
to submit similar credulity-straining claims--fact or fiction, actual or
invented, drunk or disorderly. Replies to run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Online porn + <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our unreliable ISP = The Christmas</ENAMEX>
that never was.

         
      
   
