
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> Takes Round <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> faced off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> debate of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
Here's a play-by-play analysis of the debate's key themes and exchanges.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ball</ENAMEX> control. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> can't score unless
he has the ball. Therefore, the longer you keep possession of the ball, the
more likely you are to win the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in this department
by staying on the attack. Let's look at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> plays from the debate.

            

               
                  a)
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moderator Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> asks each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whether his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opponent</ENAMEX> has "ever taken a vote of yours or a quote out of context." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
says yes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> dances around the question ("I haven't complained about any. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">… I</ENAMEX>
won't accuse him of that"), then finally says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">no. Bradley</ENAMEX> gives the honest
answer, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> gives the smart <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Normally, when you're invited to accuse
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of something, the smart course is to accept the offer. But look
more closely: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> is inviting you to accuse your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of accusing
you of something. You're the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ultimately being accused. Suppose
you say you're angry that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> has accused you of kicking your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, after turning off their televisions, will think your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> is
a vicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>. But most will wonder whether you kick your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.

            By
saying no, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> avoids this trap. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, however, walks into it. He faults
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for suggesting "that I was going to hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> [and] Latinos
with [my] health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX>" and "that I am going to destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> without
saying what it is going to be replaced with." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
charge is unfair, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> gets to repeat and elaborate on the accusation:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> is eliminated, and they're given instead a little <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> a month
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">voucher</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">…</ENAMEX> Not a single [health plan] can be purchased for anything close to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> explains that his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> is a "weighted average," not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> tells a joke making fun of "weighted average" as a nerdy weasel
word. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is lying about the "cap" and the "voucher." But politically, he wins
the round, because both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> end up spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several minutes</TIMEX> discussing the
principal charge against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> without discussing any of the charges against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  b)
                Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> asks each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> whether "you
have ever had to make a difficult decision that you knew would hurt you
politically." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> picks a vote on which he differed from "most of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, however, picks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> votes on which he differed
specifically from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s budget cuts ("I wish that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
had stood up to that one") and the authorization to use force in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> (on which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> voted no). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> answers the question at face value.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> uses it to land <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> good punches.

            

               
                  c)
                Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is invited to ask a question of the
other. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> why he isn't proposing universal health-insurance
coverage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> neutralizes the question and turns it on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. "Both of us
have proposed the same goal: high-quality health care for all," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. "I
devoted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$374 billion</NUMEX> to the solvency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. You have not devoted one
penny to ensuring the solvency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. And my question to you is: Why
not?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> complains that it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s time to ask questions. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> replies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can ask the question, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> never gets off a
solid answer to it.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s credibility problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> makes lots of allegations
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s past votes and future plans. To sustain those allegations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
needs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> his credibility. The best way to do this is to admit the truth
when it's disadvantageous to him. He begins by making such a concession about
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund-raising scandal: "It was wrong. And I think that the
phone calls that I made were a mistake." But as the debate goes on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
repeatedly strains credulity. He asks <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> "to give me a
come-from-behind upset victory here," and then, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> points out the
absurdity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s plea--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> pitch brings tears to my
eyes"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> repeats his claim that it would be an "upset victory."

            Yes,
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> wins <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, he could argue that it's an upset. And, yes, he
needs the media to buy into that assumption. But saying it so baldly, and then
repeating it, is counterproductive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> does this all the time--"risky tax
scheme," "no controlling legal authority," etc.--and seems incapable of
controlling the habit. The problem is not that he comes off as a talking-points
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">robot</ENAMEX>--which he does--but that he insults everyone's intelligence. He looks
like a suck-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who thinks he can get a good grade by parroting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s buzzwords. When he calls <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> tax cuts a "tax scheme" and
calls his hypothetical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> victory an "upset," you get the feeling
not only that he's twisting the truth, but also that he thinks you're too
stupid to realize it. And the deeper that feeling sinks in, the less attention
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will pay to anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> says.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s arrogance problem. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s flaw is dishonesty,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s flaw is moral and intellectual vanity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> began the campaign
determined to convey his virtue and wisdom, and he succeeded. Now his problem
is that he can't turn it off. The more he equates his candidacy with goodness
and enlightenment, and the more condescendingly he dismisses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> ("Let me
explain to you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>, how the private sector works. … I can say that in much
shorter words"), the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> wonder whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> knows his limits and is
capable of learning from his mistakes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>,
recognizing this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Achilles</ENAMEX>' heel, goes after it with a crowbar. Reciting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s votes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> budget cuts, against welfare reform, and against
the use force in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> asks, "Would you vote differently on
any of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> votes if you had it to do over again? Were they mistakes<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> replies that they weren't, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> pounces on this answer: "I think
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> were mistakes, but I'm not going to debate the details. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">… My</ENAMEX> point is
beyond that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>. In all those words about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different votes, one word
I didn't hear was the word 'mistake.' And here's why I think that is important.
I think our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> deserves a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who, when he makes a mistake, is
willing to acknowledge it and willing to learn from it, because I believe that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidency</ENAMEX> is not an academic exercise. It's not an extended seminar on
theory. … If I make a mistake, I'll do my best to own up to it and then to
learn from it, and learn from you [the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>] about how we can deal with the
reality as we find it."

            Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
remembers something he admits was a mistake--"I voted against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time" --and everybody laughs. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has found a big chink in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s armor. He has found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> votes on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> took unpopular
positions, and he has found that when pressed about those votes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
exposes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> trait that puts off many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. If history is any guide,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will exploit that dilemma for the rest of the campaign. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
doesn't learn to stop talking like a used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>, nobody's going to be
listening.

         
      
   
