
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Video Crack</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who don't gamble tend to view gambling as
either high-glitz <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> or megabucks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>--the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> the media
ever bother to notice. This narrow focus has protected the gambling industry,
since <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are willing to accept a vice that is clearly separated from the
rest of society--as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> are--or that offers a luscious chance at the good
life--as megabucks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX> do.

            But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> nascent
grassroots anti-gambling campaigns in the West could finally bring attention to
the real issue in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> gambling, which has nothing whatsoever to do with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX> jackpots. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
have gathered enough signatures to place a constitutional amendment on the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX> ballot to outlaw "video lottery." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> are
preparing a similar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX> ballot measure to abolish video gambling in
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. These initiatives aren't trying to eliminate all legal gambling in
their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--prohibition has been a disastrously unsuccessful strategy in the
gambling wars. Instead they are targeting only the newest and most addictive
form of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> betting: "convenience gambling." The campaigns against
convenience gambling mark the most important development in gambling politics
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            Convenience gambling--a cheerful phrase for an alarming
idea--is premised on the notion that once gambling is legal, it should be
allowed just about everywhere: convenience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, bowling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alleys</ENAMEX>, gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> permit convenience gambling now. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several</TIMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, convenience gambling takes the form of a
so-called "video lottery." To those who haven't played it, "video lottery"
sounds like some kind of high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powerball</ENAMEX>--a lottery played with a computer
instead of a ticket. In fact, "video lottery" bears no relationship at all to a
lottery. It is simply a euphemism for state-run video poker machines. Video
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> is a popular casino game, a low-stakes electronic version of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-card-draw <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>. "It means minicasinos on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street</ENAMEX> that are run by the
government," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Grey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Coalition Against Legalized</ENAMEX>
Gambling, which is organizing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> ballot initiatives. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, with about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,000</NUMEX> video poker machines that it places in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,800</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX>
gambling machines in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,400</NUMEX> locations. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> has similar numbers of machines
in similar places, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> does not run the machines.

            These Western states
introduced video gambling in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '80s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '90s</TIMEX> for one reason: It is
a stupendously effective way of parting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> from their money. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Association of State</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provincial Lotteries</ENAMEX>, the average
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> with a lottery spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $150</NUMEX> per year on the lottery.
But in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> with video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>), average per capita lottery
spending is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $600</NUMEX> per year. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, where lottery play is the
highest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> spends an amazing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750</NUMEX> per year on
the state lottery.

            This generates monster revenues for both state and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>'s government splits the revenue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-50</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>. The state clears <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, which it is using to cut
property taxes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>. (This money represents <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 5 percent</NUMEX> of the total
state budget.) In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, the state takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two-thirds</NUMEX> of the video lottery
revenues. That amounts to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $230 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 3 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>--which the state spends on education, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">salmon restoration</ENAMEX>.
("What do <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>, state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and
salmon all have in common?" boasts the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon Lottery</ENAMEX>'s home page. "They all
receive Lottery profits to help them prepare for the future!") In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>, the
state pockets <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of video gambling revenue in taxes, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close to $40</NUMEX>
million for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s treasury. (Both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> also run
traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>, but they are penny-ante games next to the video lottery:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only a quarter</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s lottery revenue comes from traditional lottery
games, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>'s does.)

            Video gambling delivers
tax revenues, but it exacts huge social costs. Video <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> is known as "video
crack." Its rate of play is dizzyingly fast--I once played <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 400</NUMEX> games
of video <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> in an hour--and the flashing lights and flickering screens send
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> into trancelike reveries. Unlike other kinds of gambling, video poker
discourages social interaction. "The machines suck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into the screen,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Thompson</ENAMEX>, a gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Nevada</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. "You don't talk or socialize. You don't trade stories. It is
different from blackjack or even handle slots. These are the most addictive of
any gambling instrument we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." It's also voracious: A typical gambler
addicted to blackjack takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 20 years</TIMEX> from placing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> bet to
bottoming out; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gambler</ENAMEX> hooked on video poker needs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than three years</TIMEX>. The
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gamblers Anonymous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> has leapt from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three to 30</NUMEX>
since video <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> was introduced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> itself recognizes the
dangers of video poker: It forbids video lottery advertising and allocates <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> for treating problem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>.) What's more, the small stakes in
video lotteries encourage addiction. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>, which offer low odds but
spectacular jackpots, video poker returns tiny but frequent pots. The state
relies on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> playing the games over and over and over again.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Addiction</ENAMEX> is not the only drawback of video gambling. It is
a cinch for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to play video lottery machines, since they are often found in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> frequent. Though it pays off more often than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>,
video poker offers poor odds compared with most casino gambling, taking about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 cents</NUMEX> of every dollar bet compared to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3 cents</NUMEX> for casino slots. Moreover,
convenience gambling doesn't deliver the secondary economic benefits that big
gambling can. Because states limit the number of machines that any one business
can have, there are no large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>. So video lottery brings none of the
ancillary jobs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> that big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> do.

            As a result, convenience
gambling is emerging as the kind of gambling that everyone can dislike, a juicy
target for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scapegoat</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of more acceptable kinds of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wagering</ENAMEX>. A bipartisan grassroots campaign in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> just eliminated
its enormous video poker industry. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> about that abolition .) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX>,
half the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">parishes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> threw out video gambling from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and truck stops. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, who
strongly supported <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>, tried to root out convenience gambling from stores
in her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The rest of the gambling industry treats convenience gambling like
an embarrassing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, routinely condemning it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> have preserved a last best argument
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>: They can't afford to drop video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governors</ENAMEX> in
both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have said they dislike relying on lottery revenues to fund
essential government services. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> has never been a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of the
lottery and of letting gambling policy drive public policy," says a spokesman
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kitzhaber</ENAMEX>. But they are too scared of losing their video
lottery funds to endorse the ballot initiatives. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> ballot
initiative was floated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitzhaber</ENAMEX> endorsed the idea of
abolishing the video lottery but said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> needed a phaseout period to
find replacement revenue. So the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> added a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> phaseout to their
ballot initiative. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitzhaber now</ENAMEX> insists on a phaseout of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least six years</TIMEX>.
"He wants to get rid of it, but then he wants <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>. He sounds like an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">addict</ENAMEX>," says the anti-gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grey</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> votes are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> away,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> signature-gathering has not yet begun. No one knows whether
even one of the initiatives can pass. The lottery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> will surely spend
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to keep their cash cow, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> are likely to campaign for
video gambling as well. But if the initiatives do squeak by, they may signal a
new and encouraging compromise, a recognition that just because gambling is
legal does not mean it has to be everywhere. If the initiatives pass, after
all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> will retain their traditional scratch-off and Powerball
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lotteries</ENAMEX>, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> will continue to offer electronic gambling
on reservations. These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> will have gambling that is accessible, but not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX>; gambling that funds state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> but does not hold it
hostage.

         
      
   
