
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">360</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Epic</ENAMEX>"

            
               The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'50s</NUMEX> begat
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Days ; the '60s, The Wonder Years ; the '70s, That</ENAMEX> '70s
Show ; and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freaks and Geeks</ENAMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> will be
distilled into a set of reductive clichés and processed into a TV sitcom. Give
the one-sentence pitch for that show. (Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carvell</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">359</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peril</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Us?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               Government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have begun to caution
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> about "speed creep"--meaning?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goddamn Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> and his shifty eyes."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonyms</ENAMEX>. Watch out for antonyms."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
had a similar answer.)

            
"Internet pharmacist."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Vehrs</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX> liked to run around nude, but I didn't realize he had
become such a menace to our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Annett</ENAMEX> )

            "The
Einsteinian possibility that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third millennium</TIMEX> will arrive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime next</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Finkle</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Paying little attention
to the preparations for various grand public ceremonials, I've only just
noticed that this is the final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> plunges into the sun
and is destroyed. (Although why that should lead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> to cancel its all-nude
fertility ritual is unclear.) It's been a great planet. I particularly enjoyed
your colored sky; a nice choice, blue, popular, everybody likes that blue. Also
evolution, very entertaining. That was some fun watching how the giant
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-headed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lizard</TIMEX>'s constant bickering among itself eventually led to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extinction</ENAMEX>, a lesson for us all and especially for my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uncle Morty and Aunt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernice</ENAMEX>. And so when I gather up my soil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> and Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Davis</ENAMEX> and return
to my home planet, I'll particularly miss those things and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>, everybody.

            
               So Where's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Problem</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers fearfully</ENAMEX> refer to
gradually going faster and faster on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>, flouting the speed limit, as
"speed creep," and it is, well, accelerating.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.9 percent</NUMEX> of interstate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> exceeded
the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">65-mph</NUMEX> limit; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, that number rose to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX>. On much of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-80</ENAMEX> and
I-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 10 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> obey the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55-mph</NUMEX> limit. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> routinely drive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 miles an hour</NUMEX> faster than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.

            Curiously, as speeds
have increased, the highway death rate has decreased, declining by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX>
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, when the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> abandoned the national <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55-mph</NUMEX> speed
limit. So one wonders why "speed creep" is reported as a problem rather than
good news: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safer</ENAMEX> faster driving saves time and lives?

            
               Metaphors of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Which of the following are from recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times articles and which are a clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruse</ENAMEX>, like those cardboard tanks the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> built in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> to trick <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> looking for plywood <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan Starts</ENAMEX> Push Through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party Hedgerows</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is engaged
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> by state, meeting by meeting political organizing required for a
losing presidential bid.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-Month</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> Dispute <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Turns Into a War of Attrition"</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Hurwitz</ENAMEX>, who
controls a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spokane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>, locked out his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Although he has
been implicated in cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">redwoods</ENAMEX> and in the collapse of a huge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas S&L</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurwitz</ENAMEX> was not involved in the siege of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stalingrad</ENAMEX> but probably
wishes he had been.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tobacco Company Turns Big Guns on Foes"</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip Morris</ENAMEX> has acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
surplus <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">artillery</ENAMEX> and intends to shell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>. "We sell a legal
product and believe in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Second Amendment</ENAMEX>. And several of the Ten
Commandments," declared a company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "If
retail is war, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> Place <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> are the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadets</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to have their boot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> on the field of battle."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Kids</ENAMEX>
attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, work at crappy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> for no pay, because … well, I'm
not sure why.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "In
Outpouring of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mexico Lawmakers Battle Over Budget"</ENAMEX>--If I understand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX>--and I don't--our southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> is governed by some kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">poisonous snakes</ENAMEX> who aren't getting along.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Giuliani Proposes Martial Law</ENAMEX>"--"And I'm not speaking metaphorically," he
declared from his bunker beneath <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Hall</ENAMEX>. Something to do with the search for
yet another new schools <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2, 4</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> are
authentic journalistic clichés.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Creepingest garment: underwear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Creepiest person</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
