
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antler Envy</ENAMEX>

            You
know it must be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday season</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tabloidland</ENAMEX> when all those dirty secrets
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red-Nosed Reindeer</ENAMEX> start to surface. With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
claiming that singing cowboy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Autry</ENAMEX> "hated" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>'s theme song and had to
be persuaded to record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas</TIMEX> classic, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX>
weighs in with a "surprising revelation": "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>!" According to
"top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> reindeer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Berg</ENAMEX>, male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reindeer</ENAMEX> have already shed
their antlers by late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, meaning that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> antler-topped reindeer
traditionally seen with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> must be female. As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enquirer</ENAMEX> explains, the "disclosure tears the wrapping off the widely
held myth that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Kringle</ENAMEX>'s sleigh is pulled by burly, macho reindeer." Since
she wasn't aware that such a myth even existed, much less that it was widely
held, Keeping Tabs wonders whether those crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> were
indulging in a rare moment of self-mockery. And we can't stop wondering: Just
what does it take to become a "top" reindeer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>?

            In
keeping with the holiday <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>, recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> have been filled with tales of
celebrity shopping excursions that amount to stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spending
outrageous sums of money very quickly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , for example, has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Lemmon</ENAMEX> dropping a cool <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> on antiques in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than an hour</TIMEX>. Not to
be outdone, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Geri Halliwell</ENAMEX> is said to have "plopped down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Prada</ENAMEX> ski outfits a mere "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX> after she tried them on."

            Our
favorite--and most flowery--account of lavish celebrity spending comes from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlene Tilton</ENAMEX>, who reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> and "two
flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy pals</ENAMEX>" were recently spotted perusing the sheets and towels at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beverly Center</ENAMEX>. "After poring over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of colors and styles,"
Tilton reports, "the fussy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellas</ENAMEX> finally agreed on over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000</NUMEX> worth of luxury
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linens</ENAMEX> and a dreamy down-filled comforter and duvet cover for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo's</ENAMEX> master
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bedroom</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , meanwhile, maintains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fiancee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Sklar</ENAMEX>, "isn't wasting any time" spending her intended's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX>
million fortune. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sklar</ENAMEX> is said to have "zigzagged through each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergdorf Goodman</ENAMEX>, where she "breathlessly scooped up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> worth
of shoes," a feat that earned her the nickname <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">"Hurricane Jessica</ENAMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergdorf</ENAMEX>'s apparently weathered the storm, though; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX>--who are, respectively, the former and
current loves of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX>--bumped into one another there while shopping for
cashmere shawls. Star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Charlton</ENAMEX> treats the outing as a
competitive event. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth</ENAMEX> won this round," she explains. "She spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,000</NUMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,500</NUMEX>." We're pleased that Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gwyneth-ness</ENAMEX> had the opportunity
to splurge; no doubt she had to recover from the traumatic experience of being
promised a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> shopping spree by new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Oseary</ENAMEX>, only to
have him take her to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niketown</ENAMEX>, where (according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> ) she
"settled" for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> worth of sneakers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paltrow</ENAMEX> is lucky, however, that she did
not have to go bargain-hunting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>'s soon-to-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie Rowe</ENAMEX>, whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> spotted "loading up on economy size gallons
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter</ENAMEX>, grape jelly, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mayonnaise</ENAMEX> and cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>" at the "Smart and
Final" discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.

            Let's
see: got the reindeer, the presents ... how about a few angels? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , insists that her dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> "gives her heavenly
advice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>!" while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jo Johnson</ENAMEX>'s late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is now her guardian angel, "watching over [her] and
guiding her to showbiz success."

            
Indeed, celestial guidance appears to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s latest must-have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accessory</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX> has been having
heart-to-hearts with her late ex-husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bono</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
says a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> psychic claims she "regularly" relays career advice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> from the great beyond. The late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Belushi</ENAMEX>, for instance, is
said to have "specifically encouraged" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX> to star in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Analyze This</ENAMEX> ,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Bruce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huston</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lyricist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Jay Lerner</ENAMEX> have
all been trying to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> to "make more comedies and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">musicals</ENAMEX>."

            But it's not all business
with those ghostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX>. The spirit of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mama</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cass Elliot</ENAMEX> has been known to
turn on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">StairMaster</ENAMEX> and move jewelry around in her old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> . Once, says current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Aykroyd</ENAMEX>, the ghost even
"crawled into bed" with him. "I just nuzzled up to whatever it was and went
back to sleep," he explains. (And for anyone left in the dark by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's high fallutin vocabulary, they helpfully provide a "Fast
Fact" box, which explains that "a ghost is a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s spirit.") Aykroyd
might want to compare notes with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER star Noah Wyle</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is
reportedly haunted by the ghost of its famous former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX>. Or perhaps he should take a cue from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Liu</ENAMEX>, who
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> says once "did more than snuggle with a spook ... she
claims she actually had sex with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>." "It was sheer bliss," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX> is quoted as
saying. "I felt everything. I climaxed. And then he floated away." Wow. We bet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scrooge</ENAMEX> never tried that with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Marley</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
