
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">354</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You're a Dead Man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX>"

            
               After drawing
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Peanuts</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 50 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schulz</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX> and ailing, is putting
down his pen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to describe his final strip.
(Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">353</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad-Ass Query</ENAMEX>"
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> made an announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important
words, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hyphenated, unlikely to show up in any of its forthcoming TV
commercials. What <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words?
            

            
"Crash-test <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Koegel</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anti-lock</ENAMEX> and scrotum."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bodacious ta</ENAMEX>-tas."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX>, now that he's turned down the endorsement
offer."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Williams</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            
"Shit-eating grins." The announcement was about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.M.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> holiday
bonuses."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ein Nod</ENAMEX>" Heimer
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Badly planned, poorly
made, and apt to burst into flames--no, not <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">prime-time</TIMEX> TV (although I, for one,
would be more likely to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> if the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> were more
frequently devastated by fatal explosions, or the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> news if furious
grease fires now and then ravaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>' hair). Rather, those are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">qualities News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> associate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.M.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, despite the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s demonstrating with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> line that it is quite capable of
producing a first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> commercial. Apparently the news hasn't reached quiz
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has shaken of the malaise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> and the
clunky gas-guzzler by invading several small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and imitating the design
and manufacturing methods of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>. I suppose that's not the sort of thing
that gets talked about on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> or in some dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. But you won't find
it so easy to knock this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and its great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> with the sort of
left-wing philosophy best expressed on a bumper sticker when you don't even
have a bumper! Try slapping a sticker on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor</ENAMEX>'s ass, and he'll toss
you right off your overcrowded, overheated, way-behind-schedule <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroad</ENAMEX>. In
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>. Maybe then you won't be too good to ride in an exploding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX>.

            
               Following Orders
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazi-Era</ENAMEX> Slaves

            Those were the words in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
headline when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Gottschalk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.M.</ENAMEX>'s general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, announced that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would likely contribute to a fund to compensate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave laborers</ENAMEX> who
worked in its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Opel</ENAMEX> division. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.M.</ENAMEX> would be the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to accept responsibility for wartime abuses."

            There are thought to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave laborers</ENAMEX>,
most of whom were concentration camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, left alive; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two million</NUMEX> others, mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> and central
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>, mostly not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, as slaves throughout the war.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> industry and government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> announced plans to establish a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.1</NUMEX>
billion fund to compensate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave laborers</ENAMEX>.

            
               Presidential Presence
Extra
            

            Which of these important
public events, some actual some not, did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> attend, and which
did he blow off?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franjo Tudjman</ENAMEX> funeral

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX> hand-over

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Running of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Show Girls</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesar's Palace</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional INS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day Body</ENAMEX>-Cavity
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Search of Terrified Immigrants</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employee</ENAMEX> who finds the gold coin wins a free
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">turkey</ENAMEX>.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dress Betrayal</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gay Rights</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Army

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Ribbon-Cutting at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bed</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ice-Cream-Cake-Cutting</ENAMEX> at Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carvel</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phony-Baloney Bipartisan Pledge</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance Reform Press Conference</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fish Fry</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet Barney the Lovable Purple Dinosaur and Gaze</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Awe</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Splendors of Capitalism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Studios Tour</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laid</ENAMEX> on to
persuade the little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">raft-boy</ENAMEX> that living in a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with plentiful
theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> is better than returning to a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Ceremonial
Presentation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Cattle to Emperor Xzarlac</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dark Lord</ENAMEX> of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galaxies</ENAMEX>

            
               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. No

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. No

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. May have attended in disguise, like that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pauper</ENAMEX> thing

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Not yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.S.V.P.'d</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Present in spirit

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. No

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Rumor is he'll show up late, sprawl beneath
soft-ice-cream tap, and suck it down until he passes out

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Yes. Except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> fry

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Probably attended by that stooge they use as his
double, so he can simultaneously attend and deny having attended

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Scheduling conflict;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> sent in his place

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gina Duclayan</ENAMEX>'s Least
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Persuasive Assertion Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "Rather than being 'toxic,' urine (which is about
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>) may actually contain some of the 
                  purest water
                that we
can drink."--from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Diet</ENAMEX>" Web site.

         
      
   
