
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">361</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lit Crit</ENAMEX>"

            
               "Oh, I can't stand
that. You could get <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> reading them, couldn't you?" Who said this about
what? (Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 360</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Epic":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'50s</NUMEX> begot <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Days ; the '60s, The Wonder Years</ENAMEX> ;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'70s, That '70s Show</ENAMEX> ; and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freaks and Geeks</ENAMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> will be distilled into a set of reductive clichés and
processed into a TV sitcom. Give the one-sentence pitch for that show.
(Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

            "World
Television presents: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DECADENT BROKER</ENAMEX>! Which indulged largely, but did
not know <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New Revolution</ENAMEX> was soon occurring. (So sorry for it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
sentence.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Kahn</ENAMEX>
            

            "Two
young Internet geniuses, who happen to be married, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">WASP</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, the other an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> gal from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich</ENAMEX> beyond belief from cashing out
of an IPO, start a company delivering frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">embryos</ENAMEX>--and hire an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in
a turban as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receptionist</ENAMEX>. The mix-ups, the lawsuits, the laughs never
stop!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Then Came Klebold</ENAMEX> : A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> travels from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, registers in
the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, gets involved in the lives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, then shoots
them."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jerks and Smirks</ENAMEX> . Politics in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Davis</ENAMEX>
            

            "TV?
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> we won't need any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stinkin</ENAMEX>' TV. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cybercitizens</ENAMEX> will be hard-wired,
and entertainment as we know it will be in the form of IPOs."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rickey</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Before plunging into TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, let's take a moment
to look back at TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>.

            When the ball fell, a huge sign was illuminated and
transmitted on every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover Card</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and its new
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Square</ENAMEX> thus achieved a complete capitulation of the civic to the
corporate, and was proud of it.

            Giddy with delight over his imposition of midtown
martial law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> showed up on every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manhole</ENAMEX> covers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welded</ENAMEX> closed; trash cans removed; mailboxes locked; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX> cops; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> police
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helicopters</ENAMEX>--it was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, except for the part about any
known threat. But it must be admitted, the festivities were unmarred by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">terrorist</ENAMEX> bombings or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant stampedes</ENAMEX>.

            The usually fatuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brokaw</ENAMEX> outdid himself when he rated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>--it was a tough one, he
blathered, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> world wars, the atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, but there
was also the triumph of the space program. I'm sure <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 million</NUMEX> murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 million</NUMEX> dead <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> would agree that the space shuttle more than made up
for mass death.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> on Airs
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> list several
priorities of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>. Which
of the following are actually on his to-do list?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Create a streamlined and corruption-free
bureaucracy.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Put a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> on moon by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> with
cool time machine.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Install a merit system for hiring and rewarding
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Ensure smooth transition by cultivating image as
lovable womanizing drunk.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Increase investment and improve productivity in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Construct theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> exciting enough to attract
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">raft boys</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Build a more powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Work for closer ties between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s regions.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> simply disappear, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX>-style.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Develop new
political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> open to professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestlers</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Semites</ENAMEX>, and fat-faced,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">egomaniac</ENAMEX> know-nothings.

            
               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 3, 5, 7</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authentic Putin</ENAMEX> plans.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            E-greed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, and presidential infidelity.

         
      
   
