
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peacemaker</ENAMEX>

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with rising hopes for a lasting peace in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. This followed a report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX> will start to get rid of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> "within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the IRA has invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John de Chastelain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> head
of an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arms decomissioning body</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> a controlled explosion
of some of its weaponry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this month</TIMEX> in an attempt to meet the terms of the
peace deal negotiated by former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX>. This "symbolic
gesture" is timed to take place before a crucial meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early February</TIMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionist Council</ENAMEX>, which is to review progress on the
IRA's commitment to disarm. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> coalition
government, has said he will resign if the IRA doesn't start to give up its
weapons.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
Independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> quoted a source in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, the political party
closely linked to the IRA, warning against "ill-informed and speculative
stories." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin McGuinness</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, told the paper
he believes there is no way the new power-sharing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> would let peace collapse over the arms question. "It is now
inconceivable that the political process that we embarked on could be brought
down over the issue," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGuinness</ENAMEX> said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> led with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trimble</ENAMEX> urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to
press <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to start IRA decomissioning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is expected to
receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in a
meeting regarded in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> as "of critical importance," the paper
said.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> remains much in demand as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacemaker</ENAMEX>. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> marking
the end of the current round of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> peace talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shepherdstown</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.V.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said that
"as the negotiations become more taxing and problematic, the involvement of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is likely to become yet more extensive." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "A web of mutual
commitment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> has been spun. The mutual relationship
features <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s commitment to the process and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s obligations with
regard to the forging of agreements, and as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guarantor</ENAMEX> in economic
and security areas."

            A
report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times of London</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossad</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> secret
service, managed to take a urine sample from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez Assad</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>
when he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1999</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>. With
the cooperation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> secret service, a special lavatory was
prepared for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assad</ENAMEX>'s exclusive use, with a urinal that led not into a drain but
into a specimen jar. His urine was then taken for analysis to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tel Hashomer</ENAMEX>
medical research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claimed. The conclusion was
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assad</ENAMEX> is living on borrowed time. "We should do everything to reach an
agreement while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assad</ENAMEX> is alive," an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> . "Nobody knows what will happen after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assad</ENAMEX>. There are
some gloomy assessments about a possible bloodbath in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assad</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> you
can <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> to stand by his word." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> that former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shimon Peres</ENAMEX> is the favorite to
succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezer Weizman</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> if the latter is forced to resign over a
financial controversy.

            
Setbacks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> war were widely seen as weakening <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>'s
position as the front-running candidate for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> presidency. The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> that he is struggling to reassert
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> "as his military campaign in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> threatened to turn from a
vote-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> into an electoral liability." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "For Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>, in the
absence of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> at home, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX> are now his most serious opposition
in the campaign ahead." The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> also reported that the
terrorist responsible for masterminding the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> hostage crisis and killing
scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX> has come out of retirement to lend his
support to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> fighting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX>. "Imad
Mugniyeh, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>'s radical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hizbollah Muslim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militia</ENAMEX>, and as notorious in the international terrorist world in the eighties
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, has been identified as responsible for plotting
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s terrorist attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX>," the paper
said.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> fronted what was taken as a call by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> to resign. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> radio station: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> needs a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to lead it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wojtyla</ENAMEX> should
admit that he is no longer capable of carrying out his task." Interviewed by
Corriere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bishop Lehmann</ENAMEX> denied having asked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s
resignation and said he was talking only about "the theoretical possibility" of
it.

            There
seemed to be agreement in the world's press that the escape of the 14-year-old
karmapa, the third-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>'s spiritual hierarchy after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> and the panchen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lama</ENAMEX>, embarrassed practically everybody. Everybody
agreed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> were embarrassed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Age of India</ENAMEX> said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was embarrassed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s request that the karmapa
should be granted political asylum in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> did not "want to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">jeopardise</ENAMEX> relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, which have witnessed a slight thaw in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> was also said to be embarrassed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the karmapa might emigrate to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> denies him asylum.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> gave
much prominence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> is planning to
move from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> in order to direct a series of one-act plays, a
project reportedly rejected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
