
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">364</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top 20</ENAMEX>"

            

               In his autobiography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> called it "the longest <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>
of my tenure as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>." What was he doing?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 363</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Edgy and Explosive":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               The list includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">daggers</ENAMEX>, pipe bombs, spears, and bows and arrows.
List of what?
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s replacements for the electric chair."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Things, other than 'love' that could've busted 'Hurricane' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> out of
jail."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Miguel González</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elián</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, refused an offer to visit
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and its vibrant anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> Hight
            

            
"Things the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daryl Hannah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> invented in the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clan of the Cave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Welcome</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood</ENAMEX>' gifts delivered to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chappaqua</ENAMEX> home
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Lieber</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Surely a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rocker</ENAMEX> response is sufficient
impetus to point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League Baseball</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, not the
actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX>--is as odious and craven a pack of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> never sued by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX>. What happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocker</ENAMEX>'s right to free (albeit despicable)
speech? While the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> limits government action, not that of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">employer</ENAMEX>, doesn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that constantly claims to symbolize
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--have sufficient respect for that doctrine not to threaten to fire a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> for expressing his (albeit despicable) views? No, as it happens, it
doesn't.

            And then, lacking the
courage to fire the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> directly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> sends <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocker</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>. Didn't we
used to deride the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> for putting those who expressed unpopular
(albeit despicable) views in mental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocker</ENAMEX> isn't insane; he's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contemptible</ENAMEX> (albeit despicable) racist. He should not be fired; he should be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">despised</ENAMEX>. Boo him from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX>, shun him in the locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, denounce him in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, but don't "treat" him and don't take away his job. Of course, Rocker
will not be banned from <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>; he's too skillful a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> will
keep him in the game without any moral courage--some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> display of
contrition, lessons learned, amends made, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> taken--but without the booing
and the shunning and the denouncing. Hardly worth it.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Benign Influence of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God</ENAMEX>'s Answer
            

            These were the most common sorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> seized
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> during the current outbreak of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
violence.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX> confiscated
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ambon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Monday</TIMEX> following clashes that left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> people
dead. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> opened fire on battling <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mobs</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>. More than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX> were slain throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in this region, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mollucas</ENAMEX>, are about the
same size, making for a more evenly matched sort of strife.

            
               Corporate Ethos
Extra
            

            This follow-up was
e-mailed to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Deshields</ENAMEX>@CNP

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12/27/99 04:35 PM</TIMEX>

            To: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square 1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Square 2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square 3</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square 4</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">4Times Square</ENAMEX> 5

            
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">2000 Glamour Swimsuit Try-On</ENAMEX>

            For all of those who
have replied and plan on participating, if you were to fall into one of the
following categories which would it be?

            Small Bust

            Large Bust

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long Torso</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waist Cincher</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pear Shaped</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tummy Control</ENAMEX>

            Large sized

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rainy-Day Fun: Match</ENAMEX>
your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> with his/her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> type and look of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">despair.</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>.)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cultural Details</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            " 'I'd like to see him do a video in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> dancing
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> in caps and a grunge look,' says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shashi Gopal</ENAMEX>, managing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnasound India Ltd.</ENAMEX>" (Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>.)
            

            This is the culturally
savvy marketing plan <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gopal</ENAMEX> described to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , by
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indipop</ENAMEX>, a hybrid of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> music, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>, rap, and reggae, will conquer
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daler Mehndi</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sikh</ENAMEX> who used to
drive a taxi in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mehndi</ENAMEX>'s first album, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bolo Ta Ra</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ra</ENAMEX> , sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> copies, the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indipop</ENAMEX> success ever. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the
Punjab, tomorrow <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>--I dunno, maybe the parts of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> with the caps and the grunge and the dancing and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            School violence, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> debate violence.

         
      
   
