
   
   
      
         
            Cashing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen Dividend</ENAMEX>

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s parliamentary elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> dominated the world's editorial
pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this week</TIMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> will remain the biggest
single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">bloc</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX>, having won <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX> of the vote, the success of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity Party</ENAMEX>, which claimed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX>, took the
ink. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s success the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechen</ENAMEX> dividend," a sentiment echoed
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , which said that "beyond bellicosity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasus</ENAMEX>, Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>
has articulated no clear policy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> headlined its editorial "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who rose without trace," and said,
"Public attention no longer focuses primarily on the ailing Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s
erratic policy-making, or even on the widespread corruption, ballooning debt
and huge disparities of wealth that have arisen during the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-rapid
privatisation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy. Instead the talk is increasingly of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resurgent</ENAMEX>, nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, pinning its hopes of salvation on a strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. And it has all happened because Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> launched <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> into a war in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>."

            In a
leader
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX>
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said the election results brought both good and bad
news: "The good news is that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX> is likely to be younger, and somewhat
more sympathetic towards economic liberalism than the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. ‚Ä¶ The bad news
is that political liberalism has been sacrificed in the process." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> took a similar tack, decrying the "rise in military influence"
and "a resumption in the sway of oligarchs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX>," but
taking heart in the shift of power "from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also attacked the style of the election, saying "the vote was influenced by an assortment of
electoral dirty tricks, involving money, rule-breaking and libelling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> on state television," but said that "given their limited choices, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were suprisingly selective, backing those who may actually do
something about the sorry state of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>."

            The
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post of Canada</ENAMEX> asked what the effect of a compatible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> and
executive would be and decided that, "In foreign policy, the recent
anti-Western tendency is likely to continue, but more cautiously and less
explicitly. Thus, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primakov</ENAMEX>'s active pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> diplomacy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
will be moderated, but Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s pursuit of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> rapprochement to
offset <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> influence will proceed at a leisurely pace."

            A
cautious note was struck in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , which said
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s future looks rosy, except as regards concrete policies, his main
one so far being the razing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> who have amassed
vast fortunes under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> are able to continue as usual and are
doubtless grinning like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cheshire cats</ENAMEX>." Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Times</ENAMEX> said, "The system of succession that will guarantee the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>'s
victory is a very positive development. For, in circumstances where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> are equally corrupt, a corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> based on
succession is preferable to a revolutionary corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, whose ascension to
the throne is accompanied by the hollow grunting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> rushing the
trough--and who, amid the cries of 'bribe-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX> to jail,' make the same pie
all over again."

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s handover of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>-administered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">442 years</TIMEX> of colonial rule was in marked contrast with the handover of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1997</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> described scenes of "unconfined joy" and "delight" at the
arrival of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Liberation Army</ENAMEX>, and according to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> , "[a]lmost everyone agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
resumption of sovereignty would help wipe out a turf war that has gripped
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX>'s gambling industry and sparked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> triad gangster killings this year
alone." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than a quarter</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> is employed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> and
gambling industries, and while gambling is illegal on the mainland, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
promise to maintain the capitalist system in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 50</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> means that gambling will most likely remain the mainstay of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>.

            

               Dawn of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
said
that now "the pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> to revert to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is likely to mount
considerably," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> reported that just before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">handover</ENAMEX> ceremonies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will speed up efforts for
reunification with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the strategy will
consist of wooing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> business groups by offering incentives for joint
ventures between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> and mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> on one hand, and "military
preparation" on the other. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All</ENAMEX>
far-sighted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world have seen, from the smooth return of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macau</ENAMEX>, that the 'one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>' policy is most appropriate and
correct and is the best approach to solving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> question." An op-ed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lee</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX>
official based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>, said there would be "no more handovers following
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau's</ENAMEX>," not least because "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> is not, and never has been, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX>
described current efforts to remove "military jargon, acronyms
and politically correct euphemisms" that crept into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> language
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 32-year</TIMEX> rule of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>. According to the piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>
were known as "socialization <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>," poverty was "pre-prosperity,"
corruption was "procedural error," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were "protected" rather than
arrested. As the old euphemisms are shed, foreign words are sometimes taking
their place, leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pramoedya Ananta Toer</ENAMEX> to conclude that "We have
returned to the colonial mentality, thinking that everything that is foreign is
more intellectual and high-minded."

         
      
   
