
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon Fever</ENAMEX>

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> issued new security warnings for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
overseas. It cautioned that those participating in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">festivities</ENAMEX> might be targeted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. Domestically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>
buckled down on airport security, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border</ENAMEX>
Patrol increased staffing at all checkpoints. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algerians</ENAMEX>--one of whom was
carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-making materials--have been arrested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last week</TIMEX> while
trying to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> illegally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. The nervous spin:
There's no safe haven from millennial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. The calm spin: Then we might
as well relax and hope for the best.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floods</ENAMEX> and mudslides devastated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 100,000</NUMEX>
are homeless and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000 to 25,000</NUMEX> are feared dead in what most are calling the
worst natural disaster in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Venezuelan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Chávez</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of being ill-prepared for the storm. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chávez</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> countered that the press was "contributing to the anguish and confusion " by speculating
about the damage without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> figures. The only bright spots: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX>
will create <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of jobs; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overpopulation</ENAMEX> will be
reduced as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> are relocated to rural areas.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s full moon appeared bigger, brighter, and longer-lasting
than any in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous 133 years</TIMEX>. The event resulted from the
rare
coincidence of three phenomena: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the moon was at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> closest
to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> was near its closest to the sun; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) it was the
winter solstice--the longest <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astronomers</ENAMEX> estimated that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moon</ENAMEX> appeared <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent to 14 percent</NUMEX> larger than normal and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
percent brighter. In Internet chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, it was hyped as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a
once-in-a-lifetime event; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) yet another reason to view <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> as
extraordinary. Astronomers demurred, comparing the visual effect to the
difference between a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100-watt and a 107-watt</NUMEX> light bulb: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Statistically</ENAMEX>, it's a
neat thing, but visually it's a dud."

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> announced stricter auto pollution
controls. The regulations will 1) make oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> reduce the sulfur
in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) require sport utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> to meet the
same emissions standards as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. The measures, which will be phased in
beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, are a compromise aimed at splitting the cost of emissions
reductions between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automakers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refineries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Environmentalists</ENAMEX>' spin: This is
the biggest clean air victory since the phaseout of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leaded gas</ENAMEX>.
Car and gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> will pay for these changes at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX>
and service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Environmentalists</ENAMEX>' counterspin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>--the added costs
will reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> even more.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vermont Supreme Court</ENAMEX> granted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> greater partnership
rights. The unanimous ruling held that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is constitutionally
required to extend to same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> the common benefits and
protections that flow from marriage under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> law." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> left it to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> to determine whether gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> will get these rights through
marriage or domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of gay rights called the decision a
"deeply disturbing" blow to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of marriage,
but they promised to limit its effects to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>. Gay rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> deemed
it a triumph of "our common humanity" that paves the way for similar rights
nationally.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> elected a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> will retain the
largest number of seats in the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>-backed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity</ENAMEX> party
made large gains. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> said the results reflected popular support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chechen war</ENAMEX>, strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> worried that
the vote signaled an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> nationalism, but they drew hope from
the increasing routineness of elections .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> made a joint appearance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>. They pledged support for campaign-finance reform and
promised to forgo unrestricted donations ("soft money") if they won their
respective nominations. The spins, in order of increasing cynicism: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> crossed a "partisan and ideological divide" for the sake of reform;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) they strengthened each other's images "as political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> who
speak their minds and could shake up the system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) they
ganged up to take pot shots at the front-runners.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> agreed to continue peace talks. The
negotiations between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farouk al-Shara</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> were the highest-level talks ever. They did not address
substantive issues but did set a schedule for discussions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> aimed at ending their 50-year-old
disputes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syria</ENAMEX> aims to win <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> withdrawal from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX>, which it
lost in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> wants official recognition from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and increased
security along its border. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Optimists</ENAMEX> said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the talks so far have achieved
their goals, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a successful accord could spread peace throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pessimists</ENAMEX> countered that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) setting a schedule wasn't much of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) both sides signaled little willingness to compromise. (See
"" for more on the talks.)

            

               
                  Peanuts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schulz</ENAMEX> is retiring. He is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>
and has colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. He said he was leaving "to focus on my health and my
family without the worry of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> deadline." The comic strip is nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and is carried by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> attributed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanuts</ENAMEX> ' enduring popularity to its gentle humor, universal themes,
and sympathetic portrayal of the "little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX> attributed it to the
strip's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> merchandising juggernaut. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cartoonists</ENAMEX> lauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX>
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Brown</ENAMEX> was
re-elected as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>,
won <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX> of the vote in a runoff election with fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supervisor Tom Ammiano</ENAMEX>. Ammiano, who would have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s first openly
gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, forced the runoff after launching a write-in campaign just three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ammiano</ENAMEX> ran on a platform of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>'
rights and reduced gentrification. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> painted him as "an inexperienced
free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spender</ENAMEX>." The gloomy liberal spin: Even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, a true liberal
can't win. The rosy liberal spin: Only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> not be
considered a true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
