
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Video</ENAMEX> Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spam the New New Thing</ENAMEX>?

            
Upstairs from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitamins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbs</ENAMEX>, at the corner of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in northwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, there's a funky little eatery
called the CyberSTOP
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe</ENAMEX>. For <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> per <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX>, you can rent time on a PC or an iMac, while you
sip an espresso and take in the zany decor (chairs upholstered in leopard skin;
a painting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Lisa</ENAMEX> holding a coffee cup). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> dropped by
with some campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in tow, trudged up a narrow
staircase, and had a campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> shoot a video with a rented digital camera
while he read a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> downloaded the video onto one
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CyberSTOP</ENAMEX> computers and e-mailed it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign. He put down
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> tip and left.

            It
was, of course, a gimmick. But all technological breakthroughs begin as
gimmicks. Does video campaign spam have a future?

            Before
answering that question, let's examine the somewhat flimsy substance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
message to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. (This won't take long.) In the video e-mail, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, with great sobriety, about an "oversight" in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign
literature concerning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> trust fund. "For my part," the flickering
image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> intoned, "I have proposed dedicating a significant portion of the
budget surplus to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> to extend the life of the trust fund." By contrast,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign literature doesn't propose similarly fencing off funds for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. "Since independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> agree that more resources will be
necessary to assure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> is strong for the future," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> continued, "my
question is, 'What specific measures do you propose to compensate for not
dedicating any of the surplus to strengthen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> trust fund?' " In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s plan to expand health coverage to uninsured
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> (which is more ambitious than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s plan) would bankrupt the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> trust fund unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> raised taxes. But the relevance of this
attack is severely compromised by the reality that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> had already
admitted he might have to raise taxes if circumstances warranted it; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
during his cybercafe appearance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> himself told reporters that "you
have to have flexibility on the fiscal side." When asked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s query,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Hauser</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was no more willing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Bradley</ENAMEX> to rule out a tax increase. (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s recent mau-mauing
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, and the strategy that lies behind it, click .)

            So
much for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. Turning to technological matters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hauser</ENAMEX> admitted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> never got around to viewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s e-mail. Neither did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hauser</ENAMEX> and
neither did anyone <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hauser</ENAMEX> knew of in the campaign (though they were familiar
with its content from reading a transcript). Apparently the video message got
lost somewhere in the maw of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign Web site. But obviously the
video wasn't really intended for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>; its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> was the national press, a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple hundred</NUMEX> of whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> received e-mail press releases with the video
attached. Thanks to its novelty, the stunt won <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> some coverage from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripps Howard</ENAMEX>, and a few other outlets.

            One
doesn't have to be a visionary to imagine where this might go. The largest
single expense that political campaigns face nowadays is TV advertising. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>,
for instance, has dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple hundred thousand</NUMEX> dollars on ads in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. Video e-mailing is much cheaper. No, wait: Make that much, much,
much cheaper. Even figuring in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> tip, the tab <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> ran up
sending his e-mail to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> probably came in at well
under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>. (It would have been even cheaper had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> been able to use the
video camera already in his personal possession, but campaign finance rules
made that too difficult.) Sending that same e-mail to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times as many people
would have cost precisely the same amount.

            For
now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign has no grand plans to start spamming unsuspecting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> with video messages. It does plan, however, to start sending video
e-mails to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have already indicated on the campaign Web site that
they'd like to receive such material. They number in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX>.
It's not too great a leap to envision that in future presidential
races--perhaps even in this one--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> will take the next step and start
buying lists of e-mail addresses so they can send targeted video messages or
advertisements. If "push" technology makes a comeback, such video ads could be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>-fed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> at large at a cost that, compared to current media
buys, would probably be microscopic. These ads probably wouldn't be as
effective as conventional TV ads--remember, most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
still aren't wired to the Internet. But they'd be so much more
cost- effective that they might still transform the way campaigns do
business.

            
               You
can watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s video by going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign site 
               and scrolling
down to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gore Sends Bradley An Email And Video Message</ENAMEX>." If you just want to
read the text, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> did, click here. 
               To read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s own spiel on health care,
go to his Web site 
               and click on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In His Own Words</ENAMEX>."
            

         
      
   
