
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stormy Weather</ENAMEX>

            
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the stock market declines in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> that were partially based on expectations of
interest-rate hikes. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on the reappointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Bank</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> said
that the move will reassure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> but questioned whether it is also "the
best news for the long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> economy." The FT
said,
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]o appoint any individual for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> term risks over-personalising the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution of the Federal Reserve Bank</ENAMEX>, and could discourage a more open
debate about policy." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> ran a front-page comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
comparing the reappointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX> tradition of
carrying in procession a statue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Protector</ENAMEX> to placate the weather.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yesterday Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> raised the blessed icon of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s central <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> against the sudden and furious storm that is sweeping
through the stock markets," it said.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> papers were more concerned with the real storm that caused huge damage
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with an
estimate that the storm will cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> economy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between 60 billion</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion French francs</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 3 percent</NUMEX> of the state budget. However, the paper
said it could also have positive effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s economic growth. According
to a report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, the storm brought down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> gardens to entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plantations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vosges Mountains</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmanuel Le Roy</ENAMEX>
Ladurie was reported as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s vast woodlands had suffered
nothing comparable since detailed records began in the reign of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XIV</ENAMEX>--"Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1660</TIMEX> at least, there has been no phenomenon on such a vast
scale."

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monde</ENAMEX> celebrated the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> anniversary of the euro, the single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
currency. "The event was historic," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> agreed to renounce their monetary sovereignty and to share it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti-European</ENAMEX> militants, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX> of all kinds had
explained for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that the project was impossible. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One year later</TIMEX>, they must
admit they were wrong: the euro exists, it has established itself as one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s great currencies and, better still, it has kept most of its
promises."

            In a
gloomy editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Times</ENAMEX> attacked the
legacy of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and questioned the merits of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>. "Everyone talks about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> as the
reform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "But the fact is, there is not a single major
reform that was not begun by [former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> and at
least slightly tarnished or rolled back under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>. And now, with this
less-than-heroic departure--immunity from prosecution tightly in hand--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
has sealed it that way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s legacy will be like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> himself,
particularly during his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX>: inarticulate, confused, self-absorbed,
weak."

            On
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Times</ENAMEX> said there is "a shocking amount of wishful
thinking masquerading as analysis." It said his record so far is "dispiriting."
He did nothing about scandals at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSB</ENAMEX> (the successor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX>) when
he was its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, and "[a]s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, his only claim to fame has been
to seize upon a truly bad situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> as an excuse to wage an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX> war, one that punishes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> in the name of protecting them." In
an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> would do anything for victory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, whatever the cost in human
lives. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> knows better than anybody that in the event of defeat--or simply
of no victory--his position could rapidly deteriorate," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> said. "So he
will do everything to win, at any cost, and whatever the number of deaths."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> added that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> "oligarchy" and will not
carry out the reforms that the West hoped for. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> will not change,
there will be no fight against corruption," he said. "Above all, the interests
and privileges of the oligarchy will be protected."

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin D. Roosevelt</ENAMEX> proposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Gaulle</ENAMEX> be ousted as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Free French movement</ENAMEX> and fobbed off with
the governorship of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madagascar</ENAMEX>, according to a report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> was reporting on secret wartime documents just
released by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Public Record Office</ENAMEX>. They show that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>
nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> could stand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Gaulle</ENAMEX>. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1943</TIMEX> "personal and most secret"
memo to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Gaulle</ENAMEX>'s attitude "well-nigh
intolerable" and accused him of stirring up vicious propaganda in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Africa</ENAMEX>
and attempting to cause strife between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algiers</ENAMEX>. When
visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> fired off a series of telegrams to his
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, proposing in one of them that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Gaulle</ENAMEX> be
"eliminated" as a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. He called the general a "vain and even
malignant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," and added, "He hates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and has left a trail of
Anglophobia behind everywhere." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> was a little kinder. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Gaulle</ENAMEX> may
be an honest man, but he has the messianic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>," he wrote.

         
      
   
