
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> Reading

            
               
                  Slate
                will be publishing
erratically for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple of weeks</TIMEX>. There seems to be some holiday going
on. The normal flood of magnificent journalism gushing from this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX> will be
reduced to a trickle, and you may want to seize this opportunity to catch up on
your 
                  Slate
                reading from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. The "
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archives"</ENAMEX> (formerly known as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Compost</ENAMEX>") is now accessible without charge,
and you can use 
                  
                     Slate
                   Search to produce a
list of articles in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> or by any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. (Of course you also can do
a normal search for occurrences of particular words.)

            We thought of providing a list of articles worth a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> look (or, for our many new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> look). But, on
reflection, we didn't want to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> break pacifying outraged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> who were left out. So we suggest that you poke around at random. Start,
if you wish, with our pre-selected list of random words beginning with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">letter M</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>

            Millennium

            Merger

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">McCain</ENAMEX>

            Money

            Or pick your own word, type it in the search window
at the bottom of this page along with "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>," and see what you get. Or go to
our search page and ask for all articles published on your
birthday. Frankly, you cannot go very wrong.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merry Christmas</ENAMEX> from all of us at

                  Slate
               . And have a nice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
