
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Maze in Grace</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: "New Age"
Isn't So New

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: Tue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan 4</TIMEX>

            
               Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraygrant</ENAMEX> wrote :
            

            

               There is a very beautiful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cathedral</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>--I believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chartres</ENAMEX>--that has a huge labyrinth on the
floor. It was covered until recently when a new, more liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bishop</ENAMEX> took over
the area. It was interesting to see something "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Agey</ENAMEX>" in such an old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX>.

            

            I have seen these old mazes on church <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> and
they are beautiful. Too bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Culturebox</ENAMEX> used the words "New Age" in the column.
If she had simply said "spirituality" then everyone would be much calmer in
their criticism.

            It seems to me that this maze idea is simply a
focusing device, like a rosary or lighting a candle, which symbolizes something
significant to us. It's just a "thing" we use to help us feel closer to God.
Why all the hub-bub?

            Personally I feel closer to God when I'm gardening
and tending "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">His" planet</ENAMEX>. Is that wrong, too?

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: Pundit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: Mon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan 3</TIMEX>

            Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>'s indisputably accurate
assessment on the effects of centralized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> labeled "self-parody"? How can the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX> hack imply that
centralized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has been a huge net plus when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> have died
directly at its hands, and when common freedoms and civic involvement have been
declining in liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX> as a direct result of this conglomeration of
power? Sounds like the usual liberal tactic of attempting (desperately) to
deride what you can't really disprove.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: Pundit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Brus

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: Tue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan 4</TIMEX>

            Obviously totalitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, both right and
left, have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. And surely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> today is too large, or at least inefficient. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX>'s new book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government's End</ENAMEX> documents
this quite well.)

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX>'s absurdity lies in linking totalitarian
programs of extermination to onerous regulations in contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. Surely there is a qualitative difference between a police state
and a sclerotic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>. (Do you really think it's just a slippery
slope from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>?)

            Remember, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> asked him to name the "greatest
catastrophes of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> responded with a
conservative buzzword ("big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>"), and tried to use real catastrophe to
further his own agenda.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            

               [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Brus</ENAMEX> writes "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" and is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraymaster</ENAMEX>.]
            

            
               Subject<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: The Dog</ENAMEX>
Who <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ate Peanuts</ENAMEX>
            

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thu Dec</ENAMEX>
30

            
               Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraygrant</ENAMEX> wrote :
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Alan Stamaty</ENAMEX> is to be
forgiven for rejecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Shepherd</ENAMEX>'s critique that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snoopy ruined Peanuts</ENAMEX>--as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stamaty</ENAMEX> has been influenced on a much deeper level by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> than
the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. I found his paean to the strip very moving.

            

            Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Caldwell</ENAMEX>, in his 
brilliant piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> Press, contends that it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX>'s "calamitous artistic misjudgment" that allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Snoopy</ENAMEX> and cuteness to
overwhelm the "left-field" magic that characterized the early strip. I think
that, once the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX> merchandizing juggernaut was well underway,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> got fat and happy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Snoopy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX>--unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>--represent the relatively banal inner life of a successful middle-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX>'s own angst disappeared, his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX>'s meaningfulness did too.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frivilous Pen</ENAMEX>

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Clark</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: Mon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan 3</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Fish</ENAMEX> is a fun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, but don't take him
too seriously. He's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> of literature--an inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gabber</ENAMEX> who
couldn't turn off his inspirations to save his life. If he wanted to, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fish</ENAMEX>
could talk <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biscuits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gravy</ENAMEX> into a thrilling subject we would all take sides
on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> is simply (!) a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talker</ENAMEX> who writes well. That's his
gift. He's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walden</ENAMEX> , who amazed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> because
while he worked hard at making baskets and blankets, and yet remained poor,
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> had only to weave arguments, and, by some magic, wealth and
standing followed." <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, and most of the rest of us are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>.

            Now, words can have powerful effects on us
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>--the more so if you have a serious talker and a serious subject. Then
again, words aren't everything (as, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish cheekily delights</ENAMEX> in pointing
out).

            Sometimes, when I read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> (his frightening
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mission Impossible</ENAMEX>" essay, for example), I get swept up by his great gift, and
am ready to move the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to the woods to avoid the end of the world. But
then I smell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX>. Ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan</ENAMEX>! It's just you and your words again!

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opening-Night Strategy</ENAMEX>
            

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Snow

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec</TIMEX>
29

            I just happened to have finished <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monster:</ENAMEX>
Living Off the Big Screen by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gregory Dunne</ENAMEX> when I read this article.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>. He makes the following point:

            The reason that opening weekend grosses are so
important is that the distributing studio bases the advertising budget on the
opening weekend grosses. Thus a feature that opens poorly doesn't get
advertised as much as one that does well. It's the criterion they use to keep
themselves from throwing money at something that is likely to fail. Although
word of mouth sometimes works, for a feature to do well in the long run it
almost always needs advertising. Thus a poor opening gross is a self-fulfilling
prediction of failure.

            
               (To reply, click here .)
            

         
      
   
