
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schulz</ENAMEX>

            The
very best comic strips, for my taste, are the magic ones. They all come from
the same place: "left field." Also known as "the blue." Or the intuition. The
other place they come from is, of course, the real world. It's a combination of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> experiences real life in some penetrating way. Then he
(or she) takes a leap into the unconscious, the dreamlike, the mysterious
within, hoping to emerge with something fresh, something original. In the best
and rarest cases, what emerges is something brilliant and enduring like
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Peanuts</ENAMEX> .

            When
it first came on the scene, it was unlike any other cartoon. It had (and has) a
powerful originality both visually and verbally. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> would set you up with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of tiny tots speaking in childlike innocence for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX>, then come
out of the wild blue yonder with one of them sounding suddenly like a
middle-aged college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> in the grip of a nervous breakdown. The
dimensions of comic-strip possibility expanded.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simplicity</ENAMEX> is its initial appeal. And openness. Innocence. It catches our eye
and draws in our psyches. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy</ENAMEX> of line with so much between the lines. A
fraught simplicity, a growing complexity, an emotional involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX>'s
deeply felt world.

            It
works because it's genuine and because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> has just the right touch of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magic</ENAMEX>. Not a bunch of schlocky gags. No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">overwrought corn</ENAMEX>. A genuine search is
going on. The comic strip has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> believes in his world and cares
about it, and so do we.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepherd</ENAMEX>, the recently deceased radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> who created magic with the spoken
word, used to berate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Snoopy</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepherd</ENAMEX> thought the whole
idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> with an imaginary life as a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>, destroyed the credibility of the strip. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepherd</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of mine. His
criticism caused me to question my own belief in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> . I took it
under consideration. I concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepherd</ENAMEX> was wrong.

            How
much leeway a comic strip can sustain, how far afield it can stretch and stray
is always a delicate balance guided by the intuition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Schulz</ENAMEX>
has great instincts. I say all of it works.

            I
especially love the nutty, out of the blue lines, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linus</ENAMEX>,
"When oak <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> get real old, they're cut down and used to make knotty-pine
recreation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>."

            That's not contrivance.
Not a hack gag. That's pure left field.

         
      
   
