
   
   
      
         
            Question the Question

            In the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> refused to answer questions as posed.
They rephrased queries, rejected scenarios, and chose options other than those
offered by the moderators. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> revise questions this way, as they
do with increasing frequency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> accuse them of "ducking." But if
someone swings a bottle at your head, what's wrong with ducking? If the answer
is fair game for scrutiny and dispute, why isn't the question?

            Think
about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> manipulate discussions of issues. They insert hidden
assumptions to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> the dialogue in their favor. They narrow the range of
options under discussion to force their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> into embarrassing dilemmas.
They frame lopsided yes/no questions and squelch attempts to articulate a
middle ground. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> use these tactics, why shouldn't they, too, be
called to account? That's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. For every artfully
framed question, they demonstrated a way to escape and counterframe it.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Reject the premise. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question of the debate went
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>. "If you had a choice between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight more years</TIMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> of a pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>," asked co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIS-TV</ENAMEX>, "which would you choose?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> replied, "I don't think that
has to be our choice. … We have to choose to stand forthrightly for the
pro-life position. … So your hypothetical is of no matter to me. We will not
face that alternative."

            A
hypothetical question is no more important than the likelihood of the scenario
it assumes. Imagine that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> were asked to choose between a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and a pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> who had pledged to appoint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> who would overturn <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> . Since no leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is pro-life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> could reasonably dismiss the question,
arguing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> is too principled to nominate a pro-lifer.
Why can't Keyes make the converse argument about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Add an option. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> question of the debate went to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX> asked, "If someone in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was raped and became
pregnant and wanted an abortion, and at the discussion with you they were
adamant in their decision to have an abortion, would you support that decision?
Or would you try to prevent it?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> replied, "If my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> or somebody
that I loved was raped, that would be the most horrible thing. … I would
comfort her. I would pray with her. I would explain to her that she couldn't
make right the terrible thing that had happened to her by taking the life of
her innocent unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. But the most important thing, sir, is not what I
would do under those circumstances, but what I would do as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. And as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> I would throw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX> in jail for a long time so <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s women
wouldn't have to worry about it."

            The
question is designed to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> choose between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terrible answers:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hypocrisy</ENAMEX> (he'd allow the abortion because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>) or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cruelty</ENAMEX> (he'd force the victim to suffer the lifelong consequences of her
rape). In his answer, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> begins by amending what he deems the less awful of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> options: He wouldn't just "prevent" the abortion, he would "comfort"
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> steps outside the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-option scenario forced
on him and argues for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> option, which he claims would prevent the
scenario. The efficacy of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> option can be debated. But until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
enlarged the question, this option wasn't even on the table.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Choose a process, not a position. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> question went
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. "A few blocks from here, on top of the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>
building, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag flies with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> flag and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> flag,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">said</ENAMEX> co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Williams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>. "The question is: Does the flag offend
you personally?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> replied, "What you're trying to get me to do is to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express the</ENAMEX> will of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> persisted, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, I'm
asking you about your personal opinion." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> elaborated, "I don't believe it's
the role of someone from outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> … to come into this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and
tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> what to do with their business when it comes
to the flag." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> repeated, "As an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, do you have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visceral</ENAMEX> reaction to seeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag?" And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> concluded, "As an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, I trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> to make the decision for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>."

            The
prolonged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> look evasive, and he was criticized afterward for
dodging the question. But why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>' formulation of the issue better than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s? Suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> were to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, "A few blocks from here,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are walking into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and receiving abortions. Does
abortion offend you personally?" And suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> were to reply, "I don't
believe it's the role of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> to go into that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> and tell those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> what to do with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. I trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> to make
that decision." Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would agree that the process <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is endorsing
(let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> decide) is more relevant than his "visceral reaction" as to
whether abortion "offends him personally." Why can't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> make the same
argument?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Insert a caveat. Halfway through the debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>
announced "a brief phase of short questions and rapid-fire answers. … We will
settle for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sentences in length, if you must. … All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> will
answer this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question. Has affirmative action made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> a better
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">nation?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> answered <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>: "Yes, but quotas have made it worse." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
answered <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>: "The idea behind affirmative action was legitimate and decent.
But when you start counting by race, you divide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, you don't bring it
together." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> answered <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>: "Only if affirmative action means equal
opportunity for everybody."

            The
question seems to demand a yes/no answer. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> reply with
"but" and "only if." This kind of qualification is often ridiculed as
evasiveness by those who demand "no ifs, ands, or buts." But why is a policy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ifs</ENAMEX> and buts worse than a policy of no ifs and buts? Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> prefer
a morality of ifs and buts, and most real-life laws and regulations are riddled
with ifs and buts. Affirmative action in particular cries out for such moral
and legal nuance. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> really needed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> on this
question were longer answers, not shorter ones. For example, what does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
mean by "equal opportunity"?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Change the question. By the time the affirmative action
question got to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Keyes</ENAMEX>, it was being completely rewritten.
"It may be more important to ask whether it's helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it was supposed
to help," he began. "And I think it has actually hurt them by damaging the
reputation of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and not giving them credit for
their real achievements."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>'
answer didn't precisely address the question, but which was more interesting
and enlightening? When the question is more specific than the answer, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> can be accused of evasion. But what's wrong with an answer that's
more specific than the question? Keyes wasn't ducking the pitch. He was tossing
back a weak, hanging slider and demanding a fastball so he could hit it
harder.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Reject the topic. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few minutes</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Trotter</ENAMEX>, a
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gentlemen</ENAMEX>, I'm curious. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>,
what is the biggest mistake that you've made, and what lesson did you learn
from it?" The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> booed, and when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotter</ENAMEX> was asked to repeat the question,
she rephrased it: "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> are curious. On a personal note, what is the
biggest mistake you made as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>, and what lesson did you learn from
it?"

            Others
answered the question, but Keyes stuffed it. "The biggest mistake I might make
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> would be to treat that as if it's a question that is appropriate to
be asked," he said. "There ought to be in our public life a certain decorum, a
certain dignity. There are things that I'll tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> in the confessional
that I will not tell you or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>." However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> added, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In</ENAMEX>
terms of what I think we believe to be relevant for the purposes of running for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> … maybe the biggest mistake I had made in my public life … was
not to have spoken out on the issue of the right of the unborn before I
did."

            Keyes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overreacted</ENAMEX>, but his answer illustrated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> lessons. First, sometimes the
propriety or significance of a question is a more important and instructive
topic than the question itself. Whether the question was improper can be
debated--as it turned out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>' comments about his "mistake" on abortion were
more interesting than his comments about the question--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> benefited
from considering both.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, challenging questions is a healthy way to hold the press accountable.
Questions are instruments of power. Who gets to choose them? <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotter</ENAMEX>
changed her question after the crowd booed her. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> she said, "I'm curious."
Then she said, "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> are curious." Obliged to account for her question,
she appealed to the notion of a popular mandate. Whether her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>
wanted her to ask that question can be checked. What questions should be asked,
why they should be asked, and who gets to choose them are now open <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> for
scrutiny.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, even if the
question was really about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>' public life, he ended up answering it.
Believing that it was framed too personally, he didn't just dismiss it. He
reframed it the way he thought it should have been asked, and he answered it.
Questions don't have to be answered with a yes or no. Neither does the question
of whether to answer them.

         
      
   
