
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vouching Toward Gore</ENAMEX>

            Toward
the end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> debate, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> had called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health-care proposal a "voucher" plan for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
finally woke up and smelled the danger. "They're not vouchers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
protested. "It is not vouchers. The health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> doesn't have vouchers."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, in their debate on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> elaborated:
"There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> who get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>. They are
all left out under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s plan because he eliminates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> and
replaces it with little <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150-</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a-month</TIMEX> vouchers." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> fired back immediately.
"That's wrong," he insisted. "It's not a voucher."

            The
"voucher" debate represents the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and decisive stage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
presidential contest. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> stage, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> tried to put his best
issues on the agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> pushed suburban sprawl, health care, and education.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> pushed gun control, health care, and campaign reform. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> got one
of his issues on the agenda--campaign reform for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, education for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--plus the issue on whose importance they agreed: health care. In the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> stage, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> fought for the high ground on those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> issues.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> won the high ground on education by proposing a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115 billion</NUMEX> school aid
package while portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> as a voucher sympathizer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> won the high
ground on campaign reform by offering a comprehensive reform plan while teaming
up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> against a fund-raising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> whose corruption <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">helpfully</ENAMEX> traced to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> stage is the battle over the remaining issue: health care. Each candidate
is trying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshal</ENAMEX> his assets on this battleground by building a thematic
bridge to it from the issue he is already winning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is trying to carry
his message of comprehensive reform from campaign finance to health care. He
proposes to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> with subsidies that would make health insurance
affordable to more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but would require those with sufficient incomes to
pay part of their premiums out of their own pockets.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, is trying to carry his message of public responsibility from
education to health care. He wants to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, by
substituting partial subsidies for guaranteed benefits, would gut the public
health-care system as well as the public education system. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> succeeds in
linking the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> issues this way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> will lose the health-care debate, and
with it the nomination. That's why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has distilled this linkage to a single
word--"vouchers"--and why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is fighting to extinguish that word with such
fury.

            In the
context of education, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has defined the word "voucher" in two negative ways.
First, vouchers are a zero-sum game. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> sees it, every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> spent on them
comes out of funds previously allocated to a fully subsidized program.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Experience</ENAMEX> shows there's a set amount of money that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> have been
willing to spend on education," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> argued on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . "If you
drain the money away from the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for private vouchers, then that
hurts the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, vouchers don't cover the cost of the program
they replace. "The flaw with the voucher theory," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, "is that the vast
majority of those who receive a tiny little down payment on the tuition cannot
afford the rest of it."

            Having
packed these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> poisonous assumptions into the word "voucher," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is now
injecting that poison into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health-care proposal by applying the same
word to both contexts. "Every single time vouchers came up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>,
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX>, you voted for them. Now you're proposing vouchers in place of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> capped at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> charged on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> . "You
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">canceled Medicaid</ENAMEX> and give people <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> vouchers to try to replace it. … If we
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cancel Medicaid</ENAMEX> and substitute little vouchers capped at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>,
there's not a single plan available here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> that you can get for
anything approximating the cap in this plan." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> expects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of health insurance subsidies to "buy into the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> benefit plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent of all the health insurance
plans that are part of [that] plan have premiums that are far in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>."

            The
"voucher" attack has at least made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s ideological position coherent. For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> vacillated between calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> a liberal budget-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buster</ENAMEX> and
calling him a crypto-Reaganite menace to federal entitlements. Now that
question is settled: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> from the left. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will defend
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and other government-guaranteed programs. He will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuse Bradley</ENAMEX> of threatening to replace these programs with risky and
inadequate "voucher" schemes. And he will direct this argument to specific
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> such as senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>, and labor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>.

            What's
not yet clear is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> will accept this arrangement. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press , he challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s leftist dogma against school vouchers: "If
[voucher] experiments demonstrated that the quality of public education was
improved, does that mean that you would not even consider vouchers<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" Then he
scoffed that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX> proposes an education program" that "comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>."
Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> refused to cede the left to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. Rather than defend the idea of
substituting vouchers for government control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> insisted that
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> options are compatible. "Every time I voted for vouchers, I voted for
it as an experimental basis," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. "And I also said that I would not
take any public money that was set aside for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. This would be new
money."

            
Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> refuses to defend the mildly libertarian position <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has
assigned him on health care. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> could affirm that his subsidies for health
insurance don't cover the entire cost of premiums. He could argue that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> ought to bear responsibility for paying a portion of their
premiums. Or he could simply argue that the amount of money the government
takes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> to subsidize health care should be limited. He could, in
short, embrace and defend the idea of vouchers.

            
Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> repudiates the word. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , he insisted
that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> he allots to each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> insurance premium is "not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX>. It's a weighted average." In a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Memo to National Reporters</ENAMEX>" after the
debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign drove home the point: "THE <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">BRADLEY PLAN</ENAMEX> IS SUPPORT
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOR HEALTH INSURANCE</ENAMEX>, NOT 'VOUCHERS.' " Calling the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> a "cost estimate," the
memo provided dictionary definitions of "subsidy" and "voucher," indicating
that vouchers are explicitly finite whereas subsidies are not. The implication
of these caveats is that if universal health insurance turns out to cost even
more than the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65 billion</NUMEX> a year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has allotted to it, the government
will tax and spend more to cover the difference.

            
Listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s equivocal remarks on school vouchers, and looking at the
sliding scale of subsidies and tax breaks he proposes for health insurance, you
get the feeling he's rather sympathetic toward solutions that take account of
market dynamics. You get the feeling that this sympathy is what he's hiding
behind noncomittal words such as "cost estimates" and "weighted averages." You
wonder whether he could win a general election coming out of the right lane of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. But first he has to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination, a race
he has clearly decided he can't win in that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX>.

            In a way, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
fault. On <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">firearms</ENAMEX> and campaign finance, he defined reform as government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. He thought he could pass <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> on the left. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> cut him
off--and now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can't connect his campaign-finance crusade, under the
rubric of reform, to his challenges to existing welfare-state policies on
health and education. Every time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> utters the word "vouchers," he's bumping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> closer to the right edge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. It's going to be a short race if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> won't bump back.

         
      
   
