
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shostakovich Joins</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mickey Mouse Club</ENAMEX>

            
               Movies

            

            

               
                  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fantasia/2000</NUMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Sixty</NUMEX> years
after the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney</ENAMEX>'s film of cartoons set to classical music,
this updated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMAX</ENAMEX> version introduces new sequences as well as a remastered
version of the original's famous "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sorcerer's Apprentice</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
are nearly unanimous: The sequel falls short but is "splendid entertainment"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nonetheless</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). The presence of "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorcerer</ENAMEX>'s Apprentice" only underlines how much better the original was. The
highlight of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> is a rendering of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Christian Andersen</ENAMEX>'s story
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Steadfast Tin Soldier" to Dmitri Shostakovich's Piano Concerto No.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . A few sniff at the new production: "The difference between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fantasia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fantasia/2000</ENAMEX> is the difference between a dialogue
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Paar</ENAMEX> and a brisk 'interview' with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Letterman</ENAMEX>, between reading a
book and answering questions posed by a CD-ROM" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Horowitz</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to visit the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denzel Washington</ENAMEX>
delivers a knockout performance as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin "Hurricane" Carter</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX> who spent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> in jail for a crime he did not commit. But the rest of the film pales
in comparison: It's "fairly standard middle-of-the-road fare, simplistic,
conventional, and, when the camera is not focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, lacking in
things to hold our attention" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). On
balance, the film works: It may be "as blatantly manipulative as a pep rally,"
but "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington</ENAMEX> leans into an otherwise schlocky movie and slams it out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s story.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galaxy Quest</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks Distribution</ENAMEX>). This gentle
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Trek</ENAMEX> spoof strikes a chord; it's "a fast, loose, and very funny
parody that pulls off the not-so-simple feat of tweaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trekkies</ENAMEX> and honoring
them" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The film's premise: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> from a long-canceled space show get "spacejacked by
naive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> in need of protection" who mistook the program for a historical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">document</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). The result is campy, goofy, and
"funny without being flip" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Kempley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to read an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigourney Weaver</ENAMEX> about her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in the movie.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tha Doggfather</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trials</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardcore Truths</ENAMEX> of Snoop
Dogg
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snoop Dogg</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davin Seay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William Morrow</ENAMEX>). Good
reviews, for the most part, for the autobiography of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of hip-hop's most
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>: "An amusing, contemplative memoir" that paints "a
surprisingly humanistic portrait" of the crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> turned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">platinum</ENAMEX>-selling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">musician</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkus Reviews</ENAMEX> ). The tales of his misspent youth and rise to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fame</ENAMEX> are "eloquently told" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Harris</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). One
reviewer splits from the pack and delivers a withering pan: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he ability to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> a lot of records has almost nothing to do with insight or maturity. …
[I]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ts author</ENAMEX> is seemingly incapable of self-examination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">…</ENAMEX> [H]e retreats behind
religious platitudes, empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sloganeering</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-truths." His coup de
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grâce</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists</ENAMEX> asserted that rap was the voice of urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and that it
should not be silenced. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tha Doggfather</ENAMEX> offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> pages of evidence to
the contrary" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ta-Nehisi Coates</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Book World</ENAMEX> ).
(This site includes
news, audio clips, and a discography for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snoop Dogg</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Book of Communism: Crimes, Terror</ENAMEX>,
Repression
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stéphane Courtois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Werth</ENAMEX>, Jean-Louis
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panné</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrzej Paczkowski</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karel Bartosek</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean-Louis Margolin</ENAMEX>; translated
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Murphy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Kramer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University Press</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> stand in
awe of this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX>-page enumeration and exploration of the crimes committed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regimes</ENAMEX> around the globe: "an extraordinary and almost unspeakably
chilling book … enormously impressive and utterly convincing" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Scammell, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ). Published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, it
immediately created a stir, drawing criticism from the left and becoming an
unexpected best seller. The book is not easy to read: "To the extent that the
book has a literary style, it is that of the recording angel. … It is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> indictment, and it rightly reads like one" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Ryan</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Review</ENAMEX> ). No one questions that communism was immensely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">destructive</ENAMEX> (the book estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between 85 million</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100 million</NUMEX> people
were killed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regimes</ENAMEX>). What causes more of a stir is the book's
assertion that "given the nature and the magnitude of the crimes committed in
its name, communism was fully the equal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazism</ENAMEX> as one of the supreme evils
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our century</TIMEX>" and the question it raises of whether "the history of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twentieth century</ENAMEX> hasn't given us objective and final proof … that human nature
itself is fallen and twisted at its core" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scammell</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
read about the book's reception when it was published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
