
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespearean Follies</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rusty Shakespeare</ENAMEX>

            
               From: 
               Guatam Makunda
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thu Dec</ENAMEX>
23

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX> needs
to brush up on her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> as well, I'm afraid. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluellen</ENAMEX>'s statement in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Act IV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scene VII</ENAMEX> is, in full:

            Kill the poys and the
luggage! 'tis expressly
against the law of arms: 'tis an arrant a piece of
knavery, mark you now, as can be offert; in your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conscience</ENAMEX>, now, is it not?

            To this statement <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gower</ENAMEX>,
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>, replies:

            'Tis certain there's
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> left alive; and
the cowardly rascals that ran from the battle <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha</NUMEX>' done
this slaughter: besides, they have burn'd and
carried away all that was in the king's tent;
wherefore the king, most worthily, hath caused every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> to cut his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>'s throat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>, 'tis a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gallant king</ENAMEX>!

            This then prompts an extended comparison on the
part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluellen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander the Great</ENAMEX>. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluellen</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condemnation</ENAMEX> was for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> slaughter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baggage</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>--a slaughter conducted, apparently, by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who fled
the battle. This is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fluellen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gower</ENAMEX> think provoked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>'s command
to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, and both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> fully approve of that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">command</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Keegan</ENAMEX>'s excellent book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Face of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> also looks at the issue and concludes that his command was well
within the norms of warfare for the period. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> is, in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s
archetype of the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hero-King</ENAMEX> precisely because of his Machiavellian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">qualities</ENAMEX> (which certainly are present)--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> understands, as he explains
during his tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agincourt</ENAMEX>, that the moral demands upon a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> are very different from those upon ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rusty Shakespeare</ENAMEX>

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
Shulevitz

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:  ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tue Dec</ENAMEX>
28

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guatam Makunda</ENAMEX> has a point. I did misread the
passage. But he (or she) is wrong to conclude that I thereby vitiate my larger
argument.

            First things first. I stand corrected: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluellen</ENAMEX> is
in fact referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> slaughter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>. But I submit
that there's a good reason for my having misread the text on the fly.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluellen</ENAMEX>'s remark follows immediately <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>'s order to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to kill their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, which would have scared anybody in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> who knows
anything about war: The side whose captured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> have been murdered
invariably retaliates by killing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> it has captured, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> ordered
to slit their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>' throats understood that. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
means for us to confuse the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> for a moment, until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gower</ENAMEX> replies and
we know where we are.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluellen</ENAMEX> does not then go on to compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander the Great</ENAMEX>, exactly. Fluellen, in the great tradition of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespearean Fool</ENAMEX>, uses the comparison to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> out to be an ass.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluellen</ENAMEX> first compares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry to Alexander the Pig</ENAMEX> , is corrected by
Gower, defends his malapropism, then goes on to say that the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexander</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> are alike is they both kill their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>! (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>, of course, killed
Falstaff metaphorically by cutting him to the quick.) Obviously, we are meant
to laugh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluellen</ENAMEX>'s nonsense, but still. When a Shakespearean fool mocks a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">king</ENAMEX>, intentionally or not, we have to sit up and take notice.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keegan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Face of Battle</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guatam Makunda</ENAMEX> inadvertently makes my point for me: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keegan</ENAMEX> would not have had
to weigh in if there wasn't a raging debate about the rightness or wrongness of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>'s actions.

            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> the archetype of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hero</ENAMEX>, Machiavellian
or otherwise? I would argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> did not create archetypes. He
created <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. Indeed, he may have created Character itself. What makes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespearean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is his roundedness, his moral complexity, his good
sides and his evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>, all mixed in. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX> puts it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
more or less invented our modern notions of psychology. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> all good? Hell
no. Is he all bad? No, not really, but he's out there, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> knew it.
My point was simply that he's not an exemplary role model, and it's ridiculous
for business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> had handed them a road map to
the unproblematic exercise of power.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moneybox</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faulty Logic</ENAMEX>

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas</ENAMEX>
Dogood

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec</TIMEX>
22

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moneybox</ENAMEX> thinks the stock market doesn't reflect
the health of the overall economy because "just" <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> own
stock. Using this reasoning, and bearing in mind that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929 less than 10</TIMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> owned stock, we may be assured that the crash of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'29</NUMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX> were only coincidental and not causally linked. Uh
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">huh</ENAMEX>.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: A Trifling
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> Trillion

            
               From: gbh

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec</TIMEX>
22

            The net worth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> household sector has
increased by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close to $20 trillion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX>. If the "wealth
effect" still follows the rule of thumb outlined by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moneybox</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 cents</NUMEX> in
consumer spending for every dollar of wealth created in the stock market--that
means a boost to consumption of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 trillion</NUMEX>. That would account for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about a</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of nominal GDP growth over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX>. Sounds pretty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consequential</ENAMEX> to me. Plus when you consider that the savings out of income is
close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, the old <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> number is undoubtedly low.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: What
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times Scandal</ENAMEX>?

            
               From: 
               Epicurus
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec</TIMEX>
22

            Chatterbox, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shaw</ENAMEX> in his interminable
piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> 
               Times , never makes it clear why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revenue-sharing</ENAMEX> arrangement between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> was such an
egregious violation of journalistic ethics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumb</ENAMEX>, maybe (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> points
out), but where is the attack on integrity? The ad side of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> is
constantly trying to get the ed side to say nice things about those
advertising. In this case, though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> in the "special issue" of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX>. And the
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> were never pressured to do puff pieces.

            Yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , almost unwittingly, was an
instrument for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> to engage in a kickback scheme--i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> leaned on
contractors and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> to pony up for ads for which they got some return. But
this breach is more an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> was on the hook for
support already. But again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> were free to write what they wanted, so
why is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> there so exercised (which they became only after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> started knocking their conduct)?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more point: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> says the LAT
participated in a bad business deal. Perhaps. But he should take into account
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also has a corporate commitment to downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> and that
through its continuing expansion, the paper as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> would benefit.
Enlightened self-interest and all that.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free</ENAMEX>
It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> !

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
Gebert

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tue Dec</ENAMEX>
28

            Your discussion of the copyright status of It's
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> is correct enough, but I think you're wrong to regard the
current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic Pictures</ENAMEX> copyright (rooted in its underlying copyright of the
musical score) as a settled legal concept. It's true no one has challenged
it--but would you want to be the station <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in Provo
who took on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s exclusive rights in court? In fact, the seemingly farfetched
act you suggest would liberate the movie. Removing the music track is not so
farfetched at all; the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Affair</ENAMEX> has been released on
video with its score replaced for exactly that reason. Surely It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> would be even more worth the trouble, if any video
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distributor</ENAMEX> thought they could do it without immediately facing a battalion of
high-priced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.

            This same legal gambit has been used for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in
the world of classic film distribution. When the balance of power among public
and private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> was fairly even, the private copyright never stood up for
very long. A famously shady and litigious film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> once tried to gain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control of</ENAMEX>, among other things, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.W. Griffith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birth of a Nation</ENAMEX>
(long since public domain) by buying up the rights to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Dixon</ENAMEX> novels
it was loosely based on; he was pretty much laughed away by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>.

            
               (To reply, click here .)
            

         
      
   
