
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of Dimness

            What an apocalypse we're
having! First a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairdresser</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stigmata</ENAMEX> collapses on a crowded
dance floor as an invisible crown of thorns is pounded into her head. Then a
lurching demon made of excrement materializes out of an overflowing toilet bowl
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dogma</ENAMEX> . And now, just in time to prove that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the millennium</TIMEX>
will indeed bring about the destruction of all movie logic, we have End of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> , in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX> pauses by a stoop, unzips his pants, and lets flow a
meandering stream of flammable urine. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casper Van Dien</ENAMEX> puts it rather
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">succinctly</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">The Omega Code</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religion</ENAMEX> would have us believe there are
demons fighting and battling over our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>. But who needs that?"

            And anyway, these
millennial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX> are a particularly clumsy lot, far less canny and elegant
than, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cassavetes</ENAMEX>, whose earthly weapon of
choice was spiked chocolate mousse. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">The Omega Code</ENAMEX> , for instance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael York's Antichrist</ENAMEX> has seeming command of all the law enforcement
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> in the world, but none of them can locate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Casper Van Dien</ENAMEX>--playing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Age</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> who has run off with a CD that will unlock "the genetic code of
the universe"--as he flees conspicuously on foot through the empty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in the dead of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forces of Darkness</ENAMEX> are so powerless that
they're reduced to hanging around their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, listening to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">befuddled Los Angeles</ENAMEX> cops on a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scanner</ENAMEX>.

            In keeping with our apostate times, all these movies
feature as their protagonist a faith-challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chosen One</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Omega</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Code , Van Dien</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, "the world-famous globe-trotting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gillen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane</ENAMEX>," cringes when somebody sings "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jesus Loves Me</ENAMEX>." "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> used to sing me
that song," he explains, "but you know what? She died in a tragic car accident
when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years old</TIMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stigmata</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Arquette</ENAMEX> plays a
frenetic party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, who, of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world, is judged to be the
best candidate for mouthing lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aramaic</ENAMEX> scriptures as unseen nails are
hammered into her appendages. ("You don't get it, do you?" she yells at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> during a lull in these proceedings, "I have fucking holes through my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wrists</ENAMEX>!") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Fiorentino</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dogma</ENAMEX> , has lost her faith over her
inability to conceive, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of Days</ENAMEX> , is
so distressed over the murders of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that he is reduced to
making smoothies out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepto-Bismol</ENAMEX> and leftover <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>.

            OK, God works in
mysterious ways, but it is the opinion of this column that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> should
not. There is a big difference between divine obfuscation and sloppy thinking.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stigmata</ENAMEX> , for instance, an unquiet dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> is desperate to notify
the world of a suppressed "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> gospel," which, when revealed, will expose the
greed and false pretenses of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. This restless spirit
has the power to cause steam vents to erupt and windows to explode in showers
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>. He can give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Arquette</ENAMEX> the stigmata and make her eyes turn red
and have her speak in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s voice in ancient languages and send her spiraling
aloft in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> until she ends up crucified in midair. What he can't do,
though, is just come out and say what's on his mind.

            His poor communication skills are mirrored by the
geographically impaired <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Satan of End of Days</ENAMEX> . It is the murky premise of
this movie that evil is not quite as renewable a resource as is commonly
believed. In order for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dark Angel</ENAMEX> to continue his important work in human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX>, he must appear on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every thousand years</TIMEX> to impregnate a young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of Days the devil</ENAMEX> is first seen as a transparent watery
wrinkle that rises out of a manhole and sashays into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurant</ENAMEX>, whereupon it makes a forcible entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of a prominent
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Byrne</ENAMEX>.

            Wearing his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX> sets forth in search of
the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with whom he must "breed" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine York</ENAMEX>, and she was chosen for this gruesome
task on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of her birth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years earlier</TIMEX>, when she was seized from her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">satanic nurse</ENAMEX> and given a quickie baptism
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rattlesnake blood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine</ENAMEX> is also being hunted by an ecclesiastical hit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squad</ENAMEX> named the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican Knights</ENAMEX>, which wants to drive a stake through her heart
before she can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>, and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jericho Cane</ENAMEX>, who just
wants to save her. In search of his beloved, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX> takes time to visit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>
in his hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> is named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Aquinas</ENAMEX>--not, disappointingly,
the reincarnated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summa Theologica</ENAMEX> but some old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geezer</ENAMEX> who has
cut out his own tongue and put it in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mayonnaise jar</ENAMEX> for reasons that it would
take a second viewing of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of Days</ENAMEX> for me to figure out. (Not in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millennium</ENAMEX>!)

            Working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nimbly</ENAMEX>, Satan
carves up this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s torso with arcane writing and, using scalpels and scissors
and other handy hospital accessories, crucifies him on the ceiling. (How strong
is that acoustic tile, anyway?) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the phrases on poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Aquinas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>," which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jericho</ENAMEX>, coming upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> shortly thereafter,
quickly deciphers to mean "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine York</ENAMEX>," the name of the mother-to-be. Two
problems: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) nobody 's that good at hermeneutics; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) why would the
archfiend, who's in a big hurry to consummate his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine</ENAMEX>
before the ball drops in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX>, interrupt his mission to leave clues for
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX> is good at many things in this movie. He can pee
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>, walk through fire, induce visions, and even resurrect the dead, but
when it comes to the simple task of locating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine</ENAMEX>--which everyone else
seems to be able to do with relative ease--he's so helpless he has to break
into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jericho</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and badger him for her whereabouts.

            It's no wonder that Good triumphs over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>, because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX> makes a lot of bad choices in this movie. Dogma at least has some
fun with the idea that God is really <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alanis Morissette</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael York</ENAMEX> in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Omega Code</ENAMEX> is as cheerful an antichrist as one could wish for, but
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of Days</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX> is finally revealed in his true form, erupting
out of the floor of a cathedral to confront <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>, guess what he is. A
giant frustrated-looking bat that roars and slobbers and flails its wings
around like a baby <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> that's not ready to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX>. With a hopeless bod
like that, it's no surprise that the devil would rather look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrne</ENAMEX>. And if movies get any stupider <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next millennium</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of Days</ENAMEX>
can't come soon enough for me.

         
      
   
