
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candidates Cagey</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX> Issues

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Records</ENAMEX> show former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> collected more campaign funds in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Valley</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third quarter of last year</TIMEX> than any other presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> also netted more contributions over the
Internet than anyone else, surpassing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX>.

            But
where does he stand on the issues that are of importance to the growing number
of Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who depend on cyberspace? And, furthermore, will
it matter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>?

            While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has been mum on some of the key Internet topics, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are
betting that digital issues will matter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, started taking out campaign ads touting his support for permanently
extending a moratorium on Internet taxes and protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pornography</ENAMEX> and other online content. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is betting that some of the
growing number of Internet policy issues will resonate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. (He's
pushing his anti-tax messages in tax-free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-porn</ENAMEX> ad has
been airing in conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> agree that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> contest is a new frontier. Never before in the
history of presidential politics have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> felt the pressure to adopt a
high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, speak out about protecting privacy over the Internet, or
sign a pledge vowing they will forever oppose Internet taxes. Though, clearly,
none of these issues yet ranks with election-deciding topics such as economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, war, or tax cuts.

            "We
believe that Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are the soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
Nehring, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of national campaigns for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform</ENAMEX>, which
asked all presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to sign a declaration opposing any Internet
taxes. "Just as soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> everyone was trying to reach
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> election, Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">users</ENAMEX> will play the same role <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>."

            The
Internet tax issue is a complicated one. It pits the interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">dot-com</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that don't want to be burdened by collecting taxes on behalf of some
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,500</NUMEX> different sales-taxing jurisdictions against the interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and
municipalities that rely on revenues to fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, law enforcement, and
public works projects. A congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> is expected to recommend a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> policy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. There are essentially <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> options: Ban sales taxes
on Internet purchases, leave the status quo (in which case it only matters
where the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is located), or give states the ability to go after
sales taxes from out-of-state Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> have signed the
no-tax pledge, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s campaign has indicated he will also sign. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> has declined. While he favors a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-to-five-year</TIMEX>
extension of the current moratorium, he wants to await the recommendations of
the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> have
also declined to sign the pledge. Both have said publicly that they want to
await the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s report and that they are also concerned about the
potential drain on state and local tax revenues if a ban on Internet sales
taxes is made permanent.

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> supports finding a solution to these issues that allows the
Internet and e-commerce to flourish without stripping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and localities of
their ability to educate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and fight crime," said an administration
official. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign declined to comment.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nehring</ENAMEX> predicted the issue could unite a block of Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>: "It's a
galvanizing force that will serve to activate Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> on a political
issue."

            But
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> disagree that any Internet issues will sway the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> at
large. "The issue of export controls on encryption technologies, or even the
tax issue, is not broad-based enough," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Cornfield</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graduate School of Political Management</ENAMEX>. "One
possible exception is if there's a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'privacy</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chernobyl</ENAMEX>.' If there is some
disaster involving a lot of peoples' privacy, that is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> issue where the
Internet would be on the agenda on a mass level. … If that happened, I think
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> would be forced to take a position on the issue."

            
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> already have taken public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> or made statements about
whether or not they believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> needs to ensure that consumer
privacy isn't violated by online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Statements from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> indicate they favor holding off on any general privacy
legislation to allow industry to "self-regulate" by posting privacy policies
and developing guidelines to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> understand how their
personally identifying information will be used. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, with
the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, who hasn't yet taken a stand, also say that certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>, including medical and financial information, should be protected by
legislation. The privacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 13</TIMEX> is already protected under
federal law. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, in a speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Future of Privacy</ENAMEX>,"
went further, saying he would shut down all federal medical databases and end
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> "as we know it" by imposing a simplified flat
tax.

            Not
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are closing the door on more general privacy protection
legislation in the future. "For the current period, we believe industry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-regulation</ENAMEX> is the way to go," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Adams</ENAMEX>, a technology policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>. "But we don't rule out regulation in the future if
industry fails to do a good job of policing itself."

            
Privacy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> say they believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are supporting industry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-regulation</ENAMEX> in order to appeal to industry interests, as opposed to the
general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. "Privacy could clearly be one of the critical issues of the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> campaign of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Rotenberg</ENAMEX>, executive
money is in self-regulation, a lot of the votes will be with legislation."

            The
pursuit of contributions from the high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is one of the reasons
that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have gone to great lengths to develop a high-tech
platform. The problem is that in order to appeal to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX>, many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have adopted postures that are eerily alike. Most of the major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> favor loosening export restrictions on encryption policy. Most favor
an international ban on tariffs on Internet purchases and services. Most favor
forgoing federal regulation at this time in favor of allowing the marketplace
to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> have a choice of Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> for
high-speed Internet services.

            Where
some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> differ is in support of federal efforts to bridge the
"digital divide." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> camp rightly takes credit for fighting for a federal
surcharge on telephone service, with the funds going to help wire public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> for Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> labeled the
program "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> tax," but even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> supports the program, although his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> say he might make some changes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, would
repeal the surcharge, which has helped provide wiring and Internet service for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> to date. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, publicly
criticized the program, saying it "will fail to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> the
level of funding they had been led to expect. It will fail to stop the
inexcusable waste of money on the fund's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. And it will fail to
keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>'s bills from going up yet again."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> camp clearly believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will be swayed by his
support of efforts to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> away from online pornography and other
potentially offensive Internet content. He's tapped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey Graham</ENAMEX> to stump for him in an ad running through a laundry list of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s accomplishments, including his fight against Internet porn. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has
been an ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> of the controversial Child <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Online Protection Act</ENAMEX>,
which seeks to criminalize Web sites that "knowingly" make harmful material
available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>. The act is currently under consideration by a federal
appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. He's also proposed legislation that would mandate filtering
software for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> that receive federal funds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
campaign says it would support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> filtering bill, which has not yet
become law.

            
Another issue that has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> staking out positions is the prosecution of
antitrust charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corp.</ENAMEX> This is also an issue on which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> campaign has taken a different position from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> has chided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for pursuing the case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, who hauled Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing, has been raising campaign funds from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
at some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> cited a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s recent ruling that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has a monopoly in desktop personal computer operating system software
as a victory for the little guy. Most of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have tried to
tread the middle ground: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> have said they will stay
silent on the issue because it is a legal matter and up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, not the
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>,
during a highly publicized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> campus, told
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> he wouldn't discuss the case. But he did say, "If competition is
valuable, which I think it is, then antitrust laws have a place in embodying
the values of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. If dominance in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area is used to prevent that
competition in another area, that's wrong."

            Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> say
they are convinced that Internet issues will matter this time around. "Internet
issues are going to be extremely important," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Berman</ENAMEX>, executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Democracy and Technology</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> could very well become very concerned about privacy, protecting kids
from bad stuff on the Net, preventing fraud on the Net, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">…</ENAMEX> and protecting the
free flow of information both here and abroad."

         
      
   
