
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=630250921-01071999><EM>TNR</EM><ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'s Man of the Millennium</ENAMEX></SPAN>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 19</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover profile admires <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>'s steely determination
to make peace. The unpretentious ex-general acts as "the national tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>."
He set an ambitious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-month</TIMEX> timetable for solving the centuries-old
Arab-Israeli conflict and back-burnered domestic issues to keep on schedule.
… A profile of auteur <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Thomas Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">new Magnolia</ENAMEX> , applauds his artistry and moxie. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX>
showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of camera movement and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> development.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> shepherded his new film into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> without letting it be dumbed
down, proving that he can protect his work from rank <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commercialism</ENAMEX>.
… An article exposes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>'s long-forgotten race
riots. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> were killed when white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> deputized a bloodthirsty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lynch mob</ENAMEX>. A state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> is finally
investigating the disturbance.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 3</TIMEX>
            

            A
millennium parody issue. … A faux-profile picks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millennium</ENAMEX>: "With his cartwheeling intellect and generous heart; with his
revolutionary brain and conservative gut ... this epoch has belonged to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith 'Dick</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX>." … A piece honors nachos as the emblematic
invention of the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thousand years</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Producing</ENAMEX> penicillin may be beyond the
mental faculties of the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>, but melting things isn't. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">…</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">achos</ENAMEX> are
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX> that unites us." … The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> also includes a
helpful list of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top Ten Stain-Removing Tips of the Millennium</ENAMEX>."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 18</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story pegged to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s parliamentary elections
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> is not in terrible shape. The crackdown on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> has swelled
the popularity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s flailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> remains robustly pluralistic. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> will probably retain a
plurality in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX>, and "reformist views may be more strongly represented."
… An article earnestly questions whether irony is eroding the
national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of post-imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>: "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of yore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superiority</ENAMEX> was proven by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. Now the point is made with a joke, and
a quiet, knowing smile." … A survey cheers the globalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>. The "best wines
of the new world can match or even surpass the great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> of the old world."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vintners</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX> now solicit the advice of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20</TIMEX>
            

            The
chilling cover photo, taken from a surveillance videotape, shows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">killers Dylan Klebold</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Harris</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> during the massacre. The
cover story reveals the contents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>' homemade
videotapes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> called his sawed-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene</ENAMEX>," after a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in
the video game <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doom</ENAMEX>, and boasted that his plan was better than those of
previous school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooters</ENAMEX>: "Not like those f___s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> with camouflage and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">.22s." Klebold</ENAMEX> hoped to kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on what he called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Judgement Day</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klebold</ENAMEX> predicted: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> will be fighting over this story," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX>
hoped for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX>. The sickest detail: When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Bernall</ENAMEX> hiding under a desk, he leaned down, said
"peek<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-a-boo</ENAMEX>," then shot her.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story names ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>."
In the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Century of the Common Man</ENAMEX>" democracy "became the norm" and " 'elite'
became a dirty word." A clunky <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-pager summarizes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> in thick
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">newsweekly</ENAMEX>-ese: "The overarching theme of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century's first half</TIMEX> was the rise
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state power</ENAMEX>. … The theme of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century's second half</TIMEX> was liberation."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "" of a generic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> deflates the genre.)
… A portfolio compiles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>'s best cartoons and quotes.
… An article explains how the stock market could have risen even
though the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard & Poor's</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> has lost
ground: Enormous gains in the technology sector boost the overall market.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story reveals that--brace yourselves--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> work a lot.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than one-third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least 50 hours</TIMEX> per week. Meanwhile,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> are scaling back to a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">35-hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">workweek</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecommuting</ENAMEX> has made long
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> easier and may be contributing to productivity gains. …
An article applauds a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> decision to build "electric drive" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">destroyers</ENAMEX> will have smaller engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> with more room for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.
The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> will be quieter, stealthier, and more efficient.
… A piece questions a new approach to cracking down on school
absenteeism: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> are imprisoning
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of chronic truants for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 90 days</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20</TIMEX>
            

            A
cover profile pokes fun at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>'s penchant
for purple prose and self-promotion verges on self-parody. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> says
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>: "Has she made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>?"
He supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> so strongly that "I'm building a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>-story
building right next to it." He regrets the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> because "I
would have loved to have had a shot to date her." … An
editorial applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> for
applying tough love to the homeless. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coddling</ENAMEX> hasn't worked. We should demand
that able-bodied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> pay for shelter.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 27</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> will become a focus of radical
politics in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>, galvanized by opposition to genetically modified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>. … An editorial claims that a tentative "red-green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>" emerged
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> havoc. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> will make it difficult for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to normalize trade relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20</TIMEX>
            

            An
item relays the rumor that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> will join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion Picture</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retiring MPAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Valenti</ENAMEX> thinks the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would make a worthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would enjoy working with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">starlets</ENAMEX>. … As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> steps up her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">faux West Wing</ENAMEX> memo proposes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> subs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s top picks are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shania Twain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX>, and "wrestling sensation" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sable</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Wing</ENAMEX> prefers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
