
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium Blues</ENAMEX>

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> tried to capture the spirit and meaning of the millennium
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrations</ENAMEX>, they generally ran into trouble. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
tried very hard indeed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX>
said that during the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> on the planet "most of
its [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>] <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> stopped, if for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one second</TIMEX>, to remember that they were
alive together, on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, the beautiful accident." There was much more in this
vein until the conclusion: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]e had been there, and we had seen each other
being there. All <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six billion</NUMEX> of us. We were there, and we were together alive,
and it was good to be alive." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX> "was a
moment of universal communality and aspiration. It was a moment when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of peace suddenly seemed to be a human possibility." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> complained in its main front-page story that it had almost
nothing to report but good news.

            More
soberly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun of Japan</ENAMEX> ran an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> pointing out that communality isn't all that it
might be. Noting that the wealth of the world's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> is greater
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNPs</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the world combined, it said that
economic globalization benefits only the developed world. "Unless the imbalance
is rectified and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> come to live stable lives, the
connections among different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cannot be said to be a genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. In one poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>, an opposition newspaper
summed up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> in the gloomiest possible
terms. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> dreams of
democracy have been dashed by a corrupt political "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX>," which has terrorized
and impoverished its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. "At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this millennium</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> seems
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miserable</ENAMEX>, bloody, abandoned, and--what is worse--believing that its shattered
hopes cannot be restored," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the main millennium stories around the world has been the failure of the Y2K
bug to bite. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> put it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year's Day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>
"dawned catastrophe-free in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> after region of a watchful world." The paper
said, "As of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early this morning</TIMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> had fallen from the sky, no nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reactors</ENAMEX> melted down, no power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">grids</ENAMEX> collapsed. Computer glitches were scarce,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> seemed to take the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> off, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> failed to begin.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Civilization</ENAMEX>, such as it is, survived." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the national daily
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
voiced fears that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, which spent billions
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> prevention, might have succumbed to hysteria generated by the
computer industry. It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Finkelstein</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of software at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University College London</ENAMEX>, as warning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year ago</TIMEX>: "The public was
ignorant, the IT <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> were drawn by the lure of filthy lucre, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> were seized with a mad-cow effect in which their advice
ceased to be rational, the nutcases were declaring the end of the world and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensible</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">empirically</ENAMEX> founded approach to risk was lost."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segodnya</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> was generally safe
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from Y2K</TIMEX> because most of its computers had been purchased in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990s</TIMEX> when
the problem was already understood by software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> ("Thus, the technical
backwardness of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> played to its advantage for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time"). The paper
quoted a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aleksander Ivanov</ENAMEX>,
as blaming the scare on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> intelligence services whose "crafty plan" was
to install new computers with spying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> refused to give the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> all the
computer information they wanted, they had pronounced the country
"ill-prepared" to deal with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> bug.

            Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, however, highlighted a warning by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> that
there may be computer glitches further down the line, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> led its
front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the news that the bug had "affected a computer at the
main <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>. … The exact nature of the
malfunction at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Ridge National Laboratory</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y-12</ENAMEX> nuclear weapons plant
was not disclosed because the computer controls a classified function," the
paper said. As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> euphoria began to evaporate, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers
led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on chaos and transport paralysis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> invaded
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for the start of what the pope has called its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">jubilee year</TIMEX>. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> press, there was criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> millennium
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrations</ENAMEX>, especially--in the letters page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> --of the
lack of public toilets along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames</ENAMEX>. "Elegantly dressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had to squat
and urinate in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> doorways because there were no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>," one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">correspondent</ENAMEX> wrote.

            Queen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth II</ENAMEX>, who had been criticized for not crossing her arms to hold hands
with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> for the singing of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auld Lang</ENAMEX> Syne" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Millennium Dome</ENAMEX>, was vindicated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by the tabloid
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> ,
which said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> are not supposed to be linked until the last verse of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Burns</ENAMEX>' poem, which starts "And there's a hand, my trusty fere [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>]."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns Federation</ENAMEX> explained, "It's no use singing 'There's
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX>' if you already have a hand." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> false messiahs were taken to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> for psychiatric
tests.

            In an editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> called for the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezer Weizman</ENAMEX>
after his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> confirmed a newspaper report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1988 and 1993</TIMEX>, when
he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX> and a government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, he received gifts of
money totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$453,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Sarusi</ENAMEX>. "Weizman must
step down as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> now, not later, because he lacks the uprightness
required of a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, and even now does not understand what he did
wrong," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> does not pay the price
for his actions, it will no longer be possible to demand proper conduct from
other public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>. The role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a symbolic one</NUMEX>, and the
symbol has to be a role model, not a symbol that engenders opprobrium."

         
      
   
