
   
   
      
         
            Yakety-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yak</ENAMEX>, Don't E-Mail Back

            The
Internet is a good place to learn about political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and campaigns--as
long as the information comes from just about anywhere but the candidates
themselves.

            That's
the belief of many politically active Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> who were recently surveyed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy Online Project</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graduate School</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Management</ENAMEX>. According to the poll of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,205</NUMEX> Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64 percent</NUMEX>
say that they are likely to believe what they read online. But a scant <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
percent think that the information offered online by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> is reliable.
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Fifty-two percent</NUMEX> put their greatest faith in Web sites sponsored by church
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 39 percent</NUMEX> say that a civic or news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> merits
similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>.

            The
survey also indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> surf the Net to learn more about community
problems, read <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> biographies, and determine who to vote for.

            Those
polled, however, appear less enthusiastic about forging an "interactive"
relationship with campaigns or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Respondents</ENAMEX> are more concerned with
whether political sites can document their positions, observe privacy policies,
and disclose sponsorship than with whether they provide an e-mail contact
address.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX>
might be less interested in exchanging comments with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> online because
they fear that no one is listening, reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Sackett</ENAMEX>, a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarrance Group</ENAMEX>, which was commissioned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Online Project</ENAMEX> to conduct the surveys along with help from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Snell Perry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Associates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sackett</ENAMEX> believes that there's a historical skepticism among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, who question whether their individual voices will be heard, much less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heeded</ENAMEX>, by political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            But to
a certain extent the medium is also having an impact on the message from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Online</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> can shop for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> just as they would shop for
goods. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are getting used to making choices on their own timetables,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sackett</ENAMEX>, arguing that political Web sites have to be as thorough, as
responsive, and as up-to-date as commercial ones. "If we don't take the lead,
we're going to get hoisted on our own petards," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sackett</ENAMEX>, apparently
referring to the cottage industry in political parody Web sites.

            To
help improve campaign Web sites, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Cornfield</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">research director</ENAMEX> at
Democracy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Online Project</ENAMEX>, has produced an online campaign primer for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">technologically</ENAMEX> challenged political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornfield</ENAMEX> has also proposed a
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> directory of official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> Web sites, to help steer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> away from parody sites.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primer</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> pages of basic tips on how to build a campaign Web site. Among
them: Buy a computer made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year or two</TIMEX>, update information often,
design the pages with the same overall color scheme, and always make sure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> know how to get back to the home page. "These aren't politicos who are
going online," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornfield</ENAMEX>. "These are Net <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> who are sidling over to
politics. If they don't like what they see, they're gone."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornfield</ENAMEX>'s proposal for the directory has come under fire from anti-government
and privacy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> who tend to view government involvement in any endeavor
as a sinister machination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornfield</ENAMEX> responds by saying that the directory he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">envisions</ENAMEX> would be a benign source of information, rather than a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good</ENAMEX>
Housekeeping seal" of approval for political Web sites.

            For now, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, have plans to include a line
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to write in their URLs on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> filing forms. And some will
post a list of official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URLs</ENAMEX> on their state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> Web sites.

         
      
   
