
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delight</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
led its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday-Monday</TIMEX> edition with a lament about "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> impotence" in
relation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> onslaught on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. It said that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Helsinki</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>, managed to achieve
nothing more than "timid warnings" to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> that they would suspend certain
cooperation agreements if it didn't stop bombing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX>. In response,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> said he understood the concerns about the
humanitarian situation in the north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caucasus</ENAMEX> but rejected any change of
"tactics" in achieving "the destruction of terrorism." Libération of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> led
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a report that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are trapped in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX>, unable to
escape the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">noose</ENAMEX>.

            The
paper also ran an interview with the powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
Berezovsky, in which he called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> conflict "a just war," claimed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> "have received funds from radical foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX>
circles that I will not name," and said there should be no more talk of Chechen
independence. "In that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> support us," he said. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Constitution</ENAMEX> must prevail in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berezovsky</ENAMEX> also criticized
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for failing to seize opportunities for negotiation. Even
so, he said he would vote for the "politically inexperienced" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> in the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> presidential election because he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> qualities that no other
candidate offers: "He is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> and he is extremely determined."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> 's
editorial was devoted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Helsinki</ENAMEX> agreement to establish a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
rapid-deployment force to intervene in trouble spots such as the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. It called this a "spectacular" affirmation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s desire "to
exist by itself, without the help of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>," going far beyond
present forms of military cooperation among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            The
death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franjo Tudjman</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Croatia</ENAMEX>, was also a
big story in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> seeing it as a positive development
for peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> reported that, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANP</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">War Crimes Tribunal</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX> had been planning
to indict <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX> for atrocities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. In its obituary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX>, the
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said he had had a "shadowy relationship" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. "In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994 and 1995</TIMEX> it was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military backing and training that helped Tudjman
and his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> to expel around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> from areas they had seized at
the start of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> disintegration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>," it said. (For

                  Slate
               's take on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX>, see this ".")

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> fronted a report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> has
"categorically ruled" that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,500-year-old</TIMEX> sculptures from the frieze of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parthenon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>--known in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elgin Marbles"</ENAMEX>--should not be
returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> recently stepped up its long-running
campaign to get them back and got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Museum</ENAMEX> to admit that it bungled
their restoration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> is poised to make a new request for the
sculptures' return as part of a deal to coincide with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic Games</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> wants to house the marbles in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> to be built under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acropolis</ENAMEX>. The sculptures were bought in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1803</TIMEX> from the then-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aristocrat</ENAMEX> Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elgin</ENAMEX>, who subsequently donated them
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Museum</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> intends to proceed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sensitively</ENAMEX> in order to avoid further antagonizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>. "The last thing
Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> wants is another row with a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> when he is
already at loggerheads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> over the
withholding tax," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> seems to be inevitable. The report
surprised some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> who thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would agree to
the return of the sculptures. A recent editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, a conservative <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, assumed that this was the case and said it "would
elevate historic sentiment over legality, creating in the process a chaotic
precedent for dispersing the world's great archaeological collections." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also accused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Hellenophiles</ENAMEX> of double standards by not
supporting the return of stolen treasures to the "non-European" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>. "To do
so would be to admit that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, is legitimately part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>,"
it said.

            But at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Helsinki</ENAMEX> summit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> finally agreed to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> membership. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s desire to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> has
hitherto been thwarted by its historic enemy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> (already a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>) and by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> concerns about its human rights record. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> led
its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> with a report that, as part of its concessions to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> has agreed to abolish the death penalty, offering hope for the rebel
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX> who has been sentenced to death for terrorism.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> must approve his execution before it can be carried out.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News Sunday</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was among
world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who telephoned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> to urge acceptance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>'s conditions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> papers generally rejoiced at the agreement. They carried headlines such
as "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ) and "The first
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurriyet</ENAMEX> ). Writing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hurriyet</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">columnist Tufan Terenc</ENAMEX> said, "This has sealed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s future and led it to the
point of no return."

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> prepares for peace talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> gave
an upbeat assessment of the prospects, leading its front page with a forecast by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farouk Shara</ENAMEX> that a peace deal could be reached within
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX>." It also offered a foretaste of what was billed as an optimistic
speech to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , he will say that peace is "within our reach" and anticipate an
agreement that will "burst apart the sense of threat on both sides, do away
with fear and suspicion, and burn out terror."

            Nearly
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> carried front-page photographs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX>
receiving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sports Personality of the Century"</ENAMEX> award at a ceremony in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. "So <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sad</ENAMEX>" was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mirror</ENAMEX> 's headline, referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>'s physical
condition, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> ran eulogies of the former boxing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. The
Times ' sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Barnes</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> "the most reckless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spendthrift</ENAMEX> of himself that the world of sport has ever seen." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> wrote:
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX> he comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> not to milk their applause but to give
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> something worth applauding. It is he that is doing the giving, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that does the receiving." In an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonnie</ENAMEX>, said: "I believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muhammad</ENAMEX>'s role is to unite people
throughout the world in peace. He is one of those rare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> like the
late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> who can walk anywhere and be well received by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>,
regardless of age, race or social background." All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>'s remark
on accepting the award, "I had a great time boxing. I enjoyed it and I may come
back."

         
      
   
