
   
   
      
         
            Money To Spurn

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> made a joint appearance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>. They pledged support for campaign-finance reform and
promised to forgo unrestricted donations ("soft money") if they won their
respective nominations. The spins, in order of increasing cynicism: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> crossed a "partisan and ideological divide" for the sake of reform;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) they strengthened each other's images "as political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> who
speak their minds and could shake up the system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) they
ganged up to take pot shots at the front-runners.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> agreed to continue peace talks. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s
negotiations between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farouk al-Shara</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> were the highest-level talks ever. They did not address
substantive issues but did set a schedule for discussions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> aimed at ending their 50-year-old
disputes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syria</ENAMEX> aims to win <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> withdrawal from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX>, which it
lost in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> wants official recognition from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and increased
security along its border. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Optimists</ENAMEX> said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the talks so far have achieved
their goals, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a successful accord could spread peace throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pessimists</ENAMEX> countered that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) setting a schedule wasn't much of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) both sides signaled little willingness to compromise. (See
"" for more on the talks.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> lost a court decision on her legal immunity. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled that her immunity agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) did not prevent her from facing state wiretapping charges and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) did not take effect until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five weeks later</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> had
contended. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> then testified that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> did not aid her
in recalling information that may be used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to implicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> called it a rough week for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>, saying the developments <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) heightened
the likelihood she would stand trial and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) expanded the evidence that could be
used against her. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> said the ruling was inconsequential
in the "war of attrition. Battles will be won and battles will be lost."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> questioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s credibility and charged she was just exacting
revenge on her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Peanuts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schulz</ENAMEX> is retiring. He is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>
and has colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. He said he was leaving "to focus on my health and my
family without the worry of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> deadline." The comic strip is nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and is carried by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> attributed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanuts</ENAMEX> ' enduring popularity to its gentle humor, universal themes,
and sympathetic portrayal of the "little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX> attributed it to the
strip's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> merchandising juggernaut. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cartoonists</ENAMEX> lauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX>
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Brown</ENAMEX> was re-elected as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, won <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX> of the vote in a runoff election with fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Democrat City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supervisor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Ammiano</ENAMEX>. Ammiano, who would have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> openly gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, forced the runoff after launching a write-in campaign
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just three weeks</TIMEX> before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ammiano</ENAMEX> ran on a platform of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>' rights and reduced gentrification. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> painted him as
"an inexperienced free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spender</ENAMEX> ." The gloomy liberal
spin: Even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, a true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> can't win. The rosy liberal spin:
Only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> not be considered a true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> showed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>' videotapes to the
press. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> of home movies show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan Klebold</ENAMEX>
planning their attack and expressing rage at their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> for allegedly mistreating them. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days</TIMEX> after the showing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>
High <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">School</ENAMEX> was closed down when a student threatened to "finish" the job.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> said they showed the tapes reluctantly after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
violated its agreement not to use direct quotes from them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX> called the
tapes chilling,
pointing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) fascination with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and violent video games;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) prescience about the lasting effect of their actions; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) desire for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fame</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> said the showing of the tapes was the most chilling act,
as it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) provided information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> before providing it to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klebold</ENAMEX> achieve exactly what

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> debated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
meeting of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> was described as their "most spirited," with
numerous disagreements over campaign finance, abortion, taxes, and ethanol
subsidies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> said the debate reinforced the race's existing dynamics: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> continued to "portray himself as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> and as the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> willing to speak often
unpopular truths"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> highlighted their
conservative credentials while painting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> as an
unprincipled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centrist</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> maintained his front-runner status , responding to attacks with "a more
assertive demeanor and a more confident manner" than in previous debates.
(
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' performances,
calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s courageous and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s effective but evasive.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> pleaded not guilty to charges of mishandling nuclear
secrets. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.M.</ENAMEX>, weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, was
indicted on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> counts of removing classified data from his computer "with the
intent to injure the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and … secure an advantage for a foreign
power." He was not charged with the more serious crime of spying.
Asian-American <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>' spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> is a "sacrificial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX>" singled out because
of his race. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s spin: He's a security threat who may have
"alter[ed] the global balance of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>' spin:
That threat would never have been so great if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> hadn't
flubbed the investigation. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, 
                  Slate
               's ""
outlined the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said the "don't ask, don't tell" policy has not
worked. He called it "out of whack," saying the policy--which allows
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gay</ENAMEX> service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to be discharged only if there is evidence of homosexual
conduct--had not been implemented as intended. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> and Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> both said the policy was unacceptable and promised to work
for its elimination if elected. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> said the exchange
showed that Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was "nudging her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> a bit to the left." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was making "his sharpest public
break with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> maintained that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s positions had not changed, saying: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had
adopted "don't ask, don't tell" only as a
compromise with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> unwilling to do more; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> had long

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> passed reforms. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>' governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> voted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) ban visits by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to cities
bidding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) create an independent ethics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
invite recent <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year ago</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> were forced to resign following allegations that they had accepted
substantial gifts from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Samaranch</ENAMEX>, who was questioned by a congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> had "solved" the corruption problems. The optimistic spin: The reforms will
improve public perception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>. The skeptical spin:
Perception is all they'll improve, since they don't have the teeth to be effective.

         
      
   
