
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dread Museum</ENAMEX>

            
Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, flames inside, gone down--
Fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> for terror, or just
An apolitical mechanical malfunction,
No one knows. Not the aeronautics
Or explosive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>; not the anchors
Paid too much to tell us; and most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terribly</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> who watch
On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> switch to Canceled on the monitors.

            Maybe
it was too much picturing--
The sheared wing thrust from the sea,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Torsos</ENAMEX> afloat like hand puppets in a tub,
The grim business of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX>, nosing through
The ribs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX>--that brought on
This nosebleed hampering me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all morning</TIMEX>.
Can't bend, can't yawn, can't make a face
Without my nostril-wad of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleenex</ENAMEX> reddening.

            
Amazing--isn't it?--how one swerves
From pity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> and body parts to hordes
Of corpuscles and antibodies surging.
Should I be ashamed? I'm not. And I'm not
That I'm elated that I'm not, once again,
The relative reaching over the butcherblock
For the telephone, and in that lurch
Having the notion common to us all--
Now's my time to pay for pleasure --
Prove true.

                          Oh, I could weep
Out of frustration for my nose, and may.
I'll put my head back, daub a few last drops
On another bloody lucky day, and dwell
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX>, on the spokes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX>,
Of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s tricycle, while someone
Whom I'll never meet and care about
As much as care imagined can, tears out
The front-page photo of a size-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>
Washed ashore, because he knows
He knows the shoe.

         
      
   
