
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">362</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judge Mental</ENAMEX>"

            
               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shira Scheindlin</ENAMEX> ruled that because there
was a "top hat" but no "bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>," something must be done. What?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">361</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lit Crit":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               "Oh, I can't stand that. You could get <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> reading them, couldn't
you?" Who said this about what? (Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonin</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pope</ENAMEX>, on applications for sainthood."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Wade</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janeane Garofalo</ENAMEX>, about romantic comedies (the ones without her in
them)."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>, reviewing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">granddaughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Best Grandfather Ever</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, about the collected works of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon Wiesenthal</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lott</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, on ads for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diabetes Walk</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophie Pollitt-Cohen</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lerangis</ENAMEX> had a similar, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candygrams</ENAMEX>, answer.)

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> built
their responses around the scorn of our putatively fiercest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
Mailer, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>. But ours is not an era of harsh condemnation; it is
an age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-praise. It is rare to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opprobrium</ENAMEX> heaped on a cherished book
or play or millennial fireworks display. The more common experience is to watch
a much-admired movie with high hopes only to discover that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> is
Short Cuts for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummies</ENAMEX>, or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry has no ideas about
its subject beyond those in any of a score of newspaper articles written about
the case. Indeed, if a movie is in color, in focus, and indoors, it was likely
to have been praised by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' departing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>. In
part, this is a form of kindness: It is terribly difficult to, say, write a
novel. Indeed, the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> of serious literary fiction is so marginal
that one hates to discourage any sincere effort. But this pseudogenerosity is
also a kind of cowardice: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> may be censured for slamming a worthy movie;
she may have to defend her judgment. But she won't have to defend her praise;
the pleasure she took in that film is its own justification. How perceptive is
she to have seen its merit. How dull I am to have missed it. I can only hope
that these low critical standards extend to my own work. Should I ever do
any.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panel</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Two-Dimensional Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schulz</ENAMEX> said it about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> detests phony-baloney religiosity, writes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Templeton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sonoma County Independent</ENAMEX> :

            

               He
cringed when I mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Circus</ENAMEX> , the strip by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Keane</ENAMEX> that is
strewn with cutesy references to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> (who wants to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>, but can't because of laws about separation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and state!) and
those sickly-sweet images of invisible deceased grandparents looming
protectively over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kindly</ENAMEX>, he added, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>,
though. A very decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> was less amiable in his assessment of
another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX>:

            

               "I
despise those shallow religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">comics</ENAMEX>," he said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menace</ENAMEX> , for instance, is the most shallow. When they show him
praying --I just can't stand that sort of thing, talking to God about
some cutesy thing that he'd done during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Ketcham</ENAMEX>
[ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>] has any deep knowledge of things like that."

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX>'s final daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Peanuts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> ran <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. Read the entire interview here.

            
               I <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do Not Choose To</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            A survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 400</NUMEX>
potential congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> listed factors that might deter them from
running. Which of these made the list?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Having to raise large
sums of money to finance campaign.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Separation from family
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Heat, humidity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
make me "sweat like a chunk of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rancid pork</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glimpsing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> and his ass in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> showers.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Loss of personal and
family privacy.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Sexual exploitation of
staff now considered "old-fashioned."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Can make more money
smuggling cigarettes into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Takes too much time
away from stalking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Diaz</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Being forced to wear
"gender-appropriate" underpants.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rivals</ENAMEX> might spread
embarrassing rumors about my so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killin</ENAMEX>' spree" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Carol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oates</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. Having to endure
negative campaigning.

            12.
Having to endure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>.

            
               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2, 5</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> made the
cut.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Backbiting novelists.

         
      
   
