
   
   
      
         
            Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muck</ENAMEX> and Morons

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I need to ask you a
question about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. I don't want to unload on her if her behavior is
normal, but I have my doubts. Whenever we're in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">restroom</ENAMEX>, she will
wash her hands (afterward) and then take a paper towel or toilet paper to turn
off the faucets, then use it to open the door to leave. She does this so she
doesn't have to touch anything with her bare hands. How crazy is that?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Sal</ENAMEX>,

            You have perhaps come to
the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. It has occurred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> that maybe she's the secret love
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Hughes</ENAMEX> because of her own slight phobia about germs.
Actually, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s routine with the paper towels is merely one of taking
precautions. What is the point, after all, of washing your hands only to then
touch a surface that a non-hand-washer has touched? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is so concerned for
health, in fact, that she travels with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, antiseptically

            

               
                  Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 and 6</NUMEX>) who were both adopted from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. Both were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amputees</ENAMEX> and therefore wear artificial limbs. I can't count the number of times
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have rushed up to me and said, "Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, what happened?" Or worse,
"What kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> did you take when you were pregnant<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" (This, of course, is
always in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.) My standard response is to stare calmly and ask,
"Why do you need to know?" I am writing for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is to remind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that this is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX> society, and everyone does not have
the right to ask about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>'s disability. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is to ask if you
have any great retorts for these morons?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.D.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear J.</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks you're
handling things perfectly. If you want to enlarge your repertoire, however, you
might try saying, "I don't believe I know you," and continue on. They will get
the underlying implicit message. The important thing for you to know is that
these foolish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who think everything is their business have their own
congenital defect: no brains.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, righteously

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               "" wrote asking
about his abnormal fixation on sex. Had he written you about an abnormal
drinking habit, you might have sent him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alcoholics Anonymous</ENAMEX>. Do you not
know that there is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexaholics Anonymous</ENAMEX>, which is a well-respected organization
dealing with fixations on sex? Send him to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sa</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               --NO NAME PLEASE
            

            Dear NO,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> knew of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, but it didn't come to mind; perhaps an indicator that sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">addiction</ENAMEX> is less established in our society than <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>. Thank you for
being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, appreciatively

            

               
                  Pru,
               
            

            
               I am having what
you'd call a philosophical argument with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. My position is that without
rules and civilized, ordered behavior, life would be nasty, brutish, and short
(to borrow from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobbes</ENAMEX>). My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> believes that anarchy might be preferable
and more "honest," with no imposed ordinances. His point is that if rules are
dictated rather than instinctive, they are false--therefore not genuine and not
worth having. What do you think about this? Maybe a word from you could settle
the matter.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philosophically Interested</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Phil</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> votes with you
... and she's relieved, by the way, that yours was a philosophical question,
because upon reading the words "nasty, brutish, and short," she thought your
letter was about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starter husband</ENAMEX>. In any case, offer your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> a very
ordinary, everyday example: Imagine the flow of traffic without lights and
signs. Of course <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX> does not think traffic lights are what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hobbes</ENAMEX> had in
mind (since they didn't exist then), but she has a hunch he would have
appreciated their contribution to civilization. If you need more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition</ENAMEX>,
just point out what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Czolgosv</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chap</ENAMEX> who assassinated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKinley</ENAMEX>.
In addition to having a name like that, he was electrocuted.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, procedurally

         
      
   
