
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sizzling Bacon</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Stir
               
               
                  of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echoes</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artisan Entertainment</ENAMEX>).
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> film <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> featuring a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who sees dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gets
decent reviews, but most say it's not as good as the similar box office smash
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sixth Sense</ENAMEX> . Echoes focuses on the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Bacon</ENAMEX> in "one of his best performances" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacon</ENAMEX> also possesses <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> sight, not to mention a
compulsion to dig up his backyard following an impromptu hypnosis session at a
party. The film "is at its best in its mysterious, genuinely chilling first
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. But as the plot kicks in, the hysteria mounts and the explanations start
coming, the tension starts to dissipate" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to find out about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Bacon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bacon Brothers</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Stigmata
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM-UA</ENAMEX>). This would-be thriller gets
punctured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>: "Possibly the funniest movie ever made about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholicism</ENAMEX>--from a theological point of view" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). The film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Arquette</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beautician</ENAMEX> who is
mysteriously afflicted with stigmata after receiving a rosary with a history
from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> term it "a silly, roiling melange of special effects
and overheated religious symbolism" that is at heart a "half-baked anticlerical
screed" with "lots of broken glass, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird feathers</ENAMEX>, dripping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and
desperately fancy camera angles" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to visit a fan page devoted to the film.)

            

               
                  Outside
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Providence</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>).
Evenly divided negative and positive reports for this unexpectedly sincere
coming-of-age story from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> of gross-out comedy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrelly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>
( There's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Something About Mary</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directed</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Corrente</ENAMEX> and based
on a novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Farrelly</ENAMEX>, it's a standard <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>-out-of-water tale (poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
from small-town <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> gets sent to a snobby boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>). Those who
like it say it's "a sweet, funny little movie" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ) and
that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> finds oneself asking how such familiar material breeds contentment
instead of contempt" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Critics also note that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great performances, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn Hatosy</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX> as his
gruff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, help lift the film above cliché. Those who pan the movie call it a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vanity</ENAMEX> project for the now-famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> that offers "nothing fresh, and
everything bland" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Or as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wloszczyna</ENAMEX> writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> : "Let's hope they have exorcised these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pap</ENAMEX>-spewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX> and get their minds back in the gutter." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrelly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, and to read
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s rave in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Things</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irony, Trust</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Commitment in America</ENAMEX>
Today
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jedediah Purdy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> dig into 24-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdy</ENAMEX>, who argues that irony and ironic figures such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX> are a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> corrupting the soul of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Unsurprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irony Inc.</ENAMEX> (a k a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> ) shreds the book, calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> on the dangers
of genetic engineering "a warning so bloated with bombast that one begins to
wish that the gene for pomposity could be extirpated for the sake of future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>. ... I say earnestly, with feeling, What garbage! " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Begley</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdy</ENAMEX> a "cornpone prophet" and blasts his
"unctuous sentimentality" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger D. Hodge</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lehmann-Haupt</ENAMEX> writes in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> that the book is "impressive if somewhat pious" but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">finds Purdy</ENAMEX>'s points unoriginal: "He labors at length such crashingly obvious
ideas as the ethical ambiguities of technology." A few stick up for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">embattled author</ENAMEX>, arguing that though "the ideas expressed aren't complicated,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdy</ENAMEX> "grapples with them with a seriousness that puts more seasoned--and
ironic--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> to shame" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX>, writing
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , seems a bit gleeful at the fact that "the brainy nature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> has
stormed the capital, panicking the languid sophisticates with an unfashionably
passionate attack on the dangers of passionlessness," only to later concede
that the book is "an arduous read that would test the syntactical skills of a
tenured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgments</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Book
            

            

               
                  'Tis: A Memoir
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank McCourt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scribner</ENAMEX>). The hype
revs up for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCourt</ENAMEX>'s follow-up to his best-selling, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ashes</ENAMEX> . 'Tis tops all fall preview lists, and now the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> review is in: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) says it's "a
considerably angrier book than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ashes</ENAMEX> . ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]his sour tone of
complaint does not make for particularly engaging or sympathetic reading."

            
               Movie
            

            

               
                  Chill
                
               
                  Factor
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>).Critics
barely even bother with this action flick starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuba Gooding Jr.</ENAMEX> and Skeet
Ulrich as a pair of ne'er-do-wells who end up with a load of heat-sensitive
poison on their hands. They drive it around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in a dilapidated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ice-cream</ENAMEX> truck trying to keep it cool. "Stale macho jokes and formulaic
cliffhangers drive this chase<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by-</NUMEX>numbers thriller on the bumpy road to nowhere"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).

         
      
   
