
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">268</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Pyramid Power&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX>-nation
conference is to present the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. General Assembly</ENAMEX> with an action plan to
reduce world population growth by employing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo Strategy</ENAMEX>. Which is
what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 267</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Be the Playwright":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               I set the stage
for a script based on an actual current event.
            

            
               Setting: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courtyard</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Prop: A briefcase
containing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX>.
            

            
               Female Lead:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KAETHE</ENAMEX>, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> wearing hot pants and a bikini top.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Male Lead: FATHER</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CHRISTOPHER</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> wearing something priestly.
            

            

               Question: What is the opening line of dialogue?
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">KAETHE: Daddy</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FATHER CHRISTOPHER</ENAMEX>: You know, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kaethe</ENAMEX>, even though you are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, and this
money was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legitimately</ENAMEX> inherited from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and I'm giving it to you in
order that you may pay for a lifesaving sweat-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gland</NUMEX>-transplant, which will
finally enable you to dress properly, I'd bet, to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>, this whole scene
would look awfully fishy."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KAETHE</ENAMEX> (Offering the briefcase): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> can you ordain me?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
            

            
"KAETHE: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>, your parish does not need more scandal. Therefore,
no, I will not tell you where I bought the hot pants."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrill Markoe</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin Warner</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FATHER CHRISTOPHER</ENAMEX>
(ripping off his mask): <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ah ha</ENAMEX>! It is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>, but I, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>! And here are my plans to invest the budget surplus of ... <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trillion</ENAMEX> !

            KAETHE
(ripping off her mask): Not so fast! For neither am I a comely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> woman
but rather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX> And we are interested in deeds not
words!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            I'm no computer-porn sex-phone perversity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>--well, not professionally--but the sex-crazed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seductress</ENAMEX> seem an unlikely match. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexpot</ENAMEX> is a stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> going
back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabelais</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Canterbury Tales</ENAMEX> , and why not? If you're going
to have chastity, you're going to have jokes about the power of sex to
overthrow that ludicrous vow. Everyone enjoys a good hypocrite joke, and
everyone likes sex. (Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Humping Monk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX>?)

            Even before the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, the
Red <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hot Menace</ENAMEX> was not entirely persuasive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ursula Andress</ENAMEX> made an unconvincing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> honey trap for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> in an early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX> movie. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unconvincing</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>; pretty persuasive as an object of desire.) But at least when those two
had sex across ideological lines they played out the traditional drama of Eros
as an anarchic force, tempting Bond from his vows of capitalism.

            The post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seductress</ENAMEX> is unconvincing in a new way. This way: hot pants? Who wears hot
pants? Nobody wears hot pants. Hot pants and money. What she's really showing
off is all that creamy cash. This isn't sex as the irresistible life force that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mocks</ENAMEX> and demolishes vows of chastity; it's sex as consumer good. It's the kind
of thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> would find appealing. It's profoundly conservative. I
don't know who Satan has doing his hiring, but no way you're going to take down
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> like that.

            
               Massive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insurance Fraud</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            KAETHE: I've just flown in on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Concorde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>,
in these tiny shorts with this huge bag of money. Want some?

            Or something like that. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaethe Schuchter</ENAMEX>, an agent
for reclusive swindler <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Frankel</ENAMEX>, flew to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Father</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> contribution to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Genesis Center</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>
would use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> to buy insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rosse</ENAMEX>, one
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankel</ENAMEX>'s aliases. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> rebuffed her. The briefcase, by the way, was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metaphoric</ENAMEX>; the money was to come from mysterious off-shore accounts.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankel</ENAMEX>'s scam,
involving prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>, and church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, has siphoned
off <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $300 million</NUMEX>. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have issued a warrant for his
arrest.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild West/Wild Weasel</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Smith</ENAMEX>'s summer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blockbuster</ENAMEX> opens, and a new list of outlawed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> takes effect. Below, a
comparison of the newly taboo ferret and the just released <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild Wild</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferret</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weasel family</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">WWW</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Product of Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferret</ENAMEX>: Frightening features include
powerful scent glands and razor sharp teeth.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">WWW : Frightening</ENAMEX> features include
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Kline</ENAMEX> in a corset.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ferret: New</ENAMEX> law calls them part of a group
that is "wild, ferocious, fierce, dangerous, or naturally inclined to do
harm."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">WWW</ENAMEX> : Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox TV</ENAMEX> that nobody
ever heard of calls it "the hippest, funniest action movie of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferret</ENAMEX>: Fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ferrets</ENAMEX> derived from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">misleading predator clichés</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">WWW : Role</ENAMEX> of co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bai Ling</ENAMEX> derived
from creepy racist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clichés</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferret</ENAMEX>: Piranhas are not in this restricted
class.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">WWW : Piranhas</ENAMEX> are not in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild Wild</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferret</ENAMEX>: "You have a ridiculous, biased and
skewered view of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>," said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> angry ferret fancier.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">WWW</ENAMEX> : He has a "knowing, newly hunky
presence," said one lovesick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Smith</ENAMEX> fancier. And it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferret</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, there were fewer than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dozen</ENAMEX> reported ferret bites serious enough to require hospitalization.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">WWW :</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, there were fewer than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Smith</ENAMEX> bite serious enough to require hospitalization.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferret</ENAMEX>: "There have been attacks reported
nationwide, and those attacks have become notorious for their severity and
their capriciousness," said hysterical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gadd</ENAMEX>, not
referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">WWW</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Smith</ENAMEX> gets attacked by some
kind of mechanical spider, probably not affiliated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferret</ENAMEX>: "In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just walk around
with them on their shoulders and in little packs! What is this administration
going to do next, ban calico <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>?" asked some other ferret fancier.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">WWW</ENAMEX> : In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild Wild West Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branagh</ENAMEX> uses a steam-powered wheelchair and a phony baloney Southern accent,
which isn't, strictly speaking, a parallel, but does kind of make you sick when
you think about how great he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferret</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferrets</ENAMEX> pose a threat when confined
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indoors</ENAMEX>," said mayoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunny Mindel</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">WWW :</ENAMEX>
"Especially when confined indoors at movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunny Mindel</ENAMEX> did not
add.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eternal Triangle</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Silow-Carroll</ENAMEX>
invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to devise a sequentially trumping topical triad along
these lines: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> crush <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> drives out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> fits.) Replies due by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Zerolnick</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headline Haiku</ENAMEX>
            

            Gay market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s urging
Love it.

            
               --Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29 1999</TIMEX>

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Concupiscent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, selling indulgences.

         
      
   
