
   
   
      
         
            Hell on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wheels</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  Bringing Out
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>
                provides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX> with a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">milieu</ENAMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his patented, pumped-up odysseys of the soul--an urban bedlam as seen
through the eyes of an emergency medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Pierce</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>). The film is based on a book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Connelly</ENAMEX>, who cruised the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'80s</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>, when the crack
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">epidemic</ENAMEX> was peaking and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> had become the embodiment of everything
untenable about major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connelly</ENAMEX> spent a lot of time picking up
shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, crackheads in the throes of cardiac arrest, and homeless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drunks</ENAMEX>--some from the first wave of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Reagan-era</TIMEX> deinstitutionalization--and
bringing them to the overpacked emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of what he calls "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Lady of</ENAMEX>
Misery" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX>. The book is a memoir reframed as a novel: It boils those
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> down to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX> clutches vainly at the last
vestiges of sanity. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Night after night</TIMEX>, he has visions of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asthmatic</ENAMEX> whom he failed to resuscitate: Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> stares accusingly at him from
the shoulders of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he passes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. It's not just that he can't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forgive</ENAMEX> himself for not having saved her life; it's that he can't forgive
himself for putting her out of his mind. He can't live with the idea that he
has become indifferent.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> has so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>-like motifs that
it's easy to see why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> fell on it and passed it on to his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driver</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Schrader</ENAMEX>, who has said he finished the
script in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>. I can believe that, and not just because there's so much
dialogue and narration from the book on screen. It's probable that Connelly
thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mean Streets</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>) when he
wrote his novel, so having it adapted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schrader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> was like closing
the circle. But what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> really needed was opening. It's not just that
slow-motion scenes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX> gliding past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> beating one another up
feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">déjà vu</ENAMEX> . It's that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schrader</ENAMEX> hasn't rethought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connelly</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trumped-up</ENAMEX> story line.

            The movie starts with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX> and his occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Goodman</ENAMEX>), trudging to the top
floor of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hell's Kitchen brownstone</ENAMEX>, where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke</ENAMEX> has been in
cardiac arrest for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX>. They manage to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke</ENAMEX>'s heart started, but
his brain shows only scant traces of activity; and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> he keeps
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flatlining</ENAMEX> and being resuscitated--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> times. In and out of the
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several nights</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX> gets chummy with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke</ENAMEX>'s estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Arquette</ENAMEX>), a lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> whose
shellshocked existence (she begins to drift back into drug abuse) seems tied in
to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s neither-living-nor-dead condition. Pretty soon I got the sinking
feeling that the movie was building to the possibility of a mercy killing as a
test of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>'s ability to overcome his internal chaos and feel
something. It's true that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>'s "altruistic" impulse is not on par with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travis Bickle</ENAMEX>'s impulse to shave his head and assassinate a presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schrader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> don't view his actions with any
irony. I have a feeling they needed an ending and this one was handy.

            Their opportunism is a shame, because there's enough
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">texture in Bringing Out the Dead</ENAMEX> for several movies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crackerjack</ENAMEX> work, and some of the cruising imagery--not a bebop legato as in
Taxi <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driver</ENAMEX> but hyperfast and strobelike--is startling. There's a
scary irony built into the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> charged with saving lives
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> can't function at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">normal rhythms</TIMEX>; that their amphetamine-jag
intensity can make them as likely to want to murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as to revive them.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schrader</ENAMEX> are at their most inspired in the raucous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> of the
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stretchers</ENAMEX> scream at one another to shut
up, and an admitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schrader</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, the brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Beth</ENAMEX>
Hurt) takes pains to let the drunks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> and failed suicides know just
how much they're imposing on her. ("Why should we help? You're just going to
get drunk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Latifah</ENAMEX> can be heard as the voices of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX>, and their calls--they often have to bully the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> to
answer--are beautifully shaped comic turns. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX> of sitcom work haven't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">softened Goodman</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> is sour, unlovable, thickened by indifference. As
another of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ving Rhames</ENAMEX> talks into the radio like a
toasty-voiced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Daddy Marcus</ENAMEX> is alive") and strides through his scenes
with an unlit cigar in his mouth, defiantly proclaiming his potency. The
mixture of jokiness and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> never feels cheap--it adds to the movie's theme,
which is horrified estrangement from one's own humanity.

            I must admit that the
movie made me weep a couple of times: It's hard to watch with detachment as
tubes are thrust down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s throats or as they're shocked back to life. Some
of the more jaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> act as if life is cheap, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> doesn't. And
everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX> does gives weight to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX>'s vision. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> has
the same flamboyantly haggard (and toothy) look he had in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vampire</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>), yet this time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> is grounded. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX> would love to soar off
into the ether--to escape into madness--but he can't quite make the leap.
"Sometimes it's less about saving lives than being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>," he says, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice-over</ENAMEX>. "I was a grief mop. It was enough that I simply showed up." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>'s
wary alertness does those words justice.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best things about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX>'s marvelous new
film 
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Straight Story</ENAMEX>
                is its play on
"straight"--which is both the name of the protagonist, the failing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">septuagenarian Alvin Straight</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Farnsworth</ENAMEX>), and a description of the
movie's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-thing-after-another mode of storytelling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farnsworth</ENAMEX> plays an old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duffer</ENAMEX> who hears that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyle</ENAMEX>, has had a stroke. It emerges that they
haven't spoken for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>, and the last time they did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin</ENAMEX> said some
devastatingly harsh things. So, as a kind of penance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin</ENAMEX> decides to travel
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> under his own power. The only vehicle he's
legally allowed to drive is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Deere</ENAMEX> lawn mower that goes maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> miles
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>. But somehow the mode of travel--and the hardship of that
travel--becomes the movie's message.

            I was impatient with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Straight Story</ENAMEX> 's
opening--the arty dissolves, the crawling pace, the sense of stasis. But once
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin</ENAMEX> left his mentally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped daughter</ENAMEX> (a radiantly simple turn by Sissy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spacek</ENAMEX>) for the open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, it becomes apparent that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynch</ENAMEX> needed those early
scenes. He needed to show you that as slow as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin</ENAMEX> is going on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor</ENAMEX>,
it's flying next to what he has been doing. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin</ENAMEX> encounters a lot of plain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>, both the character and the movie threaten to start seeming "dear." But
the vein of regret, misery, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynchian</ENAMEX> promise of decay is always just
below the surface--and always palpable. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynch</ENAMEX>'s last film, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost</ENAMEX>
Highway , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> concocted an original, twisty syntax, in which
identity was mutable and the narrative moved by quantum leaps. This time he
sticks to the path, and his work is as transcendent--and as spellbinding--as
anything he has done since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Velvet</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynch</ENAMEX> has slowed the
world down and gotten back in touch with it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Straight Story</ENAMEX> could be
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">subtitled Found Highway</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
