
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999>What's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrong With Human Rights</ENAMEX>?</SPAN></SPAN>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> argues that the human rights movement is in trouble, despite its triumph
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. Some of the movement's frailty stems from the failure to tame China
and from general compassion fatigue, but the biggest weakness is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>
make no effort to generate popular support for human rights causes. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elitism</ENAMEX> could backfire against the movement, just as affirmative action's
elitism undermined it. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rieff</ENAMEX>, whose human rights views
were recently dissected in this 
                  Slate
                ".") ... An article
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">examines J.D. Power</ENAMEX>, the consumer research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that uses public opinion polls
to rate products. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.D. Power</ENAMEX>'s populist method challenges the more established
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumers Union</ENAMEX>, which pays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to rate products. (The article is by

                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>.) ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the
cover story, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child prodigy</ENAMEX>, describes his return to piano-playing
after a decadelong hiatus. He makes the finals of a prestigious amateur
competition. ... A piece notes a bizarre Internet phenomenon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Players</ENAMEX> in
the online role-playing game <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultima</ENAMEX> now auction their virtual gold pieces for
real cash on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>. The exchange rate is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,000</NUMEX> to the dollar, making
imaginary gold pieces worth twice as much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lira</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Talk , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premiere</ENAMEX>
issue
            

            On the
back page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> writes that her sprawling new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> will end
the " 'disconnect' between literary and domestic culture." ... An
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> suggests, among other things, that she is
responsible for the recent economic boom in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">addict</ENAMEX>, and that running for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will save her marriage. ...
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNSCOM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX> blames <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> for the collapse of
weapons-inspection efforts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> failed to understand the most basic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX> rules and permitted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> to introduce gaping loopholes in the
process. ... A safari guide narrates how he and his tourist charges were
kidnapped by machete-wielding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captives</ENAMEX>
survived. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> includes many lists: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hip List"</ENAMEX> (snow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cones</ENAMEX>, blimps, scabby knees), an index of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">50 Best Talkers in America</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX>), and a reading list (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shadow</ENAMEX> , pocket-sized guides to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> design).

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
cover story notes the resurgence of cosmetic surgery,
especially among younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. New surgeries are safer, less invasive, and
more varied. Still, the anecdotes are cringe-worthy: the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
brags about his pectoral and butt implants, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> who took a
loan from a "cosmetic loan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>" (!) for laser <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">resurfacing</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story reconstructs the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> massacre and blames it
largely on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> culture. A related essay contending that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have run out of tolerance for
the "barbaric era" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> predicts that we could be "rid of the damned things"
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or 10 years</TIMEX>. (The essay seems to ignore the previous story, which notes
that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> own a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>.) ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> package focuses more on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> trading angle, noting that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> lose money.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says that rising house prices nationwide have benefited more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> than rising stock prices. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homeowners</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 trillion</NUMEX> in unrealized
gains tied up in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. Loan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are permitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> to borrow
more than ever before--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> down payments are common--so many overextended
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> could be devastated when the economy slows down.

            
               Time tours the
loopy, genial world of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art Bell</ENAMEX>, who draws <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">late-night</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX>-conspiracy, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martian</ENAMEX>-happy radio broadcast. Even if it's all a
crock, it's "great radio."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story attributes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>' mercurial behavior
to underdeveloped brains. Pubescent brains are flooded with aggression-inducing
sex <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> and aren't sophisticated enough to refer to past experience when
making judgments. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is reaching out to computer
novices , says a piece. To keep growing, it will have to win over new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> who may be tempted by easier-to-use hand-held devices and specialized
e-mail and Internet machines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is monitoring selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> to learn their hardware habits.

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>
            

            A
piece describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in their 20s "donate" <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> to infertile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of dollars. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> are currently solicited through
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">advertisements</ENAMEX> ("Pay your tuition with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>") but will soon be able to offer
their services on a specialized Internet auction site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hopeful parents</ENAMEX> often
seek out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> who are athletic, Ivy League-educated, animal-loving, or
acne-free. ... A report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> repeats the conventional wisdom that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> straw poll is a sham. The minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are spending vast amounts
of time and energy vying for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> place, but the poll is irrelevant to the
actual nomination process.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover
piece makes fun of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> convention, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX>
included a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who framed the crumbs of a piece of cake <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> ate in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who claims he controlled exactly what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> said by sending faxes to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.
Conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are so obsessed by process they will never get
anything done. See the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> below for more. ... A piece
urges the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> as a sovereign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> won't
dare go to war over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s firm stance will cow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, which
caves at any show of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> strength.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story sneers at conservative doves.
Neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Isolationists</ENAMEX> oppose interventions abroad because they despise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
and believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture is debased. Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">left-wingers</ENAMEX> did during
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, they argue that "coercive diplomacy" is wrong because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is
morally unfit to impose its will on other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. ... A piece counsels against discounting "compassionate
conservatism." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s campaign theme represents a vision of
government that balances compassion against self-interest, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
evoked individual responsibility as a counterweight to government benevolence
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. ... A dispatch reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> has turned into
an umbrella <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> for fruitcakes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Activists</ENAMEX> grasp for another flamboyant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mogul</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>, perhaps--to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>, while a bunch of
delusional nuts promote their own candidacies for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s presidential
nomination.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX>
31
            

            The
cover editorial supports multilateral interventions to
halt belligerency. Violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX> was quelled by
outside interference. The world is morally obliged to intervene and prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">atrocities</ENAMEX>, even if this intervention does not resolve the underlying
conflict.

         
      
   
