
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.W. Bush</ENAMEX> vs. gwbush.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            The
slogan on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s Web site is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prosperity With a Purpose</ENAMEX>." The slogan on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zach</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s parody of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s Web site, gwbush.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> , is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hypocrisy With Bravado</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX> means
to mock the contradiction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s presumed use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and his support
of harsh prison sentences for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But he might have an even
better case based on the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> has harassed him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are demanding the meticulous enforcement against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> of minor
campaign finance rules--rules they themselves consider dated and
ridiculous.

            In
May, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Ginsberg</ENAMEX> filed a complaint against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gwbush</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX>. In it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsberg</ENAMEX> contends that
the parody site constitutes an "independent expenditure" under federal election
law. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s Web site--a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man operation
started on a lark--should fall into the same legal category as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horton</ENAMEX> ads run against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. The intimidating letter further
warns that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX>, a free-lance computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, has spent more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, he must register it as a "political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>," which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">means</ENAMEX> filing an even more elaborate disclosure. For a Web site run by a private
individual in his spare time, meeting these requirements would constitute a
substantial burden.

            The
complaint is hypocritical on a couple of counts. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.W. Bush</ENAMEX>
himself has bought his own way out of some of the more onerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> disclosure
requirements. Because his campaign is forgoing federal matching funds, it
doesn't have to file quarterly disclosure statements electronically. That means
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s contribution reports remain essentially useless raw data for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX> while those of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> are available for database searches.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> also thinks that limits of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 and $1,000</NUMEX>, fixed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>, are
anachronistically low and should be raised. Yet he is using these pre-inflation
thresholds as the basis for his complaint. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> seems to question
his own assault. "It's a fair question to ask whether the rules should cover
him," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsberg</ENAMEX> says of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>.

            In his
response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complaint Exley</ENAMEX> rehearses the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s antagonism toward his
site, citing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>'s infamous statement that "there ought to be limits to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>." He points to a number of absurdities about his situation. "I appear
to be caught in a catch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>; so far I have not spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $250</NUMEX> per year on the
Web site," he writes. "However, paying for legal advice would put me
immediately over the FEC spending threshold, thereby validating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
complaint against me."

            This
is a clever point. In fact, though, legal fees don't count toward the
disclosure limits. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX>'s response misses is a much better argument for
why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> should leave him alone: He's press. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gwbush</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is one of the kinds
of new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> made possible by the Web. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> instinctively thinks of
it this way. "This is my private little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>," he told me. If he wants to
put his non-disclosure on a firm legal footing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> could ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisory</ENAMEX> opinion to that effect--something the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> has to rule on within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> instead of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX> would have a good case, since his
site isn't anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> propaganda so much as a wacky, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>-averse take on the
news. It links to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> parody sites as well.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> will probably not be in any hurry to settle the matter if it can avoid
doing so. The narrow issue of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s Web site constitutes an
independent expenditure opens a much larger can of worms. It points to the
reality that many of the old campaign finance laws simply don't make sense in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberspace</ENAMEX>. Should someone who starts a site stating his views have to disclose
where his money comes from in the way someone who buys a newspaper ad does? If
a Web site itself counts as an in-kind contribution to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, as an
earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> ruling indicates, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> spending limit may apply. And if
hyperlinks count as contributions, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> has also indicated, then
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> cannot legally link to
official campaign sites. Many, if not most, of the key distinctions of campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> law simply dissolve when immersed in the Internet.

            The ethos of the Web
argues against regulating private, individual activity in any way. And indeed,
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> does much to create an open and level playing field for
political expression, restraining it in the name of fairness seems
counterproductive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Democracy and Technology</ENAMEX> recently published
an excellent report on this topic, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Square Pegs and Round</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holes</ENAMEX>: Applying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign Finance Law</ENAMEX> to the Internet." It doesn't settle
any of the specific questions about how campaign finance law should work in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberspace</ENAMEX>. But it does make one thing damningly clear: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> is utterly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unequipped</ENAMEX> to deal with them.

         
      
   
