
   
   
      
         
            Picks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Litter</ENAMEX> and Catcalls

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would like to say
a word about the and the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> veterinary bill. That word is oy . Never
has so much mail descended on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>, if you don't count the handicapped stall
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imbroglio</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> wishes to report that there was a boatload of comment ...
some supportive of the advice, some ... well, catcalls. Herewith are the picks
of the litter, pardon the expression, and a very unexpected, though satisfying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Prudie,
               
            

            
               Are you nuts? You
say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitter</ENAMEX> should be reimbursed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> bill of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> specifically told him not to incur any expense? No rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would
pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, perhaps, but not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>). And letting an animal
die from natural causes is not and never has been a crime. If you think I am
heartless, think about all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> that could use <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX>, including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPCA</ENAMEX>, which would not dream of blowing it on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> animal.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">As Indifferent to Cats as They Are to People</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear As,

            You make some valid
points, though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> detects dogist sentiments in your saying one might
understandably lay out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big ones for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, but not for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>. You are
fortunate in not having a column of your own, since the dog favoritism would
surely invite much correspondence from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. But do read on.

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               From the time our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cat Chappaquiddick</ENAMEX> (don't ask) was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> until she died at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 or 21</TIMEX>, we took her
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> twice a week for dialysis. This wonderful, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">magical cat</ENAMEX> raised all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> (with some help from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, but not much in my judgment),
and she became as much a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> as any of us. Because of kidney
problems she had accidents from time to time, but we always overlooked them.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ZM"</ENAMEX> performed a saintly act in the eyes of anyone lucky enough to ever share
space with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s noblest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               --C.K.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear C.</ENAMEX>,

            What a lovely tribute to
your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>, the feline <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Poppins</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you hide this letter
from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. Please keep reading for another point of view--probably not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cat's</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I usually enjoy and
agree with your advice, but I have to take issue with your reply to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cat</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitter</ENAMEX> who loved too much. I am not a cold or cruel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> (and I am
actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>), but I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s wishes about managing the health
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> should have been heeded. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> is a lot of money to
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and I think the financial sacrifices <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are willing to make
for their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> are their decisions. Who knows, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> might have had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who needed shoes (though since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, I doubt it).
Or maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> thinks the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand</ENAMEX> would be better spent as a donation to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNICEF</ENAMEX> to help save starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (again unlikely, but possible). The point
is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't be forced to spend big bucks on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Respectfully</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan D.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dandy</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> cannot quibble
with you.

            
               Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               My first reaction to
this letter was to wonder if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> could be taken away from such an
indifferent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>. My second was to admire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZM</ENAMEX> for compassion and tenacity. If
there is no satisfactory legal solution to reimbursing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZM</ENAMEX>, I'm sure there are
many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal lovers</ENAMEX> among your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who would be happy to contribute toward
replacing some of the money <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZM</ENAMEX> spent. I would certainly like to.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear A.</ENAMEX>,

            You are admirably
generous, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> does not pass the hat, feeling certain that Messrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> would frown on such a practice. However, the following
letter--from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZM</ENAMEX> himself--provides us all with a most interesting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">denouement</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Thank you for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">replying</ENAMEX> to my letter about the sick <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>. Your advice was, as expected,
good--and I'm not just saying that because you were on my side. I thought you
might like to know that I did begin legal proceedings in small claims court,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> and I settled. I say, "former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>" because in the
process of working out an agreement, I demanded and got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> in question.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> was only willing to pay half the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> expenses, so I said, "Well then,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> mine." He said, "You want it so bad, you can have it." I'm
not fond of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> in general, but I feel a bond with this one--he's very smart
and well behaved--and I certainly feel he's better off in my care. So, we have
a happy ending.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regards</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               ZM
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear</ENAMEX>, dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Z.</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amen</ENAMEX>. And on behalf of
all those who feel as you do, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> categorically thanks you.

         
      
   
