
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">296</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Lies</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damnable Lies</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "It is simply
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">untrue</ENAMEX>," an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson testily</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. What is?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">295</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gielgud, the Bad, and the Ugly":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Following an outcry from, among others, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Academy Award-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
Gielgud, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian Institution</ENAMEX> has canceled a program. What was the
program, and the problem?
            

            "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'Laurence Olivier</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Richardson</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Unparalleled Kings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Stage</ENAMEX> and
Screen.' The problem was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gielgud</ENAMEX> has nothing left to lose and was willing
to show up with a truck <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> if necessary."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delfin</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thanks to Gielgud</ENAMEX> and fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>-goers 'from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 5 to 105</TIMEX>' won't be
able to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Hands on History: The British Aristocracy</ENAMEX>' exhibit, which
encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> to examine life-sized models of past sovereigns and then
hypothesize which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> might have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">syphilitic</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Fein</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Look at Me</ENAMEX>! I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gielgud</ENAMEX>, and I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stuck-Up Sissy-Pants</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boo Hoo Hoo</ENAMEX>!'
program. Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> formally announced that he was neither stuck-up nor a
sissy-pants, while sniffling and blowing his nose into a frilly lace
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handkerchief</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            " 'The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Branagh Film Festival</ENAMEX>' was canceled, due to excessive scenes of Branagh
in close-up, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHOUTING SHAKESPEARE</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MUSIC SWELLS and SWELLS</ENAMEX>, and he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHOUTS</ENAMEX> and ..."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Considine</ENAMEX>
            

            " 'Eat
Your Liver' was the program, and the problem was that, according to Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>,
'It tastes yucky.' When it was pointed out that there are starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> who would love to have some nice liver to eat, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gielgud</ENAMEX> replied, 'Well,
then, my dear boy, send it to them.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            How odd that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gielgud</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX> are fighting with one another, since they are, in
many ways, so alike. Both are old, both are revered, and as a result, people
tend to focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">highbrow</ENAMEX> exploits of both, while discreetly ignoring the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lowbrow</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX> may be exalted as the repository of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture
and get high marks for whenever it hosts, say, a monthlong exhibit on the
hardships of the pilgrims. But, let's face it, a disproportionate number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> just want to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie Bunker</ENAMEX>'s chair. Similarly, when Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gielgud</ENAMEX>'s obituary is written, the Shakespearean plays and films will figure
prominently; less likely to be discussed are the roles in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caligula</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Knight</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arthur 2</ENAMEX>: On <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">the Rocks</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luckily, Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> aren't so kind.) One might think they'd team up, to feature a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monthlong</ENAMEX> show of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gielgud</ENAMEX>, sitting in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie Bunker</ENAMEX>'s chair, explaining
the pilgrims to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passers-by</ENAMEX>. But one would be wrong.

            
               Arthurian
Answer
            

            The program, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Floyd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliot</ENAMEX> and others knew, was titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Foie Gras: A Gourmet's Passion"; Gielgud</ENAMEX>,
along with other animal-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, protested <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>, which was to
consist of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> discussion followed by the distribution of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>.
Apparently, the method of producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foie gras</ENAMEX>--which requires that food be
crammed down the throats of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX> and geese--is offensive to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, to
say nothing of the geese. Seems to me that an equitable compromise would be to
have the foie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gras</ENAMEX> crammed down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>' throats, but nobody
asked me. Nobody ever asks me.

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Correction From Ian</ENAMEX>
Austen
            

            I hate to dispute the
abilities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>'s crack research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but given the recent trouble over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Lakes</ENAMEX>' greatness, nitpicking seems to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>'s thing. Your answer
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quiz's No. 293</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sporting Life</ENAMEX>," said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic Stadium</ENAMEX>
was filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> watching a bloodless rodeo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>. As someone who
lives dangerously close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>, I can tell you without actually having
visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big O</ENAMEX> that it was a bloodless bullfight. To be more exact, it was
described as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>-style bullfight. Is that because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal</ENAMEX> supplies
most of the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Velcro</ENAMEX>--or is it cork? Perhaps I should look that up.

            
               Test <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your TV Knowledge</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last season</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 8</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> tuned in for the average episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash Bridges</ENAMEX> , a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-night</TIMEX> TV program starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cheech Marin</ENAMEX>, airing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>.
Is your home one of them? And if not, can you figure out which of the following
plot synopses are real, and which I've arbitrarily made up?

            

               A)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skin Deep</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> team up with a tough-talking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD Special Crimes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detective</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny Marshall</ENAMEX>) in order to track down a famous fashion model's
deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">stalker</ENAMEX>.

               B)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goodbye</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Farewell</ENAMEX>, Amen": The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX> ends. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> can't bring himself to
tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> goodbye.

               C)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High Impact": Somebody</ENAMEX> is threatening to kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>.

               D)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dance</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> lies and promises everyone that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davy Jones</ENAMEX> will be coming to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> dance; at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davy</ENAMEX> shows up to save <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. (Special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest star</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davy Jones</ENAMEX>.)

               E)
"Imposters": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> must find the stolen wig of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">impersonator</ENAMEX>.

               F)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Favor</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip Michael Thomas</ENAMEX> guest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>)
"Boomtown": A sleep-deprived <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> must track down an ingenious bomber targeting
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> he feels has wronged him. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cassidy</ENAMEX> tries to conceal her
nudity in a school play.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Puppy Episode</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> has something to tell everyone.

               I)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home Invasion": A Chinese home invasion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> turns homicidal.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J</ENAMEX>)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Slow Week</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> keep waiting for the phone to ring, but it
doesn't. So instead, they spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> catching up on paperwork, cleaning up
their desks, and going home a little earlier than usual.

            

            
               Answers
            

            A, C, E, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>, and I are
all real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash Bridges</ENAMEX> episodes. The remainder are not.

            
               Weeklong Extra
            

            A headline from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> issue equal-access guidelines."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to find, in an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, a less
enticing headline. The deadline, which had been originally announced as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, has been arbitrarily moved back to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. Get
cracking.

            
               Lowest Common
Denominator
            

            The dim prospects for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
movie.

         
      
   
