
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah Codes, Cracked</ENAMEX>

            I'm a rationalist and a skeptic, someone who safely
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">separates</ENAMEX> faith from reason. But when I read a scientific paper titled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Equidistant Letter Sequences in the Book of Genesis</ENAMEX>," I confess I felt a
strong urge to grow side-locks and a long beard and start atoning for my years
of doubt. The article, published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> in a prestigious, peer-reviewed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Science</ENAMEX> , argued with unnerving force that the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> book of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> contains embedded codes that predict events that long
postdate its writing and that these codes are, statistically speaking, "not due
to chance." As I wrote in 
                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> (see ""), the
paper's hypothesis, if correct, would all but prove both the existence of God
and the divinity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> books of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hebrew Bible</ENAMEX>).

            The paper startled me and many others. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
became <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX> because of the codes. I know of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who held off
circumcising his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> until the paper was published. It spawned a runaway best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Drosnin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">The Bible Code</ENAMEX> . It became a recruiting tool
for ultra-orthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yeshivas</ENAMEX>. And it amused, then frustrated,
mathematicians worldwide. What made the codes especially eerie was that, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> were almost universally skeptical of them, nobody could figure out
what was wrong with them. No one had published a rebuttal in a peer-reviewed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX>. As long as that remained the case, even rationalists like me had to
consider the possibility that science could support the most radical religious
conclusions.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> codes'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> is finally up. In the current issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Science</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan McKay</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have
convincingly debunked them, and the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Science</ENAMEX>
who published the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> has endorsed their rebuttal. For those of us
who were freaked out by the codes, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> comes as a relief.

            The codes' rebuttal has taken so long because the science
behind the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is very sophisticated. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>
University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eliyahu Rips</ENAMEX>, is a well-respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX>.) The
original paper sought to test the anecdotal observation that pairs of
conceptually related words tend to appear in close proximity to one another in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>, coded in what are called equidistant letter sequences. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELS</ENAMEX> is a
string of letters compiled by pulling letters out of a text at regular
intervals. For example, if you start with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> letter of this paragraph
and read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only every fourth</TIMEX> letter, you will find the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TORT</ENAMEX>." Every text
contains many such "codes," so the question was whether the observation of
codes with apparent meaning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genesis</ENAMEX> was a deliberate message from the
almighty or mere coincidence.

            To test whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genesis ELS</ENAMEX> were intentional, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doron Witztum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-authors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoav Rosenberg</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rips</ENAMEX> used a computer to search Genesis for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ELS</ENAMEX> containing the names of famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rabbis</ENAMEX> and their dates of birth or death. These rabbis were all born long after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genesis</ENAMEX> was written, so their names could not have been encoded on purpose by
any human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. Yet in the Genesis text--unlike in control texts such as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hebrew</ENAMEX> translation of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> --the rabbis appeared on average
closer to their own dates than to the others'. This seemed to show that someone
had actively encoded the text--someone who knew beforehand when rabbis would be
born or die.

            After years of onerous testing and retesting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dror Bar-Natan, Maya Bar-Hillel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil Kalai</ENAMEX>--have found the
serious methodological flaws the peer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> missed. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay et</ENAMEX> al.
note, the codes are hypersensitive to small changes in the data. Excluding only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> rabbis essentially eliminates the effect, for example.

            The core of their
critique focuses on the manner in which the rabbis were named in the
Witztum-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rips-Rosenberg</ENAMEX> paper. The names of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medieval rabbis</ENAMEX> are not fixed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that modern names are; the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses Ben Maimon</ENAMEX>, for example, is
often called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maimonides</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rambam</ENAMEX>. Searching for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELS</ENAMEX>,
therefore, required choices about what names to use for each particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witztum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rips</ENAMEX> asked a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to compile appropriate appellations for
each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>, but the rebuttal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> argues that the process used by this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> was sufficiently subjective as to bias the results. (There is
something indisputably bizarre in the spectacle of distinguished mathematicians
squabbling about the correct names of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rabbis</ENAMEX>.)

            In order to demonstrate that "data tuning" alone could
account for the effect, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-authors</ENAMEX> made their own alternative
list of appellations for the rabbis, a list they describe as "of quality
commensurate" with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witztum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rips'</ENAMEX>. This alternative list produced no
effect in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genesis</ENAMEX> but a huge effect in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> . Then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co.</ENAMEX> sought to produce the most accurate list they could, using their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>. With this list, they found no statistical evidence of codes in any
text.

            Further evidence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tuning</ENAMEX> was found in other decisions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Witztum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rips</ENAMEX> made about their data. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of the first paper erred, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> claim, in how they
chose which rabbis to include. The rabbis were supposed to be chosen by an
objective criterion--the length of their entries in a particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">encyclopedia</ENAMEX>--but because of the "careless manner" in which this was carried
out, rabbis were included who should not have been, while others were wrongly
excluded. Birth and death dates were also flawed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> collected dates
from a wide variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, but apparently did not establish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> rules to
decide among disputed dates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-authors</ENAMEX> also claim that aspects
of the experimental design (such as the way distances were measured between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rabbis</ENAMEX> and dates) were tuned. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> varied the
experimental method, the choices of dates, and the way dates were expressed,
the results almost invariably deteriorated.

            The rebuttal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> note still other problems in the
original paper. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>'s text has varied over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, and when
dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELS</ENAMEX>, tiny variations can be ruinous. Yet when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay et</ENAMEX> al.
compared the text <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Witztum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rips</ENAMEX> used to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> texts--some of which are
probably more historically reliable--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witztum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rips</ENAMEX> text produced
the strongest results. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> also note that even using the flawed
Witztum-Rips methodology, no book of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Torah besides Genesis</ENAMEX> shows any effect
at all.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>
do not accuse the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of fraud, speculate on how their data-tuning
took place, or ask whether the tuning was consciously done. But they conclude
that all the choices available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witztum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rips</ENAMEX> created "wiggle room," thus
permitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' biases to corrupt the results. "All of our many earnest
experiments produced results in line with random chance," they conclude. "In
light of these findings, we believe that [the] 'challenging puzzle' has been
solved." For all but the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>, the publication of the rebuttal paper
seems likely to end the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> codes debate.

            But for the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>, of course, the phenomenon was
always <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a mere</NUMEX> "puzzle," and they are not about to roll over. Rips was
sufficiently enraged by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Science</ENAMEX> 's acceptance of the rebuttal
paper that he retained a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, who advised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> that "the accusations
in the article about to be published ... are untrue and libelous of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rips</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rips</ENAMEX> sought a delay in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> and the chance to respond to the critique in
the same issue. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Science</ENAMEX> rejected his request but will
consider publishing his formal comments in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a later</TIMEX> issue.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rips</ENAMEX> contends that
the rebuttal paper misrepresents the original experiment's methods and that it
ignores subsequent tests that he regards as immune from data-tuning charges. He
wrote me in an e-mail, "I believe that the evidence for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah Codes</ENAMEX> is now
stronger than ever. I find the paper by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> more than extremely
unfair."

            Those who want to believe in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> codes will
always be able to find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELS</ENAMEX> that impress them. But there's a difference now. To
believe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that the almighty wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> is once again, as it should be,
a matter of faith. It's not a conclusion that can be forced on me--or anyone
else--by statistical science.

         
      
   
