
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">295</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;The Gielgud, the Bad, and the Ugly&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Following an
outcry from, among others, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Academy Award-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gielgud</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian Institution</ENAMEX> has canceled a program. What was the program, and the
problem?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 294</ENAMEX>)-- "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whose Tiara Is It, Anyway?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               Facing sinking ratings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX> pageant last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> announced a change in format, to make the telecast more entertaining for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. Name that change.
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">girls</ENAMEX> will promenade in bathing suits holding signs with their personal phone
numbers over their heads."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfa-Betty Olsen</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contestants</ENAMEX> will compete against <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mickey Blue Eyes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Grant</ENAMEX> in
the controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Run Like a Girl</ENAMEX>' event."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Ross</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Actual <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, poverty-stricken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, etc., for them to succor, as
promised."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Oder</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX> will, after being crowned, open up her head and show us all
the little gears and circuits inside."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            "It
will be held in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> woods, and the telecast will consist of jittery
footage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX>' slow descent into madness as they are
systematically stalked and disappeared/disqualified by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barker</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX>
Saucier
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            The way I figure it,
there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways to go with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s question. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, as many of you did,
is to take the competition improbably downscale--mixing implausible amounts of
sex and/or violence into the competition. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oddly</ENAMEX>, given the results of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> made the obvious leap and added farm
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> as well.) The other, largely neglected option: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imply</ENAMEX> that the
competition, as currently configured, is improbably upscale. Perhaps the
pageant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> could prune the readings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ionesco</ENAMEX> and the madrigal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recital</ENAMEX>, or they could finally stop forcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX> to defend their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theses</ENAMEX>. Or they could replace the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>-translation portion of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>
with--oh, I don't know, something frivolous. A swimsuit portion, or perhaps an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX> gown competition. Everyone likes evening gowns.

            
               Congenial
Answer
            

            The pageant's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>
are cutting back on the number of performances from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> semifinalists to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>,
and they'll be backed by professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>. According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , pageant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Beck</ENAMEX> has found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> get bored
watching the amateur talent routines. "You can flip to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 or 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and
find great entertainment," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX> says. "If, by great entertainment, you mean
programs starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dweezil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmet Zappa</ENAMEX>, or the umpteenth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery Channel</ENAMEX>
special on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>," he did not add. In other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> news, single
diners tip best.

            
               You Be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critic</ENAMEX>!
Extra
            

            As the best-known film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> (and the only one ever to win a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>), the erstwhile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">broadcasting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Siskel</ENAMEX> holds a position of unique influence in
film. Play along as we rank the following movies, from best to worst, according
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner, buffalo</ENAMEX>)

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrival</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Sheen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>)

            
               Booty Call (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie</ENAMEX>
Foxx, booty)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushmore</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, prep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>)

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Heads</ENAMEX> in a Duffel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bag</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Pesci</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> in a duffel bag)

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usual Suspects</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Spacey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyser Soze</ENAMEX>)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Velvet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dennis</ENAMEX>
Hopper, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Dreams</ENAMEX>")

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghost</ENAMEX> and the

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosencrantz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guildenstern Are Dead</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Roth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard</ENAMEX>)

            
               Answer
            

            They are in the correct
order. Each film received a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> less than the one that precedes it. Which
means that, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Booty Call</ENAMEX> was twice as good as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX>
Velvet . And that he walked out of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Usual Suspects</ENAMEX> saying, "It was
good, but it was no <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> ."

            
               Weeklong Extra
            

            A headline from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> issue equal-access guidelines."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to find, in an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, a less
enticing headline. Deadline is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. Answers will be posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> as contestants
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jell-O</ENAMEX>-wrestle while answering difficult questions from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis Philbin</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
