
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yo-Yo Peace Plan</ENAMEX> 

            With
peace talks on a yo-yo, the previously <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>-obsessed editorial pages largely
ignore the subject. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>
venture forth with scolding opinions on the peace plan. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s admission that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> may not now come under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> is irresponsible; only the probably tardy deployment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> forces
can stop it being disastrous." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal Independent</ENAMEX> : "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>]or should we crack open the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> if, or
when, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> finally signs on the dotted line. The aftermath of
such an agreement may prove to be almost as nightmarish as what came before."
It concluded, "The military victory will, however, pale into insignificance by
comparison with the task of recreating a civil society in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. Above all,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> needs to win its own battles against intolerance. That will be a much
more difficult war to fight."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s papers showed no reluctance to pontificate on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
elections. The slowness of the vote count, reported <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> , resulted in the tabulation of less
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 116 million</NUMEX> votes by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, and the
Straits
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> reported
that "[s]ome tempers flared over the pace of the vote count." The government
had promised a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> count by that time. An election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> that the final result wouldn't be announced until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>. There
were also reports of vote-buying by the incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golkar Party of</ENAMEX>
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> and of "logistical problems" such as defective ballots
and "indelible ink" (designed to prevent multiple voting), which, in practice,
"washed off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' thumbs in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>."

            An
editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX> declared the elections "a triumph for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and democracy," but in light of predictions that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golkar</ENAMEX> would
poll strongly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s outer islands and might be able to hold on to
power with the help of small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said, "It would
be a hollow victory and a terrible irony if our exercise in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> failed to
produce the very goal of the whole process: Voting out the status quo and
putting a proreform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in its place."

            
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, the state ideology of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pancasila</ENAMEX>"
declares it to be a secular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. As a piece in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> noted, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, business interests and foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are watching to see whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> gain ground"
in the polling. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> contesting the election are
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Muslim</ENAMEX>-based, and some want to make Islam the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s established religion.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the final weeks</TIMEX> of the campaign, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> called on the faithful
to support <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>-affiliated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, which was seen by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> as an
attempt to undermine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megawati Sukarnoputri</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesian Democratic Party</ENAMEX>-Struggle and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sukarno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founding president</ENAMEX>. The story reported that there was a clash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in
Sulawesi between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, who questioned whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian Muslims</ENAMEX>
would accept a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Megawati</ENAMEX>. The Straits
Times editorialized that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indonesians</ENAMEX> are free to vote for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> they
want, but that choice should be based on what unites them as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX> with
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, not what separates them."

            
Although it now appears that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> election the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Congress</ENAMEX> failed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> seat to reach the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> majority that
would have given it the power to change the constitution, editorials supported
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President-elect Thabo Mbeki</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer of India</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">welcomed Mbeki</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Africanist</ENAMEX>" agenda: "Immediately after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dismantling of Apartheid</ENAMEX>, [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX>'s main message was one of
reconciliation among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mbeki</ENAMEX>'s must be to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africanize</ENAMEX>. It
must be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mbeki</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> and responsibility to take a firmer stance on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
empowerment in every shape or form." Giving a positive spin to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mbeki</ENAMEX>'s
perceived "grayness" compared with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer</ENAMEX> said,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> will be missed, of course. On the other hand, perhaps, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>
may even be able to get a clearer view of its harsh realities, and its uphill
tasks, without his overarching charisma. As we in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> know only too well, in
this process, charisma, sometimes, can play saboteur."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> not faring so
well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX>, who celebrates her "official
birthday" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> attacked the "dour new image" of the monarch on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>'s new
coins, even mentioning her "double chin." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> complained that the
money carries "the visage of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>"--hardly surprising since the queen
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX>. Meanwhile, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press of Christchurch</ENAMEX> was underwhelming in its support
of the sovereign. Under the headline "Why we still need the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royals</ENAMEX>," a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> wrote, "It's not so much that we've gone off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Royal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, we
have merely outgrown them. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>] is such an integral part of our
history and our culture, I cannot envisage us formally breaking all our ties.
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> did not push us to the brink, nothing will."

         
      
   
