
   
   
      
         
             Tarzan

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Jung</ENAMEX> once observed that it is easier to
discern the presence of archetypes from the collective subconscious in works of
pulp fiction by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Rider Haggard</ENAMEX> than it is in literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masterpieces</ENAMEX>. If only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jung</ENAMEX> had put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Rice Burroughs</ENAMEX> on his
depth-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX>, creating
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarzan</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters beings</ENAMEX> as profoundly mythical--and as
stereotypically superficial--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Vader</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Skywalker</ENAMEX>'s saga, the
tale of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> mixes and matches motifs from the archetype-haunted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dreamtime</ENAMEX> of
humanity anatomized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jung</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jung</ENAMEX>'s disciple, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Campbell</ENAMEX>. The tale of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> raised in secret by adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luke Skywalker</ENAMEX>) is
fused with the story of the feral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romulus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remus</ENAMEX>,
Enkidu, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mowgli, Pecos Bill</ENAMEX>) in the romance of the orphaned <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> lord raised
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foster family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apes</ENAMEX>.

            The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> is really an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lord</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Greystoke</ENAMEX>, to be precise--was central to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>' conception of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. In the pulp fiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>, as in pulp fiction of any
period, timeless archetypes rub shoulders with the vulgar prejudices of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. In the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s race/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>/gender
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> can easily find a key to the racial, social, and sexual anxieties of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 20 th -century</TIMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. When the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> books were published, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Empire</ENAMEX> ruled the waves, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> had recently joined the ranks of imperial powers, and white supremacy
was the norm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and throughout the world. Confidence in the
innate superiority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Caucasian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>--and, within that race, of its
Anglo-Saxon variant--coexisted with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> about the yellow peril and black
"savagery."

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major characters
in the oeuvre of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Rice Burroughs</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tarzan of the Apes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carter</ENAMEX> never made it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> the way that
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> in the jungle jockstrap did, it is worth reviving him to make a
point. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carter</ENAMEX> were both exemplars of Anglo-Saxon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masculinity</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarzan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to an aristocratic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>, an upper-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginian</ENAMEX> by birth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> stories can be
viewed as experiments--take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> ruling class, strip him
of all his advantages, and put him in a radically different environment, in
order that the innate superiority of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> may be demonstrated. Whether in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> (the symbol of precivilized savagery) or on an old, desiccated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> (the
symbol of overrefinement and cultural exhaustion), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> proves
that he is royalty. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarzan</ENAMEX> becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jungle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carter</ENAMEX> weds the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>. Space, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>, is a metaphor for time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> represent the era of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-American</ENAMEX> civilization, at the midpoint
between prehistoric barbarism and post-historic decadence.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> can be seen in the way that he redeemed
the imagery of savagery for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> ape<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-man</ENAMEX>. In the mythology of white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supremacy</ENAMEX>, even before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Darwin</ENAMEX>, black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> and other nonwhites were
assimilated to apes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>, in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> , finds credible the rumor that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women mate</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orangutans</ENAMEX>). In much <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> - and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 20 th -century</TIMEX> pulp
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fiction</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Indians</ENAMEX> and black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have a mystical rapport with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> alike understood arose from their proximity
on the evolutionary scale. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs' Tarzan</ENAMEX> is closer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> than
the black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> who live nearby. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great White Hope</ENAMEX> is at once more
civilized and more savage than the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX>"--he is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lone Ranger</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonto</ENAMEX>. With Tarzan monopolizing the highest and lowest rungs of the
Chain of Being, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX>" find themselves deprived of the one asset that
racist mythology attributed to them, closeness to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, leaving them
without any particular function in the economy of kitsch literature, except to
be rescued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rogue elephants</ENAMEX> and the occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch doctor</ENAMEX>.

            When first published, the
Tarzan stories provided a largely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> with
a fantasy version of the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Guy</ENAMEX>, the virile aristocrat, who, far
from being effete and degenerate, could go <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ape</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ascot</ENAMEX>. Something like
this vision inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, the asthmatic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> patrician who
turned himself into a cowboy and, as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-president</ENAMEX>, nearly died while
exploring a tributary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, in an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> that might have
been scripted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>--a professed admirer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX>--is the
Tarzan of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>: A patrician <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yalie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord Greystoke</ENAMEX>), and at the same time a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> redneck (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX>), engaged in wildcatting (could there be a more
metaphorically resonant term?). By jumping out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
continues to battle the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wimp Factor</ENAMEX>. Perhaps he should swing from vines as
well. By contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>, a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who, unlike his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, sat out the
war of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> mythos, then, depends on a balance of
tensions--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between Tarzan</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ape</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-Man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greystoke</ENAMEX>, between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>, between civilization and savagery. Play down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the equation,
and the meaning of this whole system of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">pre-World War II</ENAMEX> social stereotypes
collapses.

            This is what happened
when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> got hold of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> story. Beginning with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>
Weissmuller films, the jungle began eclipsing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">manor</ENAMEX>. Tarzan became
simply a feral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, a white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mowgli</ENAMEX>. The genre changed to pastoral: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> became the equivalents of the innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shepherds</ENAMEX> and shepherdesses of
Hellenistic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> pastoral fiction, striving to preserve their
natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">idyll</ENAMEX> from corruption by civilization. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pastoral Tarzan</ENAMEX> need not be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English lord</ENAMEX>. He need not even be white. A black or brown or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Tarzan</ENAMEX> would
defeat the whole point of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX> mythos but would not be out of place in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> or TV versions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s new animated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarzan</ENAMEX> is the politically correct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> of several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood Tarzans</ENAMEX>--a facsimile of a facsimile.
Gone is the social Darwinist worldview that underpinned the original. In the
prologue we see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarzan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, but we do not learn they are titled. Indeed,
from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> at assembling a tree <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we might think that they are,
not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Greystoke</ENAMEX>, but Mr. and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> (as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crusoe</ENAMEX> or Swiss
Family). The embarrassing problem of what to do with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX>" in a
post-racist age is solved by eliminating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX> altogether. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s
gorillas live in a jungle uninhabited by human beings, until Europeans
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intrude</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyfied Tarzan</ENAMEX> is
such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp</ENAMEX> that he is not allowed to kill anything or anybody, although our
Paleolithic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> is permitted to use martial arts techniques in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-defense</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> of the movie are a homicidal (and simiocidal)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cheetah</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil White</ENAMEX> Male without which no PC epic
would be complete. But when the time comes for them to die, both do themselves
in accidentally while fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cheetah</ENAMEX> falls atop a spearhead that
Tarzan happens to be holding, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman inadvertently</ENAMEX> hangs himself on
jungle vines. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our day</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
refuses to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> into combat because one of them might actually get
hurt.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epic of Gilgamesh</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> lures <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enkidu</ENAMEX> away
from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal companions</ENAMEX>. Once he has slept with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> refuse
to associate with him; he cannot go home again. Masculine wildness is overcome
by civilized femininity. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarzan</ENAMEX> film, nature is feminine and
civilization masculine. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> is not only post-imperial, post-racist,
and post-classist but also post-masculine. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">momma</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foster mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kala</ENAMEX> (whose voice is provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Close</ENAMEX>), remains on the
scene after he reaches adulthood. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> introduces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane to Kala</ENAMEX>, he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grovels</ENAMEX> and whimpers before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">disapproving Ma Gorilla</ENAMEX>.

            Halfway through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film, Tarzan</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX>-era <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enkidu</ENAMEX>, lured by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>, is prepared to follow her
back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. But then, having learned how evil civilized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englishmen</ENAMEX> can be,
Tarzan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> (in the PC universe, old and feeble white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tolerable</ENAMEX>) decide to renounce civilized society for the jungle. There, by happy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coincidence</ENAMEX>, the two alpha <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerchak</ENAMEX> the bull <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ape</ENAMEX> and the evil English
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hunter</ENAMEX>) are gone, clearing the way for the utopia of beta males and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> is now nominally in control, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kala</ENAMEX> the
Ape-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Empress Dowager of the Jungle</ENAMEX>, is really in charge. At movie's
end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> move in with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and her furry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, like '90s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX>
who have given up and moved back home. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>'s widowed human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wed Tarzan</ENAMEX>'s widowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> (so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Baptist Convention</ENAMEX> should
be worried about bestiality but not homosexuality).

            If the pulp fiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Rice Burroughs</ENAMEX> gives us a
glimpse into the often appalling collective unconscious of white-supremacist
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> will provide a similar service
to future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> pondering the equally weird mentality of feminized and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. If the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarzan</ENAMEX> celebrated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> male
proving his superiority over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> red in tooth and claw, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s version
embodies the ideology that vilifies the "white male" and idealizes the feminine
(human and ape) and the wilderness imagined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nature Store</ENAMEX>.
Me, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarzan</ENAMEX>. You, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nature Good</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civilization Bad</ENAMEX>. Girls good. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> bad.

            Rumor has it that the next object of touchy-feely
bowdlerization by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beowulf</ENAMEX>. No doubt in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> version, Beowulf
and the feisty, coed-army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior-princess</ENAMEX> who inevitably will be written into
the script as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> will befriend a misunderstood <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grendel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grendel</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mom</ENAMEX> (it's not easy being green). For my part, I plan to endorse the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX>
boycott of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> is evil--not because it's turning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, but because it's turning them into wimps.

         
      
   
