
   
   
      
         
            How the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa Electronic Markets Work</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> often talk about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s stock going
up or down. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa Electronic Markets</ENAMEX> (operated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Iowa</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry B. Tippie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College of Business</ENAMEX>), this really happens. You can bet on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> by buying stock in him or her. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> wins, you get a
dollar for each share you own. If he loses, your shares are worthless. The
amount you pay for each share depends on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX>'s confidence that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> will win. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is doing well in the race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are
confident that their stock will pay off, so they charge more for it when they
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX>. When he's doing poorly, they charge less. If you buy shares in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> when his stock is low, you don't have to wait for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX> to
cash in. You can sell your shares at a profit as soon as his stock
improves.

            Right now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> markets are trading stock in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> contests: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> presidential nomination (click here to see the prospectus and latest quotes), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
presidential nomination (click here ), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> race (click here ), and which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> will control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> (click here). "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Pool</ENAMEX>" reports the latest share price for each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> as of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, along with 
                  Slate
               's
analysis of who's up, who's down, and why. For updates or more complete
information, visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa Electronic Markets</ENAMEX> site.

         
      
   
