
   
   
      
         
            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Goes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of state ever to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>,
arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> describing
him in a profile as an "insipid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who inspires indifference." But
not for everyone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> also said that his visit "is likely to rank with those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolae Ceaucescu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirohito</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> as among the most controversial
of the Queen's reign." It said it would be "the focus of large demonstrations
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s suppression of human rights and its occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>." The
paper noted that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> still have no idea whether he will be
furious and cut short his program, or whether he will ride out the protests as
he did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Post</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX>, the spiritual cult recently
banned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, planned to carry out spiritual exercises in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s visit to show him how peaceful the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is.
"We hope to be able to practise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> of our exercises," one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">organizers</ENAMEX> told the paper. "If it is raining, we may not be able to do all of
them because some require us to sit on the ground." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> is seeking
permission to hold a candlelight vigil in the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
while the queen is hosting a banquet for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckingham Palace</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> said, however, that larger demonstrations were expected in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> goes there at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the week</TIMEX>. It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shui Li</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation of Democratic China</ENAMEX>, as saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
will be a key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to hold protests because there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> there and a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>."

            
Improbably, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> 's main angle on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> was that it would
"bring brighter prospects to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> financial service industry." This was
how the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government newspaper</ENAMEX> introduced an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, who said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> was "very keen" that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> should join
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overenthusiastically</ENAMEX> described the handover of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> as "the
most successful joint venture we have ever done with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> or anybody else." In
an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> also supported <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s renewed bid
to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> but said that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> should speak more firmly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> and human rights.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said that since "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> consensus behind its role on the global
stage is weakening," <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> should no longer be content "to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> take
the lead in handling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> ran an article by its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
correspondent saying that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX> would be "pivotal" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. "If successful, working visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Summers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Under-Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pickering</ENAMEX>
could go a long way in getting day-to-day links back to the level they were
before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX>'s bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. But it
quoted senior administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> as saying that the situation was still
"highly fragile." One said, "In some ways we feel like recovering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX>.
We are taking everything <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one day</TIMEX> at a time."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> in an interview that his recent meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> had been "positive and constructive" and "very important for the
improvement and development of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> relations." But he said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> "must take further action to remove all the severe negative effects of
the bombing" and must "stop its arms sales to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, and refrain from creating
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX> on the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>." (On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> because it
wanted to send a signal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>. It said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> was
originally on a list of prohibited targets but was removed after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> forces
discovered it was operating as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> army re-broadcasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>.)

            In the
same interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rees-Mogg</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> claimed to have been a "good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panchen Lama</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>
and, after his death, said he went to his temple there and--"despite the thin
air"--spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> meditating about his life. But this didn't prevent him
taking an unyielding line on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> issue. Another subject broached by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was the future of the Internet. He described it has having
great advantages for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, but said he hoped that this
generation would be able to protect its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> from things on the
Internet that "are not good." He also said that "no matter how quickly the
internet develops, it can never take the place of the relationship between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ... computers are machines, and machines don't have feelings."

            These
themes were also debated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>
television. Questioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Paxman</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s leading TV
interviewers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> said that "none of the work being done on software today
holds the potential to create a truly intelligent device," but he was less
reassuring about protecting the young against stuff that was "not good." While
he wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s software to be used for things that are "positive and
good," he admitted that he didn't "have control over exactly how that's done."
(But what's "not good"? Paxman was talking about pornography; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> may well
have been thinking about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX>.) In an article for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paxman</ENAMEX> wrote that he found it
"quite impossible to reconcile this public <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> [fabulously rich, powerful,
and therefore an object of much hatred] with the awkward, shy, nasal character
I found seated opposite me."

         
      
   
