
   
   
      
         
             Show Me the Numbers

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential campaign has already begun--a
little early for my taste. The speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> are busily at work spinning out
their anodyne alliterations, their balanced bromides, their cautious clarion
calls. They have already produced for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Compassionate</ENAMEX>
Conservatism" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prosperity with a Purpose</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> seems to be ditching
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reinventing Government</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Inventing the Internet</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Global Warming</ENAMEX>," "The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> Way," and all those other nerdy notions. He is aiming directly at the
soft American heart by offering himself as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friend of the Family</ENAMEX>."

            With the change of a few words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s
compassionate conservatisms could have been delivered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s qualification to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friend of the Family</ENAMEX> is that he
isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>--a qualification he shares with quite a few other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            After a while, the
campaign will embrace the "specifics." There will be speeches or position
papers about education, the environment, the budget, and other issues conveying
information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' intentions. But it will still be in the
domain of advertising--full of "new and improved!" claims, like the ones you
find on cereal boxes.

            I had direct experience with this process during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> presidential campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> accompanied him on the campaign and advised him about what to say to get
elected. The other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, on which I served, stayed home and wrote papers about
how he should govern after he got elected. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> did not communicate
with each other, fearing, I suppose, diversion from their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different
objectives.

            I don't complain much
about this deviousness and evasiveness, and I don't expect it to change. I have
only a modest request. Before the campaign concludes, I would like to see more
attention to the numbers. Many of the policy issues confronting us hinge on
quantities--on how much. Whether a condition is a problem requiring government
remedies depends on how much of the condition there is. And whether a proposed
policy is worth its cost or is likely to be effective also depends on its
size.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> we already hear relates to taxation. The number
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>--no new taxes. At some point we will get another number--a percentage
by which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> proposes to cut income tax rates. That is supposed to
tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> how much better off he will be if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is elected. For
that purpose, obviously, the bigger the number the better. But the tax numbers
need to be seen in national and historical perspective. From the national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">standpoint</ENAMEX>, lower taxes are not necessarily better than higher ones. In the
been <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18.8 percent</NUMEX> of GDP plus or minus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX> percentage points. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surprisingly</ENAMEX>,
the low point came in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> administration, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
administration.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> should tell us where, inside or outside that
range, they would want federal tax receipts to be. That would give us some clue
to the national economic significance of the difference between them.

            The tax question
immediately raises the question of the budget surplus. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> we had a
rule for the proper relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> expenditures and
revenues--or we pretended to have a rule. The rule was that the budget should
be in balance, meaning no deficit. But we are beyond that now. We have in
prospect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> in which, with existing policies, there will be a surplus,
and there is a question about how big that surplus should be. That is a
question neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> nor the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want to face.
In his recent budget, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> tried to conceal the fact that there was a
surplus, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, with their talk about a "lockbox" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, have confused everyone, probably including themselves. But the
subject is important, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> should tell us how much, if any,
surplus they would plan to have.

            As long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> continues to bask in prosperity,
there will be no debate about general economic policy during this campaign.
Everyone will agree on the most important requirement for sustaining
prosperity, which is to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> healthy. So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are likely
to focus, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> has already done, on those who do not share in the
general prosperity--those who have been left behind. But there are hard
quantitative questions about this. How many are left behind? Is it a major
problem? We have official estimates of the proportion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> who are
in poverty. It is something like <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> and has been near that for the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>. But there are other estimates--equally plausible, which may not be
very plausible at all--saying that the poverty rate has been falling sharply
and is now <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 1 percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>. Which of these estimates you believe
makes a big difference to the priority you give to this problem. So, if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are going to make a big issue about helping those who are falling
behind, I would like to hear their views about how many there are.

            I give examples only from
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of policy with which I have some familiarity. But one can also see the
value of quantification in many other areas: health care, education, the
environment, and others.

            Asking political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to quantify their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> may
seem unrealistic because they don't want to pin themselves down and because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> will tune out. But there have been cases where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> gave us
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">relevant</ENAMEX> numbers--and with success. I think particularly of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reagan</ENAMEX>
campaign. Serious questions were being raised about whether the policies he was
proposing for taxes, expenditures, and the deficit added up. He then made a
speech in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1980</TIMEX> in which he laid out the quantities involved and the
underlying assumptions. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including me, criticized parts of the
story. But I think it helped to support the idea that he knew what he was
doing. In a limited way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> speech served as guidance for his policies
after he came into office. So, I don't think the request for more numbers is
simply the idiosyncrasy of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
