
   
   
      
         
            Green Estate

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klein</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Tue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>

            Yes, I had some nice things to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
campaign, especially the bold and clear speeches he's made on a variety of
issues (particularly health care), but I've also had some nice things to say in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. I think they're all running
suprisingly substantive campaigns and deserve some credit for that. But I
haven't "endorsed" anyone, or come close. (In fact, I have no idea whom I'll be
voting for).

            (To reply, click
here.)

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> .]
            

            
               Subject:
My Own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Estate</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John B.</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Tue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>

            My own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a year</TIMEX> after I was
born; I never really knew him. A career military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, he left my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and
his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> little in an economic sense, but the mementos of his life,
including photographs, his military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">decorations</ENAMEX> and the memories of those whose
lives he touched, are cherished to this day. Even in the midst of his loss, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> should be grateful to have enjoyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> into their
old age; even if we don't realize it at the time, each and every moment that we
have with our loved ones should be considered, and treated as, a blessing.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Class Warfare</ENAMEX>? Try Progress
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dupont</ENAMEX>
Date: Tue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct 26</TIMEX>

            I enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Stein</ENAMEX>'s TV show, but the essay is
troubling. The tribute to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is touching and well-deserved, but his
views on the estate tax are appalling.

            At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX> point does he tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> the size of the
initial exemption. In fact, estates must exceed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $600,00</NUMEX> before ANY tax
is applied. It is my impression that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1 percent to 2 percent</NUMEX> of all estates
are subject to any tax. This is not class warfare. This is sensible economic
and public policy. Many of the wealthy realized the benefits of disbursing
wealth at death (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Carnegie</ENAMEX>, e.g.). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Stein</ENAMEX> should know better than to make
the occasion of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s death into a political complaint.

            (To reply, click
here.)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estates</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX> Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall C. Sanders</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Tue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>

            I am in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of estate tax planning. With a
modicum of planning, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> could have seriously reduced or
eliminated the amount of taxes that were payable by his estate. It is also true
that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> certainly deserved to share in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s largess,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> and any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> were merely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the "lucky sperm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>."

            We all take something out of society. We all should
put something back into society. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, whom I disagreed with on a
good many things, did put something into society, besides taxes. But assume he
had not; should he or anyone else be allowed to accumulate substantial wealth
or should it be filtered back into the society from whence it came and from
whence it might do more public good? I will leave that question for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               To
read a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on estate taxes between former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Packwood</ENAMEX> and economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Glassman</ENAMEX>, click .
            

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> as Cultural Badge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">varese</ENAMEX> layzer

            
               Date: Tue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Baron</ENAMEX> writes with reference to another
minority language that "[c]ultural-loyalty movements like the class in Navajo
tend to spring up when cultural preservation is in danger, and their record of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> is not impressive."

            I would add that it depends on who starts the
class. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX> is a minority language closely associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> culture and
sometimes with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> nationalism. Some of the most positive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> are
those who have acquired what they call "prison <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>." Not necessarily studied
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, this is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> learned on a need-to-know basis,
but a cultural need to know. If these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> don't fashion this
connection to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irishness</ENAMEX> they feel otherwise culturally deprived, to a greater
or lesser degree. The most enthusiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> I have ever met are not native
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> who grow up in comfortable government-subsidized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-only
neighborhoods in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Galway</ENAMEX>, but those who have clawed their way to a brand of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cultural Irishness</ENAMEX> that they choose to mark by the use of language.

            So I wonder if there isn't a proviso that
cultural-loyalty movements of language revival may be likely to fail if they
are instituted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, but perhaps more likely to succeed if they
are instituted in spite of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Because state-supported <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> has a much more temperamental success rate. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there seem to feel that their culture is plenty intact without this
old-fashioned language dragging them further back behind the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Is
Irish a special language case?

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebonics</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Techno</ENAMEX> Babble
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From:
Keter Tzadik

            
               Date: Tue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>

            I and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> happen to be Ebonics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>.
We are all young, urban "heads" ( heads is "ebonics" for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>") who
run a multimedia <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. We speak our own urbanized form of computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tech</ENAMEX>-speak a lot of the time because we find that terms like "information
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superhighway</ENAMEX>" and "surf the web" are just not compatible with an urban
lifestyle. How many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> have been surfing? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naw'meen</ENAMEX>?

            I myself speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Ebonics</ENAMEX>, so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Proper English</ENAMEX>,
some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>, and media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">techno-babble</ENAMEX>. I've blended
all of these together into my own urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> language. I think that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to communicate so there should be a shared mode of communication,
but, acting like so-called proper <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American English</ENAMEX> is more than a "slang
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dialect</ENAMEX>" itself is just wrong. I mean, we do NOT speak the Queen's <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, nor
would we want to. Further, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> itself is just a bastardized version of
other languages like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, and eventually Sanskrit.

            So before the next time one of these language
elitists rolls up into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-11</ENAMEX> and talks trash about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> behind the
counter speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">broken English</ENAMEX>, he should instead thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> because
his precious <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language was "invented" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX>' ancestors.

            Shalom.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Architectural Digest</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masses</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX>
Date: Fri <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct 22</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>, and her many imitators, have taught us how
to make our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>, the many domestic arts and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sciences</ENAMEX> were divided between "homey" but provincial cooking and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX>-style
decorating, on the one hand, and the haute <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Child</ENAMEX> and
decorating by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Architectural Digest</ENAMEX> on the other. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> taught the
new, educated and traveled middle class how to find a middle ground for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decorating</ENAMEX> and cooking. Her style remains essentially that.

            If you disagree--then compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>
Living with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Architectural Digest</ENAMEX> . If the great unwashed wish to
serve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> in bottles and an open bag of chips and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velveeta</ENAMEX> on triskits on the
picnic table out back, as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>-inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delicacies-crudit√</ENAMEX>©s and
margaritas, so what? Why does she need to be so vociferously criticized? Why do
the hoi polloi feel so threatened by her and her style? She never feels
threatened by THEM and she has NEVER, despite what the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parodies</ENAMEX> say,
preached AGAINST a more casual style of entertaining or said her way was the
ONLY way.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Said</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
                ""

            
               From:
JoelBrian

            
               Date: Sat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>

            I'm sure your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> know that the very name
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>" is no accident. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>" has represented domesticity for almost two
millennia, when she complained to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> was
spending all her time listening at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the feet</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, while she, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>, had to
work serving. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>' answer is classic: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>, thou art careful and
troubled about many things. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing is needful; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> hath chosen that
good part, which shall not be taken away from her" [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Luke 10</ENAMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38-42</NUMEX>]. Thus "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>"
represents intellect and devotion, which trumps domestic chores. But nowadays
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary"</ENAMEX> won't get very far with an IPO.

            (To reply, click here .)

         
      
   
