
   
   
      
         
            Getting Past the Past

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I was adopted and grew up in a very abusive
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. I don't seem to be able to get past the bitterness and resentment I feel
for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> I have wanted to confront them about the beatings I
took, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s drinking, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s complete indifference. At 30 years
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>, I am sober and reasonably successful, despite having not completed my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree in accounting. I've had my own struggle with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>, and
I have difficulty concentrating on much else besides how I grew up--though I'm
trying to get past it.
            

            
               Meanwhile, probably to assuage their guilt, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> constantly ask me questions such as, "Did we raise you right?" It is hard
to bite my tongue and lie to them, telling them they spent plenty of quality
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> with me, etc. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> has been very supportive and has suggested that
when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> open the door with their questions that I should take advantage
of it and unload.
            

            
               What's your
take?
            

            

               --Closed door in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Closed</ENAMEX>,

            It certainly sounds as though your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have
accumulated many debits in your emotional ledger. Prudie salutes you for
pulling yourself together considering some overwhelming obstacles. It's clear
that you need to unburden yourself, either to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> or to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>.
Until all the resentment gets out, it will eat away at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> it is stored
in: you.

            It is interesting, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks meaningful, that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> continually pose these questions.
At some level of consciousness, they know the answers. This might be their way
of asking you to give voice to your feelings and to confront them. You
certainly have nothing to lose. Next time such a question is posed, ask them if
they really want the answer. If they say yes, then try to hold yourself
together and, as calmly as you can, give a truthful response. Tears are OK;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hollering</ENAMEX> is not. This may be what they've been waiting for so that they can
talk about the past and apologize. They , as well as you, might need to
give the disastrous past an airing. A repair is possible, but if it
doesn't happen, you've unburdened yourself, let in some sunlight, and
lost nothing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is for realism and honesty, and hopes the balance sheet
comes out with an improved bottom line.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, encouragingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> of marriage and raising our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I have decided to stop torturing each other. We broke
the news of the divorce gently to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, and now are in the
process of dividing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> of assets. Because we see no sense in causing more
financial distress than necessary, we are still under the same roof while we
work out the details.
            

            
               The problem is: We
are not enemies. It seems no one can stand this, and whenever we encounter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, they invariably ask personal questions to try to get each
of us to speak ill of the other. As we don't do this, the next comment is
always something like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, then, why are you getting divorced<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" The worst
one was, "I don't think you really want a divorce, or you would have gotten one
by now." Please, do you have an answer for these "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-wishers</ENAMEX>" that would not
require giving them private and personal information?
            

            

               --shan
            

            Dear sha,

            Who are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>--a bunch of divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks it's marvelous that you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> are able
to unhitch in a civilized, amiable manner. Unfortunately, it has become a
commonplace for about-to-be exes to badmouth each other to whomever will
listen. Friendly divorces are somewhat unusual, but possible. (Prudie
has even had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.)

            The next time one of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yentas</ENAMEX> tries to goad you into dishing your soon-to-be-former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX>, just
smile and say, "Oh, I am saving our life together for my memoirs." That kind of
non-answer always conveys the subtext: nothing forthcoming here; on to the next
subject.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, admiringly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               For my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>'s
birthday <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, I took her out to a very expensive restaurant and bought
her a nice gift. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One month later</TIMEX>, for my birthday, she took me to a relatively
cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and gave me a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beanie Baby</ENAMEX>. (I hate stuffed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>,
and she knows that.) We are both in similar financial situations, and I felt
cheated. Her birthday is coming up soon. Should I take her out again, or just
give her a small gift and forget our tradition of the birthday dinner?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living With Selfish</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Liv</ENAMEX>,

            
               If you are sure
that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of you are in financially similar circumstances and also that she
knows of your dislike for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stuffed animals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you send out for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for her birthday dinner and give her back the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beanie Baby</ENAMEX> with a
funny card. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> says this because the roomie is obviously cheap--and maybe
even hostile. If she remarks on the "tradition" being different for her
birthday <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> than last, simply tell her that you are following her lead
about what level of celebration is appropriate. This may totally louse up the
living situation, so be prepared. Because you refer to her as "selfish,"
however, you may not wish to keep this arrangement going forever. Maybe stick a
birthday candle into the fortune cookie.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, reciprocally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               During college, my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> was a fellow
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>. We operated a small business together and continued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> contact
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 10 years</TIMEX>. Things have gone smoothly for for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>: He moved to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, and has worked as a high-ranking government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. Since
his move, however, our friendship has hit some snags. (He hangs out with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pompous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the political establishment, has grown arrogant, and doesn't
have time to return my calls.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Late last week</TIMEX> I heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> is getting
married (to the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of a political crony) and has failed to
invite me.
            

            
               Here's where I'm
stuck. Even though my feelings are hurt, should I send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> a polite note of
congratulations? Shall I assume our friendship is over because he didn't invite
me? I welcome your insightful advice.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joey</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jo</ENAMEX>,

            The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> didn't
invite you, by itself, would not signal the friendship's end, but the
too-busy-to-return-phone-calls does. You <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have obviously grown apart. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> (not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>) often cool formerly warm relationships. Prudie
thinks it would be fine, as a tip of the hat to what used to be, to write him a
congratulatory note, if that is your inclination. Don't do it, however, if its
purpose would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) to get an invitation or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) to give him the needle. Just by
the by, it sounds as if you disapprove of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s "pompous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>" and
growing arrogance, so give the friendship a decent burial, emotionally,
remember the good times, and move on.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
realistically

         
      
   
