
   
   
      
         
             Shooting Script

            "You have to be true to yourself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, but I
don't think you have a responsibility beyond that," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Helgeland</ENAMEX>, the
opening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> at "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guns Don't Kill People ... Writers Do</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> discussion
sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers Guild of America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>. "Hopefully that's
enough, if you take yourself seriously." Enough for what or for whom? Helgeland
didn't specify. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX> of the ultraviolent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX> movie
Payback squirmed uncomfortably in his chair on a dais in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX>
hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballroom</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few hundred yards</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX>, pondering the
question of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who make violent movies are morally responsible for
inciting real-world violence. Dressed in frayed shorts and sandals, blond hair
flowing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helgeland</ENAMEX> looked as if he had stashed his surfboard behind the stage
and couldn't wait to escape into the waves crashing outside.

            On the opposite end of the stage was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion Picture</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of America</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Valenti</ENAMEX>, suited and tied, camera-ready,
and eager to pontificate. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX> included scripters of major screen
mayhem: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven De Souza</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Hard</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callie Khouri</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel Tejada-Flores</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fright Night Part II</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mastrosimone</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extremities</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sy Gomberg</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When Willie Comes Marching</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Petrie Jr.</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills Cop</ENAMEX> ); and producer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Daniel</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Mummy</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> was packed with worried industry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> still reeling from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s just-announced call for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department/FTC</ENAMEX> investigation to determine if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> markets violent
product to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. (For this we need a federal investigation? Does anyone
think it was over<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-17s</TIMEX> who bought <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$162 million</NUMEX> worth of tickets to The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matrix</ENAMEX> ?) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> was awash in rumors of imminent subpoenas, and talk of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>'s threats of criminal
prosecution and censorship.

            Adopting the "cigarettes
don't cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>" posture, studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> have declined credit for encouraging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to commit murder. Apparently they were counting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--whose
coffers are stuffed with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> cash--to go easy on them. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valenti</ENAMEX>'s
recommendation, they snubbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s invitation to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> conference
on violence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, letting slip their best chance to get out in front of
the issue. Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> appeared to be punishing them for their hubris. "You
turn down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> at your own peril," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> movie
producer. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valenti</ENAMEX> should know that. He worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>."

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> suits block feelings of guilt with
reiterations of their commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers Guild</ENAMEX> talk
revealed a creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> roiled by emotions ranging from angry defiance to
extreme remorse to abject terror. Sparring over their role in instigating
high-school gun battles, they fell into lock step on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point: God save us
from regulation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> has lost
luster elsewhere, it is ever the rallying cry in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, where free speech
can be relied upon to protect profitable dreck. At the same time, this
overwhelmingly liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, happy to jettison the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Second Amendment</ENAMEX>, is
steamed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has gone soft on the gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>.

            "I feel that the
viewpoint I just heard is a very dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ivory towerism</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mastrosimone</ENAMEX>,
the prickliest conscience in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, countering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helgeland</ENAMEX>'s "be true to
yourself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>" remarks. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who say it's all our fault are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extremists</ENAMEX>, and I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who say we have no responsibilities are also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>. If we're really looking for the truth, we'll find it somewhere in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>. It is unquestionable there is a cause-and-effect between what goes up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">onscreen</ENAMEX> and behavior--there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of scientific studies since the '60s
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose to ignore because it's really not lucrative to obey them.
And we have become very spoiled because we enjoy this freedom, and we don't
want anybody on the outside telling us what to do."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Souza</ENAMEX> was up next, a flinty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">showman</ENAMEX> who played the scene
aggressively. "This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I've ever volunteered to come and be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scapegoat</ENAMEX>," he said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Souza</ENAMEX> disputed the link between screen violence and
real-world violence but also ranted against gun proliferation, arguing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> watch violent movies but don't go out and kill each
other. Like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifth-grader</ENAMEX> at show-and-tell, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Souza</ENAMEX> held up the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
propaganda <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signal</ENAMEX> and pointed out sanitized images of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth groups</ENAMEX>. "Here you had the most wholesome, upstanding media you can
imagine, and meanwhile offstage is the most mechanized bloodbath in history,"
he said. He spread the moral responsibility around, noting that legally the
studio is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a movie. "I tell you, every picture I have done has
come out more violent than what I wrote. I have sat at the screening of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
my movies and been stunned at the level of mayhem that somebody put onscreen.
So now do I feel guilty?" He didn't answer his own question.

            Khouri, a native of
Paducah, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, site of a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> shooting, cited the familiar litany of
parental neglect, breakdown of education and community, and the Internet as
causes of teen violence. Yet she was ambivalent about blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>.
"There's no one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that can be held responsible for this," she said. "But
for us to sit here and say 'feed 'em a steady diet of whatever they want,' and
then when they act out it's your fault ... it doesn't add up. We're trying to
make sense out of something that will never make sense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> read The
Catcher in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rye</ENAMEX> and shoot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX>. There's always going to be
somebody who is going to misinterpret something." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khouri</ENAMEX> added that she was
stunned at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> 's first screening when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> cheered
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> for shooting a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attacker</ENAMEX>. "I had hoped for a completely
different reaction from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, a realization that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> had
just sealed her fate in a horrible way. I was terrified. And I realized that I
can't control how my work is perceived." After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> , Khouri
challenged herself to write a movie with no <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in it. "It's harder," she
says.

            "Do we want the world to be as frightened as so many of us
are, and so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are?" asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomberg</ENAMEX>, who organized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> to
End <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Violence</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonesboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>, killings. "Do we have the right to
impose this gun culture on the world? They all want to be like us! I don't
think we do." Gomberg advocated the elimination of "excessive or gratuitous or
unpunished" violence in movies and television. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Souza</ENAMEX>, rankled, barked, "When
you say unpunished violence it reminds me of the old green code." Undeterred,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gomberg</ENAMEX> continued, "We have to aim our sights higher. ... I hate to use the
term 'aim sights' ... but the easiest thing in the world to write is a villain
you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> so involved in hating that you scream inside for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>
to demolish him. Creatively we can find ways to get the same kind of tensions
and passions going."

            "By that definition
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> 
               the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third</ENAMEX> is a terrible, evil play," responded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Souza</ENAMEX>,
knowing that no discussion of violence in art is complete without an invocation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX>. "It spends all of its time making us hate, hate that villain. And
there's a gory, bloody end and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. Let's not even go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titus</ENAMEX>
Andronicus !" That got a big laugh, which encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helgeland</ENAMEX> to drop the
other bit of Shakespearean boilerplate: "What if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> who was hopelessly
in love saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo and Juliet</ENAMEX> and decided to kill himself? Should we not
perform <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo and Juliet</ENAMEX> any more?"

            Patiently awaiting his moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valenti</ENAMEX> erupted in a burst
of his usual flowery oratory. "If I've learned one thing in the movie business
and the world of politics," he intoned, "it is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
spare, unadorned words, bleached dry of all ambiguity--is the one clause in the
Constitution that guarantees all others. And it's not easy to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
Amendment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, because then you have to allow into this marketplace that
which you believe to be soiling and meretricious and tawdry and unwholesome and
sometimes vile. And then sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get so vexed, they want to call their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> and say, 'pass a law to stop all this stuff.' But I always say to
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, be wary and be cautious. Before you make that call, remember that
when a tyrant first appears he always comes as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX>." Hoots of
approval rose up from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>.

            Billed as a session of
self-scrutiny, the discussion was turning into a call to arms against enemies
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>, wrapping up the session, soberly reminded his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> that those who have abused their absolute freedoms by making movies
that are soiling and unwholesome have only themselves to blame if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s
era of unregulated bliss is over. "All of us have to understand that we are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> whether we like it or not," he warned. "Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> have
rendered articulate and righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>. But none of us should leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> without an understanding
that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the fear is real, the problems of
raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are real."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballroom emptied</ENAMEX>, leaving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s topic frustratingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unprobed</ENAMEX>. No one had bothered to press <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valenti</ENAMEX> on whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should
properly give more weight to the safety of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> than to free speech.
Neither had there been any mention of the roots of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s love affair with
violence. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX> (who spoke later on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> on comedy)
pointed out, "The thing that is rarely mentioned is that because this is a
puritanical society and you can't show sex, we eroticize violence. It started
with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wild Bunch : We</ENAMEX> sexualized violence, we made it beautiful."

            Was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> a watershed? Under pressure from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> says it will now bar
the under-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-rated movies; rumors have it that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> will be
stricter about slapping R ratings onto violent movies; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> plans to stop
featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in its marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> have canceled the
development of some teen horror movies.

            Are these serious measures by moviemakers and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>? With so much money and so many votes at stake, both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> are driven by fear and committed to appearances. If there were a
little bit less finger pointing and a little more assumption of responsibility
for a problem whose causes are many, it would be easier to have faith.

         
      
   
