
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anti-War Semites</ENAMEX>

            Last
fall, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> signed a peace agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> tried to blow up an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> bus.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> faulted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> for failing to stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX> and, prodded by outraged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX>,
began stalling the agreement to death. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>, signed another deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> struck
again. This time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of justice vouched for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s "commitment
to fighting terror" and urged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> to stand with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> in "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sane people</ENAMEX> versus the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of peace."

            The
words coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> these days are as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> as the
deeds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> are not merely changing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s policy toward
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. They are trying to redefine and reconfigure the whole
conflict. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> saw a struggle between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> perceives a struggle between those who support the peace process and
those who oppose it. In this configuration, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militants</ENAMEX> are allies
not of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> but of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>, and terrorism
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is a reason for more collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>, not less.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX>, invoking the old configuration, blamed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s attacks on
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>" in general. They accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> of betraying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and
demanded that he suspend the new agreement. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>, while affirming
that "no peace process shall prevail over the personal security of the people
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>," rejected the premise that the former threatened the latter. They
denied that peace talks were a "zero-sum game," and they dismissed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
right's equation of terrorism with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>. "We can't blame
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> every time there's a terror incident," argued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Israeli</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deputy Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ephraim Sneh</ENAMEX>.

            From
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s perspective, the latest bombings were an attack not on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> but on
the peace process. "There are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> who are very determined to disrupt the
process through terror and murder. We won't let them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sneh</ENAMEX> vowed. "We cannot
dance to the tune of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Jihad</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of industry
sketched a symbiotic relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hawks</ENAMEX>, warning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rightists</ENAMEX> to "refrain from the kind of fiery rhetoric
they used in the past, which only encourages the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>." Conversely,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s chief of military intelligence suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX> recognized terrorism as a threat to its interests. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> proposed a "joint <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> fist" against terrorism and
reaffirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>" were fulfilling their
"commitment to fight against terrorist acts."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> reciprocated this spin, reiterating
their "policy of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> tolerance for terror" and declaring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> pointed out that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> had arrested numerous terrorist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> and confiscated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. "Someone who sends a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car bomb</ENAMEX> today is trying
to destroy the hopes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> official
declared. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> charged that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>
sought "the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>." Another asserted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli Arabs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> shared a commitment to "the law and the democratic rules
of the game. Whoever carried out [the bombings] is enemy number one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>."

            Having
defined the conflict this way, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s
best means of defeating terrorism was to cooperate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX>. They accused the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of peace" of staging attacks "aimed at
destroying the entire peace process." "The answer to anyone who tries to
undermine the peace process is that we are determined to continue," proclaimed
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saeb Erekat</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>--everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> has paid so much in the absence of peace. It's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for reconciliation."

            The
new configuration is beginning to take hold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> to cooperate in probe of bombings," announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>: Car bombs will not derail process," added <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juxtaposing Arafat</ENAMEX> with "anti-peace <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>." Op-ed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> cautioned
against "a self-defeating freeze on the peace process," called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>" in the "fight against terrorism," and observed that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>"--namely, mass-murderer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baruch Goldstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yigal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amir</ENAMEX>--had staged attacks "aimed at halting the peace process." Borrowing the
language of war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> called the latest bombings "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> test of
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s] resolve to march toward the final status agreement 'uninterrupted.'
"

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> press, too, is adopting this pro-peace/anti-peace analysis of the
conflict. "The explosions will give ammunition to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s right wing,"
predicted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that
"terrorism" was once again challenging the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> relationship."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , inferring that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> sought "to sabotage
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacemaking</ENAMEX>," stipulated, "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> do not support
terror attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, which they regard as only impeding progress
toward the tangible benefits of peace."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Framing</ENAMEX> is a transcendent art. It can serve petty advantage or profound reform.
It can be used to achieve goals or to rethink them, to defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> or to
reassess them, to win wars or to stop them. "There is a war going on between
the peace process and terror" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> territories,
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yaron Ezrhahi</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>
"are fighting the peace process because they know it promises to kill terror
once and for all." Is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ezrhahi Israeli</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> didn't
say. And if he's right, it doesn't matter.

         
      
   
