
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>

            Here is a (partial) list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> has gilded on recent TV shows: pomegranates, pumpkins, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate truffles</ENAMEX>, wrapping paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oak leaves</ENAMEX>, acorns, and--no kidding--okra.
The only thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> has not gilded is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lily</ENAMEX>. But wait till it's back in
season.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> has proved that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alchemy</ENAMEX> is not impossible: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brush</ENAMEX> enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> paint on enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX>, and
eventually you'll make real <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s initial public offering for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart Living Omnimedia</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omnimedia</ENAMEX>, has there ever been a more perfect
name?--killed on Wall Street, rising from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18 to $52</NUMEX> before settling at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36</NUMEX>.
She arrived at the stock exchange that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> toting a tray of brioches. She
left <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX> holding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> (in stock, not dough). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> bought
a brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omnimedia</ENAMEX>--a Web site, mail-order operation, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> TV shows,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kmart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> books--netted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
from the gospel of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>. Kmart sold <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $750 million</NUMEX> worth of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>-branded products in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. Her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> decision to divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> and
go solo--a split that cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">her more than $50 million</NUMEX>--has never looked
better.

            What was missing from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s IPO was the sniping and
mockery that has dogged all of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX>. Traditionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> has been
battered by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX>. First, she is simply ludicrous. You could not
imagine better comic material than her ideas of "living": the "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> omelet
dinner for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> baskets the size of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX>; the advice (in this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>) to make your own envelopes out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood veneer</ENAMEX>, folding them
with a bone <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parodies</ENAMEX> barely exaggerate when they imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> turning
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> ("a lovely Merlot") or manufacturing condoms from her own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX>.
A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and more thoughtful batch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> has charged her with encouraging
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">class</ENAMEX> division, promoting soulless domestic conformism, and undermining working
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> by making them feel domestically inadequate.

            The final criticism has
been personal. As her unauthorized biography, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Desserts</ENAMEX> , contends,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> is an icy, horrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who abused her (now ex-) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, ignores her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, belittles her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, sues her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pennies</NUMEX>, plagiarizes
recipes from better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX>, and humiliates her staff. Her fabled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Remembering</ENAMEX>"
columns are a hash of bunkum and hyperbole. The persona she cultivates--the
warm, welcoming hostess with a close-knit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--is a fraud.

            These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> have subsided partly because of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
culture of financial idolatry. Anyone who's worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion</NUMEX> on paper is worth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sucking</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> is benefiting from parody fatigue as well. She has been a
figure of fun since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Entertaining</ENAMEX> was published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, so all the jokes
are old. And the vitality of the economy is inoculating her. Fripperies that
seemed obscene during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX> recession are quite modest by the
standards of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.

            But the critical silence
may also represent a long-overdue recognition that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> is, as she would say,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Thing</ENAMEX>. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> TV interview, she called herself a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>. ... We
are offering information, high-quality, well-researched, how-to information."
That is a fair description. What she does is not silly at all, or at least no
more silly than most advice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and TV shows retain just
enough nonsense to make them irksome ("sew your own pashmina from home-raised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">llamas</ENAMEX>," and the like), but she supplies valuable instruction about the mundane
tasks of life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart Living</ENAMEX> may be the most useful magazine
this side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX>'s issue, for example, offers
excellent advice about making spicy popcorn <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX>, cleaning ovens, and storing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX>, among other subjects. Her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> segment packs more
helpful cooking information into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six minutes</TIMEX> than most cooking shows do in an
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX>. It is not false consciousness that makes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions</NUMEX> of people
follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>. It is her good advice.

            But the great achievement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s domestic gospel is
not practical but moral. She has a puritanical sensibility. She believes in the
uplifting power of work. She instructs you so that you will know how to create
objects yourself , grow plants yourself , learn home repair
yourself , cook food yourself . Doing something well is good and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liberating</ENAMEX> and fulfilling. It strengthens friendships and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>: When I saw
her making waffles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>, it made me want to make waffles this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.
If I make waffles on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, I will invite the downstairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> up to eat
them, and that is undoubtedly a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Thing</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> practices
materialism, but not consumerism. She believes, rightly, that it makes
you wiser and happier to cook your own applesauce than to buy it. Well, you may
say, it's easy for her to make homemade applesauce. That's her job. But she did
it when it wasn't her job, too. Even if most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> rarely practice anything
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> preaches--she calls such slackers "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Dreamers</ENAMEX>" as opposed to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Doers</ENAMEX>"--she is still a worthy goad.

            Her DIY credo makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> democratically snobbish. She
hews to a country-house sensibility, but anyone can follow it. It
doesn't cost much, because you do it yourself. If a middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> can blossom into an affected, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Breck</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> faux-WASP, you can
too!

            The final, and most
important, reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> is escaping criticism is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has been separated from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> the brand. The principal topic of
discussion about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart Living</ENAMEX> IPO was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>'s death.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> speculated what would happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omnimedia</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> were hit by a bus
or cab (or succumbed to an accident in "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">potting</ENAMEX> shed," as the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Byron</ENAMEX> nicely put it). There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> answers:
First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has bought a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$67 million</NUMEX> life-insurance policy on her.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brand</ENAMEX> can survive without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph Lauren</ENAMEX> the brand survives without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph Lauren</ENAMEX> selling every shirt.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> does not appear at all in the current issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living</ENAMEX> .) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zooming</ENAMEX> stock price is evidence that Wall Street can distinguish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> from
her product.

            We should do the same. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have savaged her fraudulent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persona</ENAMEX> and monomaniacal perfectionism for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>. There is a subtle
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sexism</ENAMEX> in that: The female domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> is obliged to behave better than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. (This is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s private life is examined more carefully than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman's</ENAMEX>.)

            Fortunately, commerce has trumped personality.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> is finally being treated as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omnimedia</ENAMEX>, not
as a bitchy hausfrau. In the age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divine entrepreneur</ENAMEX>, no one cares how
badly you treat your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>. We admire perfectionist monomania in Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tycoons</ENAMEX>, so why not in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> get away with advertising bogus
family bliss; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> should too. On television, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> shows us how to make a
romantic dinner for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> she doesn't have, host a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> she
doesn't like, bake muffins for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> who hate her. But those are her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tragedies</ENAMEX>, not our business (or Wall Street's). The muffins are still tasty,
and that's what matters.

         
      
   
