
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Symbolic Logic&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               
                  A federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>, to make a change in its official city seal.
What change?
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">274</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chants Taking":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 
                                    Over the past
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> shouted: "Down with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>," "Oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX>, shame on you!" and "Jerks!" Who was protesting
what?
                                 
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "The
few disappointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of 'John <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasich</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "Wait,
has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> 's annual cruise left already?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            "Let
me guess: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cineplex Odeon</ENAMEX> has raised prices <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another quarter</TIMEX>, hasn't it?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Off</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> coast, student <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins angrily</ENAMEX> picketed their corrupt undersea
government, before turning violent and eating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plankton</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Bodow</ENAMEX>
            

            "Wow,
I knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> were upset about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Gonzalez</ENAMEX> not starting the All-Star
game, but they really have to chill out."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Schatz</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
Star had a similar answer.)

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s chants,
particularly when chanted in translation, sound a little silly. But some of our
own anti-battle cries have been a little lazy, perhaps because of the too-easy
rhyming of "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>" and "war"--as in "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three, four</TIMEX>/ we don't want your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stinking</ENAMEX> ..." well, you know. Indeed, anything that employs counting seems
cheap. As comfy as it is to be led from "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>" to "smash the
state," it is kind of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Roses</ENAMEX> are red, violets are blue" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> inciting.
Disappointing, really. "No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>, no peace," barks out a fierce equivalency,
although to the uninitiated it may sound like a list of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> is rejecting: justice and peace. Paired phrases do have rhetorical vigor,
particularly in the call and response of "What do we want?" (something good!),
"When do we want it?"--there's the problem; the answer is so predictable. It's
not like we want it by mid-February. There was a briefly popular in-group
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incantation</ENAMEX> (if by in<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-group</ENAMEX> we mean me), an acknowledgement of how crowded a
demonstration could be: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Raza Unida Is Standing on My Feet-a</ENAMEX>!" but when I
chanted it--and I did--it was thought to denote a lack of seriousness, which it
did not. But I should have known better. If airy persiflage went down well at
street demonstrations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noël Coward</ENAMEX> would have had a whole other career.

            
               Off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pigs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Well</ENAMEX>
Maybe Not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pigs</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">but Definitely Off Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            Pro-democracy student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tehran</ENAMEX>
University are calling for a faster movement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> toward democracy
and the rule of law but still within the framework of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>. And
they're not too happy about being beaten and killed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vigilantes</ENAMEX>.

            Other chants included:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, why kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>?," a cry of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Islamic revolution</ENAMEX> two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Filthy Swine!"</ENAMEX> "Death to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>!" "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are miserable! The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerics</ENAMEX> are acting like gods!" and, if my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farsi</ENAMEX> is any good (and it's not),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, although uninvolved in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> affairs, sucks."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live Free or Lightly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salted Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> bolts the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> and a beloved advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is recalled to duty. Two
unrelated stories? Perhaps. Or maybe a single story about a place called
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planters</ENAMEX>. OK, that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things again, but the
challenge remains: Which of these remarks refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>, and which refer to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanut</ENAMEX>?

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comments:</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. He is "a leverage point to talk about the
quality, taste, and fun that separates us from other nuts."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "There is a certain integrity to him, as amusing
as that sounds."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> "weren't
qualified to kiss the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hem</ENAMEX> of his garment."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "Our research shows [him] to be seen as a
regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, everyman."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was "a died-in-the-wool
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. He said he'd vote for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ticket if he had
to."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. He is considered "a party <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dignified</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>, especially young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, realize that
his appearance is meant to be tongue-in-cheek, with a fun edge."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 11</TIMEX>, "bet a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who lived down the road
and had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, a dollar versus a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> would win the
election."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Makes frequent references to Mr. Smith Goes
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thinks Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX> are
"probably gay" but looks forward to seeing them have sex in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide</ENAMEX>
Shut .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. Received letter from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP Chair Jim Nicholson</ENAMEX> and found it "petty, it's vindictive and it's
insulting."

            
               Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>:
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanut</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanut</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanut</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanut</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanut</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. I believe that was me.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>.

            (Note:
All Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanut</ENAMEX> comments from some ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . All Bob
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> comments come from his speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katzenberg</ENAMEX> settlement.

         
      
   
