
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>?

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last time</TIMEX> a new medium transformed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was,
of course, television, and the signal event was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> presidential
debate, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to be broadcast live to a national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. Radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>
polled afterward gave the victory to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> won the debate--and
arguably the election--because he came off better on television. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> looked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cooler</ENAMEX>, more confident, and more handsome. He also knew something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>
didn't--how to project himself through the new technology. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> took
further advantage of the medium, using television to shape the public
perception of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. After press conferences, he would replay his
films in private, critiquing the lighting and camera angles.

            It is
already a cliché that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election signals the advent of another new
medium, the Internet. As is often the case with the Web, predictions of
dominance come in two flavors: utopian and apocalyptic. Utopians think the Net
has the power to undo the damage wrought upon <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics by television.
In their view, it stands to increase the power of ideas and diminish the
importance of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> attack ads. It will disenfranchise unelected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> and
give democratic power back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. It will reduce the power of money.
Gloom-and-doomsters, on the other hand, assert that the Net will do just the
opposite, reducing genuine participation, threatening personal privacy, and
lending itself to new forms of manipulation by amoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> and moneyed
interests.

            My
prediction: This election will be more important to the Net than the Net will
be to the election. Just as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> conferred legitimacy on TV journalism,
Campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> promises to put the Net on the political map. It's less of a
given, though, that the Net will actually affect the campaign. In terms of the
TV analogy, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> may be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956 or 1948</TIMEX> rather than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>. Television existed in
those elections and was spreading rapidly into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of homes. But for a
variety of reasons, it wasn't yet a decisive or central factor.

            So,
how can we know how important the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is this time around? Only by casting a
skeptical eye on the ambitious claims being made on its behalf and evaluating
them against reality. 
                  Slate
                and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry Standard</ENAMEX> have
joined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> for a continuing real-time examination of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign as it
happens on the Web. In this column, we'll follow the topic where it takes us.
But to start out, here are some of the subjects "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net Election</ENAMEX>" is likely to
consider and reconsider over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 14 months</TIMEX>.

            
               Net

               Fund Raising
            

            One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way those</ENAMEX> goofy can quickly establish their value is by raising gobs of money.
So far, they've helped a bit. According to its most recent filing with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign so far has received
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$330,000</NUMEX> from its Web
site . This is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 3 percent</NUMEX> of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has collected
overall. But there are reasons for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> to like Web money
more than other kinds. One is that the cost of raising money on the Net is very
low compared with sending out direct mail or throwing a gala. A Web site is
basically an electronic collection plate, which consumes few of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>. For this reason, Net-based political fund raising is destined to
grow--and probably just as quickly as other forms of e-commerce.

            Web
fund raising may also point the way toward campaign finance reform. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> initiated a practice that will surely become the norm:
declaring contributions immediately online , instead of
waiting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> FEC deadlines. You could do worse than the system of
campaign finance that is evolving on the Web, where contributions limited to
the less-than-influential amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>--approximately
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has raised so far--are immediately
disclosed. To be sure, there remains the problem of many times larger soft
money donations. But thanks to the Web, it's at least easy to discover which
special interests are supporting which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The best disclosure site,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FECInfo</ENAMEX>, puts at everyone's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fingertips</ENAMEX> information that used to require trips to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of poring over dim microfiches.

            
               Net

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizing</ENAMEX>
            

            
Another advantage of Web contributions is that they often come with a promise
of volunteer time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> roots <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoveOn</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>, which was formed to oppose impeaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, quickly gathered pledges of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX>
signatures on a petition, just by pinging e-mail back and forth. What's more,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pledged <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">750,000 hours</TIMEX> of volunteer time to defeat pro-impeachment
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election. You can't trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>-haters, but if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> live up to their promises, they stand to become a significant factor
in the contest for control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> targeted for defeat may harness the same techniques in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-defense</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign reports that he has already
signed up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> on the twin Web sites <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RudyYes</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HillaryNo</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Those with little inclination to hand out leaflets
at rainy commuter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">rush hour</TIMEX> can become "e-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>." By using the
Web in this way, a campaign can convert mass support into grass roots support.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>' Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Segal</ENAMEX> tried to work the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> straw poll this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>. He set up a national e-mail tree designed to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to send their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. How great an effect it had is
hard to say.

            
               Net

               Advertising
            

            Like
Net fund raising, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX> advertising isn't destined to replace the older method
(i.e., television) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>--or ever. But it is certain to grow as a share of
the total. TV ads are dumb, both in the sense that they tend to be crudely
demagogic appeals, and because they can't target segments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>
with any degree of accuracy. Web advertising is smart, in the sense that it can
be far more detailed and specific and because it can reach a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> with
surgical precision. Already, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> has plans to focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>-oriented
sites. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> intends to advertise on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading and investment sites,
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might vote for him are likely to be found. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possibility is
that these ads will develop into a new form of micro-pandering, but the process
will be interesting no matter where it leads. Techniques and conventions that
will come to seem eternal and inevitable will actually be invented in the
coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.

            
               Net

               Issues
            

            In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, several congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> campaigned against Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pornography</ENAMEX>--an issue of greater interest to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off-line than to those
online. This time, you're more likely to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> vowing to protect
electronic privacy or block taxes on e-commerce. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to gauge how important
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> is by watching how seriously <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> take the Net's own
special interest issues. What we have yet to see, but can expect fairly soon,
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who fit the computer industry's political profile. Internet
politics are basically soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">libertarian</ENAMEX>--liberal on social issues, anti-tax,
and anti-regulation (but pro-environment and pro-gun control). The tech
industry's dream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> would combine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s views on abortion, gay
rights, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>' dedication to lower capital gains taxes.
That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to be running in this campaign, but he or she may
emerge in the course of it (possibly occupying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of a current candidate
expressing somewhat different views).

            
               Net

               Coverage
            

            The
campaign news cycle has grown shorter with each successive election. Thanks to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>, it may be entirely repealed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, everyone has a Web
site and a big established news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> can drop an election-transforming
scoop into the mix at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any hour of the day or night</TIMEX>, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> can.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> won't have much luck with a traditional stratagem such as
semi-suppressing a story by not responding until after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news
deadlines. Rapid response will become more rapid than ever, with several
volleys being fired in the course of what used to be a campaign day.

            
There's lots more that we intend to chew over here: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> voting, Net gossip, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cybersquatting</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the most interesting question will be the extent to
which the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign will happen in cyberspace as well as in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> space. One
role model may be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, who integrated the real and the
virtual to an impressive degree in his Web-savvy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>
organized his original effort by e-mail, tracked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> tour with digital
pictures, and encouraged a lively bulletin board discussion of it. To a
considerable degree, his Web site was where his campaign actually happened. As
bandwidth increases, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> will be able to bypass the press by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">producing C-SPAN</ENAMEX>-style coverage of their own races. Whether anyone will be
watching is yet another question.

            
               Click

               
                  here to
visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry Standard</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
