
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquiring Minds</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovakia</ENAMEX>

            With <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of summer</TIMEX> upon us, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX>'
thoughts have turned to a high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovakia</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> teacher
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Fenton</ENAMEX> has been using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> as a "teaching tool"
in her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> classes. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovakia</ENAMEX> read a lot--and they see the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> as a big scoop of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture," the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Palm Beach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX>
tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> . "Their vocabulary is growing rapidly ... and they
are learning a lot about life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>."

            No doubt. How else would
those poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slovakian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have been able to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Dentist to the Stars"</ENAMEX>? In
fact, we shudder to think of all that our young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slovakian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> might have
missed without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, from the detailed story of the
wedding of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> missing the entire lower <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> (she walked up the
aisle on her hands, with the garter concealed under her sleeve) to the
assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> may be more electable than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> because of his
strong jaw and cheekbones.

            Perhaps most important, it's reassuring to know that all
those <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Slovakian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>, far away though they may be, will learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>, who's previously dabbled in astrology, has moved on
to what she calls "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rumpology</ENAMEX>," the supposedly ancient art of reading prints
made from inking a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s posterior. "[It] goes right back to the time of
Nostradamus," asserts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Stallone</ENAMEX>. "It's all written on your behind who
you're going to marry, love affairs, health--and most important of all in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, whether you're going to have a successful career." "It may sound
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crazy</ENAMEX>," notes "top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astrologer</ENAMEX> and palmist" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Carr</ENAMEX>, "but I think she's on
to something with this."

            It's unclear whether it
could have been predicted by a good rump-reading from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sly Stallone</ENAMEX>
leads the pack of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> having meltdowns over seemingly innocuous slights
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports that while shooting a movie in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Columbia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> "went <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX>" and threw a meal of hot
chicken, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fries</ENAMEX>, and coleslaw out the door of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX>, splattering a
"shocked crew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> apparently flipped out because, like everyone
else in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, he's on a no carbohydrate diet. "When I say I want a f-----g
chicken, I want a f-----<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">g chicken</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> reportedly screamed. "I want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ONE</ENAMEX>
chicken!" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> apparently missed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's story claiming that
the no-carb, high-protein diet that slimmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX> down is
dangerously unhealthy and "could even be fatal.")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Lopez</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, stormed off the set of her
latest film because she was unhappy with the wig she was supposed to wear, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , which also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX> was "rude, difficult and
furious" when he was required to have a skull X-ray after an on-set mishap. The
most bizarre celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">snit</ENAMEX> might be that of Jesse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina</ENAMEX>
Applegate, who the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> says is feuding with her show's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>
because she refuses to conceal the "unsightly" bags under her eyes, claiming
they give her working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> authenticity. "They think she's acting
like a spoiled brat and an ingrate," says a set insider.

            In fact, the tabs have
been uncommonly fixated on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">under</NUMEX>-eye maladies of late. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>
complains that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> stamp honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> makes him look like an "old geezer ... with eye bags big enough to pack
for an overnight trip." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> felt compelled to point out that
when her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> suffered a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX> rushed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Columbia</ENAMEX>, "without stopping to put on makeup." A source
confirmed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>'s eyes were "puffy from lack of sleep.
She was pale and wore no makeup." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditto for Dana Scurry</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> of
hospitalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Lawrence</ENAMEX>, who according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX> waited by
his bedside with "bloodshot" eyes and makeup "smeared from crying." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , however, reports that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shamicka Gibbs</ENAMEX>,
who has been "sitting at [his] bedside clutching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>'s limp hand and praying
to God to spare his troubled life." Perhaps not surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibbs</ENAMEX> is said to
have got into a "vicious catfight" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> with an unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
claimed to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>. We certainly hope, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>'s sake, that
it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scurry</ENAMEX>.

            It appears that the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
without bags under her eyes is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Taylor</ENAMEX>, who's suffering from a
vertebrae fracture that the tabs fear may leave her unable to walk. But at
least she'll look good. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , famed hairstylist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Eber</ENAMEX> has visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cedars</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> Hospital several times to do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s hair
and makeup. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports that she has been greeting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> in a "glamorous pink chiffon negligee" and is being pampered "with her
favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soaps</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oils</ENAMEX>" by "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> specially trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>."

            With no celebrity ailment
too inconsequential to mine for dramatic potential, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends star</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courteney Cox</ENAMEX>'s routine LASIK surgery to correct her nearsightedness is treated
with the kind of life-and-death anguish usually reserved for quadruple bypass
operations and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> transplants. Far be it from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX>--who's no
stranger to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>-bottle lenses--to appear unsympathetic to the visually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impaired</ENAMEX>, but we raised our eyebrows just a tad at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's assessment
that this "miracle eye surgery saved [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX>'s] vision" when the story explains
that it was simple vanity about wearing thick glasses that put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cox</ENAMEX> under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">knife</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> weighed in with a story titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"How Courteney beat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blindness</ENAMEX>," which included the touching detail that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX> awoke from the
operation sobbing, "Oh my God, I can see!" while her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Arquette</ENAMEX>,
was "so moved by [her] joy" that he began to cry as well. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>
claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX>'s surgery "saved her career," given that the ever-squinting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> couldn't read cue cards well enough to host <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> .
Things got so bad, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX> "often couldn't tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kudrow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX> apart" and occasionally knocked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> over. Thank
God for modern medicine.

            If she weren't so spectacle-averse, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX> might have turned
for help to former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">televangelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Faye Bakker</ENAMEX>, who the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
reports has amassed an impressive collection of eyeglasses belonging to dead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. "I believe the eyes are the soul," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bakker</ENAMEX> says by way of explanation.
Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX>, the story says, are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">glasses</ENAMEX> belonging to her late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>,
apparently because of their almost meditative powers. "I like to put them on
and think, 'You know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Momma</ENAMEX> looked through these,' " she tells the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bakker</ENAMEX> shares this maudlin optical fascination with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Sheindlin</ENAMEX>, who (according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> ) almost "burst into
tears" and stopped production of her TV show when she misplaced her reading
glasses, which once belonged to her beloved late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.

            Finally, as he prepares to launch his own <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>
show, we thought we'd highlight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX>'s confident prediction that "there'll never, ever be a post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
photo showing Bill [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>] with a cigar." Memo to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walker</ENAMEX>: Check out Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> . Where did you get that tip--from a rump
reading?

         
      
   
