
   
   
      
         
            <I>Gorgeous</I> Isn't Even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skin-Deep</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drop Dead Gorgeous</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miserable</ENAMEX> reviews for this
mockumentary about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> teen beauty pageant starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Barkin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirstie Alley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Richards</ENAMEX>. The idea of spoofing the superficial,
back-stabbing world of teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pageants</ENAMEX> seems funny to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, but all agree
that the execution is abysmal. It relies heavily on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>-bashing--the film
has "more lutefisk and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX> gags than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Prairie Home</ENAMEX>
Companion " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> )--and predictable jokes about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stage mothers</ENAMEX> and bitchy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drop Dead Gorgeous</ENAMEX> was written by a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota Miss Teen</ENAMEX> runner-up, but despite this insider angle, it offers
nothing that wasn't done better in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Smile</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pageant News Bureau</ENAMEX> thought of the film.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haunting</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks SKG</ENAMEX>). Frighteningly bad reviews for this
old-school horror movie: "The scariest thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Haunting</ENAMEX> is how
awful it is. No, worse than awful: desperate" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Instead of going for the tongue-in-cheek, campy
horror style so popular of late, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan De Bont</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speed</ENAMEX> ) relies on
old-fashioned things-that-go-bump-in-the-night scares. Despite a tasty cast
(including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Wilson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lili Taylor</ENAMEX>),
the only faintly amusing element of the film is the computer-generated special
effects, which give the haunted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> moving statues and doors that sprout
arms. A remake of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> film adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Jackson</ENAMEX>'s novel The
Haunting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill House</ENAMEX> , this version cuts out the psychological elements
that made the original compelling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> to speak up
in favor of the film, citing the scenery and effects as reason enough to see
it. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to watch the trailer.)

            

               Magazine
            

            

               
                  Talk
               . The buzz on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celeb-mag</ENAMEX> reaches a fever pitch
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> before the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue appears. Already, unasked-for publicity has been
showered on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, which is being published in partnership with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> denied permission to host the
launch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Yard</ENAMEX>, apparently after hearing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
seat rival <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> was going to be on the cover. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) A parody Web site by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s Content <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Colton</ENAMEX> was shut down by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> but was reinstated after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> saw it and called off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. And
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> have been charting every whisper of gossip on the
magazine for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> has also been making the rounds talking up her new
project: Already <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> she's done an interview in the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and been quoted at length in a piece in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Business</ENAMEX>" section of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Kuczynski</ENAMEX> writes that
Talk "more closely resembles a postmodern version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
magazine or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paris Match</ENAMEX> " than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , and says that yes, the
cover will feature <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, but it will also give space to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> star
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> and
online gossip sites, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> is steamed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> went to press before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> crashed, thus missing the biggest story of the
moment. (Not to mention the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graydon Carter</ENAMEX> stopped the presses
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX> on the latest issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> to change the
cover to a pic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Bessette Kennedy</ENAMEX>.) The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> copies of Talk
will be handed out at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX>'s launch party--held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty</ENAMEX>, which is federal, not state, property--and it hits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> in

                  Slate
               .)

            

               Event
            

            
               Woodstock
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'99</NUMEX> . The massive rock festival ended in mayhem with fires, looting,
and riot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> of music from acts such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alanis Morissette, Insane Clown Posse, Rage</ENAMEX> Against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machine</ENAMEX>,
Metallica, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Hot Chili Peppers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Limp Bizkit</ENAMEX> (the last band drawing the
biggest response from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few hundred</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">estimated 200,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX> broke loose. Highlights from the melee included: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor-trailers</ENAMEX>
set on fire, impromptu stripteases, giant bonfires with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> leaping through
the flames, looting of T-shirt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booths</ENAMEX>, smashed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATMs</ENAMEX>, and a food fight
with liberated soft pretzels. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webcasts</ENAMEX> from the festival on the official site.)

         
      
   
