
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitutional Coup</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s
main English-language <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, ran three
editorials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>--about literacy, rural health care, and an initiative
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, to halt
international trafficking in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--but none about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
military coup. In its main front-page story <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> said there had been
signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pervaiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Musharraf</ENAMEX> seized power <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> but that he quickly imposed tight control. The
paper, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musharraf</ENAMEX> didn't talk about martial law or of any new
constitutional arrangements in his address to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, cited reports that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has been in direct contact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> military urging
it to desist from doing anything unconstitutional. It said the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-hour</TIMEX> delay
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was told the outcome of the coup attempt may have been caused
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz Sharif</ENAMEX>'s refusal to resign as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> looked for a
constitutional way to remove him. In a profile of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musharraf</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> commando for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and served in
"several self-propelled artillery regiments"--a phrase from his official
biography.

            The
paper's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> noted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> reluctance to condemn the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s
seizure of power, or even to characterize it as a coup, apparently because it
hoped to avoid the automatic triggering of new sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> reported "growing disquiet" among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> about
the prospect of a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> being controlled by a general. "A coming
together of the hardline <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and religious right-wing political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> may be
the perfect recipe for disaster in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asia</ENAMEX>," it quoted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unnamed official
as saying. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> went on full alert, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX> is
aware that the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX> will mean more trouble in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>.
Cross-border terrorism will naturally also be stepped up."

            In the
rest of the world, the coup provoked different reactions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> almost
welcomed it. "[I]n almost every way, the fault for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s latest crisis can
be laid squarely with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> himself," it said in an editorial.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seldom</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> so frivolously squandered the goodwill that originally
brought him victory against the tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benazir Bhutto</ENAMEX>. ... The
outside world, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s frustrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, may feel that a new
government, even one brought in by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, might be less bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
than the distorted democracy it has endured until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
called the coup "a blow to democracy, a blow to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s image abroad, and a
blow to those who hope for peace in the subcontinent."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Herald</ENAMEX> , pointing out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX> is now "under the
immediate, direct and absolute control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>," said the risk was "not
that the unthinkable--the use of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>--will suddenly be thought
about seriously by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX>. Rather, it is that without even the
pretence of civilian control over its nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s armed forces
may feel more confident about flexing their conventional military muscles in
pursuit of their own objectives. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Musharraf</ENAMEX> has acted in an illegal
and indefensible way. He must not be allowed to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> that with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recklessness</ENAMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post</ENAMEX> warned that the world may be faced "not only
with a military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> but, more worryingly, with the possibility of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Talibanisation of Pakistan</ENAMEX>." It added in an editorial, "In these circumstances--which may of course
change quickly--the West is right to cut off aid and to withdraw diplomatic
support. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taliban</ENAMEX>-friendly coup can only add a further element of instability
to an already unstable region."

            
Marking the official arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarajevo</ENAMEX> of the world's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> billionth inhabitant,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX>
quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu Rongji</ENAMEX> as saying that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would
continue to make family planning "a fundamental state policy." Meanwhile,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has declared that homosexuality is "abnormal and unacceptable
to the public." It is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has ruled on the nature of
homosexuality, and it did so in awarding damages for psychological damage to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> described as gay in the best-selling book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homosexuals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> . The
court ruled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had suffered "depression and psychological pain" and
damage to his reputation by being described as gay. The author of the book,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fang Dang</ENAMEX>, said he might appeal. "It is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, to say if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX> is abnormal," he commented. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> says that it is considered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abnormal</ENAMEX>, but by whom--all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>? The most authoritative
definition is by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organisation</ENAMEX> which has removed it from its
list of illnesses."

            The
Independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fisk</ENAMEX>, reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has extradited to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who will almost certainly face the death penalty within a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani el-Sayegh</ENAMEX>, wanted for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dhahran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>, in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s 'justice'--regularly criticised
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US State Department</ENAMEX> for its routine denial of access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and
trials which fail to meet any international standards--is likely to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el-Sayegh</ENAMEX> to death whether or not he protests his innocence," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisk</ENAMEX> wrote. He
said executions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> have increased threefold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>: "At least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--have been publicly beheaded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>,
including foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan, Chad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigerians</ENAMEX>, had their scarves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ritually</ENAMEX> stripped from their heads before
being put to death by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> beside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosques</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
