
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Oct. 4</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inn Express</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Fallon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX> (outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>)

            As far as I can tell, there have been three
brilliant diet-food innovations over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 15 years</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was fat-free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entenmann's</ENAMEX>. I was skeptical of this product until the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War of 1991</ENAMEX>. During
the congressional deliberations on whether to approve the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to drive
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Foley</ENAMEX> delivered a rousing call for
bipartisan patriotism. I covered the speech and was struck by how thoughtful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX> was, what a skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orator</ENAMEX> he was, and quite frankly, how thin he'd
become over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX>. After the speech, I went grocery shopping at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway</ENAMEX> and, as luck would have it, spotted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> picking
up some provisions himself. I went over to him and, under the guise of
congratulating him on his moving speech, attempted to check out what he had in
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cart</ENAMEX>. It was filled with boxes of fat-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entenmann's</ENAMEX>. I mean, his cart
was a virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entenmann</ENAMEX>'s mountain. I became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> great dietetic discovery was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baked Lay</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potato Chips</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> has already discoursed at length on this delectable treat,
so there is no need for me to elaborate here.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> of our journey to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>, I discovered the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> major innovation. We were just outside of
Hagerstown, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>, when we chanced upon a strange-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>. It was
packed with the usual pimply high-schoolers, but it was tiny, and carried a
bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McProducts we</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hadn</ENAMEX>' t seen before. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> stood out from the rest: The
McSalad <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shaker</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McSalad Shaker</ENAMEX> comes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a slurpee</TIMEX>-style cup with a domed
lid. You add the dressing (I chose a low-fat, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-calorie concoction) then shake
vigorously.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McSalad Shaker</ENAMEX> solves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> previously
intractable problems of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> consumption. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the unequal
distribution of dressing. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is the tendency of lazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">restaurateurs</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chop salad</ENAMEX> into large, unwieldy pieces, making it impossible to eat without
violating the etiquette rule against eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> with a knife. The
McSalads are diced into tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX>, barely discernible to the human eye. You
can spoon them into your mouth as if you were eating a hot-fudge sundae. Like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fat-free Entenmann's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baked Lay's</ENAMEX>, this product fools your brain into
thinking you are consuming some obesity-inducing treat. But unlike those other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">innovations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McSalad</ENAMEX> is actually nutritionally sound. Indeed, it provides
something that is desperately missing from most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> diets.

            There is a slight problem with the McSalad
slogan--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dress</ENAMEX> 'em, Shake 'em, Enjoy 'em"--which sounds vaguely lewd. And also
because the product fits into an automobile cup-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>, there are potential
liability <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> recently issued a press release that reads:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WARNING, WARNING, WARNING</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Salad</ENAMEX> consumption requires a fork, and hence, two
hands, so do not partake of this product while driving a motor vehicle or
operating heavy machinery!" -- a disclaimer that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> "Do not take your
toaster oven into the shower with you."

            Sadly, as we have discovered during a long
McSalad-free trek across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McSalad Shaker</ENAMEX> is available only at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX>
experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> should stop focusing on transforming
the entire health care system and pass legislation requiring that the McSalad
Shaker be extended to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> coverage! The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would
end up saving so much on the health care of otherwise obese <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> that
solvency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> could be ensured into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next millennium</TIMEX>.

            Besides not being able to find another McSalad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shaker</ENAMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things I'm scared of on this trip: sex and death.
Regarding the latter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> tells me that, in his experience, every time you
drive across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> there is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one moment</TIMEX> when you almost die. You'll have
been driving for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 straight hours</TIMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> when suddenly the wind
blows a huge metal road sign into your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX>. Or a row of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> barreling at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles an hour</NUMEX> won't let you merge into their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX>. I've been certain that this
moment of doom has already occurred several times, but Bob assures me it's
still to come.

            Regarding sex, I think I'm safe, at least through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Seaboard</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachians</ENAMEX>.

            On the radio, they are still talking about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>'s controversial art exhibit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> is clearly wrong in
trying to stop the exhibit, but how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> right now
would be trying to shut it down if the art was offensive in other, even less
acceptable, ways? If it were racist, for example. What if there was a big
picture of, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>. That would cause a sensation, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saatchi</ENAMEX>!

            Regarding my traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX> forbade me
from talking about his germ phobia, although it was kind of hard to understand
what he was saying through that surgical mask he was wearing. (Just joking!)
But just between you and me, it's really bad. He thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contaminated</ENAMEX>, he won' t take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cubes</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>. He calls them "death
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cubes</ENAMEX>." And we can't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> that comes with our complimentary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">continental</ENAMEX> breakfast because they might have drawn the water first thing in
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> without letting the taps run for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX> required to flush
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> out of the pipes. ("Even if they said they'd done it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> says,
"would you believe them?")

            Pray for me.

         
      
   
