
   
   
      
         
            Timor the Merrier

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> passed a ban on "partial-birth" abortions. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s promised veto. The measure would ban a particular procedure often
used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-term</TIMEX> abortions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX>' spin: Abortionists are killing live <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX>' spin:
You're trying to kill 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX>
               . (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>,

                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Atul Gawande</ENAMEX> the arguments over partial-birth
abortion.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> dropped out of the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. She said
her inability to keep up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s fund raising made
her campaign "futile." Dole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>' spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaigns</ENAMEX> are now decided by money, not message. Dole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX>' spin: The
reason no one gave her money is that she had no message. Feminists debated
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) broke new ground for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in politics; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) failed to provide
an agenda for future progress. 

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> elected new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and voted to relinquish control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> contested election in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s history, the assembly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">selected Abdurraham Wahid</ENAMEX>, a moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> cleric, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. After a day
of violent protest by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megawati Sukarnoputri</ENAMEX>,
the assembly elected her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> said the elections were
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> in name only and questioned the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s ability to unite
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and revive the economy. But the New York
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> deemed the elections a promising break
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s autocratic history.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Yankees</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX> are in the World
Series. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Mets</ENAMEX> to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX>
Championship. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> prevailed over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pairing</ENAMEX> is a rematch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1996 World Series</ENAMEX>, which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> won. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX>, who are making their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> appearance
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>, are billed as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>). With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>
Championships, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> are claiming the title of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>."

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> blocked campaign-finance legislation. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 53</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> voted to cut off a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> filibuster, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven</NUMEX> short of the number
needed to force a vote on the bill. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Feingold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>, scaled back the legislation, which had been
approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, in order to increase support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. The bill
would have banned "soft money" but would not have regulated issue ads.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> had held that the measures would infringe on free speech. But the

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
                called this argument "a sham,"
saying big money is not only corrupting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political system, it is
"holding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> ." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> spin: We handed
reformers their hats. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> spin: No, you handed us a campaign
issue.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> recovered an intact woolly mammoth in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX>. They
dug the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> out of permafrost soil and transported it--still
frozen--to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This spring</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> will thaw the block
and examine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> and surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> said the find
offered unprecedented opportunities: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) to determine why <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mammoths</ENAMEX> became
extinct; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) to understand the world's climate at the time; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) to clone the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supervising scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Mol</ENAMEX> said, "This is a dream for me--to find
the soft parts and touch them and even smell them. It's very
exciting."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> resigned from the criminal investigation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Ray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, will complete the
investigations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> conduct regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s sexual
harassment allegations and the dismissal of travel-office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> will also
oversee the final report on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> said his work
will be "responsible and cost-effective," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> said he was a
politically motivated ideologue. The 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
                said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s legacy was mixed, but
"he should be remembered as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who--hampered alike by intensely adverse
conditions and by his own missteps--managed to perform a significant public
service." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s spin: Personal attacks and political divisiveness made it
impossible for me to continue. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' spin: Now you know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>
have felt for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are meeting to
negotiate the budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has threatened to veto many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'
proposals. With only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> appropriations bills approved, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> was
forced to extend the temporary spending measure that is keeping the government
open beyond its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> expiration. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> spin: We'll protect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> tax hikes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin: We'll protect social programs from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> budget cuts. The cynical spin: The numbers require either tax hikes
or budget cuts. The feel-good spin: At least now they're talking .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> promised to restructure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and
restore democracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pervaiz Musharraf</ENAMEX>, who led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> coup
that ousted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz Sharif</ENAMEX>, announced that a military-civilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">council</ENAMEX> would be formed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a week</TIMEX> to govern the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but provided no
timetable for relinquishing power. He also withdrew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
border and called for the resumption of peace talks. The rosy spin: After
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX>'s corruption and ineptitude, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musharraf</ENAMEX> is a godsend. The gloomy
spin: Without a timetable for democracy, he's still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>.

            

was the biggest decline in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>. The most frequently cited causes were: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s cautionary comments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> (he warned that
stocks and bonds could plunge if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> were to lose confidence in the
market); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) anticipation of higher interest rates; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) fear of inflation.
The bearish spin: The big correction is starting. The bullish spin: Relax,
we're already bouncing back. ("" explains what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> really said.)

         
      
   
