
   
   
      
         
            The Avengers 

            The execution-style killings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-July</TIMEX> left a tight knot in my gut. Not any tighter than
the knots left by the accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> atrocities against <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX>,
just different. For I can't help asking: Do these acts of revenge undermine the
humanitarian rationale of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>? Does the barbarism of
a few of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> vitiate the justness of the war? Can we
continue to view the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX> as the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>? Although I can arrive
at rational answers to these questions--no, no, and yes ()--the knot doesn't go
away.

            Postwar acts of
vengeance--ranging from isolated killings to the recommencing of full-scale
combat--are as historically commonplace as they are morally problematic. The
impulse to avenge is human, and the opportunities for it are abundant at the
end of a war, when law and authority evaporate. But that doesn't make them easy
either to condone or to condemn unequivocally.

            Consider the aftermath of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> rolled into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, a few of them raped and killed
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, some of those who had suffered
under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> rule turned violently against their oppressors--or their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oppressors</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX>--and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>, even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, may have been killed. (It's
important, however pedantic it may sound, to keep stressing that only "some" or
"a few" partook of such vengeance, since even choosing to discuss these
acts--and not the vastly more extensive crimes that preceded them--threatens to
distort history.) No one would cheer these reprisals, but only the most twisted
would shed their deepest tears for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, though scant among
the revenge-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX>, did in some cases seek retribution as well--and this
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War II</ENAMEX> retaliation has been especially problematic
(as I explain ). In a penetrating essay in the Forward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>, Hillel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Halkin</ENAMEX> asked whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who pursued extremely drastic retaliation were
"courageously honest in seeking to act out what others merely dreamed of, or
... shockingly criminal? Or both? Or are all such categories simply irrelevant
to the experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who, maddened by the loss of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and
entire worlds, might best be considered to have been 'temporarily insane' in
the full and exculpatory legal sense of the term?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> he specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Halkin</ENAMEX> refers is the legendary
(or notorious) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revenge Group</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX> by a young,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">charismatic poet</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abba Kovner</ENAMEX>, who is at the center of a fascinating
little chapter in the history of revenge killings. During the war, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kovner</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vainly</ENAMEX> tried to defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ghetto</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vilna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, and at the war's end
he banded together with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ghetto-defenders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX>. They all shared
an apartment in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lublin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> they were sitting around
drinking, contemplating their next move. "We sat with our glasses and the idea
flew out of us and suddenly it was no longer in the air but on the table,"
recalled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasha Reichman</ENAMEX>. "Everyone wanted revenge." Specifically,
they concocted the idea of a mass murder of their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> oppressors. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
Harmatz, one of their number, explained, they felt the only reason they had
been spared death like so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and kin was so that they could
administer revenge.

            The small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
soon grew in number to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 40</NUMEX>, according to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX>, drawing on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> of the death <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX>. They devised
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> plans. Plan A involved poisoning the water supplies of major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.
Plan B entailed killing off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> held in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> POW <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kovner</ENAMEX>
tried to enlist support from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, they balked--some out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">horror</ENAMEX>, some indifference. Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kovner</ENAMEX> procured some poison from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX> in the future <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reichman</ENAMEX> and others--posing
as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> or, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harmatz</ENAMEX>'s case, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knight</ENAMEX>--got jobs in the
waterworks of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nuremberg</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. They secured blueprints to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>' water mains, staying up late to memorize every detail. They figured
out where to administer the poison as well as how to spare the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were living.

            Plan A went awry, however, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> arrested Kovner
as he attempted to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reichman</ENAMEX> decided to revert to Plan B--the
killing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13, 1946</TIMEX>, under a full moon, a handful of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> broke into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nuremberg</ENAMEX> that provided <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX>'
Stalag 13 POW <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they had planted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX> had managed to hide
under the floorboards several bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arsenic</ENAMEX>, which had been tested on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cat</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> died.) They sprinkled the white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">loaves</ENAMEX> of
black <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rye bread</ENAMEX> that were headed for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Stalag 13</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reichman</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> knew that
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> received only plain white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> to
eat.) Suddenly, hearing the banging of window shutters that had come loose,
security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> arrived, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reichman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> fled. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">loaves</ENAMEX> were
shipped off anyway--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> suspected a burglary, not a poisoning--and as a
result <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 2,000</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> came down with food poisoning. None,
apparently, died.

            With the failure of these
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> plans, most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revenge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> migrated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>. A few pursued a
Plan C: retribution against known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. They were joined in this
dark enterprise by some renegade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Brigade</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who lived
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> during the war and fought with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brigade members</ENAMEX> had arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> at the war's tail end and, arriving
too late for combat, vented their revenge impulses by hunting down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gestapo</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> border.

            Eventually, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> got hold of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gestapo</ENAMEX> official
who provided them with a list of names of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, their wartime activities,
even their addresses. They proceeded to track down some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who had
participated in the mass extermination of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and, on their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>,
kill them. Typically, they would dress up as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX>, drive
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and ask him to come with them on some conventional
business. Then they would shoot or suffocate him.

            The vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, of course, did nothing
of the sort--just like the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pole</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>.
As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Jonah Goldhagen</ENAMEX> has written, what is striking among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Holocaust survivors</ENAMEX> was, in fact, the relative absence of avenging actions. The
more common response among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> was to devote themselves to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zionism</ENAMEX> as a
bulwark against future persecution, or to engage in symbolic retribution
(banning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> national radio), or to pursue justice through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nuremberg</ENAMEX> war crimes tribunals or other legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">arenas</ENAMEX> of justice. Likewise,
many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> were punished, sometimes with death, by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> courts
of law.

            It is always futile to try to draw practical
lessons from history. Yet it seems possible that one reason <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> acts of
vengeance were relatively few was simply that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nuremberg</ENAMEX> trials existed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> could take comfort that at least some of the most evil of their oppressors
would be punished by a united world opinion. Other efforts to prosecute <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>--from the apprehension of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adolf Eichmann</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> to the ongoing
efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon Wiesenthal Center</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Office of Special</ENAMEX>
Investigations--continue the honorable policy of replacing lawless revenge with
legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. Even so, it's worth considering that a more vigorous
pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, while unlikely to stop every retaliatory
killing, might nonetheless send a signal that the world believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> to be
a substitute--not an instrument--for revenge.

         
      
   
