
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Online Political Advertising</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Salesman Reports</ENAMEX> 

            Over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>, the advertising business as a whole has moved from a mood
of hostile skepticism toward the Internet to an almost euphoric embrace of its
possibilities. In my new job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of political advertising for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Network</ENAMEX>, I'm experiencing what feels like a warp-speed repetition of
the same process. For the moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> are still resistant to the new medium.
But I suspect that their doubts will melt as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign demonstrates the
open-ended potential of political advertising on the Web.

            The
basis for skepticism about Web-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> advertising is that few have
ever seen such a campaign, let alone one that had a demonstrable result. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>
Vallone, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> who ran against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> last time
around, was one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to make significant use of banner ads in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vallone</ENAMEX> ran negative ads about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> Web
site, among other places. While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> study suggests that these ads diminished
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>'s favorability rating among those who saw them, the negligible boost to
a losing campaign didn't quite make the case.

            A year
from now, we'll have better data about the effectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> ads. What
we can say in the meantime is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> advertising is capable of doing things
no other kind of political advertising can. Here are some of the advantages I'm
touting to political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> and campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> this election
season.

            

               Targeting
            

            When
you advertise on television or radio, you base your spending decisions on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX> surveys, but you can't target precise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of swing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that might matter to you. With the Web, you can strike at them
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surgically</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of niche <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> on the Web as well as Internet
service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, network portals, and free e-mail services. These sites pride
themselves on collecting highly specific information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, through
registration, subscription, and the use of "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>" (for more on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>, see

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>). Banner ads can be directed at
precise demographic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> defined by age, ZIP code, income, and various other
characteristics. What's more, several of the larger portal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are able to
"merge and purge" their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> data with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> lists. This means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can target not just middle-aged basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> but also middle-aged
basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> who are registered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. Of
course, the more precise the targeting, the more expensive the ad. Reaching
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">generic New Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> might cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> per thousand impressions. For a
specific category of registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, the price might rise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as high as $70</NUMEX> per
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">thousand</ENAMEX>.

            

               Activization
            

            The
Web can serve as a tool to motivate those that are passionate about issues. A
recent campaign hosted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juno Advocacy Network</ENAMEX> shows this potential. Juno
sent an e-mail on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Forests Campaign</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>. In response to this, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">171,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> sent e-mail messages to Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> asking him to help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX>--without cutting down
any <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. That's a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> response rate. With more expensive conventional
direct mail, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent to 5 percent</NUMEX> response is considered highly
effective.

            

               Measurability
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>
returned from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> interaction with Internet ads far outweighs what you can
discern from television, radio, or direct-mail campaigns. Thanks to the miracle
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> know precisely how many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> they targeted
interacted with their ad in a number of ways. A banner ad that contains a
streaming video version of a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> spot can tell you not only how many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> viewed the commercial but also where in the commercial they got bored
and clicked out.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first</ENAMEX> banner ads were relatively obvious appeals for a "click-through." Now
they are becoming interactive in ever more imaginative ways. Think of a banner
ad as the Internet on a bumper sticker. It can do just about anything with
video, sound, or animation. But first it has to grab your attention from a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three-quarter inch</NUMEX> space on the computer screen. The most popular forms at the
moment include:

            
               Active

               Information Banners
            

            The
AIB delivers real-time information in the banner. The ad displays information
in a format similar to a stock ticker. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Advertisers</ENAMEX> control the text in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">banner</ENAMEX> and can target it by demographic or issue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Advertisers</ENAMEX> might also
use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIB</ENAMEX> to respond to a recent news event they're taking a position on or
for any other rapid-response need.

            
               E-Mail

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banners</ENAMEX>
            

            The
e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> banner ad gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> an opportunity to collect e-mail
addresses from Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertiser</ENAMEX> may then use the information to
distribute e-mail messages, create user demographic profiles, and gather
information. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, this banner provides an easy, convenient way to
subscribe to e-mail announcements from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> or campaign of choice.

            
               Expanding

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menu Banners</ENAMEX>
            

            The
expanding menu banner contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> buttons that activate menus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> then
choose from a menu and navigate to different locations on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertiser</ENAMEX>'s Web
site. This allows a campaign based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> key issues to "drill down" on each
of them in great detail. Once the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> has found the issue he wants more
information about, a click of the mouse takes him directly to the page that
interests him.

            
               Streaming

               Video Banners
            

            Most
of the political/issue campaigns that will advertise on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> will have
already produced TV ads. Those TV spots can now be compressed and delivered to
Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> from a banner ad: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Click</ENAMEX> here for my stance on free air time for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>!" This option becomes more attractive when combined with the
capability to deliver specific messages to targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> or geographic
locations.

            Come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX>, I
expect the question will no longer be whether Web-based political advertising
works, but whether it works too well.

         
      
   
