
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Issue</ENAMEX>

            A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> announced his candidacy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
he promised to defend the right to abortion. "Some try to duck the issue of
choice," declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. "Not me. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> must be able to make that
decision for themselves. I will stand up for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s right to choose." To
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wags</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> replied: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>] won't duck the
issue; he just won't say what its name is."

            
Abortion rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> have ducked the A-word for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> they said
they stood for "choice," then they changed their name to "pro-choice," and
finally they obliterated the debate's physical substance by renaming it "the
choice issue." For this, they were skewered by abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. But now the
anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>, too, are dropping the A-word. Abortion is becoming "the
life issue."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life</ENAMEX>
issues" aren't new. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> has long discussed abortion,
euthanasia, and the death penalty under the rubric of "life issues," and a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Right-to-Life</ENAMEX> (i.e., anti-abortion) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Willke</ENAMEX>, has been running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Issues Institute</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. What's
new is the conversion of the plural phrase "life issues," which sensibly
connected topics relating to mortality, into the singular phrase "the life
issue," whose only purpose is to replace the word "abortion."

            This
verbal conversion is being driven by a political conversion. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> supported the right to abortion
and was ostracized by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> has made up
with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, largely by coming out against legal abortion. He
seems just as uncomfortable railing against abortion in this election as he was
defending it in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--perhaps because he's faking it, perhaps because
he worries that pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifers</ENAMEX> think he's faking it, and perhaps because he
worries that pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choicers</ENAMEX> think he's not. To avoid the dreaded word, he has
renamed it.

            Two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> about
"abortion." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> responded with a long lecture on "the life issue," his
"pro-life" position, "partial birth," and "parental consent." Not once did he
mention the A-word. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Press</ENAMEX> asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> about "abortion." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> replied, "On the life issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, I've laid
out a plan of action to move the issue forward." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last weekend</TIMEX> on Late
Edition , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bragged</ENAMEX> that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> he had "put out a plan of action to
move the life issue forward." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX>, understandably puzzled, asked,
"On abortion rights, you mean?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> answered: "In terms of ... preserving
the sanctity of life."

            "The
life issue" seems to be catching on. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hopeful Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> stood in front of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> abortion clinic and challenged
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> "to get a lot more serious about the sanctity-of-life issue." Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> press release castigated other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for refusing to
litmus-test judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> on "the pro-life issue." The word "abortion"
didn't appear until the end of the release.

            
Euphemisms reveal as much as they obscure. Abortion rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> adopted
"the choice issue" because they concluded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> didn't like abortion. If
abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> adopt "the life issue," it will signify that they have
concluded the public doesn't like attacks on abortion, either. It will also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liberate Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> to change the subject to tax cuts, school deregulation,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> privatization--or, as he prefers to call them, the "choice"
issues.

         
      
   
