
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">285</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Counterintuitive</ENAMEX>, Sir!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the
Army <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Caldera</ENAMEX> has announced a plan that will put more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. What is this program called?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">284</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gamy":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, speaking on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Sperling</ENAMEX> said it reminded him of the game
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twister</ENAMEX>. What?
                     
                  
               
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nude Greco-Roman</ENAMEX> wrestling that concludes every episode of Late
Edition ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Puff</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> game, 'Twizter.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John J. Edwards</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> had a similar, but "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bendy Reachy</ENAMEX>," answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s efforts to distinguish between sins of malice and sins of
weakness."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Thompson</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>
Pyron , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leary</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX> )

            " 'Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infantile</ENAMEX> and soul-dead, hyper-consumeristic ways in a world where sunsets go
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unnoticed</ENAMEX>,' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sperling</ENAMEX>, looking up from an essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McKibben</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
O'Grady
            

            "I
haven't read the question yet, but my answer is Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            "In all discussion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">metaphor</ENAMEX>," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. W. Fowler</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Modern English Usage</ENAMEX> , "it must be
borne in mind that some metaphors are living, i.e., are offered and accepted
with a consciousness of their nature as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substitutes</ENAMEX> for their literal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">equivalents</ENAMEX>, while others are dead, i.e., have been so often used that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hearer</ENAMEX> have ceased to be aware that the words used are not literal."
Certainly we can consign all sports metaphors to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">linguistic cemetery</ENAMEX>. And
now, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Sperling</ENAMEX>, we can bury the metaphors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crapshoot</ENAMEX>, a spin of the wheel, a stacked deck--replacing them with the vibrant
metaphors of the rec <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twister</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> must be a little skeptical of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sperling</ENAMEX>'s personal experience with the game. Does he himself play, or has he
merely observed others? (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colleagues</ENAMEX>? High-priced hookers?) But even if he
lacks direct knowledge, he has chosen the perfect suburban verbal style for
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, an excellent advance on "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>." Presumably, a
living, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonian Einstein</ENAMEX> would declare, "I cannot believe that God plays
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> with the world."

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxing Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> economic arguments--in particular the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s defense of its proposed tax cut--remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Sperling</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twister</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> passed separate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> tax-cut bills, which they hope to reconcile in conference
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> recess begins at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this week</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has
vowed to veto any tax cut of that size, saying it favors the rich over the
poor, could drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> into deficit, and fails to provide for urgent
needs including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> reforms, education, and debt reduction.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metaphor Fun</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Can you give the literal
meaning of these figures of speech, each of which appeared in a recent
quotation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. A new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Another large piece of plaster

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. A dangerous slope

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. A bad apple in the box

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. A bunch of ayatollahs

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. A gangster

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. The girl

            
               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>, firmly in control of the
non-tax-cheating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>. Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>, "We have a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sheriff</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX>, and it's a brand new game."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Hens Green</ENAMEX>'s ruling that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX> did not illegally distribute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> guides meant
to boost <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. Says campaign finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert F. Bauer</ENAMEX>,
"This is certainly another large piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plaster</ENAMEX> which is falling off the
ceiling of campaign finance regulation."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The new sound system for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Opera</ENAMEX>
that will not amplify voices. Worries <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lofti Mansourie</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Opera</ENAMEX>, "It is a dangerous slope. ... We have to fight hard not to
compromise the natural sound of the voice and its natural projection."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Banker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mathewson</ENAMEX> who gives <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cayman Islands</ENAMEX>
money-laundering a bad name. Says banking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Feldhaus</ENAMEX>, "There is a
very legitimate role for places like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caymans</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want the ability
to operate in a regulatory-neutral and tax-neutral atmosphere. ... Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathewson</ENAMEX> was just a bad apple in the box."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Intolerant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> who disdain sex of any kind.
Says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gorman</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
battling an incursion of hot-bed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> neighborhood, "We have a
very active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX>, but we're not a bunch of ayatollahs."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6, 7, 8</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Chou</ENAMEX>, a promoter of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> statehood for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, "China is like a gangster; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>. Every
time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangster</ENAMEX> tries to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, she has to call the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> to come save her. Our job is to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> married to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>. Then there is no danger, and the protection is permanent."

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
