
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hays</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6, 1999</TIMEX>

            Last night was not the best.

            As part of her ongoing I-am-not-a-princess
campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> has been claiming she wants to stay at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> that cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29.95</NUMEX>. I
have resisted so far. Last night we picked out a nice-looking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$62.95</NUMEX>
establishment that shall remain nameless (for reasons that will become
obvious). We were heading up to our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> when the pleasant, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>
said, "Oh, one thing: If you turn on the heater, the smoke alarm will go off."
Since it was a cold <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, this had a slight Monty Pythonesque quality--"Should
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> come into your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and hit you over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with a hammer, pay no
mind!" We imprudently forged ahead and settled into our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> (we're sharing,
though as part of my "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands-off</ENAMEX>' "policy--see below--I always ask for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beds</ENAMEX>). After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> of sleep, E turned on the light, and announced
"I'm not feeling well." Indeed, she was feverish, and large red welts had
appeared all over her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. I rushed her to the local emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s diagnosis: The sheets had poisoned her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> explained this was
not uncommon (apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX> used by some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> can cause an
allergic reaction) and sent her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different prescriptions, which
returned her skin to its previous lustrous condition but rendered her
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">semi-comatose.</ENAMEX>

            This incident decisively ended the
I-am-not-a-princess campaign, which quite frankly wasn't working anyway.
Note to E : I see where you have called me a hypochondriac in your
earlier entry ... But I don't have to be taken to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> if my thread
count falls below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>.

            To be fair, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> has (until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>) required less
maintenance than expected. Her morning beauty routine is minimal to
nonexistent. She just jumps into the shower and puts her wet hair back into a
ponytail, which emphasizes her deceptively childlike appearance, and makes me
feel slightly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humbertish</ENAMEX> at check-in time. (It doesn't help when I ask for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
beds.)

            Some non<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-E</ENAMEX>-related points:

            
               Trends noticed in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's Heartland</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
Skyline improvement. Postmodernism may have worn out its welcome, but it has
certainly made cities look better from a distance. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>--all now have a fabulous, turreted, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oz</ENAMEX>-like appearance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) More
hitchhikers than there were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindy Hop</ENAMEX> (whatever that
is). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Frampton Revival</ENAMEX>!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Favorite Billboard</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monks</ENAMEX>? Yes!
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-800-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me-a-Monk</ENAMEX>"

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tipper Principle</ENAMEX>: By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2000</TIMEX>, I
predict, we will all hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX>. This is not because she is particularly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unlikable</ENAMEX>. To the contrary--it's precisely because she is likable that
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX> will stick her in our faces until we can't stand the
sight of her. This now appears to be an ineluctable law of modern politics: All
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> become unpopular. If they're unpopular to begin with, the law is
satisfied ab initio . If they are popular to begin with, they will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overexposed</ENAMEX> until they aren't. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernestine Bradley</ENAMEX> is next.

            Back to E: I do think I may have scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some</NUMEX> points
with my protective response during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pea</ENAMEX> episode. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> strategy is to take no overt romantic actions, in keeping
with the founding lie of this journey. Make her wonder why I'm not
hitting on her.

            She hasn't made any moves on me either. Perhaps
she's trying the same approach.

         
      
   
