
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannibalism</ENAMEX>? <I>Yeah, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby</ENAMEX>!!!</I>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Spy Who Shagged Me</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinema</ENAMEX>). Good reviews overall. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> carp that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Myers</ENAMEX>' horny '60s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swinger</ENAMEX> is not as novel the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time around: "Most of the silliness has
become pretty strenuous and some of the sweetness has settled into desperation"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). But despite their
protestations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> can't help recounting all their favorite jokes from
the film, a habit that effectively dilutes their complaints. On the plus side:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> and his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Evil</ENAMEX>, are fleshed out and funnier
this time around. On the minus side: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Graham</ENAMEX> doesn't match up to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Hurley</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX>' ladylove. (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the film's biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, saying it's "better than anyone dared hope:
bigger, more inventive, and more frolicsome than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, with a grab
bag of scatological gags that are almost as riotous when you think back on
them." Click to read the rest.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Red Violin</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fran√</ENAMEX>ßois
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girard</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirty-Two Short Films About Glenn Gould</ENAMEX> ) hits the musical theme
again in this "odd, piquant tale" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ) that traces the peregrinations of a priceless
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">17 th -century violin</ENAMEX>. Is it an "utterly predictable" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Schickel, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) gimmick for a costume drama, or is it a fascinating ride
through history? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>) is in the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX>, complaining that as soon as the spectacular score subsides the movie
"clatters back down to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>." But others find the film "beautifully crafted,
intricately designed" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Harrison</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ) and credit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel L. Jackson</ENAMEX>'s outstanding performance as a crotchety and morally
ambiguous violin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appraiser</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about the film.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hannibal</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Harris</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delacorte</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>
raves in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> that this sequel to The
Silence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> surpasses its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>: "It is, in fact, one of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most frightening popular novels of our time, the other being The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Exorcist</ENAMEX> . ... If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannibal Lecter</ENAMEX> isn't a Count <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> for the
computer-and-cell-phone age, then we don't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
Lehmann-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haupt</ENAMEX> (the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) speaks for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> when he
notes that this one, while a fantastic thriller, "simply lacks the compact
power of the previous books." A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are horrified by the amped-up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gore</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> cuts off his own face, feeds it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, then has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stomachs</ENAMEX> pumped so he can try to have the recovered nose surgically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reattached</ENAMEX>). Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre Donahue</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ): "You end up wanting to
quickly kill off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hannibal</ENAMEX> Lecter yourself, just to stanch the flow of foul
language, repellent imagery and bloodshed." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King's</ENAMEX> review; the page also includes a
clip of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> reading from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hannibal</ENAMEX> .)

            

               
                  Elementals: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stories of Fire and Ice</ENAMEX>
               ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.S. Byatt</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.S. Byatt</ENAMEX>'s collection of fanciful
tales wins the hearts of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, although all admit that some stories
don't quite work. But when she's on, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byatt</ENAMEX>'s writing "leaps and pirouettes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shimmies</ENAMEX> and shivers" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriella Stern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ) and has
an "aura of extravagant ingenuity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Barber</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). A
few find the tales a bit too similar--there is a theme throughout of the
conflict between the warm southern temperament and the cold northern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--but
most deem the sameness unimportant when the writing is so superb. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to read an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byatt</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Surrender
               ,by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical Brothers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMD/Astralwerks</ENAMEX>).
The dance-music duo surprise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> with their latest: "Instead of revisiting
blocks already rocked, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> down untravelled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX> from which
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> have shied away. ... The world has already praised the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> of clever, catchy dance <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surrender</ENAMEX> will
finally make the public respect these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> as mature, intelligent and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enterprising musicians</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">(M. Tye Comer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMJ</ENAMEX> ). What's different this time
is that they've relaxed a little and broadened their horizons from exclusively
dance-oriented music: "This is a subtler, moodier, sweeter, funkier record,
less in-your-face, more in-your-heart. Even the dance instrumentals are booty
shakers, not bone crunchers" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to listen to
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> from the new album.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terror Twilight</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavement</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matador</ENAMEX>). Excellent
reviews for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> album from indie rock's favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lo-fi sons</ENAMEX>. It's not as
groundbreaking as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crooked Rain, Crooked Rain</ENAMEX> , but it's close:
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he music is leaner and cleaner, with lunatic word play that remains an
advanced course in pretzel logic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Nashawaty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> ). The album
"redefines the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s stellar status" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Berry</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vocalist-guitarist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Malkmus</ENAMEX> delivers not just the
expected musical power-punch but dead-on lyrics as well: It's "his most direct
statement of purpose ever (in short: Things hurt, and growing up is hard, but
kissing helps)" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Levy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to listen.)

            

               
                  Californication
               , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Hot Chili</ENAMEX> Peppers
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WEA/Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). After years of addiction and attempts at recovery, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 16-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> has entered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> land. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> come
down hard: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> says "it's mostly midtempo mush," and
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Browne</ENAMEX> detects a "whiff of desperation" on
the record. On the upside: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guitarist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Frusciante</ENAMEX> returns to give
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> a hint of their former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jammy-jammin</ENAMEX>' glory; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> is wildly positive (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>), if completely alone in its
enthusiasm--"They've written a whole album's worth of tunes that tickle the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ear</ENAMEX>, romance the booty, swell the heart, moisten the tear ducts and dilate the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> eye" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Tate</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to watch a multimedia presentation on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Music
            

            
               
                  Learning
Curve
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ Rap</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony/Columbia</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> give a polite nod to the
debut album from one of the few female <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DJs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> world of
electronic music. Most praise her for being able to hold her own, as opposed to
noticing any genuine musical ability, and note that the album is far more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>-oriented than the drum 'n' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass</ENAMEX> and jungle she spins live.

         
      
   
