
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bum Situation</ENAMEX>

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I hope you will take a look at my situation.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four years ago</TIMEX> I took in my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> (then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31 years old</TIMEX>) who was down on
his luck. I was divorced and raising <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and it really was nice
to have the adult contact. I remarried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> doesn't
seem to want to leave.
            

            
               He has never had a
place of his own--always staying with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. He finally got a
part-time job, but there's no way he could afford to live on his own. He pays
me <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> a week <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, which of course doesn't begin to cover his
expenses. The worst part is that he has "borrowed" many things from my home and
sold them for money. We have had so many discussions about this that now he
just hides in my den (his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>), and I hardly ever see him. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> tries
to stay out of the line of fire and is no help at all. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> tell me I am
an enabler and that I should put him out, but I can't. I am his only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in
the state and am so afraid that if I do, someday a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> will knock on my
door to tell me that they found my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> frozen to death in some paper box
under a bridge! I know that I'm not doing him a service letting him stay, but
what am I to do?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caring Sibling</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Care</ENAMEX>,

            What a lovely sister you are. Now you must be a
strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. He has no life living in your den and hocking your belongings.
For your sake and his, he has got to go. Do not look at it as "putting him
out," but rather steering him to an independent life. It sounds like there's an
underlying emotional problem in his way. Get him in touch with a local mental
health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. For example, he may be clinically depressed, in which case
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> might jump-start a new and motivated life. Family Service America
provides low-cost or free therapy and job training. Ask advice about arranging
housing--maybe a group situation allied with a service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, perhaps someplace
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX>.

            Painful as it may be,
tough love is what's called for. If you can afford it, give him a stipend for a
specified period of time as a tangible sign of your helping hand. That would
also lessen any guilt you might have. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four years</TIMEX> is a long time to provide a
crash pad for anyone. If you don't do something soon, you may lose your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
and still have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> hiding in the den. Much luck to you.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, positively

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I have always wanted
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was recently widowed. How can I approach her without seeming
like a vulture? Should I, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine</ENAMEX>, make it clear that I am "there
for her"?
            

            

               --Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mr.</ENAMEX>,

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> approach would be fine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kindness</ENAMEX> is
never confused with being predatory, assuming you are already <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Prudie
would suggest you not ask the recently bereaved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> to a dancing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> as
your opening salvo; instead an invitation to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> brunch and a stroll would
strike the right casual note. You won't, of course, confess you've always had a
yen for her. Got that?

            Small caveat: Since you
do not say just when the deceased shuffled off this mortal coil, check with
mutual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to see just how grief-stricken she is. If she's in terrible
shape, give her some time before you ask her out. In fact, a phone call to ask
how she's doing would be a good precursor to any invitation.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, sensitively

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have been dating
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year and a half</TIMEX>. I left my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> for him, which I now
know was a huge mistake. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is still married, but he tells me that he
doesn't love his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. He says he loves me and promises that eventually we will
be together. I know being with him is wrong, however I can't not see him. I
realize the best thing to do is forget about him, but how do I do
that?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hopeless</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Hope</ENAMEX>,

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> for every married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
swore he didn't love his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and that "eventually" he and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>
"would be together," her fortune would rival that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. Borrowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> are bad news--even when they leave her and marry you .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> who cheat have a screw loose, forgive the unfortunate metaphor.

            How do you forget him? You review the situation and
tote up a big list of every negative thing you can think of ... starting with
the fact that you left your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inamorato</ENAMEX> did zip. You're the dish
on the side, period. As a mechanistic approach, start acting like you're
available, spend time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, get active in hobbies or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, do
things where single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> meet each other. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hears that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Habitat</ENAMEX> for
Humanity projects, for example, are quite a good venue.)

            Now repeat after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>:
Borrowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> are bad news. And if the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> in your signature refers to your
age, that's the prime time to attract suitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. And even if it refers to
your waist, get cracking.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, wisely

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I was recently asked
by a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> to be his best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. While deeply honored, this occasion
presents me with great difficulty. You see, I am gay. Though it may not be
apparent to everyone, my close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are fully aware of my "persuasion."
Having said that, my big problem centers on the "traditional" stag <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that
the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is asked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. Since the groom has both straight and gay male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, how does a gay best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> host a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stag party</ENAMEX> that will be fun for my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> as well as those in attendance? Should his gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> not be invited?
Thanks in advance for your advice, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best Man</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Best</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has a hunch that
girls jumping out of cakes would amuse anyone ... if they still do that kind of
thing. Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> doesn't know what goes on at stag <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Which is why
she suggests you enlist a straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the groom to help you plan the
party. That way, you will come up with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> enjoyable for both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterosexual</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and nature's bachelors. Keeping a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--gay and
straight--amused for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> should not be all that difficult. And what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">honoree</ENAMEX> will remember best is that all his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> were there.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, festively

         
      
   
