
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;A Touching</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smelling</ENAMEX>) Tale&quot;

            
               "You're telling me
I have to touch anyone who comes in here, even if I don't want to? I have to
get up really close to them and smell their perfume, smell their breath<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" asked
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incredulous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Damico</ENAMEX>. As it turns out, yes, he does. And what does he
have to do after that?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 259</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Even Educated Fleas Do It":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> and middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do it, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say
that's fine, as long as they do it for "health purposes" and not to "promote
superstition, spread rumors, engage in sedition, destroy social order or hold
mass assemblies." Do what?
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Golf?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie Haskins</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dissident bingo</ENAMEX>, every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Methodist</ENAMEX>!!!"--Ananda
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gupta</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s banned book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> had a
similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santería.</ENAMEX> Or menopause. It's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or the other, I'm fairly sure."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Simon</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            It's not what you do,
it's the purpose for which you do it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty-five years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pinball</ENAMEX> machines displayed this warning: "for entertainment purposes only."
Apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> was concerned that they might be used for gambling
or, as I recall, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> ritual. Since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Judaism</ENAMEX> has changed a lot;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX>, incidentally, has not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> condom
machines of that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> were marked "for prevention of disease only," lest someone
seek sexual pleasure, i.e., have sex for entertainment purposes only. Even now
ads for stocks are tagged "for information purposes only," i.e., this ad is not
an ad: It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">René Magritte</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX>. It is not foolish to consider intent,
hence the distinction between murder and accident and serious dieting. If a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> rendered you unconscious and went at you with a knife, it would mean
one thing if it were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O. J. Simpson</ENAMEX>--or any other former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great</ENAMEX>--but
something else altogether if it were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>. Or an old-school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>,
performing a relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bris</ENAMEX> atop a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pinball</ENAMEX> machine.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sect Crimes</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> law).

            Fearing government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harassment</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Hongzhi</ENAMEX>, moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. In a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>, he accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> of trying to pay off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> to extradite him. Denying rumors of an imminent crackdown,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the sect that as long as they stick
to group breathing and meditation exercises in public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> they face no
repression. They are, however, forbidden to "stir up chaos and destroy social
stability."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>' Corner
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s official state Web site offers this fun activity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> enjoys
sending and receiving letters. If you would like to receive an on-line letter
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>, type your name, choose a question and select submit!" That
is: You can receive a reply the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> didn't write to a question you didn't
write that he didn't read. Easy to see why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> enjoys that.

            Which of the following
are actual prewritten questions from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.W.'s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> list, and which are merely
crude attempts to mock and deride him?

            

               What are you doing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> a better place to live?

               What would you like to say to young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> considering a career in politics
or public service?

               What makes a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> and a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>?

               How did you get to be so handsome?

               What has your business experience taught you?

               Have you ever heard an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> use the term "business experience"?

               Why doesn't your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> bio mention your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX>? Trouble
with the cops?

               Is it true that exploiting your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s political, business, and social
connections will only get you through the door, and after that you've got to do
a fairly good job much of the time?

               Did that previous question seem too smirky for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>? 'Cause I could, you
know, ask more stuff about your business experience.

               Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> slogan, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prosperity With a Purpose</ENAMEX>--what purpose? Could it be
killing space <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>? Or the poor?

               Your prep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> isn't in your bio. More trouble? Stealing from another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kid</ENAMEX>'s locker?

               Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts Jr.</ENAMEX> said: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has the vision to see all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as they can be and not as they are."
But when I don't see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as they are, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> get my urine tested. Is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX>? (You mean when they, like, turn into monsters, right?)

            

            
               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Actual Prewritten Questions</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2, 3</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.

            Crude <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Attempts To Mock</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deride</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, 6-12</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Zazinski</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headline Haiku</ENAMEX>
            

            Gain off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fat Pension</ENAMEX>

            Fridge full of beer

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Immigrants</ENAMEX> on the job

            Busy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15, 1999</TIMEX>

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Front</ENAMEX> page only)

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX> and sex.

         
      
   
