
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999><ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Horrors</ENAMEX></SPAN></SPAN>

            

               
                  New
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 5</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story tracks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> narcissistic young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> as they claw through
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s casting maw. They misrepresent their ages, dress the part of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ingénue</ENAMEX>, and make sure to be seen at the right hot spots pledging dedication to
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>. They all get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s determination to
capitalize on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomlet</ENAMEX> by churning out cookie-cutter teen dramas.
... An article forecasts that commercially available high-resolution
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">satellites</ENAMEX> will make the world safer by enabling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdogs</ENAMEX> to monitor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">troublemaking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> will be cowed by the prospect of
surveillance. ... In an essay, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Singer</ENAMEX> argues that every yuppie
contributes to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s death when he chooses foie gras rather than donating
to UNICEF (for more on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> below).

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 4</TIMEX>
            

            The cover story worries that earlier retirement and
reduced birthrates in the West will contract the labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and reduce living
standards. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> should expunge pension incentives that encourage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to quit early and should create more "bridge" jobs to ease the
transition to retirement. ... An editorial laments <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s failure to live up to its
geopolitical potential. Despite having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
attracts relatively little foreign investment and trade. If <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>'s
elections lead to political stability, the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could enhance
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s standing by harmonizing relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, liberalizing trade
policy, and privatizing industry.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have embarked on "a
national orgy of thrill seeking." Bored <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> seeking the stimulation of
endangerment are participating in more adventure sports, sinking more money
into highly speculative stocks, and changing jobs with greater bravado than
ever before because traditional risks have been minimized by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and
government regulation. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have hauled in
record amounts of "soft money." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of this year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> raised
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29.4 million</NUMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24.2 million</NUMEX>. But the bumper harvest
might be both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>' last, according to an article. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Donors</ENAMEX> are balking at
perpetual political dunning. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 100</NUMEX> large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have formed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to
press for reform. Big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> have already spurned
overtures for cash.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story questions whether high-stakes standardized tests
are improving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Testing helps assess progress, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> are
mandating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> be held back for failing, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are sanctioning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for low scores. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Schools</ENAMEX> are focusing their curricula on exams to the
detriment of long-term learning. ... A book
excerpt traces the roots of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reformers</ENAMEX> seeking to create
opportunities for underprivileged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> adopted the test to assess
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">scholastic aptitude</ENAMEX>. Rather than equalize opportunity, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> turns the
uppermost percentile into a privileged class and perpetuates the educational
disadvantage of other test-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX>. ... An article rethinks the drug war. During the crack epidemic,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> imposed draconian mandatory minimum sentences for drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">offenses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> needs to roll back these wrong-headed laws and treat drug
offenders more compassionately.

            

               
                  The
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6</TIMEX>
            

            A
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Singer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> of ethical treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, pinpoints
the radical philosopher's inconsistencies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> argues that all sentient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> are equally valuable and that you should donate your income until
you're as impoverished as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bengali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX>, but he lives in comfort. He
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates euthanasia</ENAMEX> and condemns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for caring more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strangers</ENAMEX>, but he provides his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>-afflicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> with
around-the-clock care. ... An article chronicles the aborted return of
offbeat television. Hoping to revive the taste for surreal television, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">hired Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> a noirish program called
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mulholland Drive</ENAMEX> . After insisting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> cut down on
cigarette-smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog poop</ENAMEX>, the risk-averse network
ditched the series and filled its time slot with another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clone</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
