
   
   
      
         
            Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dictators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benevolent</ENAMEX> and Otherwise

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>, who took office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, was heralded
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
Post as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
Party dominance, which ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> has "artfully protected his
freedom of movement," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial.
"He has built a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that cannot be brought down by any single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>,
surrounded himself with a deliberately weak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>, and left outside his
government a demoralized and confused opposition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than a third</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX>. In short, the newly launched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> era has the makings of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> version of a benevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> , which led
its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a report
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> is planning to seek détente with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s "enemy number one," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>,
against strong objections by his own military intelligence, also pointed out in
its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> has "achieved his fundamental goal--a
government unthreatened by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Damocles</ENAMEX> over its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>." It said that the
hopes and expectations of "the entire public" are with him.

            
Abroad, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s overtures toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> will be "widely welcomed" but warned that he needs to get a move on.
Although he now enjoys "a formidable amount of individual political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>,"
it is unlikely that he will "be able to retain such power on a permanent
basis," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial. "It will not be long before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX>
Party starts to resent its semi-detached <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, before secular and religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> find cause to conspire against each other within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>, and
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> demand immediate action on other domestic issues." A comment piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> has
come to power "with the immense advantage of succeeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>,
who, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, became the most widely detested <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> at home and
abroad since the formation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> is now expected to
disappear, unlamented in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lecture tour circuit,
though there are no signs of anybody offering the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> he is asking for a
single speech."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> ,
which led its front page with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s advocacy of a "peace of the brave"
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, published an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hosni Mubarak</ENAMEX>, who described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> as a "promising" prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> who will "probably adopt the same line as [assassinated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabin</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mubarak</ENAMEX> also said he hopes to arrange an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> summit
meeting--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>--in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX>, with the inclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> "at a
level of participation still to be determined." Asked why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> caved in to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military pressure while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mubarak</ENAMEX> replied, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the
other in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> published an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warmly</ENAMEX> praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> as a brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who will push the peace process forward
and finish the work her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> did until his murder in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>
will create a completely different climate from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that of the past three years</TIMEX>,
during which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> "continually went back on his word with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and
nurtured the culture of distrust," she said.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestiya</ENAMEX> published a rare interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> in which he said he will retire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> when his current term of
office ends and hand over power to a successor elected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. While
this disclosure failed to excite those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> who think that the main issue
is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> will live to see out his term, it was described in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> Times
as "noteworthy" in view of the speculation that has been going on in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that he will never voluntarily give up power. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestiya</ENAMEX> that he has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> in mind but will not
identify him because "as soon as I name him, he won't be let live calmly, he
will be henpecked." But he warned against this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> being regarded as "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> to the throne," since the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> will be chosen not by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, but by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> also confirmed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX> will eventually be removed from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Square</ENAMEX> and buried in an ordinary grave (a story taken up
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on the front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX> ). "The question is when," he said. "The
problem is a serious one. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX> is an historical symbol of our
past, but I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexiy II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, when he says that it
isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>-like behavior to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of a long-dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on public
display."

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the jailing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>
of a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> who sparked the biggest anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> demonstration since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war by breaking into a broadcast of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> championship match
to urge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to take to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. The demonstration by around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leskovac</ENAMEX> was one of several across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tabloid Daily Express</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that attempts to secure asylum
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> have all come to
nothing.

            Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also reported a speech in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in which
former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> has left her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
"reputation for loyalty and fair dealing in tatters." She said that his arrest
while under sedation in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> was "inhumane" and "unlawful," and
that while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chileans</ENAMEX> have so far responded to it "with great restraint," it
should not be assumed that they will continue to do so, "particularly if Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>, who is not in the best of health, were to die in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>." In an
editorial, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> agreed with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was doing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> unnecessary harm
"merely to enable the vengeful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> in pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> to settle their
scores."

         
      
   
