
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lame Movie</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Runaway Bride</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Marshall</ENAMEX>
scored the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time he paired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> , but he flounders on this outing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> complain about
the trite story line--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> plays a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who has a habit of leaving
her grooms waiting at the altar--and the lack of chemistry between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> notes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Runaway Bride</ENAMEX> marks
the "flatlining" of the traditional romantic comedy and the birth of a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre</ENAMEX>: the unsympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> comedy (see also: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Best Friend's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wedding</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Weddings</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funeral</ENAMEX> ). A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> come to its
defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) serves up a remarkably bland,
neither-here-nor-there review: "[Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gere</ENAMEX>'s] and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX>'s reunion with
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> guarantees a comedy that's easy on the eyes and dependable in the
laugh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX> also pronounces the film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">passable</ENAMEX>: "Although the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dawdles</ENAMEX> and repeats itself, it is often
charming." Denby even goes against the conventional wisdom, contending that
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gere-Roberts</ENAMEX> connection is still alive." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to check out a site devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> and here for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> devoted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gere</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twin Falls Idaho</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). This <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX>-ian
film about a love triangle involving a pair of conjoined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>
provokes a fittingly dual response from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ratcheting</ENAMEX> up the weirdness
is the fact it was written and directed by a pair of non-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">conjoined</NUMEX> identical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twins</ENAMEX>.) Some find it "spellbinding," with "a solemn eroticism [that] sometimes
recalls <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Elephant Man</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). Others say the "slapped-on eeriness peels away to reveal little
more than simplistic dramatic ploys" and that it is "neither weighty nor as
weird as it would like to think" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Lim</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). The
balance tips slightly in the film's favor: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' Maslin
writes that the film "has style, gravity and originality to spare ... dwells as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hauntingly</ENAMEX> in loneliness as it does on never actually being able to be alone."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to visit the film's official site.)

            

               Magazine
            

            

               
                  Talk
               . Just about every possible media outlet covers
the premiere of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> devotes more than
a page, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than one</NUMEX>, each featuring a photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and
the cover of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue. The early response is surprisingly kind:
Conventional wisdom has held that everyone was waiting to knock <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> off her
cloud, but there are notably few scathing condemnations or laudatory pieces
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Instead, reports focus on the phenomenon
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s buzz machine and the celeb-studded party she threw <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>,
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> described as "so much fun, I loved it" in the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . As for the prospects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, most agree that "if anyone
could dust off the genre [of a general interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>], it's probably <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brown</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Koepp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to check out
Talk 's official Web site. Click to read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>"
on early Talk hype.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Certain Age</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tama Janowitz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubleday</ENAMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brittle</ENAMEX>, shallow, single, gold-digging, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirtysomething</TIMEX> protagonist of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janowitz</ENAMEX>'s latest hate letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> is pronounced so unpleasant as to
make the entire novel (which follows her search for a suitably rich and
connected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>) quite a drag: "A hateful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> and a catalog of
conspicuous consuming do not an amusing read make" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Gleick</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the least likable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in modern fiction history.
More self-obsessed than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Portnoy</ENAMEX>, more marriage crazed than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Jones</ENAMEX>, this
skinny blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twit</ENAMEX> is truly horrid" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.J. Jacobs, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ).
The closest thing the novel gets to a positive review is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-line mention in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> roundup of new books on single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klinghoffer</ENAMEX> writes that the novel is "darkly funny." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
to read an excerpt from the book and here to listen to an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Run Catch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Sohn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX> Press sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Sohn</ENAMEX> turns in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel about ... a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-based sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> and her wild shenanigans with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are
more amused than impressed: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reads ... with equal parts astonished
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">admiration</ENAMEX> and mounting horror at the calculated brazenness of it all" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Rozzo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clarissa Cruz</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> )
finds that parts of the dialogue are "laugh out loud funny," but overall it's
"a frivolous read that's far more titillating than scintillating." More biting
reviews say it's yet another in the recent rash of single-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>-in-the-city
novels, just a "wobbly attempt to follow in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Jones</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manolo Blahniks</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahlin Chan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Get Skintight
               , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donnas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lookout</ENAMEX>!). This
foursome of female juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> gets solid reviews for its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
album. "These bad-ass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> roll out rude, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ace Frehley</ENAMEX>-inspired guitar hooks
at a feverish rate, capturing the rebellious, mischievous and instantly
gratifying rock 'n' roll spirit of teenage trash culture" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen Sansone</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMJ</ENAMEX> ). As all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> are under legal drinking age, the
lyrics touch on subjects such as driving around on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawn</ENAMEX>, hanging
out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slurpee</ENAMEX> machine, and looking at cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. On the downside, the band
relies heavily on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, and some songs sound lifted directly from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramones</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Runaways</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mötley Crüe</ENAMEX> (they also cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crüe</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too</ENAMEX>
Fast <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">For Love"</ENAMEX>). But most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> don't sweat the album's derivative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tendencies</ENAMEX>, pointing out that this kind of music isn't supposed to be blazingly
original, it's supposed to be fun. "A timeless burst of renegade teen spirit"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Dougherty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> on its official site, and
here to check
out the "I have a crush on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Donnas</ENAMEX>" Web site.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Music
            

            
               
                  Out of
Business
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPMD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Def  Jam</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duo</ENAMEX>'s latest offering as "their best album since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>'s Business As
Usual " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Hart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMJ</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erick Sermon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish Smith</ENAMEX>'s music is up
to their usual high standards, but even more impressive are their lyrics, which
"weave together tapestries of obscure pop-culture references and rap history
homages that could keep lesser rhymers in business forever" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Diehl</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ).

         
      
   
