
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> Bloat

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A day</TIMEX> doesn't go by that I don't read in the press
... or some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> sidles up to me ... or even my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> says,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey, Shuman</ENAMEX>, why is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> software so bloated, so full of junk, sucking up
megs of space on my hard drive, hogging memory, and taking forever to load! The
toolbar buttons look like they were lifted from the cockpit of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16</ENAMEX>." My
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grouchy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are ramping up again as the very large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> software
suite hits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuman</ENAMEX>, why don't you and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy developers</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> write some trim and tight code<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gentlemen</ENAMEX>, I'm going to let you in on a little secret. The problem with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">software</ENAMEX> today is not that it is bloated. The problem is that it's not
bloated enough!
            

            What is bloat? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloat</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dream: bigger, better,
and everywhere all at once. Supersize it! From VCRs to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
Expeditions, industry has historically provided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> with features to
have , not necessarily to use. How many of you have programmed your VCR?
Minced carrots with your Cuisinart? Or gone off-roading in your SUV?

            Why should software be
any different? Do you really think software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> add features just for
fun, like some cackling tormentor? If only that were the case. Sadly, it is
you, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>, who demands bloat, forever clamoring for new features.
Software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> take your wish lists seriously, and then make them happen.
It's like the violence-in-the-media argument: We hate it, but we buy it.

            Now, I don't deny that software is getting, um, alarmingly
large. A complete installation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> requires <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 megabytes</NUMEX> of
hard-disk space. This compares to the puny installation requirement of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> megs
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> megs of hard-disk space for a similar array of DOS applications, circa
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lotus 123</ENAMEX>, dBase, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crosstalk</ENAMEX>, etc.

            But thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX> and its corollaries,
computer power continues to double <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 18 months</TIMEX> and prices keep falling.
Most computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> want to do fancy new things with their speedy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentium</ENAMEX> chips and mongolarge hard drives, not just run their old applications
faster. So if computers are getting more powerful, shouldn't we developers
harness that capacity?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-bloat</ENAMEX> whiners
would have you believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is coercing them into using our
extralarded software products! I call their bluff. The elegance of the Windows
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> operating system is that it runs practically every application from the DOS
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and all those goofy Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.1</NUMEX> programs. If you want to run unbloated
legacy programs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WordStar for Windows or Bitcom</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DOS</ENAMEX> instead of new
applications, be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>. (Also, you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> of legacy applications should know
that one of the reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows 95 and Windows</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> are so "bloated" is so that
they can run the old applications.)

            It is precisely because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> can ignore the new releases
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corel</ENAMEX> that the software industry works overtime to
add new features to software, features that will convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>
on an upgrade to do the same computing as they're doing now, only with more
bells and whistles and excitement. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> fails to convince you
to upgrade--i.e., to buy a product that the malcontents call bloated--is the
day that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redmond</ENAMEX> becomes a ghost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.

            Most bloatware complaints
come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> who own <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2- to 3-year-old</TIMEX> machines. They don't understand that
the new (bloated) versions of software are meant for the new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX>-megahertz
machines and the wickedly fast machines to come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 18</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>--including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-gigahertz computers--not their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pentium 133</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">doorstops</ENAMEX>. Or
the complainers single out features that they never use, such as AutoSummarize
in Word or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> feature in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Outlook</ENAMEX> (that can slow even the fastest
computer to a crawl). My advice to these complainers: Turn these features off
or ignore them.

            Having praised bloat, let me confide that when I worked on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Outlook</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, bloat was my biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. A mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biff</ENAMEX>
routinely yelled hurtful things at me when I wrote indulgent, fat code, because
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> wanted programs to load and work quickly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook SWAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> swooped
down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> to reduce the size of our code. I remember endless hallway
discussions about how to balance the demand for lean and quick code against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bloat</ENAMEX> required to add new and nifty features. (We were ultimately successful:
If you compare Outlook <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> version, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Outlook 97</ENAMEX>, you'll see a vast
improvement in performance and stability. You'll also see a lot more cool
features, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTML</ENAMEX> mail and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preview Pane</ENAMEX>, to name but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.)

            The struggle between
concise code and bloated code plays out under the threat of a deadline. If our
software is occasionally too fat, we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> fall back on the same excuse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philosopher Blaise Pascal</ENAMEX> offered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three centuries ago</TIMEX> for his verbose letters:
"I have only made this [letter] longer because I have not had the time to make
it shorter."

            If you're truly anti-bloat, there's a whole subgenre of
dainty, low-bloat computers out there for you: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">PalmPilot and Windows</ENAMEX> CE
handheld devices. They pack a lot a power into little boxes, but let's not kid
anybody: Sometimes you can make do with a bicycle, but other times you need a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. A fast <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. A fast <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with a big noisy engine and a bone-crushing CD
sound <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloatmobile</ENAMEX>.

            I began this column with the provocative thesis that
software isn't anywhere near bloated enough. By that I meant that if we
software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> were really doing our jobs instead of resting and vesting
our stock options, word processors would have already bloated into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99.999</NUMEX>
percent reliable voice-recognition software. Your computer would have fused the
functions of your telephone, television, and fax machine into one seamless
whole. Your computer would have become the instantly searchable repository of
all your correspondence, financial transactions, data searches, and phone
conversations. Plus, it would be making smart connections between your data and
actions. For instance, it will tell me, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey, Shuman</ENAMEX>, you can get a better auto
insurance policy from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GEICO</ENAMEX>." Or, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey, Shuman</ENAMEX>, lay off the fatty, fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>,
why doncha? You want to get bloated or something?"

         
      
   
