
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dangerous Sport</ENAMEX>

            Nearly
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led their front pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> holiday tragedy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>--the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Switzerland</ENAMEX> while engaging in the adventure sport of "canyoning." Canyoning, a
combination of rappelling and riding rapids without <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, sometimes described
as whitewater rafting without the raft, has been banned in several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, mostly from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, were drowned
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saxet River</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Interlaken</ENAMEX> when a thunderstorm caused a flash flood in
a ravine. The papers described canyoning as an "underground" sport with no
official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to check equipment, offer advice, or govern safety. To
attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> promoting it promise maximum thrills with minimum
danger. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> adorns its Web site with the slogan "Canyoning: no
risk, much fun."

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gnjilane</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eastern Kosovo</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Navy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">welders</ENAMEX> have repaired a statue of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> that was damaged by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian Kosovars</ENAMEX>. The statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
Lazar, who led the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to a legendary defeat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1389</TIMEX>,
was lassoed and pulled to the ground by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, assisted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, took the metal
statue to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base camp</ENAMEX> and welded it together again. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> said
the work was intended to show <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> that the cultural monuments
of both must be protected. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> need to understand that you can't destroy
their culture and think that they will respect yours," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaminski</ENAMEX>. But he admitted that this is a lesson that neither side is eager to
learn. "This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild West</ENAMEX>," he explained.

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> also reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pancevo</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing campaign caused an
environmental catastrophe. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> concluded that severe air pollution existed
before the air attacks, which had merely worsened it in some places. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX>
reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> that, according to estimates prepared for the European
Commission, the reconstruction of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> damaged or destroyed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX> of conflict would cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 1.1 billion</NUMEX> euros
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.17 billion</NUMEX>). A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> report said that of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">204,585</NUMEX> housing units
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119,500</NUMEX> were damaged, of which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78,000</NUMEX> were either
severely damaged or completely destroyed.

In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said the warning by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> will face "serious consequences" if it conducts another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">long-range</ENAMEX> ballistic missile test "carries the ring of desperation." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said, "It marks the latest low point in a largely unsuccessful
process, begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, to persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pyongyang</ENAMEX> leadership to stop building
(and selling) weapons of mass destruction and their delivery systems."

In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, Le
Figaro of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> reported explosive growth in the sale of mobile phones,
which it described as a phenomenon without parallel in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> commercial
history. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> million mobile phones have been sold since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, bringing the total in use to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14 million</NUMEX>. This number is expected to
rise to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 million</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2002</TIMEX>, to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 million</NUMEX>,
which is more than half the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only two years ago</TIMEX>,
there were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than 1 million</NUMEX> mobile phones in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> led on the European
single currency, the euro, bouncing back against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar, with a gain
of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX> after a fall of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX> since the beginning
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the euro is now established as "one
of the world's great currencies" whose ups and downs against the dollar are a
minor issue. There is, however, a danger that in a future trade war the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> might force the euro up too high by playing the "weak dollar"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX>.

In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> quoted defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as saying that peace
negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> are likely to proceed more quickly than those with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> because the issues are less complex and already fully understood
by both sides. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> also believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez Assad</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>
"wants to bequeath his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> a legacy of peace, in order
to facilitate the continued rule of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alawite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

An editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ma'ariv</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> for
making "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and superfluous statements" about wanting to change parts of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement, such as the timetable for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> withdrawals from the West
Bank, without first talking privately to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>. "A
few more meetings like that held last night [between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>]
will be necessary before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> can be sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> toward whom it
is worthwhile taking another step," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX> put a positive spin on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s talks between
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, saying that closer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> ties are
"in the best interests of both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>." But when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Undersecretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Aaron</ENAMEX> offered condolences over the bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Trade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shi Guangsheng</ENAMEX> replied that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> still awaited a satisfactory explanation.

         
      
   
