
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tabloids Show Restraint</ENAMEX>!

            From the moment it became clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> and his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> had been lost at sea, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX>--who was
passingly acquainted with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>--began to brace herself for the inevitable
tabloid onslaught. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> after the crash, though, the tabs
seemed so stunned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s death that they exercised--dare we say it?--a
modicum of restraint. Sure, they couldn't resist a few salacious details here
and there ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX> was haunted by dire premonition!" screamed the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> ), but they all weighed in with elaborately reverent photo tributes
that were virtually indistinguishable from those in the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , which called its special memorial issue "a loving tribute,"
even offered to forward its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' condolences to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, a
gesture that seemed touching in its inappropriateness.

            But the honeymoon was short-lived. The
tabs--especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> --soon woke from their stupor and attacked the
story with their usual zeal, claiming to have the inside track on everything
from the "secrets the tragic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> took to the grave" to the precise condition
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. A look at some of the sorrier moments in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
coverage:

            
               Most tenuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> tie-in: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's story about the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Gould</ENAMEX>, best known as
nosy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladys Kravitz on Bewitched</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> manages
to find it "ironic" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, given that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis</ENAMEX> once bumped into her at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomingdale's</ENAMEX> and confided
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caroline</ENAMEX> were "huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>."

            
               Most tasteless
headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kennedy Clan: Who's Left?</ENAMEX>" above a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> photo spread
identifying each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> cousins.

            
               Trend we'd like to see nipped in the bud right
now: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Star 's anointing of Caroline Schlossberg</ENAMEX>'s 6-year-old son
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> apparent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> mantle, noting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s "charming
personality and ease with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>" as well as his "uncanny resemblance" to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>.

            
               Story so pathetic it almost made us laugh:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's insistence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> could have "averted tragedy" had he
heeded his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16</TIMEX> horoscope, which warned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sagittarians</ENAMEX> to "remain close to
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>." "His headstrong Sagittarian nature refused to bow to the laws of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universe</ENAMEX>," laments astrologer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne Palmer</ENAMEX>.

            
               Photo so pathetic it
almost made us laugh: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's shot of convenience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> employee
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mesfin Gebreegziabher</ENAMEX> holding items similar to the ones <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> purchased on
his way to the airport <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> he died: a bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX>,
and a package of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duracell</ENAMEX> batteries.

            
               Most unnecessary story: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's
list of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream Couple</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> favorite things," including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Bessette</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite masseuse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bree Neumann</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal</ENAMEX> (oatmeal).

            
               Most unnecessary photo: A tie between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's full-page shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> receiving what is said to be his last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">communion</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's grainy frame-grab purportedly showing the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> show's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katie Couric</ENAMEX> "breaking down" while reporting from Hyannis
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Port</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            
               Most groan-inducing
euphemism for death: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s lifelong love
affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> ends by suggesting that "on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16</TIMEX>, like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> took
his big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> to heaven."

            With the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> story so dominating the tabs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>,
what little other news there is seems incidental. (You know something's
going on when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> devotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pages to a behind-the-scenes look at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiques Roadshow</ENAMEX> .) Perhaps that's why they devote so much ink to
happenings in the world of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. For starters, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>
reports that for his recent wedding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Collins</ENAMEX> booked his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> into a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350-</NUMEX>a<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-night</TIMEX> luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>. (The bad news in this case would apparently be for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>' new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>, who had to make do with a standard <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$280</NUMEX> room.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Michelle Gellar</ENAMEX>--whose thoughts on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s passing are dutifully recorded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hollywood Weeps</ENAMEX>"
story--threw a lavish, catered birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thor</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> of his
nearest and dearest. And canine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> everywhere will no doubt sleep easier
knowing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bea Arthur</ENAMEX> is on their side: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports that
she has begun a crusade on behalf of the "innocent greyhounds" abused in dog
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">racing</ENAMEX>.

            It's not all fun and games for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity canines</ENAMEX>,
however. As if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> family didn't have enough to deal with, the
Star reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>, who is married to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cousin Maria Shriver</ENAMEX>, accidentally killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s chocolate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Labrador</ENAMEX> when
he ran over it with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humvee</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nicholson</ENAMEX> accidentally hit his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shih Tzu</ENAMEX> with a golf club; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pup</ENAMEX> reportedly recovered after receiving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> stitches to the abdomen. (In other
golfing mishaps, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery "</ENAMEX>screamed in
pain" after being "hit in the butt by a stray golf ball that raised an angry
red welt.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauly Shore</ENAMEX> is terrified that
his missing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> has been eaten by coyotes, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> forces his
"overweight mutt" to work out on a treadmill for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> a day. The
Star , meanwhile, says that a jealous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> is hoping to buy a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">girlfriend Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pooch</ENAMEX> she "adores" was a gift from her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ex-fiance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tate Donovan</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aniston</ENAMEX>, by the way, might want to compare
notes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connery</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> says that she too fell victim to a
freak rear end accident <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> when an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">overzealous deer</ENAMEX> "nipped her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hindquarters</ENAMEX>.")

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> has been
obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aniston</ENAMEX> of late but can't seem to make up its mind about
just what's happening in their bed. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Charlton</ENAMEX> claimed
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> has "spiced up" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s "already sizzling sex life" by bringing
home the "tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>" props he wears in the film he's now shooting. But just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton</ENAMEX> shared the distressing news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s love life
is being ruined by his penchant for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">antiques</ENAMEX> hunting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>: He's
apparently "so caught up" in his Net surfing that he "forgets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>'s
keeping his bed warm."

            And while we're on the subject of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>' short
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX>: Why can't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX> remember what it says about country
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superstar Shania Twain</ENAMEX>? The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 27</TIMEX> issue boasted that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photographers</ENAMEX> had snagged the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> photo ever taken of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twain</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mutt Lange</ENAMEX>, whom the story claimed is so camera-shy that he wouldn't even pose
for his own wedding photos. So imagine our happy surprise when we saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twain</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">secret wedding album</ENAMEX>" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX> issue, including no fewer
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> shots of the dashing groom himself.

            And finally, while the public's grief over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diff'rent Strokes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dana Plato</ENAMEX>'s death might not have been on a par
with that afforded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX>, has plans to erect a memorial to his late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> at an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> sandwich <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. It will be, a source explains, a "small-scale version
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Althorp</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>." Keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tabs</ENAMEX> hopes they all rest in
peace.

         
      
   
