
   
   
      
         
            Summer of Spam

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX> is a virtuoso
filmmaker, a wizard at selling a sequence, but he'll never make an entirely
coherent movie until he learns to go deeper into his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> instead of wider
with them. In <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> , the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee Joint</ENAMEX>, he substitutes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">panorama</ENAMEX> for point of view, piling on perspectives until the picture becomes a
shambles--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee Disjoint</ENAMEX>.

            The film, with its mostly white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>,
was drafted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Colicchio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Imperioli</ENAMEX> (the thickheaded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> ) and then revised--and embellished and
tarted-up--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>. Summer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> is consequently several movies in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
The thing that links them all is a time and place--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>. A hot one. And we know from this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do the Right Thing</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>) that during hot ones the essential self comes out--the essential self
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> being hate-filled and destructive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Racist</ENAMEX>, too, but race is confined to
the margins of this story. Here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> dress in polyester, line up to
get into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discos</ENAMEX>, snort <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, cheat on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>, and have sex with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">imperfect strangers</ENAMEX>. It's the most jittery of periods, both exhibitionistic and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paranoid</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Berkowitz</ENAMEX>--the self-proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sam</ENAMEX>--emerges from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ocean</ENAMEX> of decadence like a toxic monster, a puritanical avenger.

            What are the sundry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strands</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> ? The whole mess is introduced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Breslin</ENAMEX>,
one-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkowitz</ENAMEX>'s most hammily psychotic missives, who says,
"There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 million</NUMEX> stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naked City</ENAMEX>, and this is one." Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> want
us to giggle at this cliché-spouting hack or to feel nostalgic for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> were so unself-consciously purple? Probably both. For his part,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> is self-consciously purple. In a garish, green- and crimson-lit hovel,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkowitz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Badalucco</ENAMEX>) screams and writhes on his mattress while a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> barks at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eardrum</NUMEX>-buckling volume. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> later issues orders in
the voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Turturro</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> having evidently run out of human weirdos
to impersonate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s subsequent killings are loud and splattery,
photographed in the style of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> --which was filmed, maybe not so
coincidentally, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>.

            The opening makes you think that Summer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> will
be a police procedural, a step-by-step hunt for a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>. It is, but
only in tiny, widely spaced patches. As it turns out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> himself is a
kind of red <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX>. The real drama unfolds in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>, a setting for several
of the murders, where the combination of heat, terror of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.44</NUMEX>-caliber
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">killer</ENAMEX>, and a piggishly macho culture create a breeding ground for lynch-mob
hysteria. It doesn't do much for marriages, either. The film's dim protagonist
is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stud hairdresser</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vinnie</ENAMEX> (the distractingly Latino-looking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leguizamo</ENAMEX>), who skips out on his pretty, ingenuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionna</ENAMEX> (Mira
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorvino</ENAMEX>), at a disco to have sordid sex in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>. Driving home
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the evening</TIMEX>, he passes the spot where he parked for his quickie
and sees that it's surrounded by police <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cruisers</ENAMEX> and yellow crime-scene tape. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> lie dead, their brains all over the dashboard. Spooked and stricken
(that could have been him!), he staggers over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and touches the latest
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.44</NUMEX>-caliber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. (I kept waiting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to show up later at his
door and announce that his fingerprints were on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, but that touch must
have been metaphorical.) Dear God, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vinnie</ENAMEX>, I'll never cheat on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
again. The problem is, he likes his sex rough and dirty, and good Italian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> can't have rough, dirty sex with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> , for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chrissake</ENAMEX>.

            The core of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colicchio</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperioli</ENAMEX>'s original screenplay was likely <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vinnie's Judas</ENAMEX> turn with Ritchie
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrien Brody</ENAMEX>), his neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> who returns after an absence with spiked
hair and the news that he's playing with a punk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBGB</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritchie</ENAMEX>--who
also dances at an all-male strip joint and turns tricks with middle-aged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--is meant to be the quintessential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>, the inevitable receptacle of
whatever ill will is in the air. As it happens, he's also the mildest, least
threatening punk you'll ever see--and hetero, for all his gay experiences,
taking up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Esposito</ENAMEX>), the 'hood's good-hearted slut. When a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> ask a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> chieftain (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Gazzara</ENAMEX>) for help in
their search for the serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>, the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully boys</ENAMEX> show a little too much
fascist zeal, keeping tabs on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s movements and pulling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. They're looking funny at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritchie</ENAMEX>, too. That hair: He's clearly in a
satanic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>, he's clearly in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">satanic cult</ENAMEX>, too. So <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> plus
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> equals ... duhhhh.

            In his last film, the lyric basketball saga He Got
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Game</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> composed his frames so that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> had a weathered
grandeur; they were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">icons</ENAMEX>. This time, he keeps a queasy
distance from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on screen. He seems to loathe them all--and why
shouldn't he? They're morons--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guidos</ENAMEX>. They think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Mays</ENAMEX> just got lucky.
They're the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would have chased <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> out of their neighborhoods
with baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bats</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> in which a crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> goes around shooting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Italians: To Lee</ENAMEX> this must feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shangri-La.</ENAMEX> He goes out of his way to show
that white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> deal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, too. He doubtless had to fight the urge to make
Summer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> a whole-hog whitesploitation picture. Apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sorvino</ENAMEX>,
who gives a tremulous and surprisingly soulful performance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have
zero stature, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leguizamo</ENAMEX> has been stuck with one of the most thankless roles
ever written: an oversexed yet essentially impotent loser--a guilty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bystander</ENAMEX>.

            The problem with these
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> sequences is not conceptual. It's that they're crudely staged and written
and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who conclude that the skinny, harmless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ritchie</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sam</ENAMEX>
seem like a gathering of village <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX>. Even the neighborhood's queeny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transvestite</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Tarantina</ENAMEX>)--until that point a target of harassment--joins
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lynch mob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy</ENAMEX> to go after someone who's even more of an Other. The best
reason to tell a story such as this would be to demonstrate that in the right
circumstances, we could be infected by the same delusions and hunt for the same
kinds of scapegoats. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>--whose treatment of violence in his other movies
is considerably more equivocal--maintains a rare, moralistic distance. He adds
a further layer of irony by taking his cameras to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX>-Stuyvesant
neighborhood, where a zombielike TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsman</ENAMEX> (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>) interviews
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> for a feature called "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dark Perspective</ENAMEX>."
Says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who serves as the picture's lone voice of reason: "I thank God it
is a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who kills all of those white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. If it were a black man
there would be a race riot." So much for empathy with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> has been attempting to craft a new
kind of artfully slapdash film syntax--one that mixes jivey jump-cuts with
Brechtian exhortations, that tries to build immense dramatic structures out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dissonance</ENAMEX> and opposition. His work in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> is often formally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thrilling</ENAMEX>. The bleached, posterized cinematography (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Kuras</ENAMEX>) makes the
images seem cooked, even irradiated, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> brings out the eerie portents in
the throbbing blandness of disco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abba</ENAMEX>. The pity is that when he
does something well, he can't seem to control it and do it more selectively.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terence Blanchard</ENAMEX>'s music strikes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same</TIMEX> note of mournful counterpoint again
and again, and the picture teems with conscious and unconscious echoes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mean Streets</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi Driver</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>); it could have been
called Summer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> . A sequence of punk thrashing and shooting-up
set to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Who's</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baba O'Riley</ENAMEX>" brings the narrative to an embarrassing halt:
It's just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike</ENAMEX> flexing his cinematic muscles, showing how much montage he can
bench press. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overambition</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> is easy to forgive; what's less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sufferable</ENAMEX> is grandiosity--the compulsive urge to dazzle us with omniscience.
He doesn't seem to get that understanding is a byproduct of focus and not of
how many connections you can make.

         
      
   
