
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mental Shutdown</ENAMEX>

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> didn't exist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> would have to invent him. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority whip</ENAMEX> had told
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s anticipated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14 billion</NUMEX> budget
surplus--and had intended to do so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year long</TIMEX>"--to "force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
to pay for any additional spending requests out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
surplus." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> pounced on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s remarks. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> has
revealed that actually they have a secret strategy ... to raid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security surplus to pay for ... a risky economic scheme. They say they're
spending more money now to force that result," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> declared. "I can think
of nothing more cynical and irresponsible."

            
Welcome to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Shutdown III</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
refused to compromise on appropriations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> ground to a halt, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, facing another impasse, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> caved
and accepted additional spending demanded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> has
decided to engineer the showdown so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will have the upper hand and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will take the blame. The plan is magnificently self-defeating. The
party that will lose the showdown is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that is perceived to have
engineered it. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> has just handed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> all the evidence he needs.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
Strategy. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> referred twice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
"strategy" and said it had been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX>: "From the get-go, the
strategy has always been we're going to spend what's left." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> immediately
dubbed this a "secret strategy"--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podesta</ENAMEX>
repeated that phrase twice on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> --and the press climbed all
over it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> front page explored the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
"strategy" to "deliberately spend" the surplus. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> affirmed
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> had been plotting "all along." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
Voinovich, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, chided <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> for "setting up" a crash with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>.
DeLay failed to grasp that when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> collide, the public will blame the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that doesn't look surprised. If you're going to have a secret strategy,
keep it secret.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
Provocation. Having broadcast his "strategy," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> signaled his intention
to start the war. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> Picks a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Budget Fight</ENAMEX>," announced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , citing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' "deliberate provocations" and "confrontation strategy."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett News Service</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> was "daring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>." Rather than
squelch this story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> went on television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and when asked whether he
was negotiating with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> answered, "There's nobody to negotiate. He doesn't
negotiate. He goes out [and] does photo ops." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowland Evans</ENAMEX> concluded
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> "certainly is not in a negotiating mood" and "has presented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with a fait accompli --take it or leave it." When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> leaves it, guess which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> the public will blame?

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> paraphrased <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> as saying that his "plan" would
"force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to pay for any additional spending requests out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> surplus." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> after the story appeared, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> held a press conference to brag about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s freshly
passed tax cut. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> pressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> about "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s strategy" to
"force a showdown." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> "planned
... to force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to pay for his spending programs from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
surplus." If the plan works, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will dip into the trust fund. And then,
with a mountain of press clips to back him up, he will repeat what he said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> deliberately "forced that result."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
Spite. "We will negotiate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, after he vetoes the bills, on
his knees," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . "We've got him in the box." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smelling blood</ENAMEX>, hyped these quotes on every talk show. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
somehow banking on the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ... will have to, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> said, get
on his knees and beg," observed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> . "DeLay
has made no secret he would relish such a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX> ... with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> 'on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">knees</ENAMEX>,' " added the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>. Everyone agrees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> is determined to beat and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">humiliate Clinton</ENAMEX> at any cost. And guess who will get the blame for a shutdown?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who seems determined to beat and humiliate his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> at any
cost.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
Blame. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> "indicated that if the spending
caps were lifted, that was acceptable 'as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
understand it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> busting the caps, not us.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> Blitzer
repeated this quote and discussed the charge "that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> wants the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to go into that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> trust fund, in order to accuse him of
breaking it." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> concluded that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> ... are betting
that the public will blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, for squandering the
money he has insisted be saved to shore up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Committee</ENAMEX> even conducted a poll on the subject."
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> end up looking as though they care more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> contest than
about the fiscal consequences--which is the surest way to lose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
contest.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s opening salvo conveyed the words <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will use to package
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s plan: "cynical and irresponsible." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That day</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> budget "doesn't meet the responsibility test.
... It's a cynical plan.'' On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lew</ENAMEX> assailed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s "cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">charade</ENAMEX>." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , Podesta
attacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "strategy to go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> surplus in the
vain hope that the public will blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. It's cynical and it's
wrong." Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Podesta</ENAMEX> projected pacifism and public-spirited
diligence. ''I am not nearly as pessimistic as a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are about the
prospects of our reaching an agreement, and I am determined to try to do it,''
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. When asked whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would shut down
again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Podesta</ENAMEX> replied sadly, "I hope not. That's certainly not in the public's
interest."

            On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> side, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> have been left to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s mess. "I'm not seeking a showdown," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> insisted on This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> bombarded him with questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s plot. "We're not
looking for a battle. We're looking for solutions." On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> assured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>. "We will continue to work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." "On his
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">knees?</ENAMEX>" asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX>. "No, of course not," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX> pleaded. In the event of another
budget impasse, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> explained, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would "keep funding programs at the
current <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s level" to "avoid a train wreck" while they negotiate. That's
"the solution," he suggested.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>,
of course, put it differently. "There's a little trick that you can use called
[a] continuing resolution that continues spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least year</TIMEX>'s level. And we
can keep that up all through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> if we have to," he bragged on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>. "If
he vetoes that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will have shut down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." Rather than
call this plan a "solution," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> did, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> had
conceived it as " 'a little trick' that would put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at risk of being
blamed for a shutdown."

            You
can understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> keeps boasting of his "tricks" and "strategies." He's
determined not to lose the shutdown the way he did last time--and thanks to his
new plan, he won't. Above all, he's determined to prove his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> wrong. They
said he had no plan. They said he was stupid. Well, he showed them.

         
      
   
