
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget Fudging</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> opened his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourlong</TIMEX> news conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with a defense
of his budget proposals and a critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> tax-cut plans. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspapers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">duly</ENAMEX> reported his quarrels with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> over revenue projections and the cost
of new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> benefits. Which side will prevail on these matters remains to
be seen. But the underlying struggle to shape the terms of the debate remains
invisible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is winning that struggle hands down.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
Whose money is it? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> used to argue constantly that federal
money belonged to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>, not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>." Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> took up this theme. But now both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are gone, and nobody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
seems capable of battling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s counterspin. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> chooses words that
oblige the media and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to look at every financial question from the
standpoint of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> tax cut
plan will "cost" too much and cause "an enormous loss to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> argued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. This obscures the alternative point of view--that
taxes themselves impose "costs" and "losses" on everyone who has to pay the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX>.

            
Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> shrewdly portrays tax cuts as a kind of "spending." At his
news conference, he questioned how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> could "finance" their tax cuts.
Words such as these dissolve the moral difference between giving money "back"
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it came from, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> used to put it, and passing
it on to others instead. Once the question is framed as how to "finance" tax
cuts--implying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> owns the money and gets to decide who should
receive it--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> can't win.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
Who can spend it more wisely? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> used to frame this question as
a choice between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> "spending" and private "investment." "Investment"
meant the money was working and growing. "Spending" meant it was being wasted.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has turned this language on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. "We must decide whether to invest
the surplus, to strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> over the long-term, or to squander it for
the short-term," he argued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. To "squander" the money, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
language, is to "spend" it on tax cuts. To "invest" it is to allocate it to
"long-term goals," which used to be called government programs.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> constantly borrows capitalist terminology to make federal budget
decisions appear as productive as corporate budget decisions. At his news
conference, he made clear that allocating money to poverty-stricken parts of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> isn't subsidizing the poor; it's "investing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s new
markets." Adding prescription drug coverage to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> isn't additional
spending; it's "modernizing" the program to meet future needs.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
Who deserves it most? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> used to dominate the moral dimension of budget
debates by posing a choice between hard-working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> and irresponsible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of government programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s greatest feat has been to
reverse this hierarchy. The question, as he put it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, is no longer
whether to spend more money on programs but whether "to meet our basic
responsibilities in education, defense, the environment," and other
commitments.

            What
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s responsibility to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> explained that in
contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s "risky" tax-relief plan, he favors only "tax cuts we can
afford," since we must maintain "fiscal discipline." "We" refers, of course, to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. "Afford" makes clear that it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s money and that
tax cuts are a secondary and purely elective consideration. Our
"responsibilities" come first, and to forsake "fiscal discipline" by cutting
taxes would be immoral as well as imprudent. This spin keeps the alternative
interpretation of fiscal discipline--cutting taxes <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, and then cutting
spending accordingly--conveniently out of the picture.

            Good
spin wins the issue of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, but great spin goes further. It wins the war
invisibly, by skewing the debate at such a deep level that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> can't see
it. And it so permeates public discourse that even the opposition helplessly or
unwittingly succumbs. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four months ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> launched his
presidential exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, he defended tax cuts by arguing that it was
"compassionate" of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> "to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more money." That's not a
challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. That's a tribute.

         
      
   
