
   
   
      
         
            Drug Bust

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> said he 
               hasn't used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> he vowed never to discuss his drug history. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> he admitted
that he had "made some mistakes" and "learned from those" but said he would
have passed a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year</TIMEX> background check in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. The media debated whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s drug history should be probed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX> called the inquiries "" in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>," but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stacks</ENAMEX> argued in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> that past dabblings with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> could make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s hard-line drug enforcement policy hypocritical.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s past after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of
investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serbs</ENAMEX> rallied against 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>. As
many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as 150,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> attended the rally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speakers</ENAMEX> from the
various opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> disagreed over when and how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> should be
removed. The unanimous spin: The democratic factions are still too divided to
unseat him.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Episcopal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> are uniting. They
will keep separate creeds and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> but will share <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX>, sacraments, and
missionary projects. The pious spin: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oneness</ENAMEX> becomes a proof of the authenticity of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gospel</ENAMEX> ," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . The
practical spin: The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> need to pool their dwindling resources and
memberships.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> will merge to create the world's
largest financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>. Bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> will
resuscitate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> banking industry and thus the entire economy. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> hails the move as "a long-overdue effort to deal with the
realities of an overcrowded market, massive bad loans and woefully low profit
margins."

            

               A federal study reported that teen 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> abuse fell in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. The optimistic spin: The war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is finally working. The
pessimistic fine print: drug abuse among young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and minority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> is
rising steadily. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">berates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> for
her ditzy stand on drug policy.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> will resign before the 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year's end</TIMEX>. The
judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> that appointed him split over whether his work should continue.
Since the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> statute has expired, no one knows whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
can legally be replaced. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> editorial urges him to stay on
but to finish the job fast.

            

               A former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> official 
               called the espionage
allegations against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> racist. The former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counterintelligence</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> targeted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> because he is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese-American</ENAMEX> and that there is not a "shred of evidence" against him
               . However,
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> that the charges
of racism are bunk and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> initial suspects in the case
were of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> background.

            

               An earthquake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 10,000</NUMEX> and possibly as many as
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurriyet</ENAMEX> in effect charged
construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> with , and international papers roundly condemned
their shoddy building standards.

            

               Bosnian <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Croat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> stole <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in public
funds and international aid. The money was intended to rebuild
infrastructure and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports that the
corruption will chill private investment and charitable contributions to the
region.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> was confirmed as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>.
Indifferent to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s latest pick and distracted by upcoming parliamentary
and presidential elections, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX> rubber-stamped the appointment. Instead,
attention focused on former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX>'s announcement of his
alliance with a new political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dagestan</ENAMEX> and bombed neighboring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. Newly confirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> vowed to crush
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> immediately, but Chechens girded for another drawn-out conflict.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> dropped their investigation of the crash that killed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>. They concluded it was caused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s loss of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> reported that former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX> has
volunteered to act as a liaison between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Al Fayed</ENAMEX> in
the dispute over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> intelligence about the crash .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> straw poll. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> placed
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>. "" reports on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unanimous</ENAMEX> spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> won solidly but not overwhelmingly enough to send other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> packing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> spent his way into <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is once again
a vice presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate-designate</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> rates the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the , and the in "Ballot Box</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> dropped his presidential bid. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press , he conceded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s nomination is assured by a
"powerful force." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> a worthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> but agreed
that "another moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> with a famous name and far more money ."
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> would be the next to go.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High School</ENAMEX> reopened. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> attended a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take Back</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>" rally, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> made a human <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of slain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> complained about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s "rah, rah, let's
forget about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that died " tone. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second day</TIMEX> of school,
swastikas were found scrawled on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.

            

               Planet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> filed for bankruptcy. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>'s failure on bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and worse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">PGA Championship</ENAMEX>. He beat 19-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergio Garc√</ENAMEX>≠a by one stroke. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> is
finally fulfilling the hype that surrounded his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
Masters victory, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garc√≠a</ENAMEX> stole the show . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators salivated</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> of a rivalry between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
