
   
   
      
         
             A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Philistine's Guide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>

            I just got back from honeymooning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. Before
I went there, I was a philistine. Now I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philistine</ENAMEX> who's been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. I
did learn a few things. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiefly</ENAMEX>, I learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guidebooks</ENAMEX> are designed
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are interested in broadening themselves. Here's a guide for the
rest of us.

            
               Art. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the big
attraction is villas, which charge you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few thousand lire</NUMEX> to admire their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gardens</ENAMEX> and sculptures. The gardens are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> patio and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>. Some
sculptures depict the Count of So-and-So, who used to own the villa. Others
memorialize his bad taste. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, most of the art is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">churches</ENAMEX> called duomi . The ceilings of the duomi are
spectacular. So are the floors. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> suggested that we model our bathroom
floor after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> are checkered with marble slabs
commemorating rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The more money you give to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, the bigger
your slab, and the better your location. Basically, it works like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religion</ENAMEX>. Most of the art in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> is religious. The big
theme is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuses</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baby Jesus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spurting Jesus</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floating Jesus</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Propeller-Head Jesus</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> sits in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s lap. He has
adult features and expressions wholly inappropriate to an infant. In some
paintings he looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Pesci</ENAMEX>; in others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Rickles</ENAMEX>; in others,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Walken</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Uffizi Gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baby Jesus</ENAMEX> that's a
dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ringer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Hornacek</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Utah Jazz</ENAMEX>. Occasionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baby Jesus</ENAMEX>
suckles at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary's</ENAMEX> breast. Evidently the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who painted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> had never seen
a naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Her breast starts around the collarbone and takes off like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">torpedo</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spurting Jesus</ENAMEX> hangs on the cross and spouts <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gash</ENAMEX> in his chest. Lots and lots and lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dormitory of San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>, there's a whole row of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monks</ENAMEX>' cells, each of which has a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spurting Jesus</ENAMEX> on the wall. The monks were supposed to meditate on these
paintings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>. This can't have been helpful. Maybe they meditated on
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>-on-the-cross had a penis. He seems to have had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when he
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, but now <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> are conveniently placed to obscure it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floating Jesus</ENAMEX> is my
favorite. He wears a white robe and hovers over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> who have just dug
up his grave. With one hand, he makes Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX>'s "live long and prosper" sign.
With the other, he carries the flag of some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            Propeller-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> has a halo with a red cross in it that
looks like a propeller. This is the easiest way to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>. Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
in these paintings look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, and they all have halos. Sometimes one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX>'s halo blocks your view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> behind him. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> discussing a huge mural of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Supper</ENAMEX> before we realized that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> we thought was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was really <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judas</ENAMEX>. Very embarrassing. We should have
looked for the propeller. What it's supposed to convey, I don't know. What it
conveys to me is: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey</ENAMEX>! Over here! This one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>!"

            I don't mean to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disrespectful</ENAMEX> to religion. I loved the duomi and the little shrines
nestled into odd corners of the hill <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>. But let's face it, much of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> history is bloody awful. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Gimignano</ENAMEX>, there's a whole torture
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> specializing in instruments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inquisition</ENAMEX>. (The "skull crusher" and
"rectal pear" are particularly memorable.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> charges twice the
admission fee that other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> charge, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay it because, basically,
we love cruelty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> pretends to teach the lessons of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s inhumanity
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s inhumanity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> make the appropriate
noises of disgust as they study each device. But the truth is, we're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fascinated</ENAMEX>. One exhibit presents the electric chair as a testament to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
brutality. I suppose I am a brute. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, packed into a
compartment with several nice old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>, I peered out the window at
the sky stretching toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and pronounced it "excellent bombing
weather." "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charming</ENAMEX>," my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> replied coldly as she shrank into her seat.

            D riving. If you take the "scenic" back
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, don't expect to notice the scenery. You'll spend the whole trip with
your eyes glued to the road and occasionally your rearview mirror, in which a
caravan of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> will be tailgating you. You're too terrified to
speed up because the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> is narrow and winds sharply around hillsides. They
can't pass you for the same reason. My advice is to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. The bus we
took along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Como</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bellagio</ENAMEX> careened around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of bends, any of which
could have plunged us <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of feet</NUMEX> into the lake. At first I thought the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> we passed on that road were nuts. Then I saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bikers</ENAMEX>. They wore
racing gear and refused to get out of our way.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Cars</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> build wide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> to fit big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. Italians build
little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> to fit old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Siena</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> drive
miniature <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-wheeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vans</ENAMEX>, pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, and even dump <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> designed to
navigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s tiny medieval passageways. Thanks to the proprietress of
our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, who climbed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> seat and issued directions, I
maneuvered our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat Punto</ENAMEX> through a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7-foot-</NUMEX>wide stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">maze</ENAMEX>, up and down a
series of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> at harrowing right angles, past scaffolding and cafe tables,
to the parking lot.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> anguage. In preparation for our trip, I
spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> studying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> soccer on television. I mastered the words
"portiere " (goalkeeper), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">colpo di testa "</ENAMEX> (header), and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">quattro minuti di ricupero</ENAMEX> " (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four minutes</TIMEX> of injury time). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> is
better-known as the language of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, of course, which is one reason why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> honeymoon there. The other reason is that the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>"
are easier to practice in a foreign language.

            Less than a week into our marriage, we were touring
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Como</ENAMEX> on a ferry when we cruised past a wedding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> tooted
his horn and called out over a megaphone, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vivano</ENAMEX> gli sposi! " (Long live
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> and groom.) Everyone smiled and sighed. The scene was perfectly
scripted for a honeymoon. What wasn't scripted for a honeymoon was our phrase
book, which included translations for "Is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> here," "I'd like
you to use a condom," and "You can't stay here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>." Part of the problem is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> makes everything sound like a sex act: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menaggio, Dongo, Lemna</ENAMEX>,
Cadenabbia, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faggeto, Bellagio</ENAMEX>. And those are just the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Como</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pigeons</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">piazzas</ENAMEX> are full of pigeons. I hate pigeons.
They're slow, stupid, ugly, and rude. Not only do the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> feed them, they
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> bags of birdseed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, who in turn feed the pigeons. Naturally, the
pigeons hang out in the piazzas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>, cooing and crapping and waiting to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fed</ENAMEX>. Welfare for flying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. I was delighted to discover skyward prongs in the
ledges of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Basilico San Marco</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, designed to prevent pigeons from
alighting there. I also watched a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lucca</ENAMEX> try to run over pigeons with his
bike. My only regret is that I passed up a chance to order roasted pigeon in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florence</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> ourists. The affinity between pigeons and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> makes sense. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, too, are slow, stupid, ugly, and rude. They
set off flash <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bulbs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>. They thrust their fingers within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of priceless paintings, pointing out the obvious. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>
took snapshots. Now they make videotapes. They videotape anything that moves
and much that doesn't. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Gimignano</ENAMEX>, I watched a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> painstakingly
videotape a door. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, I watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> on a bridge videotape tourists
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, who in turn were videotaping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> is one of their favorite travel spots. Somehow this makes me
uncomfortable. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> travel, particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, has never been good news.
Everyone has their ethnic hang-up; I suppose this is mine. I don't know why.
Maybe it's that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> thing. Not that I hold it against all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>. In
fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> we stayed at in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bellagio</ENAMEX> was run by a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
Lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. And I was becoming quite comfortable with the whole German
atmosphere, really--right up until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lufthansa</ENAMEX> flight attendant showed me how
to place the mask securely over my nose and mouth and breathe deeply.

            F ood. The best advice I got before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trip</ENAMEX> was from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, who said, "Order the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>." If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waiter</ENAMEX> asks whether you want gas or no gas, he's referring not to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> but
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, which comes with or without bubbles. The only bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, which provides all the blandness of matzot without the moral
satisfaction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream varies</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Gimignano</ENAMEX>, it's outstanding. In
Lucca, it's a rip-off. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> sells the same bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX>,
evidently at the behest of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> we saw unloading their
sinister cargo at various docks. In case you get homesick, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> now has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>, with menus tastefully adapted for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> sensibilities. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McChicken</ENAMEX> is called a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">McChicken</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Filet-o-Fish</ENAMEX> is called a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Filet-o-Fish</ENAMEX>.

            
               Cell phones. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, we saw a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a green suit and sunglasses prancing around a storefront, gesticulating
wildly and apparently arguing with himself. Eventually we figured out that he
was talking to a tiny phone in his ear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> go out to eat with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and
spend the whole time yapping with somebody else on the phone. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Siena</ENAMEX>, a man
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> dined at the outdoor table next to ours. They both wore wedding
rings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had brought his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> along. His phone rang, and he spent the rest
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> in what sounded like a playful conversation with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. The woman
just went on eating. It doesn't add up. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> wanted to talk to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>,
why did he leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> at home? If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> was at home, why was the dog at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>? If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, why was he ignoring her? If
she wasn't his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, why were they wearing rings? If she was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, why
didn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> hand her the phone? I don't get it. But then, being a philistine
is all about not getting it--and never having to say you're sorry.

         
      
   
