
   
   
      
         
            To Hang or Not To Hang

            The
sentencing to death for murder and treason of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish</ENAMEX> separatist leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX> was the top story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, with practically all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to call off his execution. An array of
editorials in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> trotted out much the
same arguments: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanging Ocalan</ENAMEX> would ignite more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> and
further strain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>,
which it wants to join. It was also widely claimed that the arrest and
conviction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> offers a rare opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> to negotiate a peace
settlement with its rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> proposed a do-nothing policy "until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s passion and
polemics fade away." It said: "Formally commuting the death sentence might, for
now, strike <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> as weak. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX> was alive, in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, with a
death sentence over his head, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKK</ENAMEX> [his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish Workers' Party</ENAMEX>] might
exercise more restraint: meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> might win time for a
broader approach to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> question." The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said it would be
"greatly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s interest" to embark on a dialogue with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>. It said:
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> question, the existence of which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> officially denies,
continues in reality to disrupt its internal affairs. ... It has hampered
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s ambition to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>, and raised concerns about its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
membership. The constant stream of condemnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s oppression of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority poisons</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> its commerce with the world." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> said that
although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX> was no saint or democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, hanging him would only make
things worse by turning him into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> cause.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> led
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> indignation at the death sentence and appeals for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> to commute
it. In a front-page commentary, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said it was true that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> has
blood on his hands and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want revenge, but it also said
that "a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> would be immortal as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> cause." In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, Le Figaro
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> was "mobilizing" to save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX> and commented on its front
page that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> has every reason to show generosity toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>: "It is
in a position of strength on the ground, and it knows that a gesture of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">appeasement</ENAMEX> would convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> to look more favorably on its
application to join, which has been on the table since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also led on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> warnings to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> not to carry out the
death sentence, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> said that just as the price for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s cooperation
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> had been a huge loan, so perhaps the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s life would be
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s entry into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> would be committing "a grave
error" if it carries out the death penalty against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX>, since it has "an
historic opportunity to exercise magnanimity and to lay the foundations of a
reconciliation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>."

            The
other main stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big
demonstration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cliff</ENAMEX>-hanging negotiations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> on the implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> peace settlement, for which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> has
declared <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> the "absolute" deadline. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers were
dominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> that wiped out all play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX> tennis
championships and by an administrative fiasco at the government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passport Agency</ENAMEX>,
which has left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> due to travel abroad within the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next four weeks</TIMEX> waiting for passports.

            With
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> reopening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, her birthday, for its second
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer season</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Althorp</ENAMEX>, her family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 25,000</NUMEX> tickets still remain unsold,
whereas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> tickets were snatched up before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">opening day</TIMEX>. This
is one of a number of recent indications that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> fever has declined
substantially. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reported that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX>, is
considering breaking his ties with the memorial fund through which the proceeds
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> have until now been channeled for charitable purposes, while
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Express</ENAMEX> reported a plan to build the world's
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> permanent monument to the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> on a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three-acre</NUMEX> site in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
