
   
   
      
         
            Pushing Politics and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I didn't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> should , so I'm glad he decided not to. I do think you should run for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Not only does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Congresswoman Prudie</ENAMEX> have a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>, but your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents/readers</ENAMEX> would definitely benefit from all the sound advice you
could impart to all those bozos such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> currently taking up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and I have collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23</NUMEX> to get your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> started. So
think about it.
            

            
               --Electorally
yours,
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Elect</ENAMEX>,

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> were paranoid
she would think some of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> were trying to get her out of the advice
business, what with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>, "," wanting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and
now you suggesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Prudie, however, is not paranoid, so she thanks
you for the ... well, vote of confidence. As for the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23</NUMEX>, why don't you start
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PrudiePac</ENAMEX> and see if you can't straighten out the dolts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>?

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, politically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
have begun taking anti-depressants. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> for depression, I guess, the other to
quit smoking. Because they are on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-depressants</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, they think EVERYONE
needs them and have literally been making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointments</ENAMEX> for their whole
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>! Both have told me I definitely need them. I have a professional
therapist with whom I discussed this, and she disagrees. (My therapist is not
against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>, and in fact recommends it for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.) When I
explained this to these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>, they both shook their heads--like they know
better than my therapist. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> came right out and shouted that I was in denial.
Wouldn't it be nice if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> restricted their opinions to those areas in which
they had professional expertise? What do you think?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            The last time Prudie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">checked</ENAMEX>, girlfriends could not prescribe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. It is a rule of human nature
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> often, when they add or subtract something from their lives, think
everyone else should do the same. Tune out the suggestions of these amateur
shrinks. You are right that it would be nice if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> only spoke of things
about which they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>. It would also be nice if every female over the
age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> had a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> gift certificate at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany's</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, my dear, neither
one is likely to come to pass.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, realistically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Do we as a society
need a refresher course on what things to say (or not to say) to a pregnant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>? My best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37 weeks</TIMEX> pregnant with her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. She has been
getting comments about how large she is for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three months</TIMEX>. Worse than
even the comments, one woman just stood in front of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and gaped,
saying, "Oh my God!" Why would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel the need to point out a pregnant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s size? And is there an appropriate response to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that would
remind them their comments are not appreciated?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               Annoyed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neb.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ann</ENAMEX>,

            As for why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say
inappropriate things, it usually has to do with the connector cable between
brain and mouth being on the fritz. These rude and unappreciated remarks just
slip out; the verbal equivalent of being a klutz. The way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> knows this is
that she, herself, has made this mistake a time or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ... well, maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>. If your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> with the belly spanning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ZIP codes wants to have a
comeback, she might try looking down, then remarking, "Pretty good, huh? And
I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two months</TIMEX> along." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> promises you the thoughtless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> will
have nothing more to say.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, pointedly

            

               
                  Prudie,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> is a
staunch supporter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Buchanan</ENAMEX> for prez. I feel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is way too
liberal for my taste (I have been a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> also listens to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX>, but I know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush</ENAMEX> has been a
running <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog lackey</ENAMEX> of the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> news media for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. A typical
liberal country club <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>! I was going to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> in his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Taxpayers Party</ENAMEX>, but now that he's withdrawn,
there seems to be no one true to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> legacy. The question is, should I
dump the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Red</ENAMEX>,

            You're kidding, right?
The part about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> being too liberal supplied the hint. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redmond</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home base</ENAMEX> for 
                  Slate
               , so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will offer a choice of answers
allowing for all contingencies. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) If the political chasm is legitimate, and as
wide as you describe, yes, undo from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>. If you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have such
different outlooks now , future differences have the potential for major
fireworks. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) If you are a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Microsoftie</ENAMEX> pulling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s leg to kill time
before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jolt Cola</ENAMEX>-break, why don't you get back to work, hmmm?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
constructively

         
      
   
