
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakeout</ENAMEX>

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>'s straw poll in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, kicked off the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> and
sorted out the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> field. Everyone agrees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-runner</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> is in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> place, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>, who
finished back in the pack with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>, will soon join <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> on the
sidelines. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> failed to resolve the fate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who came in
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>--and the one who skipped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>. For these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, the post-game spin contest is crucial. Here's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playback</ENAMEX> of their takes on the straw poll results and a look ahead at their
playbook of messages for the remainder of the race.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
Dole
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Playback</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> needed to get within striking distance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and to seal off the rest of the pack behind her. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation , and Late Edition</ENAMEX> , she boasted that she had
cracked "the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundits</ENAMEX> bought the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-winners line, treating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX>
as a horse race ("win, place, and show") and noting that "no one's ever won the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> nomination without finishing in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>" at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX>,
cramped for space, confined their headlines to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. Though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX> was closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9</ENAMEX> than to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>, she earned a
"solid <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>" and a place among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> by crossing the "double-digit"
threshold. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Cameron</ENAMEX> put it: "The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> could
not crack double digits."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Race for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> were expected to
finish <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> concluded, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Myers</ENAMEX> put it on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , that "the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> here was for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>
won that." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of this
contest-within-the-contest." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> touted her "victory" on every talk show and
cited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> quotes in a press release. At a news
conference, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> as the straw poll's "real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underdog</ENAMEX>. In every TV interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> claimed to have been
"outspent by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>." Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> told reporters that "on a
dollar-per-vote basis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> trounced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> love an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>. "From a strict cost-benefit standpoint, the big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> may be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>," concluded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> .

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Comeback <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dismissive</ENAMEX> coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> before the straw
poll played to her advantage, as everyone marveled at her "surprisingly" strong
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole Revived</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's front page proclaimed. On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> conceded, "There had been a lot of very skeptical
stories about whether her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would show up. She, therefore, I think, is the
biggest winner."

            

               Playbook
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Race for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> wants to fast-forward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
tournament to a finals bracket: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>. To prevent this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> needs to
create a semifinal playoff--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>--to determine who gets to play
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' huge financial advantage, "we finished close to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> told reporters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. "This is going to become a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-person
race." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> agreed. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> had growing hopes ... that he might upset <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
or finish a close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>," recalled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . Instead, "he finished
closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> than to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Experience. Having narrowed the field to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> needs
to focus the contest on criteria that favor her. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of these is
political experience, of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has little and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> has almost none. On
every talk show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> vowed "to demonstrate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> with the most
experience is more qualified than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> with the most money. ... We're
talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Gender. This is the more obvious criterion that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distinguishes Dole</ENAMEX>. She hardly needs to mention it--the media bring it up
anyway--but she invokes it subtly, alluding (as she did on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two Sunday</TIMEX> talk
shows) to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who drive their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> halfway across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to shake my
hand, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> they dare to believe in." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> hail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>
as evidence "that she can attract new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Playback</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> needed to crack the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tier</ENAMEX> and
seal off the pack. Since sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analogies</ENAMEX> tend to cut off the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tier</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
rather than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> (e.g., "bronze medal," "win, place, and show"), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> changed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">metaphors</ENAMEX>, telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that he had reached "the first rung of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>"
and that lower finishers might soon perish. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , he called
himself the "breakout <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>." While some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> lumped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>, others offered him the next best position--"leading the rest of the
pack"--or at least distinguished him from the "losers."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> conservative quarterfinal. This was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s big spin
win. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, he won a crucial "contest-within-the-contest." His scant margin
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.9 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.3 percent</NUMEX>--became a huge factor in the
post-poll analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> "did what he had to do ...
beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>," and therefore "can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legitimately</ENAMEX> say he is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>," establishing himself as "one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>," the "three
or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who "got their tickets punched" to stay in the race. Talk
show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> that he had lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> and asked whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> was finished.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Conservative semifinal. Having scored well ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> anointed himself "the conservative in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-man race"
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> disagreed, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> took his side. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
Battle for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Right</TIMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> proclaimed, concluding that because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>
failed to break away, "he and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> are likely to continue a long and tough
fight for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underdog</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> couldn't claim to be more strapped than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, so he claimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> status on the basis of low name recognition,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inexperience</ENAMEX>, and working-class heritage. "I am running against some big bios
... the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> argued on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> . "I have never run for president
or office before. And yet here we come in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> place." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brooks</ENAMEX> wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> "overcame his own financial disadvantages" and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">joined Dole</ENAMEX> as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> surviving "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have-Not</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>."

            

               Playbook
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> will defect. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s combativeness and
loyal base make him hard to write off as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> have persuaded
the media at least to write him off as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> by inferring that his low
score at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> will prompt him to transfer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>. The more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> fends off comparisons to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> by emphasizing his protectionism, the
more he plays into this scenario.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Populism</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> out of the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> will go after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>. When asked on television about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' claim to represent the right.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' wealth and called himself "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."
On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> "is becoming the
populist in the race," noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> "love the fact that he
was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Conservatism. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> wins the social conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quarterfinal</ENAMEX> and the conservative semifinal, he gets to run as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> against "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>" moderation on abortion, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and
other hot-button issues. This bracket<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by-</NUMEX>bracket tournament strategy reduces
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s obstacles from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. He can target <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, knowing
that if he prevails, either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> will have vanquished the other in the
moderate semifinal. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s success at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> arguably helps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> by
giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> a semifinal contest.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">McCain</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Playback</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> meant nothing to him. Despite having skipped the straw
poll, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was invited onto <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX>
to discuss it. "If you're going to be taken seriously," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> asked him,
"don't you have to face up to the fact, when all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> decide
that an event is worth attending ... that maybe you've got to play too?" In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reply</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> repeatedly called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> "meaningless." His chutzpah bowled over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s no-show "a pretty smart move" and
portrayed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83</NUMEX> votes he won in the straw poll--putting him in last place
among active <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--as evidence of his strength.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> meant death for others. Noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> had
bypassed the event, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> explained on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> that he, too,
"almost took a pass on this. It wasn't until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> said he was going to
participate that then I said, 'OK, we've got to do it,' out of respect to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>." The result, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> pleaded, was that he lost to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, explaining his
decision to stay out, espoused a less sentimental philosophy: "You always want
to fight on ground that is most favorable to you." For this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> executed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> and spared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> might be gone, but I
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is still in," concluded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX> in
reverse: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> ducked the fight, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> took the beating.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Viability. "Once the dust has settled from the straw poll,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> regally announced, "I will review the new political landscape" and begin
"engaging the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>." Why does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> get a bye? Because
he has convinced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that he has enough money and support in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to skip <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and catch fire later.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and
several TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> remains formidable, wasn't hurt by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX>,
and may well end up as the principal alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Vote-buying. To undermine the straw poll's authority as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arbiter</ENAMEX> of his candidacy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> called it a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX>," "a sham and a joke"
in which campaigns spent "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>" to "buy" votes. "My campaign theme is to
try to reform the system that is now awash with money and the influence of
special interests," he argued on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retort</ENAMEX>--"that this whole process isn't quite pure enough for you"--played right
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">into McCain</ENAMEX>'s hands. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> doesn't need to persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that his reasons
for skipping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> were morally sound. He just needs to persuade them that his
reasons were moral rather than political.

            

               Playbook
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Real votes. The vote-buying complaint only gets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> a
bye on the straw poll. To get another bye on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses, he'll
rely on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other moral arguments. First, he'll claim that caucuses aren't
"real votes." "We'll have real votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> argued on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
News <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> . "That's where real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are motivated to vote." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , he suggested that he would focus on "the genuine balloting
process, which takes place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ethanol</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, fancying themselves shrewd, suggest
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s true reason for skipping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> is that he has "taken a position on
ethanol subsidies that's unpalatable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ,
Stephanopoulos suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> might "have to do something dramatic,"
such as "make a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stand</ENAMEX> and say, 'We're not going to compete in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. We think
these ethanol subsidies are an abomination.' " This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s greatest
triumph: He has conned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> into disbelieving his political calculations
and accusing him instead of principle. "I've taken a lot of unpopular
positions," he conceded on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> .

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Experience. The longer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> stays out of the race without
damaging his credibility, the more the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> narrows to his advantage.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, are already gone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, won't be far behind. If the field dwindles to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> can sell himself as the only experienced officeholder running
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s third-place finish at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX>, coupled with her victory
in the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> spin contest, complicates this plan.

            So
here's how the race shapes up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> will frame it as a populist showdown,
chiefly between himself and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> will frame it as a fight between the
establishment, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, led by himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> will
exploit feminism as well as feminine stereotypes, pitching herself as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of change, civility, and moral renewal. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> will fortify his
war chest while his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> battle and bleed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> has organized the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contestants</ENAMEX>. Let the games begin.

         
      
   
