
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">323</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Smooth Talker&quot</ENAMEX>; 

            
               "We deal in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">basics</ENAMEX>, and all those basics are necessary necessities," said a smiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>,
patiently explaining to some CNNfn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would thrive even
in an economic downturn. Why was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> smiling?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">322</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Deliver?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doolittle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, "Sometimes it's barbecue;
sometimes it's fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, sometimes it's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>; frequently it's more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those things." What is?
            

            "The
shocking diet of talking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Frellick</ENAMEX>
had similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, depending on where he's
campaigning."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Finkle</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Cigarette flavors <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> tried while not targeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dishes</ENAMEX> made out of euthanized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Singer</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of
animal-friendly fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX>.
A martini should be <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gin</ENAMEX> and vermouth and a twist. That's it. There's no call
for 'secret' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredients</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Manella</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> responses
and in the wider culture (if there is one), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is used as a metaphor for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideology</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX>; let them eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>) and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>: Their
attitudes toward eating reveal something, well, distasteful about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calista Flockhart</ENAMEX>. It is also a metaphor for sex and never more
delightfully so than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX>-eating scene in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Richardson</ENAMEX>'s movie of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Jones</ENAMEX> . There is, however, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> place I can think of where the
equation is reversed so that sex is a metaphor for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampopo</ENAMEX> ,
when the incredibly attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in white are not actually in a gourmet
frenzy, sex is simply food carried on by other means. And it really makes you
hungry. If that's the appetite I mean.

            
               Meals for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wheels</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doolittle</ENAMEX> is listing the free eats Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, serves up at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> during
late-night sessions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, just one of the ways he has become, according
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Whitmann</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>, "the most powerful majority
whip in the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>."

            And he's handing out more than ribs. The basis of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s power is ladling out cash to those who please him. The chief
than half the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s money. And those who supply the funds are not neglected
either. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Mitchell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Lacey</ENAMEX> report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> has long had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> cabinet of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> who meet with him
regularly."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> is now launching a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX> fund-raising
campaign to fight trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> through the innovative method of establishing a
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that can raise unlimited cash without disclosing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>,
a plan his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Shays</ENAMEX> calls, "unbelievably
sick."

            In a rare case of
bipartisan agreement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Obey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, notes, "To me, the worst thing in
politics is anonymous, under-the-bedclothes money," he said. "Along with some
of the things I've seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> shower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>," he did not add.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Interfaith Extra 2</ENAMEX>--Can
I Hug the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead Guy</ENAMEX>?
            

            I guess we've all had one drink too many and
embarrassed ourselves at a funeral. Or borrowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> funds that we had every
intention of returning, so there was really no reason to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. But
would you know how to treat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> at someone else's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX>, or
prayer thingy?

            Name the Appropriate
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Behavior Upon Viewing the Body</ENAMEX> for each of these religious faiths:

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religions</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Baptist</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hindu</ENAMEX>

               Episcopalian

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jehovah's Witnesses</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Church of Canada</ENAMEX>

            

            
               The Behavior
            

            

               Join the line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> and view the body silently and somberly. ( No
cutting ahead saying, "I just have this quart of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.")
               

               Look reverently upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and do not touch it. ( Especially not with
cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">utensils</ENAMEX>.)
               

               A moment of silent prayer. ( During which you can think about where to go
for lunch. Like he'd mind. He's dead.)
               

               Look upon it somberly for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few moments</TIMEX>. ( Then look upon him with a big
goofy grin on your face and sing him a medley of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole Porter</ENAMEX> tunes. He would
have wanted it that way.)
               

               Stand quietly and then move on. (Pretty much the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> orders
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> to behave in every situation.)
               

               A kiss is appropriate, but no tongue unless you were close before death.
OK, I just made that one up. But wouldn't that make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> weirdly
exciting?

               This is optional, but if it is a memorial service, there will be no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to
view. ( With their excellent system of national health, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> never
die.)
               

            

            (All actual facts from
How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Be a Perfect Stranger: a Guide to Etiquette in Other People</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Religious Ceremonies</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vol.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> and II.)

            
               Signs That the '60s Are
Finally <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Over Ongoing Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "We're both irreverent, hip and fun, but also
trusted and respectable brands."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Levitan</ENAMEX>, co-founder of some kind of
online gift certificate thing, describes his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and Whoopi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to submit other actual
news items that sound taps for that turbulent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, if you'll accept the idea
that his pairing of "hip" and "respectable brands" travesties the spirit of
that era, which might be easier to accept if you thought that he was on acid
when he said it, or if you were right now.

            Results to run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            The plebian tastes of our gluttonous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
