
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">269</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Coaching Staff&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sometime Thursday</TIMEX>,
Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> will take off her crown, put on a purple and green dress in a
thistle pattern, and step into her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriage</ENAMEX>. Where's she going?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 268</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pyramid Power":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX>-nation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conference</ENAMEX> is to present the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. General Assembly</ENAMEX>
with an action plan to reduce world population growth by employing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>
Strategy. Which is what?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX> inside every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Hobson</ENAMEX>
            

            "Not
having sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
reintroduction of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> into major urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Brax</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cancel</ENAMEX> plans for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Straight Pride Month</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O'Grady</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "I
missed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of days</TIMEX> because of a computer crash. Is it too late to
make fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Many of you suggested
that a great way to discourage sexual urges was to flash a photo of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX>
ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. But this seems unlikely to be effective. Such a powerful visual
image certainly didn't deter the unattractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from mating with one
another--there do seem to be rather a lot of them--while attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
in distinctly short supply. (Hence the high rates charged by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elite Models</ENAMEX>. And
try to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>: Sheesh! Like you're a criminal for asking.
Like my real name couldn't be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre LeCluck</ENAMEX>.) Perhaps it's because the
beauties are wan, weak, overbred: They've lost their erotic vitality like some
brittle-boned show <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelman</ENAMEX>'s consort. Certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> with a
history of goofball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>-race ideas and a reputation for being grim and
plodding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>--you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>--have long associated sexual vigor with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Africans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trolls</ENAMEX>, frequently depicting us as ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX> coupling
with enthusiasm, skill, and joy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX> isn't pretty.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey, You Kids, Keep It</ENAMEX>
Down Answer
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, agreed that the best way to curb population
growth was not to set numerical targets and launch birth-control campaigns, but
to try to improve the social status, education, and health of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. By
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> estimate, this plan would incur a rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> from the present <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.8 billion</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2050</TIMEX>, and stabilize at that level. However, at recent
meetings, conservative elements, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Catholics</ENAMEX>, have
sought to thwart various socially progressive aspects of the plan.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Silow-Carroll</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Roundelay Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> were
invited to devise a sequentially trumping topical triad--rock, paper,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scissors</ENAMEX>--along these lines: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crush Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> drives out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> fits).

            "
'Palestinian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>' issue dogs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> hires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville, Carville</ENAMEX> founds
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> send big checks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> gets elected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is appropriately grateful to said
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> unfortunately tried to skip Step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Welty</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English language</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language has
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">infiltrated Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">slang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX> caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> to vomit,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> mangles the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> will want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX> to return the letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maynard</ENAMEX>. That way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>
can screw <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX>, too."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Brant</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Supposed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> frighten the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, which denounces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s bombing of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, which kills supposed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            "God
creates world; world creates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX> the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandler</ENAMEX> supplants
God, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thousand years</TIMEX> of wailing and torment follow."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
Danenberg
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angelos</ENAMEX> buys <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> can't beat anybody, anybody would be better than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Angelos</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>'s
Variation
            

            "
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'News Roundelay</ENAMEX>' reminds me of a game some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and I invented in college,
which we called "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anything"</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, on the count of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>,
form an approximation of something with their hands and announce what that
something is: for instance, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>. Then a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> player
acts as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arbiter</ENAMEX> and decides which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> wins (in this case, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX>, because
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX> flaps its wings and sets into a motion a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of events that
ends with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> slipping on a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana peel</ENAMEX> and falling into a cement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mixer</ENAMEX>). Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">loser</ENAMEX> acts as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arbiter</ENAMEX> for the next round. Or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, who
cares? This is not a goal-oriented game."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick O'Brien</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headline Haiku</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic Snub Strikes</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget Pie And</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greens</ENAMEX>
Fees

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arid Rainy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Season</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Front</ENAMEX> page, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29, 1999</TIMEX>

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Exodus.

         
      
   
