
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Junction</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 7, 1999</TIMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, we began the best part of our journey,
the stretch between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moab</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>. E seemed to be buoyant, even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exuberant</ENAMEX>. As we climbed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rockies</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, she sighed, "I love
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX>. I think I could even live here. Why would anyone not want to
live here?" We cruised through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> that replaced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loveland</ENAMEX> pass, and
floated down a long, steep grade. The mood was mellow. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Multicolored</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pines</ENAMEX> lined
our path. "I'm so happy now," she said. In the distance, a storm sent the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twilight</ENAMEX> careening at crazy angles. Snow glistened on a perfect peak. I noticed
a billboard that said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coach Factory Outlet</ENAMEX>. Left at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Next Exit</ENAMEX>." I laughed and
pointed it out. "Look at that. Isn't that ridiculous? What a cheap commercial
thing to put into this fabulous natural scene."

            E looked at the billboard, then barked "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turn</ENAMEX> left.
Now!"

            E wasn't mellow anymore. She was possessed, a look
of stony purpose on her face. As we approached the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach store</ENAMEX>, she spotted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Karan</ENAMEX> in the distance.

            "Oh, my goodness."

            This said quietly, reverentially, as if she were
Balboa discovering the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>. As it turns out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> had never seen a factory
outlet store before. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The next three hours</TIMEX> were lost. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> seemed ecstatic.

            I fear, however, that I may not be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>'s new mood. I admit the warning signs are subtle.

            Have I mentioned yet that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> attracts perverts and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">molesters</ENAMEX> like a magnet? It must have something to do with her deceptively
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">childlike</ENAMEX> look. We were once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, living across the street
from the chancery of an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that will go unnamed. Various
surly young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> attached to this diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outpost</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">their afternoons</TIMEX>
working on old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buicks</ENAMEX> in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX>, one of these men
exposed himself to E while she was walking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. Oddly, E argued for
giving this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> the benefit of the doubt. She said his penis might have just
fallen out of his pants by accident. I thought otherwise. On this trip already,
a strange, long-haired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> parking lot where we were making
a U-turn has struck up a gratuitous conversation. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two nights ago</TIMEX>, the motel
night <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> phoned our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">room</ENAMEX> "just to check and see if everything is all
right."

            The point is, E realizes she's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prey</ENAMEX>, and is usually
afraid to be alone for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. Last night, we went to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7-Eleven</TIMEX> down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> from the motel. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> behind the counter, a slightly dissolute ski-bum
type, seemed disturbingly interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E. And E</ENAMEX> seemed disturbingly interested
in him. Later, she insisted on returning to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 7-Eleven</TIMEX>, alone, "for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>."

            "But I thought you'd sworn off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>."

            "I think I'm going to need it if I'm going to post
anything <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>."

            "Do you want me to go with you? It's dark."

            "Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">no. Thanks</ENAMEX>. What could happen to me?"

            She's also been checking her e-mail obsessively. In
the glow of the screen, I can see her chuckling to herself. And once when she
made a phone call, she asked me to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Toward me, she's pleasant
and friendly, but nothing more.

            I admit, I expected something else. Was I crazy?
I've transported her and looked after her for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000 miles</NUMEX>. I took her to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX>. I do all the manly, driverly things. I check the oil and I tighten
the straps that are holding her fucking sofabed onto the roof. We have good
times in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. Then, nothing. Nothing.

            I'm tired. I'll be damned if I'm going to stay up
for her to get back from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 7-Eleven</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
