
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gun Owner's Bible</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 26</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story makes grand but familiar observations
about the Internet's impact on business. ("New technologies have always changed
the world in unforeseeable ways.") Predictions: Blue-chip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will use
the Internet to transform themselves; business-to-business e-commerce will
flourish; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will outsource everything but their core functions.
... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> spoofs recent juvenile-crime legislation with a set of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> "gun commandments." No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honour</ENAMEX> thy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and thy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, or they will
blow thy head off." No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thou</ENAMEX> shalt not kill, except when provoked. But if
thou dost, remember that thy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> had nothing to do with it."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX>
            

            A
dishy piece names the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Mikulski</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>, throw things; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Sanford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> buy him lunch but doesn't reimburse them; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Torricelli</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, welcomes new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> with a threat to ruin their lives if they ever wrong
him. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> take to the pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> to
defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>: "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> truly tried to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover review of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> biography
argues that she had a personal stake in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> represents the two evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> that shaped her childhood: communism,
which her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> claimed drove him from his beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX>, and ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hatred</ENAMEX>, which led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents perished</ENAMEX>.
(See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX>'s "" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               .) ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> calls purported moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> a closet
conservative. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example: When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed a law giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">states</ENAMEX> money to
cover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> without medical insurance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> proposed insuring fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
than the law allowed, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has the second-highest percentage of
uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. ... A piece argues for a communitarian reading of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX>
Amendment. It makes a tricky distinction: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> does not have an
inviolable right to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> collectively do have a right to
arm themselves against tyranny.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story chronicles how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> lost the race to the moon. The space
program was competing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> pitted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">space</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> against each other rather than encouraging them to cooperate.
Ironically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> might have beaten the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> had their quest been
all aura, according to a profile. The former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>, and New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Knick</ENAMEX> is promising big ideas but does not offer any. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> he is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crotchety</ENAMEX> and condescending. ... An article scoffs at the rise of the
credentialed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. Applications to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masters of Fine Arts</ENAMEX> programs are rising.
The academies provide aspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> but encourage trendy,
theory-laden art.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story claims mass killings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> were part of a
systematic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> effort to crush the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX> and rid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>. The plan, called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Horseshoe</ENAMEX>, was devised by a high-ranking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> and carried out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of paramilitaries, special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, and
nationalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>. In one massacre, an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> watched her father
being marched off and later found his charred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. She buried his remains to
spare her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> the gruesome sight. ... An article says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> a potent campaign issue by killing gun control in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. Even
better for the veep, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> signed a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> law forbidding
class-action lawsuits against <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, a bill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association Protection</ENAMEX> Act.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28</TIMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> massacre story runs inside. The cover
package celebrates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> in entertainment with anecdotes told by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and their hangers-on: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Gershwin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> describes how he
manufactured <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ketchup</ENAMEX> (he said "to-may-toes," but his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> said
"to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">mah</NUMEX>-toes"); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Ricky</ENAMEX> remembers what it was like to grow up as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desi</ENAMEX>'s TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX> claims she was never a shrew on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">set</ENAMEX>; a
Titanic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> tells how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Winslet</ENAMEX> improvised an enduring moment in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cinema</ENAMEX>--spitting in the face of co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Zane</ENAMEX>, etc. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
story details a massacre in which local nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> and
paramilitaries murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gang</ENAMEX>-raped, butchered, and left to bleed to death, shorn of her limbs. During
the rampage, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> told her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to pretend they were dead, unaware that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> already were. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s 2-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> cried out; he was
silenced with a shot to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28</TIMEX>
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> retirement guide
                celebrates the rise of the
"shareholder <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>" but notes the downside of investment mania: profound
ignorance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one-third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> know that when interest rates increase,
bond prices drop. ... An article criticizes the stagy kickoffs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
campaigns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> arranged focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to evaluate his speaking style, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> hired a drama <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>. ... A piece says political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> think like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, not
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> want a guaranteed return, they favor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> over
his primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>. In
the worst-case scenario, at least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> can peddle his influence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is unemployed.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story rehabilitates <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Colson</ENAMEX>. Born again while
serving his <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> sentence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colson</ENAMEX> founded a prison <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Prison</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fellowship</ENAMEX> draws <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> study and seminars in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and has
made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colson</ENAMEX> one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. ...
An article identifies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Achilles</ENAMEX>' heel: abortion. His effort to
straddle the pro-choice/pro-life debate reveals a lack of moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>,
invites media scrutiny, and allows primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> to attack him from the
right.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Forbes</ENAMEX>
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, surprise, tops the annual list of the world's 200
wealthiest billionaires (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">265</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaires</ENAMEX> didn't make the list). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>'
fortune appreciated by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 billion</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsofties</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>--make the Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX> keeps <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> place at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36 billion</NUMEX>. Cause for most envy: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dell</ENAMEX> ranks <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> with
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.5 billion</NUMEX>. ... An article peeks into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute Le Rosey</ENAMEX>, a high
school for the international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> per year boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> boasts
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2-to-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>-faculty ratio and a high concentration of royalty. For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> moves to a chalet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gstaad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> may learn how to ski with aristocratic ease.

         
      
   
