
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">312</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Ominous</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anomalous&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
God. Which does not belong? Why?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 311</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> Treatment":
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Beatrix</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX>
reopens one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX>'s most popular tourist attractions after extensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">renovations</ENAMEX>. What attraction?
                     
                  
               
            

            "Her
warm, welcoming bosoms."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nikonovich-Kahn</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "Queen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrix</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mystery Spot</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrill Markoe</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheft</ENAMEX> )

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house Anne Frank</ENAMEX> lived in with 'Diversity,' 'Trench,' and 'Otto' during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first Real World</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful World of It's None of Our Business</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>
World, where all sorts of fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> come
out to play with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of all ages!"-- t
               he other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wrap-</ENAMEX>
               Up
            

            Sex, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and hidden
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>! That's what I remember about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX>. Or perhaps that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> remember about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>. Here's what they've
forgotten--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rembrandt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van Gogh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spinoza</ENAMEX>, hydraulic engineering, silver skates,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boswell</ENAMEX>'s education, (I was sure there'd be many a smartass remark about his
law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>), treat, courage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, rub, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">elm disease</ENAMEX>, those damned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
Hapsburgs, that crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> Reformation (the long hair, the beads,
the--oh, wait, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX> again), the seizure of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>, the wars with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
and their possible connection to the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Marlowe</ENAMEX> (who never
got to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> naked, but might have if only he and she had been at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s new maturity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> when it took its place among
other great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Coal and Steel Commission</ENAMEX>.

            
               Despite

               Everything <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Believe This Is the Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX>
which hid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> officially unveiled
its new look <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> of renovation," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> reports. "The snack
bar, the gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roller coaster</ENAMEX>--the entire place is just
Annetastic!" they did not add. "Makes other <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> look like a lot
of boring <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>," also went unsaid.

            
               Some

               Highlights
            

            

               Black-and-white photos of the neighborhood in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1940s</TIMEX> have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affixed</ENAMEX> to the windows for a sense of going back in time.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne Frank Foundation</ENAMEX> has re-created the atmosphere of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> as it
was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>, including the smell of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX>.

               A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>' cafe* and a virtual tour through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on computer have
been added.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> remained open throughout the renovations. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">822,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.

            

            

               *
               Rainy 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day Fun</ENAMEX>
Draw your own menu for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne Frank House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafe</ENAMEX>. Is there a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s menu? Can you include the phrases "all you can eat" and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fajitas"</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloutier's Auto-Translation Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            What I have done is translate the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> back to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alta Vista</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>.

            Below, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wrap</ENAMEX>
Up:

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANDY</ENAMEX>
AUFRAEUMARBEITEN

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> I explain to
you, what I do not understand--why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoshanna Sofaer</ENAMEX> of the university
Baruch cranky sounds in such a way. (necessities few sabbatical?) Or why
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">congress</ENAMEX> (necessities <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designate delimitations</ENAMEX>? Of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 30 seconds</TIMEX>?) It
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corresponds</ENAMEX> to labels strongly for the normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for attaching a group
complaint however more simply, so that enormous oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> pump free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> of
the general <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and at a profit, probably at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> sells it (necessities--OH
-, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> begins? With sentimentally nonsense <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">world war II</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.k.</ENAMEX>. There!) those large turbines refuel, in order to expose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> for
telecasting the halfpopular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaldaunen</ENAMEX> on the general Airwaves at the
considerable profits, for the maintenance of the bored oil platform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> out
in any as soon as-excellent national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. (you need a good book memory
beginning with a series author appearance, possibly with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>? It is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> from understanding. And slogans) know you, whom would understand? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>. Quite obviously to it. But like a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> its heading more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pound</ENAMEX> even weighed and with a special pig iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> to be fastened had,
evenly above he cannot not to understand, why love is a crime, the assortment
of the crime spells out in a provisional order of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NECESSITIES ITS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GODDAMNED HEADING CHECKING</ENAMEX>!!!!) who OH is, thus ready for use, to ignore
everything a person it says and believes you simply that everything, which says
any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> even if it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> is! Hypothetically speaking. Answer me this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoshanna Sofaer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> Baruch! Where is your whole
government advice now?

            

            
               Our

               Corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Philosophers Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three hundred</NUMEX> corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">titans</ENAMEX> are gathered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune Global Forum</ENAMEX>. Some big ideas
from these exemplars of capitalism:

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altruism</ENAMEX>

            "When you go into a
market like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, you recognize talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and give them an opportunity
for expression. That's an important public role. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> like ours have a
role to play in creating world harmony."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald M. Levin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, said this with a straight face.

            On the Role of the
Press

            "Journalistic integrity
must prevail in the final analysis, but that doesn't meant that journalistic
integrity should be exercised in a way that is unnecessarily offensive to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in which you operate."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sumner Redstone</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>,
said this and did not die of shame.

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
