
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">288</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Futurific&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>'s present
is rosy, with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second quarter</TIMEX> sales up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> and profits up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.25 billion</NUMEX>. And its future is even better. Marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flickinger</ENAMEX> sees something coming that is "the best possible thing that can
happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> and the worst thing that could happen to every major
competitor." What?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 287</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First-Class Male":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Fournier</ENAMEX>, a health insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Novato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, goes
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> gather round: "They say, 'Boy, that's neat!'
" What do the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> admire?*
            

            

               (*a gun-free question)
            

            "The
envelopes he made himself from soy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">noodles</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrill Markoe</ENAMEX>
            

            "His
smoking package, if you know what I mean, and I think you do."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carvell</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Fredericksen</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "The
first form of postage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX> that has nothing to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bros.</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Schoenberg</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
went to high school with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Fournier</ENAMEX>, and believe me there's nothing to
admire."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Cass</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>,
since you outlawed the obvious gun jokes, it must be his double-barreled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penis</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Basial</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            It is easy to mock the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">postal</ENAMEX> service, but--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33 cents</NUMEX>! Anywhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>! In just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>! And
you don't even have to lick the stamps anymore, which frankly, for that one
about prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, is kind of a relief. Indeed, headline-grabbing diseases
seem to make up an increasing proportion of our stamps, along with
noncontroversial nature and beloved pop culture figures. Coincidentally, these
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> categories describe most of the programs on public television lately.
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> outlet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ran a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> special on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bee Gees</ENAMEX>
followed by a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90-minute</TIMEX> special on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Feliciano</ENAMEX>. Then somebody got ripped
apart by a diseased ferret, but only, alas, in my <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90-minute</TIMEX> dream. ) Perhaps a
joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> is possible: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> can issue stamps that promote the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snoozy PBS</ENAMEX> programming, and both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> can share the profits. The only
obstacle: To be on a stamp you must actually be dead; to be on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> you need
merely seem dead.

            
               Priority
Answer
            

            All admire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fournier</ENAMEX>'s digital postage, which he's
been using since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> when it was only a crazy experiment.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> announced the
nationwide availability of stamps that can be downloaded from the Internet. For
a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> fee on top of the postage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> can pay with credit cards and
print out a special bar code, the first new method of supplying stamps since
postal <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meters</NUMEX> went into service in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
E-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stamp</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stamps</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, offer the service; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowes and Neopost</ENAMEX> may soon be approved to compete. Incidentally, former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Postmaster General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin Runyon</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stamps</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Which is
completely legal.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Philip</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Peoples</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            I give the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, you
give the racist remark made about it by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> II

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Guinea</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Bonus</ENAMEX>:
the jobless

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speaks</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Touring a high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>,
he noticed a poorly wired fuse box: "It looks as though it was put in by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. He asked a driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX>: "How do you keep
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> long enough to get them past the test?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. During a visit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peking</ENAMEX> was
"ghastly" and told a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>: "If you stay here much longer
you'll all be slitty-eyed."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. He said at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wildlife Fund</ENAMEX> function: "If
it has got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> legs and it's not a chair, if it has got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX> and it is
not an aeroplane, and if it swims and it's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cantonese</ENAMEX> will
eat it."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. He told a tourist: "You can't have been here
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX>, you've no potbelly."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. He asked a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Edinburgh Award-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> who
had just returned from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua</ENAMEX>: "You didn't manage to get eaten then?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. At the height of the
recession in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, he grumbled: "Everybody wanted more leisure. Now they
complain they're unemployed."

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
