
   
   
      
         
            Offspring Obligations

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twit</ENAMEX> who inquired about dissing the offspring of the discarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> needs
perhaps something more along the lines of a swift kick in the rear. If these
are older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, as is suggested by requests for letters of recommendation
and invites to graduations, then these are more or less formed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, who
deserve to be accepted or rejected on their own merits--not for any slight
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> may or may not have committed. Anything less is the moral
equivalent of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> not buying a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VW Beetle</ENAMEX> because it's made by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, a sort of inherited grudge, if not racism.
            

            
               In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, they
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are important, or not, based on their birth. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and
we hold that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> deserve to be admired or respected because they have earned
respect or admiration.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yours</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunswick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mike</ENAMEX>,

            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> doubts the
estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> will be swayed by your opinion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees with you and
hopes that your thoughts might make a difference in someone else's
thinking.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, agreeably

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               We have close
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have us to their home for dinner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every week</TIMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
doesn't want to go out or come to our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.) When we're there, however, she
spends a large part of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> on the phone or on the computer. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
says she actually spends less time on either because we're there. Should we be
honored or insulted?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insulted</ENAMEX> and Ignored
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Ig</ENAMEX>,

            I don't know what her problem is, but I bet it's
hard to pronounce. The mistake that is commonly made about neurotics is to
suppose that they are interesting. It is not interesting to be engrossed with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oneself</ENAMEX> and socially idiosyncratic. Or rude.

            It sounds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> as
though there is a genuine friendship amongst the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of you, though given the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s peculiarities, it may be that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. If this has
been going on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>, which is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> infers, go along with the
program without being honored or insulted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s behavior has little to
do with you. For whatever reason, she is glued to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and not interested
in social intercourse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes, by the way, that the hospitality-free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hostess</ENAMEX> is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, understandingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               As you no doubt know, living with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates</ENAMEX> is
no longer just a college thing. Many single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> live with other nonrelated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to defray the high cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">city</ENAMEX> rents. I currently share a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-bedroom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Here's the problem: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of us don't like the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> and are unsure of how to get rid of him.
            

            
               What's wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roommate No. 4</ENAMEX>? Well, that's
difficult to put a name to. He does his chores, pays rent on time, isn't noisy
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, and isn't messy. The problem is he's a know-it-all with something
negative to say about everything. What makes the situation difficult is that
there's no obvious reason to ask him to leave, and he seems intent on staying.
It's to the point where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> of us bristle when we hear him come
through the door. He is oblivious.
            

            
               We aren't
comfortable saying, "We just don't like you. Please leave." Is there a polite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to tell him, "This just isn't working out"? Is that even legal? I'm the
only original lease-signer still living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and we now rent
month-to-month. He's lived here a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>. Your assistance is
appreciated.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               Have a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nice Life Somewhere Else</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Have</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has met <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> you
describe. She calls them <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The World's Greatest Experts</ENAMEX>, because they know
everything. But to answer your question: There is nothing legally tricky in
your situation, though you might have to give him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>'s notice. On
month-to-month tenancies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> has to give notice, usually
equivalent to the period of rent payments. This may not apply to nonsignatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roommates</ENAMEX>, but it seems the decent thing.

            There is nothing wrong
with saying, "This isn't working well," or "Sometimes it's just time for a
change." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would say, simply because she couldn't resist, "We don't know
how to tell you this, but the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us are seeing someone else."

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, puckishly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Am I obliged to
return a voice mail that is garbled ... where the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and most
of the message is garbled (because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> is slurring), but the number is
the only understandable part of the message?
            

            

               --Slurred Off in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Slur</ENAMEX>,

            This all depends on the mood you're in. Unclear
messages are annoying, and you have every right to ignore them. If the number,
however, is clear, and you're feeling charitable, you might call back and say,
"This is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slurred Off</ENAMEX>. I have no idea what you said in your message, but I am
returning your call."

            If the number is
familiar to you, this may help to decide which way you're going to play it. And
just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FYI</ENAMEX>, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it's important to reach you, they will keep trying.
And keep in mind that we are dealing with machinery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slurred</ENAMEX> messages are not
always signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Beam</ENAMEX> or careless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX>. They may, in fact, be courtesy of
faulty microchips.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, clearly

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Prudie</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               In re "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Need of Help</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> ," I think I am half of "this other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> who invited us to be their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> at a minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game." I
think I'll call and let them off the hook, maybe schedule a dinner or something
...
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear D.</ENAMEX>,

            How wonderful that both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in a dilemma are reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>! This just proves that virtual reality
is its own reward.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, ecstatically

         
      
   
