
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rules of Engagement</ENAMEX>

            If the
Internet is going to become the new campaign battleground, then a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-from federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> to election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>-will
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jockey</ENAMEX> to define the rules of engagement.

            Should
individual political activity online, such as posting a message urging people
to vote for a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, be considered free speech or a campaign
contribution?

            Should
links between political Web sites be considered informational, or should
campaigns have to put a monetary value on a link and include it in federal
election filings?

            Should
a new top-level domain-.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pol</ENAMEX>, for example, if it's not already taken-be created
for political Web sites to stem the growth of counterfeit or unauthorized
sites?

            These
were among the issues considered at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-day</TIMEX> conference-"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaigns</ENAMEX> in
Cyberspace: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Practice of Digital Politics</ENAMEX>"-held recently by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aspen Institute</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX> assembled a panel of election
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, Internet political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> (including this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>), and others to devise recommendations to
help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX> revise laws for Internet
campaigning.

            "The
Internet is sort of the new town hall. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizens</ENAMEX> can speak their minds and talk
to each other and talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> freely," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Varney</ENAMEX>, a
conference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> who now heads the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>'s standing committee on elections. "At the same time,
regulations exist to safeguard against abuses and fraud. The question is how to
do that effectively on the Net. My position on all of these issues is to make
sure we don't intervene until we see more maturity in the marketplace."

            The
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> agreed, recommending that political activity on the Internet
be promoted, "absent specific intent to use the Internet to circumvent the
law." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> also proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> be allowed
to link their Web sites to others without considering the links contributions
or expenditures. In addition, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> prohibited from making direct
contributions in federal elections, namely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, should be
allowed to link to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> Web sites as long as the links are bipartisan.

            Two
additional provisions would look at proposals to stem the growth of
unauthorized Web sites that purport to belong to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> and would require
periodic review of regulations to judge their impact on the use of the Internet
to spread political activity.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aspen Institute</ENAMEX>'s conference presages an inquiry by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX>, which could come
as soon as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 28</TIMEX>, to examine a whole slew of issues. Among the questions on
the docket: how the Internet fits with current regulations regarding political
action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who want to express
advocacy of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> or an issue online. At press time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> was
finalizing a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>-page draft proposal outlining the specific issues that the
commission intends to examine.

            "We
needed to have a generic inquiry as opposed to addressing one aspect at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mason</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> who attended the conference.
"We're not proposing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> pages of regulations of the Internet. We're posing
questions."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Thomas</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> who was also at the conference, noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election</ENAMEX>
Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1971</ENAMEX> outlined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> principles that need to be preserved on the
Internet: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) disclosure of how money is raised and spent to influence
elections; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) limits on the amount that any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can contribute to a
campaign; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) restrictions on independent spending by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
