
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party of Buchanan</ENAMEX>

            Before <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> toss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> for saying
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should have stayed out of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, they should
listen to some of their own rhetoric about more recent foreign policy
controversies. No one but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> is saying in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> that we were wrong to help stop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, but leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are saying things <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that lead you to wonder
what they would have been saying in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Republic</ENAMEX>, Not an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> , chronicles how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of woolly-headed idealists repeatedly
dragged the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> into pointless overseas conflicts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> contends
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> posed no real threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s vital interests after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>
and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> either bumbled his way into the world war or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deceitfully</ENAMEX> conspired to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> embroiled in a war it need not have
fought. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for 
                  Slate
               's assessment of the book's historical
accuracy.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> declared that "anyone who repudiates our involvement against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> obviously does not reflect the views of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, much less the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>" and invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> said
she was "appalled." Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week or so</TIMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have concluded
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s threat to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> was no threat at all: His views
are too extreme and unconscionable for him to remain a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s views are extreme and unconscionable but thinks he
should stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> anyway.)

            What's really striking, though, about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s ideas is
not how different, but really how very similar they are to the foreign policy
thinking that dominates the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caucus</ENAMEX>. If you start with
the foreign policy assumptions held by most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s central argument--that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> didn't threaten <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s vital
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>--is not that far off the mark.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> actually
says is this: By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1940</TIMEX>, after the worst of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, it
had become clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> would not be able to mount a cross-channel
invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> couldn't invade the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> asks, how could they credibly pose a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, who had a broad conception of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s national interests, did not have much trouble answering that
question. But if you agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s highly constricted view of the
national interest, it's not a bad point.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s premise is as a continental nation <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has
few vital national interests beyond our own shores and still fewer outside our
own hemisphere. A corollary is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s membership in international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> imperils the national interest by threatening to drag the country
into needless conflicts overseas. Another corollary is that mere humanitarian
considerations should play little or no role in decisions about when to
intervene in faraway places. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> can't be the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> or its
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX>."

            All this sounds a lot
like what congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been saying since the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just a few months ago</TIMEX> neo-isolationist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were arguing that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> should stay out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> because we had no vital interests in
the peace and stability of southeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX> insisted
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war "should not have been fought [because] the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> [had]
never made a convincing case for putting the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> at risk in a
war where we have no vital national interest at stake." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
DeLay of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> fulminated on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is starting to resemble
a power-hungry imperialist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>," and he claimed that "the crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
poses no security threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> or our welfare."
Many of these same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> routinely declare that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> liberties and
"sovereignty" are being stolen by bow-tied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>, and even by foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>.

            Beyond situational sound bites, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
leadership share the same underlying theory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s foreign policy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberal internationalists</ENAMEX> believe that there is a moral dimension to our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in the international community. They also believe that international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, on balance, reduce future threats to our vital interests. This
often means anticipating future threats at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or two stages of remove and
recognizing that our values and our interests, though not identical, are not
wholly separate either. But many prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> prefer a policy of
avoiding international commitments and keeping a robust national defense in
store for any power that directly threatens our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> or our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
Genocide in another part of the world may be tragic. Regional instability on
some other continent may be something to keep an eye on. But unless our access
to strategic natural resources is threatened or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> actually start flying
our way, it's simply best not to get involved.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s book
accurately notes, this isolationist mentality has deep roots in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Taft</ENAMEX> tried to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1930s</TIMEX> and then sought to restrain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s overseas commitments in
the early <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Before the advent of modern weaponry, one of the
central tenets of the isolationist catechism was that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s status as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">continental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, flanked by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great oceans, gave us the luxury of doing
without all the treaties and alliances that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> had to bother with. At mid-century, when internationalism was at its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zenith</ENAMEX>, it was commonly thought that a mixture of technology and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX> status had made such thinking obsolete. But the impulse remains. It
is actually one of the key motivators behind the conservative obsession with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> missile defense--a technological fix that would conveniently replace
the oceans in allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to avoid a lot of pro-active foreign
involvement.

            The case for not acting until you have to was put most
vividly by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, in a
remark that also captures the hard-nosed attitude regarding humanitarian
concerns. During <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nickles</ENAMEX> said publicly that he had told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, "I don't think that we should begin bombing unless and until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
really begin a very significant massacre."

            Isolationist sentiments
don't prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Co.</ENAMEX> from saber-rattling; and given the belligerent
stands they often take toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, "petulant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unilateralists</ENAMEX>" might be a better term for them. Whether or not this attitude
is morally vacant and ultimately self-defeating, as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> charge, it's
hard to see how anyone who seriously holds these views, whatever you call them,
could really have had much to argue about with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Firsters</ENAMEX> in the late
1930s.

            Not all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> think this way. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> has been eloquently critical of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neo-isolationism</ENAMEX> and is
pushing something called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"National Greatness conservatism</ENAMEX>," a program of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">muscular American</ENAMEX> engagement around the globe. The mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> foreign
policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagleburgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scowcrofts</ENAMEX> and the like) still espouses
a trimmed-down, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">realist</ENAMEX>" variant of internationalism. And some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
increasing anti-interventionism can be ascribed to hysterical dislike of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, rather than to principled belief, and is likely to wane when
he is gone. But as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, the majority of the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who actually run for office and get elected--embraces a theory of
national interests that is very similar to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page-turner</ENAMEX>.

            The main difference between these congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is that none of them have been thoughtful enough
to apply their beliefs to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, or politically foolish enough to
mention it if they have.

         
      
   
