
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War of Attrition</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, declared his candidacy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. He
did everything by the book: highlighted favorable issues, exploited his
personal history, and portrayed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>' advantages as vices. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
also defied the political playbook by deprecating himself in a shrewd effort to
pre-empt criticism and turn up the heat on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>. Here's a breakdown of
his tactics.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. 
               Focus on foreign policy. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has
expertise in a particular terrain of issues. The advantage will go to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> on whose terrain the battle is fought. If the election is about
cultural concerns, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> has the advantage. If it's about economic
growth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> has the advantage. If it's about poverty, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> has the
advantage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, thanks to his military career, owns the terrain of foreign
policy. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can argue that poverty is the most morally pressing
concern, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can argue that growth is the most fundamental, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> can argue
that cultural decay is foremost in the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> can argue that
military issues are the most grave. "The most solemn responsibility given the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>," he declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. Of the time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> spent discussing issues, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> was devoted to the military and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s role in the world.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. 
               Emphasize biography. Since the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>,
it has been difficult to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to focus on foreign policy. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
can frame the election to his advantage in another way. He can bypass the
choice among issues by persuading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biographies</ENAMEX> instead of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX>. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> launches his campaign
with a glossy account of his upbringing and career, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s heroism in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> makes his story a far easier sell than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> exploits this advantage by filling his speeches with the word "service."
"Serving my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is an honor, indeed, the most honorable life an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
can lead," he said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. "I have passed from a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to an old one in the
service of my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. 
               Moralize the issues. Once he has convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior character</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> exports this advantage by describing every
subject in moral terms. In his announcement address, as in previous speeches,
he framed domestic issues in terms of "honor," "courage," "strength," "faith,"
"selfishness," "honesty," and "respect." He called trade protectionists
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowards</ENAMEX>," accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of swindling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>, and denounced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for breaking his promise to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. Two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, addressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Council of La Raza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, "Their support is my honor." Couching every issue in such language
maximizes the leverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s heroism.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Stigmatize 
               wealth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite pedigrees</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> make them vulnerable to a populist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>. Auditioning for this role,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> uses economic issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> uses Midwestern humility, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>'s ethic of obedience, teamwork, and self-sacrifice. "I don't
begin this mission with any sense of entitlement. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> doesn't owe me
anything," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> proclaimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. "I was born into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s service. ... I
want to return our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> back to whom it belongs--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. So that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> can believe once again that public service is a summons to duty and
not a lifetime of privilege."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. 
generated significant interest among independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and needs their help in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>'s open primary. Moreover, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has made
numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> in his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> by promoting legislation that would restrict
campaign contributions and require tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to pay for health care and
anti-smoking education. To convert this adversity into an advantage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
accuses his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of subverting the national interest for the sake of
"partisan ambitions." He scolds "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>" as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>" as
well as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>" as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>.

            
Conventional strategy dictates that having framed the election along these
lines, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> should emphasize his superiority in each respect. Instead, he
proclaims his own inadequacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s favorite words are shame, blame,
failure, and disgrace. In every account of his POW ordeal, he absurdly
concludes that he "failed" to withstand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>'s torture. In speeches, he
accepts "blame" for everything <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> does wrong, says he "failed" to prevent
it, and vows to "try harder" next time. He is "ashamed" of
everything--political <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>, unwise military procurements, high-dollar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electioneering</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whom I serve believe that the means by which I came
to office corrupt me," he declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months ago</TIMEX>. "And that shames me. That
shames me. Their contempt is a stain upon my honor, and I cannot live with it."
Pundits choked up at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s words. Since then, he has repeated them verbatim
on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least five</NUMEX> occasions. Shame has become his shtick.

            This
accomplishes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things. First, it pre-empts criticism from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. It's no
fun whipping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> when he's already whipping himself. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it establishes
a test no other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> can survive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> with a
biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>. When he calls himself weak and corrupt, nobody believes
him. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> were to call himself weak and corrupt, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> would replay
his confession as a campaign ad.

            To
beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has stripped character down to experience. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> speaks the
language of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and has plenty of foreign policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> on which to
rely. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> wants to take those assets out of the game, reducing the
comparison to what each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has done with his life. In military confrontations,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> warned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, "there comes a time when our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> can no
longer rely on briefing books and talking points ... when the sum total of
one's life becomes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> from which he or she makes the decisions that
determine the future of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is a lonely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a
dark <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> when the casualty reports come in. I am not afraid of the burden. I
know both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessing</ENAMEX> and the price of freedom." With that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> began a
refrain--"I am not afraid"--designed to shame his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> is cynicism. He plays it up because it endangers his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> more than it endangers him. The central line of his speech proclaimed
a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Patriotic Challenge</ENAMEX>. It is a challenge to each of us to join in the
fight against the pervasive cynicism that is debilitating our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>." It
corrodes every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>. "We who are currently privileged
to hold public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> have ourselves to blame," he laments in his stump speech.
"It is we who have squandered the public trust, we who have time and again
placed our personal or partisan interest before the national interest, earning
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s contempt with our poll-driven policies, our phony posturing, the
lies we call spin. ... We are all corrupted."

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> wants to portray as corrupted is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. "At a time when
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are growing increasingly cynical about public service and
increasingly disillusioned about their political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> charged
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, "I was disappointed to see my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' reaction to recent
comments and writings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> concerning our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s role in defeating
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX>. By continuing to appease <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, several of our candidates
appear to have put politics ahead of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s principles. ... Like Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, I want to see a united <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>. But no political campaign is
worth sacrificing our principles."

            So
much for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s "war against cynicism." He hates cynicism like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stalingrad</ENAMEX> hated the snow.

         
      
   
