
   
   
      
         
            Right Stuff Yogurt

            
               High
Culture
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Broadcasting Corp.</ENAMEX> reports that microbiologists at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of</ENAMEX>
Biomedical Problems in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> have developed a special yogurt made from
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria culled</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva</ENAMEX> and guts of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cosmonauts</ENAMEX>. Originally
developed to help space <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> maintain healthy levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intestines</ENAMEX>, the yogurt has become so popular with the cosmonauts that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institute</ENAMEX> is marketing it commercially, along with new varieties of cottage
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese products</ENAMEX> made with the same cultures. Who
knows what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> may be up to, but one <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">microbiologist</ENAMEX> has remarked that
there is no evidence that the out-of-this-world yogurt is really better than
any other yogurt product.

            
               Fungi
Man
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">five-year</ENAMEX> study by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> has produced a "family tree" of the
plant world that details the relations of the world's million species of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photosynthesizers</ENAMEX>. Findings include: There is not one plant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>;
a rare tropical flower is the closest living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s first
flowering <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>; and many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> appear to have evolved from a single
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>," whose close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> survive in some of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s more pristine lakes.
The study also confirmed the theory that fungi are more closely related to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> than to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>.

            
               Not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shroud of</ENAMEX>
Doubt?
            

            New
research
by botany <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avinoam Danin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>)
lends credence to the theory that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shroud of Turin</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>'s burial
cloth. Based on his analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollen grains</ENAMEX> and plant images (imprints of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant parts</ENAMEX>) taken from the shroud, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danin</ENAMEX> says the cloth
existed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the eighth century</TIMEX>, and maybe even before. He presented his findings
at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th International Botanical Congress</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>
and also offered evidence that the shroud originated in or near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> reports. Continuing to dispute the theory
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shroud</ENAMEX> wrapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>, who reiterate the results of their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> carbon dating of the cloth:
The cloth is no more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">600 years old</TIMEX>, they say. "It's not the burial cloth
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>," physics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Donahue</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Control</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Pundits</ENAMEX>
            

            Legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boon</ENAMEX> or bane? Both, say law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erwin</ENAMEX>
Levenson of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loyola Law School</ENAMEX>. TV and radio legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> both educate
and mislead the public about legal proceedings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chemerinsky</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>. The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> say the remedy for out-of-control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> is a set of
voluntary guidelines (outlined here ), which will "raise the professional quality of
behavior" of legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> and the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> that broadcast them. The
guidelines suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) comment only on subjects that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commentator</ENAMEX> knows first hand, by watching the trial or reading trial
transcripts; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) speak as neutral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> whenever possible, and disclose
potential conflicts of interest and biases; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) refrain from scoring trials
like sports events or predicting jury verdicts." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> nationwide voluntary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers</ENAMEX>--have adopted similar codes for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in response to the proposal, which has been outlined in recent law
review articles.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Full Monty</ENAMEX>
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State University</ENAMEX> law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> is returning to work after a year
off following a sexual harassment charge. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Sixty</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William McHugh</ENAMEX>
was placed on paid leave (read the letter
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy D'Alemberte</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McHugh</ENAMEX>) after dropping his shorts to
show a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> his hernia scar--a move that also exposed his genitals.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> filed a sexual harassment complaint against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McHugh</ENAMEX>, who admitted to
showing his hernia scar but insisted that the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty</ENAMEX> was accidental.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> , a panel of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>
concluded a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-month</TIMEX> investigation recently and found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McHugh</ENAMEX> had,
indeed, suffered from accidental exposure.

            
               They're
Here
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> has launched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent Gay Forum</ENAMEX> ,
which declares itself independent of left-right politics. Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">libertarian-</ENAMEX>minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institution</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Olson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato Institute</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boaz</ENAMEX>.

            
               Boomeranging
Diploma
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>
has revoked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> the diploma of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Yoo</ENAMEX> for his
role in the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Krueger</ENAMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> . As "pledge trainer" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phi Gamma Delta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoo</ENAMEX> supplied <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and whiskey
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krueger</ENAMEX> and other pledging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX>, instructing them in how to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gamma Delta</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>." After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krueger</ENAMEX> drank the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX>, he consumed
some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spiced rum</ENAMEX> provided by another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and fell into a coma, suffocating
on his own vomit. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krueger</ENAMEX>'s death, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> indicted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fraternity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> for manslaughter and hazing. (The case
was never tried because the fraternity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> had disbanded by the time of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arraignment</ENAMEX>; click here for a list of news items from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> on the
subject.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Discipline revoked Yoo</ENAMEX>'s diploma after reviewing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dean</ENAMEX>'s official investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krueger</ENAMEX>'s death. Although it isn't unusual for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> to suspend degrees for cheating or plagiarizing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoo</ENAMEX>'s punishment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> what may be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a degree has been revoked for a violation of
student disciplinary code.

            
               Information Wants
To Be Free?
            

            The
academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is protesting a new law that will require all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of
federal research grants to make their research data public through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Freedom of Information Act</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> fret that corporate
and political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> will use the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">FOIA</ENAMEX> powers to stifle research on
controversial subjects by bombarding them with information requests.
Confidentiality agreements will also suffer, they worry. The law would also
require the disclosure of what has traditionally been confidential--from
medical histories of research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>' e-mail addresses and
notebooks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has proposed a regulatory fix that would
limit the definition of what information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> must make public, as well
as the "reasonable fees" that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> can charge for obtaining
requested data. The budget office intends to publish its final regulations by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 30</TIMEX>.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doctor Is</ENAMEX>
Out
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> has ousted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome P. Kassirer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the society-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Journal of</ENAMEX>
Medicine , citing differences of opinion concerning "administrative and
publishing issues." More specifically, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kassirer</ENAMEX> opposed "branding"--using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>'s prestige to sell other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMS</ENAMEX>-owned products and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HealthNews</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart Watch</ENAMEX> , whose quality and accuracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> do
not control. Additionally, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> has been striking
deals, such as a partnership with barnesandnoble.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and upgrading its online
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>--activities that strike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> as too commercial.
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Angell</ENAMEX> assumed the interim <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
position on the condition that the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> not use the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England Journal</ENAMEX>" in the title of new society-run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>.

            
               Egghead
Updates
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, "" reported
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> boycott at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obafemi Awolow University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>'
demand--that a top university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> be fired for failing to confront
issues of campus cult violence--has been embraced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa News</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> to
eradicate the cults and established a commission to investigate cult activity
and the inaction by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Autonomous</ENAMEX>
University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> strike is stretching into its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifth month</TIMEX>. The protest over
increased tuition--from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 cents</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $150</NUMEX>--has evolved into a fight
for the future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has consented to a
revocation of the tuition hike, reports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX>, but now the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> are insisting on a more active say in how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX> is run. The strike may be losing steam, though: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> who want to
return to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> are holding demonstrations against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strikers</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
