
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remembering Herb</ENAMEX>

            "A reviewer once said that I was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the
'Don't Know' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of economics," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX> in his last book,
What I Think . And then he added, "I don't know that I am the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of
it, but I surely avow membership in it more openly than most other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
do."

            That mixture of wry humor and openness to further
argument endeared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX> to the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> who mourn his death
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 83</TIMEX>. His embrace of don't-knowism was real. ("I have always
been mystified by international finance since I took a course in it at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62 years ago</TIMEX>," he wrote in a 
                  Slate
                ""
exchange <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>--almost, but not quite, embarrassing me out of a
disquisition on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> and the sad state of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economies.) But his reticence was not grounded in false
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modesty</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX> well knew how keen was his intellect and how sharp his wit. And,
especially in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier years</TIMEX>, he did not suffer fools gladly--at least if
they were stubborn in their foolishness. "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--even those who read
editorial and op-ed pages--do not want to encounter opposing views," he mourned
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What I Think</ENAMEX> . "They want to be massaged not informed."

            But mind-massages were
not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX>. He recognized, perhaps better than most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, how complicated and fast-changing the world can be. And so he kept
his mind open to new facts, new ideas whether about , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">,</ENAMEX> , or ("what produces
them for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> has very little to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>").

            Unfortunately one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX>'s all-time great pieces of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parody</ENAMEX>, written for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , on whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of</ENAMEX>
Contributors he sat for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two decades</TIMEX>, is not available on the Web. But
anyone with access to back copies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> should consult "The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marriage Act of 1977</ENAMEX>," in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, having expressed its ranked
preference for marriages made in heaven, arranged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, arranged
through the personals column of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, or arranged by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, undertakes to provide "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> of last resort."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX> was as ready for new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adventures</ENAMEX> as he was for new ideas. How many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX>'s distinction,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accomplishments</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> would, for example, undertake to write for an online
magazine startup? Yet, even before 
                  Slate
                moved from Kinsleyspace
to cyberspace, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX> signed up to moderate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s "." And how fewer
still would be those with the daring (and the sense of humor) to top off that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">taxing</ENAMEX> experiment with an even bolder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>: "." 
                  Slate
               's
original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the public on matters of morals, manners, and
macroeconomics was, in fact, none other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX> did it anonymously, of course (though a sharp-eyed reader
might have guessed from the drawing of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>" that accompanied the column
if they hadn't already been tipped off by the tone). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX> enjoyed it so
much--and he did it with such flair--that I don't think he would mind my
revealing the secret.

            And he did enjoy it. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> cure for unrequited love,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> reminded a lovelorn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, "is requited love. There are other cures
also, such as devotion to the study of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX> language." To a reader
worried about being bad at small talk, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence counseled</ENAMEX>, "You are making too
much of this. What everyone wants in a conversationalist is not a good talker
but a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX>. You could be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX> and no one would go home from a
party saying, 'Gee, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> was witty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>.' Many would go home saying, 'Gee,
I was witty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>.' " In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of automatic door unlockers, should a man
still walk around a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to unlock the door for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he is escorting?
Absolutely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> replied, noting the opportunity thus afforded for "sweetly
kissing her on the cheek. Modern gadgets will not do all that and real men
don't want them to. Something has to be left for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to do." As for the shy
advice-seeker worried "about the possibility of having to kiss a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> replied, "If that situation arises, you will have no problem. Perhaps
you will 'have' to kiss her because she has kissed you. In that case your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spontaneous</ENAMEX>, unpondered reaction will be to kiss her back. Your problem will
not be hesitancy about kissing but addiction to it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX> was deeply saddened by the death of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
Mildred, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>. He wrote about his loss only indirectly, in what was
surely the most popular of his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Seems to Me ...</ENAMEX>" columns in

                  Slate
               , "." Why, he asked, as he watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>
walking up the hill to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center</ENAMEX> for a performance, "is this basic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> so valuable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose hand or arm she is holding?" And in his
exploration of the question, it was clear that he had in mind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> with
whom he had "walked up that hill to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center</ENAMEX> many times."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX> once set down a list of "," sayings that you
won't find in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX>'s but that "resonated" with him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
ranged from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan Kundera</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dante</ENAMEX> to , whom he served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Economic Advisers</ENAMEX>. He also included an aphorism of his own: "If
something cannot go on forever, it will stop." Sadly, that was true of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX>
himself.

         
      
   
