
   
   
      
         
             Touched by a Tabloid

            Maybe it's a touch of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">premillennial fever</ENAMEX> or all
that post-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> soul-searching, but for whatever reason, the tabloids turn
their collective eyes toward heaven <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> and find God. Even when the Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX> himself is not explicitly mentioned--and he's mentioned plenty--the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> of tabloid offerings brims with so many transcendent crises
(life-threatening illnesses, brushes with sudden death, ruminations on
mortality, profligate lives steered straight and narrow) that it feels like one
long episode of Touched by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angel</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , for starters, details not one but
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> exorcisms underway <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> performed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke Ramsey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
of murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX>, to "rid [him] of any remaining
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX>" from the murder; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M√∂tley Cr√</ENAMEX>ºe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Lee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exorcism</ENAMEX> has supposedly unearthed the "sweet little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>" inside him, spurring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ex-wife Pamela Anderson</ENAMEX> to run back into his tattooed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>--and, apparently,
into his bed. Pregnancy rumors abound, but only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> has a damning
photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s abdomen, highlighted with a red <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> to point out its
eyebrow-raising convexity.

            Talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX> has also had spiritual matters on her mind of late. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> as
a lapsed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX> recently "took God
back into her heart." And, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , she is so terrified of
dying young that she has entered into a pact with perhaps the world's most
famous lapsed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>, to make sure her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will be cared for.
Hoping to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grim Reaper</ENAMEX> at bay, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX> is also said to be assiduously
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dieting</ENAMEX> and exercising.

            We heartily recommend that she do whatever it takes to stay
in the here and now, if only to avoid being included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scandals of the Century</ENAMEX>" double issue, which devotes an entire section ("The
Quick and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead"</ENAMEX>) to celebs cut down too soon. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> River
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX> was apparently quite keen on the idea of checking out early. "I don't
want to die from old age in a nursing home," he reportedly told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. "I'll
be the best-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the morgue." It was surely in the interest of
proving the accuracy of this prediction, therefore, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>
chose to run a post-mortem photo of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>. And while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> finds it
inappropriate to quibble over the attractiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX>, we will bestow
upon <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> our special nod for clarity in the face of eternity; it was he who
reportedly shouted, "I'm gonna die, dude!" on his way out.

            On the brighter side,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> have saved--or tried to save--so many lives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> that we
wonder if anyone's getting any real work done in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. They've
revived an ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Edwards</ENAMEX>), spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700</NUMEX> nursing a
rabbit back to health (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gretchen Mol</ENAMEX>), spearheaded efforts to free an
inhumanely <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">caged gorilla</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Day</ENAMEX>), and aided <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> that suffer
from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Floppy Trunk Syndrome</ENAMEX>," a malady that keeps the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> from eating
properly (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alicia Silverstone</ENAMEX>).

            Business has been no less brisk for human rescues. The
Enquirer details lifesaving efforts by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX>, among others. The re-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christianized Rosie O'Donnell</ENAMEX> is reported
to have made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> daring rescues aboard her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jet Ski</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> .
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>, reportedly saved her own life by
calling a taxi in the middle of a mild heart attack. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>
suggests that "lonely" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX> was forced to make the call because she's been
"abandoned" by her ex-husband. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , on the other hand, has the
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> "rush[ing] right over" to be with his ex and thanking--you guessed
it--God that she was all right.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographer</ENAMEX>'s prayers must have been answered when he followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Shields</ENAMEX>
and new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Henchy</ENAMEX> on what was supposed to be a simple exercise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outing</ENAMEX>. The "lensman was expecting to snap some fun photos of the couple
enjoying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring day</TIMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> explains breezily, as if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographer</ENAMEX> had actually been invited along for the trip. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> is on
emotional thin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>, having recently filed for divorce from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and
having lost a fellow Suddenly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> cast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> to suicide; and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographer</ENAMEX> was "stunned" when she suddenly began "sobbing uncontrollably."
Luckily for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, the quick-thinking paparazzo was not
so stunned that he couldn't get off several frames of the disconsolate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> quickly pulled herself together, however, and she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henchy headed for</ENAMEX>
a "trendy health-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>" to buy organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>.

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> failed to capture the
pair choosing hydroponic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX>, we feel fairly confident that they did not
buy any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>' breakdown may be in part
attributable to the fact that the "stressed-out" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> is battling a
"crippling disease": temporal mandibular joint <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>, or TMJ, which sounds a
bit like the aforementioned floppy trunk syndrome. With all due respect to TMJ
sufferers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> can't help but note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>' symptoms, while no
doubt troublesome, seem to fall just a bit short of "crippling." "It got to the
point where I just couldn't open my mouth wide enough to eat an apple," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>
is quoted as saying. "I had to get someone to 'start' my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> for me." Fear
not, apple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eaters</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> very thoughtfully reprints the address of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TMJ Association</ENAMEX>'s Web site.

            And finally, the tabloids try to account for the end
of soap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Lucci</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>-time losing streak at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daytime Emmys</TIMEX>. (The
Star asserts that she'll now quit <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All My Children</ENAMEX> for her own
talk show. But there's no word on whether she'll consider the path taken by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soap</ENAMEX>-stars-turned-preachers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Hayes</ENAMEX>, who according to the
Star have "traded in steamy scenes between the sheets" to "devote their
lives to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> offers this rather down-to-earth
explanation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucci's</ENAMEX> win, straight from an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emmy judge: She snagged the trophy</ENAMEX>
because she finally stopped submitting tapes with "overly dramatic"
performances and went with something subtler instead. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Less</ENAMEX>, apparently, is
more, even for a soap opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who's been married to virtually everyone
on the show and once impersonated a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , however, looks to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fates</ENAMEX> to explain her win, calling in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> numerologists to mull over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucci</ENAMEX>'s
birth date, the cosmic significance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1999</TIMEX>, and the importance of the
number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> in her life. Should we even feign surprise that she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> when she
"survived a devastating car accident"? Or that it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 years ago</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucci</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">son Andreas</ENAMEX> made it through a "touch-and-go" health scare? As far as the
numerologists are concerned, the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> shouldn't even have bothered to
show up on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emmy night</ENAMEX>. Numbers, shnumbers. Keeping Tabs is certain that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucci</ENAMEX>'s
win was, quite simply, the will of God.

         
      
   
