
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>? It's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fault</ENAMEX>

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s "massive,
wasteful consumption of a disproportionate share of the planet's resources." An
editorial opined, "Brutal though it may be to say so, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX> is a
necessary warning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which contributes more than any other to
global warming." In an op-ed article, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> asked why disasters in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> receive so much more
attention in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press than much worse disasters elsewhere. Answer:
"The truth is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>--and not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, who at least admit to
it--positively enjoy transatlantic misfortune. Perhaps, in an era of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
global hegemony, we need to have it confirmed to us that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> are
gun-obsessed crazies or that their lovingly constructed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> beachfront
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condos</ENAMEX> can be smashed to smithereens within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> by some arbitrary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of
nature."

            The
Independent
said that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> massacre in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, "may in some respects
have done the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> a favour." It said, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he issue of gun control will certainly have a central
place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s presidential election campaign." But in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s gun control is about as lax as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's</ENAMEX>, at least
on the non-domestic front." He said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> sold <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
whose human rights records fail to receive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX> seal of
approval and that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> foreign policy has long been a confection of
self-interest spiced by opportunism and cling-wrapped in sanctimony."

            In an
editorial about an antitrust challenge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> genetically modified food
industry by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> alleging misuse of intellectual
property to restrict competition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> took the side of the underdogs. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]wo
factors make this a special case," it said in an editorial.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> is the immense speed of scientific advance in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> food technology, and in
bio-engineering generally. The other is that control of several important
markets for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> products is already highly concentrated, and that industry
consolidation appears set to accelerate through acquisitions." On its front
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are considering trying to break <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> if they win their
antitrust case against it. "A break-up of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> would be highly
controversial and politically contentious, especially in the run-up to a
presidential election," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            A big
story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was the release of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MI5</TIMEX> intelligence files
showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.G. Wodehouse</ENAMEX> received <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> payments from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> during a
crucial period of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and could have faced treason charges if he had
returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the postwar years</TIMEX>. The files,
showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wodehouse</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> payments through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between May</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1944</TIMEX>, challenged previous historical judgments
that he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> lacking in worldly wisdom but in no sense a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Herald</ENAMEX> , noting that the commitment of "a mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>" to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> is already seriously straining the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s defense budget, called
for a large increase in its defense capability. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> message coming loud and
clear out of the recent flurry of diplomatic activity over a peacekeeping force
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> is that, as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is concerned, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> is
on its own in dealing with such regional problems," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an
editorial. While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> eventually agreed to offer "token" logistical
support to the peacekeeping effort, it "proceeded reluctantly, refusing to take
the initiative from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canberra</ENAMEX> or even lend it the kind of significant military
support it was requesting."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX>-strong, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> was expected
to arrive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at the latest. In an editorial, it once again placed all the blame for the
humanitarian catastrophe on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. "No matter how they
explain it, or what excuses they come up with for the situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>,
the bottom line is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> is responsible for everything that has happened
there," it said. "We have lost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, and nothing we do now can deny East
Timorese their well-deserved independence. ... By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, we hope our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have
truly learned their lessons well: that as a self-respecting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and member
of the international community, we must respect universal humanitarian values
and live up to our responsibilities."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> defended the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> against charges that they are
biased against the right because they rushed to investigate corruption
allegations against former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. "If the police
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> does not rush to investigate suspicions against a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>,
it will not have the moral justification to act against ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>,"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. In an interview
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> , former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> MI5 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shayler</ENAMEX> said that as
recently as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> expelled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for
operating on its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> without permission. Shayler, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> is seeking
to extradite from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> for breaches of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Official Secrets Act</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
repeatedly turned down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> requests to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.
Even so, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossad</ENAMEX> secretly sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent operators</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to gather information
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>" and "MI5 exposed these undeclared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and quietly
instructed them to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Ministry</ENAMEX> described
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shayler</ENAMEX>'s claims as "completely baseless."

            
Writing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roj Medvedev</ENAMEX> said that the wave of terrorist
bombings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is now shaking the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> ruling class to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>.
"With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> voice, all the leading political figures are asking [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to resign," he wrote. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> are asking it." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medvedev</ENAMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is
also being rocked by a flood of compromising documents to the press, among them
a recording of a conspiratorial telephone conversation between the media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> guerrilla <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shamil Bassayev</ENAMEX>. "The
conviction is growing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s collective consciousness that its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> ready to do anything, however bad," he
wrote. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medvedev</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> has lost control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and that "if there
is still logic in this world, he should resign as soon as possible, before
things go too far." He added that he believed he would do so.

         
      
   
