
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>, I Hardly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knew Ye</ENAMEX>

            There will be a lot written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming days</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who didn't really know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>. Those of us who had the
pleasure of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, if only for a few, seemingly fleeting moments, will
have to struggle on to keep his true memory alive.

            I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX> at a fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for his
magazine in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">swank Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. It was the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> he
could have lived in, if he'd wanted to, but he chose to make his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the
gritty industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TriBeCa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> was wearing one of his trademark
tailored suits. I made eye contact and smiled. I thought I saw the flicker of a
responsive grin cross his face. He wheeled around, turning his back to me, and
started to talk to someone on the other side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, a malnourished blond
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had been trying to get his attention. I instantly recognized this as
something his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>, must have taught him. Who else could have
disciplined him to show such natural grace and reticence, coupled with the
noblesse oblige to talk to those you might otherwise prefer to
avoid?

            After that, our
relationship stabilized. We dined frequently in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, albeit in different
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX> and with different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. We went to concerts and movies. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">encounter</ENAMEX> was especially evocative, I think, of the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> he was. One
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollerblading</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> when I spotted him. He was
blading <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few yards</NUMEX> away, lean and handsome as ever, wearing the tank top and
the backward baseball cap I'd come to know. I had just started to skate toward
him when he saw me. Almost immediately, he sped ahead. With his long powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strides</ENAMEX>, in no time at all he was a football <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> in front of me. He looked
back, and I recognized that old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy competitiveness</ENAMEX>, the playful funhouse
spirit epitomized by the famous impromptu touch football games at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hyannis Port</ENAMEX>.
He was challenging me to catch him! I tried, panting and sweating. His
challenge called forth resources in me I didn't know I had--he had that effect
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>! But for an unfortunate encounter with an incompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sorbet peddler</ENAMEX>,
I would have caught him and shared a good laugh.

            I had a chance to make light of the incident when I next
saw him, near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of his beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> . I was in the elevator,
heading to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> floor to pick up a kill fee for a piece I'd
submitted to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hachette</ENAMEX> publication. At the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14 th</NUMEX> floor, the
door opened, and there he was. It was just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> to use the common elevator
instead of, say, chartering a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> to pluck him off the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
floor and deposit him on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> , or buying a rocket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>, or
rappelling up the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, all of which, I knew, he could have
chosen. Instead, he was here, in an elevator, with me.

            I hadn't seen him in such
a long time, I immediately burst out my greetings, perhaps a bit too
enthusiastically. I added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few</NUMEX> suggestions for the future editorial direction
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> . He took it all in stride, pausing for a moment, obviously
wondering whether to show emotion. "Oh ... uh ... hi," he stammered. I found
this humility, this forced gracelessness--when of course some modicum of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suavity</ENAMEX> would have come so easily to him--breathtakingly charming. I could tell
he wanted to call me by my name but was afraid that would hurt the feelings of
the others in the elevator who perhaps didn't know him so well. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> often had
this sense when talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, this sense of reserve, of intimacies
withheld.

            Then he did something that showed a side of him I'd only
heard about. He looked at me, squarely, directly--the effect was powerful--and
asked: "Who are you? Do I know you?" I was stunned by the philosophical
depth of his questions. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few seconds</TIMEX>, he had penetrated to the core of my
identity, indeed to the very question of identity. Who was I? Was it ever
possible to really know another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>? I've pondered these issues ever
since. And to think there are some who say his good looks made up for a lack of
intellectual heft!

            And so it went for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. I would run into him. He might say something insightful, or boisterous,
like the time he jokingly yelled, "Are you insane?" when I came up behind him
as he was using an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> machine. But despite the warmth of our friendship, there
were clear limits, boundaries to our relationship that we both recognized. He
never took me sailing with him, for example, or included me in his intimate
family outings. Ultimately, there was no getting around the fact that I was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, his natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>.

            There came a time when an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, to whom I'd casually
mentioned my acquaintance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, asked me to write a short piece about one
of his mother's book projects. I agonized about it for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several long minutes</TIMEX>.
Was I only getting this assignment because of my connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>? Would I
be guilty of cashing in on our relationship? Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> feel I was betraying
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>, given his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedyesque</ENAMEX> obsession with privacy? And, perhaps most
difficult, could I see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> honestly, on her own terms, and not just as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>? Ultimately, I decided to write the piece, and a few details
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and me found their way into the text.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> must have taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>--though at what I can't
imagine--because our friendship foundered after that. We no longer spoke. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gulf</ENAMEX> grew between us. It was a deeply saddening time.

            His too-early departure, therefore, is especially
tragic to me because our relationship can now never be healed. But I will
always deeply treasure the mementos of our friendship he left with me. There is
the rejection letter I received from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> , which he was too modest to
put his own name on. (He must have kept the original, however, because what I
have looks like a duplicate.) And I still have a copy of the restraining order
he obtained when I attempted, in an excess of neighborly zeal, to climb the
fire escape in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX> next to his in that gritty industrial area he called
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Characteristically, he didn't sign it, or even add <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his famous
cheery little messages. Such was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. I will miss him.

         
      
   
