
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>

            Even if you haven't cracked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> , you know
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> and his semi-fictional namesake. And you probably haven't
avoided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>: the tireless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> who dogs your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX>-surfing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strangely</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> on the gab-show circuit begs to
differ with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writer</ENAMEX>. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writer</ENAMEX> can be cleareyed about
his subject, calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> "banal" and an "airhead," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund the Promoter</ENAMEX> fawns
like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reaganaut</ENAMEX>, constantly trumpeting a "great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX> I
claims he only made up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund III</ENAMEX> weaves tales that are flatly
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">contradicted in Edmund I's</ENAMEX> book.

            A striking instance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inter-Edmund</ENAMEX> strife comes from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Live</ENAMEX> . There,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund the Promoter</ENAMEX> told how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> almost joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>.
And why didn't he? "The party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> heard about his desire to join, realized
at once that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was not doctrinary material. He was too open and too
honest, and he couldn't be trusted to keep party secrets. So they asked him
politely to stay the hell away."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writer</ENAMEX> tells a very different version of the
same story in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> . He quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Fast</ENAMEX>, a party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwart</ENAMEX>.
According to Fast, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> tried to join, "the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> asked
around, and word came back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flake</ENAMEX> ... [who] couldn't be trusted
with any political opinion for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than 20 minutes</TIMEX>."

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX> I writes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> was too stupid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>, and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund III</ENAMEX> improves
the story for television by making him too virtuous. (Defending the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contradiction, Morris</ENAMEX> says, "flaky means he couldn't be trusted with secrets.")
Once you start making stuff up, apparently, it's harder to stop than you think.
But which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX> is correct? Maybe neither. It turns out that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writer</ENAMEX> may have been embroidering more than his own role.

            D utch devotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pages to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CP</ENAMEX> episode.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly half</NUMEX> of this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-page stretch consists of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' conversation with
Fast, presented as screenplay dialogue. It is a dramatic scene with Fast
dishing a shocking piece of information that the obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> has never
heard before. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> pours on the color--they are in a reception at the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Public Library</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astor Hall</ENAMEX>, they shake hands, they are wearing tuxedos,
the buzz of billionaires is in the background, and so on.

            But these are all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
herrings, distracting from the fact that the scene is a silly vehicle for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploring Reagan</ENAMEX>'s flirtation with communism. Fast never claims to have met
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> or to have had firsthand knowledge of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s application to join the
party. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astor Hall</ENAMEX> reception was the only time he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> spoke, Fast
says. Fast now admits to recycling gossip, "This was a story told to me at a
dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. I can't remember who told it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historian Ronald Radosh</ENAMEX> notes that
Fast has a reputation for "inconsistently remembering his time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>,"
including contradictory recitations in his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> memoirs. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX>, having
stumbled upon a juicy story, never seriously questions Fast's reliability or
pokes logical holes in his account.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> does recount his attempts to nail down Fast's story.
He describes conversations with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> acquaintances, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Albert</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> does not say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> was a party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, but he
strongly hints that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> operated on "behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPUSA</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> confirmed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> did indeed discuss joining the party
and was ultimately dissuaded. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> writes that when he tried to question
the aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> further, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> caged up as expected."

            Oddly, when I called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>, he was anything but cagey. In fact he couldn't stop screaming into the
phone: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, but he was stupid. He didn't have a clue about
any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> business. He talked about being a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>. We all did. But he
never did anything about it. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">One night</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> sat down and told him the party
was a load of crap." But was this just a ploy? Were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
secretly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>, conspiring to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>? "No." Did
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> this question? "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>] is an asshole," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>. And
even Fast can't confirm what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> implies, "I have no idea whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie</ENAMEX> was
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or not."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Albert</ENAMEX> may be lying, of course, and corroborating the
Fast version of events may not be possible. But there are gaping holes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' reporting that can easily be filled with a few phone calls. For
instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fast</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> dealt with a local party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, "a
well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>." Fast wouldn't identify
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> doesn't mention any attempt to track him down.
But only one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> fits this bill: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Howard Lawson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reds</ENAMEX> who reemerged to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> in the late
'40s. And Fast confirmed to me that he was talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX>.

            Or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> could have contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Healey</ENAMEX>, who
was the chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern California Communist Party</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Healey</ENAMEX> told me: "This has to be apocrypha. It's nonsense. Of course, we never
rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for being too flaky. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> had been rejected, I would
have definitely heard about it." And in an interview, the authorized biographer
concedes that he didn't investigate thoroughly: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger</ENAMEX> once told
me that he had dirt on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> buried in his filing system. But I never went
after him."

            Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> episode is one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' most oft-mentioned scoops, he didn't even have it first. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Fast</ENAMEX>
told essentially the same story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. (And probably has been dining out on it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>.) Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> did
amazingly little to try to nail it down. But who has time to dig for facts when
you've got to make up not one but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different fantasies?

         
      
   
