
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">317</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;She's Still Got It&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "We are quite the
best <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. In my lifetime all the problems have come from mainland
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> have come from the English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of
the world," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> in her first speech at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX>
conference since stepping down as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Thatcher</ENAMEX> was
inspired to speak by a particular cause. What?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 316</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don't Do It, Deacon Don</ENAMEX>!":
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deacon Don Thomas</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of God</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairbanks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, defends what he does to reach the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>: "Yeah, we want to compel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to come to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, but at the same
time we don't want to intrude on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. I think there's a big difference."
What does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deacon Don</ENAMEX> do? 
                        ( Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassenberg</ENAMEX>. )
                     
                  
               
            

            "Nude
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">choir</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>,
that explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'You May Already Have Been Saved</ENAMEX>!' letter that came
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
think keeping your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> is an excellent method of giving the
impression of nonintrusiveness."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael S. Gilman</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kids</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. Isn't the threat of eternal damnation compelling
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">enough?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Cass</ENAMEX>
            

            "You
know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fairbanks</ENAMEX> is such a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, he probably wouldn't have to do much
besides hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> dying for your sins and shooting a
good game of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-ball, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> would just follow him. It would be something
to do, and once they got bored with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>'s sermons, they could eat
him."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Kate Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            A method adopted by
demure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> who don't wish to intrude is to ask permission. When you buy
something online or fill out a warranty card, there's often a little box at the
bottom: Check here if you wish to receive announcements about our new products
and services that may delight and amuse you. Some go further and involve other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: Check here if you'd like us to sell your name to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> who will
send you information about utterly unrelated products that will frighten and
confuse you. They never ask you to volunteer for the really good stuff: Check
here if you'd like more information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Pospisil</ENAMEX>, say. I believe they
use a similar form for undergraduates having sex at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX>. Check here if
you'd like me to unbutton your blouse. Check here if you'd like me to touch you
there. Check here if you'd like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> to save you from burning in hell for what
we just did so pleasantly to one another. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deacon Don</ENAMEX>, help!

            

               Technochrist 
               Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deacon Don</ENAMEX> used "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice Blast</ENAMEX>," a technology for
sending phone messages simultaneously to an unlimited number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, reports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley Foss</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>.

            And it's not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deacon Don</ENAMEX>. Ball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> are
calling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of season ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are contacting everybody's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and disaster-prone regions are planning emergency warning systems. But
some consider blast voice mail a nuisance and, when unsolicited, an invasion of
privacy.

            "It's just, like, phone spam," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Catlett</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junkbusters Corp.</ENAMEX> A former database <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, Catlett
started <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junkbusters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> defend themselves against
telephone marketing.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Clark</ENAMEX> left messages on the
answering machines of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> to promote the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Music Awards on ABC</ENAMEX>, a front-page story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
described his pitch as a "telephonic assault" on the public's ear. "The
geriatric old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> should be dragged out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> and trampled by wild
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> did not add.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telephone Consumers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Protection Act of 1991</ENAMEX> prohibits automated ads to residential phones without
prior consent, but allows blast voice mail for institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and emergency services, and compelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hallelujah</ENAMEX>.

            
               Though

               Dead, He's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Still Got It Too Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            The release of the
latest batch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> tapes shows that death has not softened the old
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Semite</ENAMEX>, except in the sense that he's dead. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX>:

            

               On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Frankel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "Don't give them anything.
And because of that damned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jew Frankel</ENAMEX> all the time--he's bad you know. Don't
give him anything."

               On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Ellsberg</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, I hope to God he's not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> is
he?"

               On <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> communism: "The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> conspiracy
were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>. Many felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> was. He could have been a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, but
he was not by religion. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. Every other one was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>. And
it raised hell with us."

               On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon Papers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray Gurfein</ENAMEX>: "He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, a liberal. But I
think tough. I think tough. But he may be sucking up to the liberal left. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, you just can't tell what happens to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>."

            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon Library</ENAMEX> issued
a statement saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>. Then we all had a good
laugh and went out to dinner.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me-Wonderful-Me Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> were invited to submit actual examples
of authorial self-praise as smug and fatuous as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Adler</ENAMEX>'s: "My novels ...
explore the mysteries behind love and hate, the darkly amusing, deeply
disturbing and ultimately unanswerable questions that they inspire."

            Read more of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adler</ENAMEX>'s insights into the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Adler</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">warrenadler</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> page appears to
be printed on parchment, so you know he's a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.

            "
'When I cleverly coined the phrase "nattering nabobs of negativism." ' (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
Safire, every <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> column.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'It</ENAMEX>'s a weird book. It doesn't move the way normal books do. It's got a whole
bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. I think it makes at least an in-good-faith attempt to be
fun and riveting enough on a page-by-page level so I don't feel like I'm
hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> with a mallet, you know, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, here's this really hard
impossibly smart thing. Fuck you. See if you can read it." I know books like
that and they piss me off. I loved the book, but I think anyone with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> pages
of footnotes in a book of fiction is in fact saying "Fuck you, see if you can
read it." ' (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Foster Wallace</ENAMEX>, about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinite Jest</ENAMEX> [weighing in at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,088</NUMEX> pages, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> odd pages of footnotes] in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> .)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>
            

            "
'What I try to write about are the darkest things in the soul, the mortal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dreads</ENAMEX>. I try to go into those places in me that contain the cauldrons. I want
to dip up the fire, and I want to put it on paper. The closer I get to the
burning core of my being, the things which are most painful to me, the better
is my work.' ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlan Ellison</ENAMEX>.)"-- CK
            

            " 'You
see what happens with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Faulkner</ENAMEX> is that as long as I am alive he has to
drink to feel good about having the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX>. He does not realize that I
have no respect for that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> and was truly happy for him when he got
it.' (Not, strictly speaking, self-praise, but it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX> in
Selected Letters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917-1961</TIMEX> , edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Baker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">768-769</ENAMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Dickinson</ENAMEX>
            

            " 'My
fault is honesty.' (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>. Not, strictly speaking, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. But
killing himself with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> might accelerate his reincarnation as a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">38DD</NUMEX> bra, so
better to let him swim along in his pool of piety.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Barnicle</ENAMEX>
            

            "
'Someday someone's going to dissect my whole life through my work. When I
finished writing (the opening episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasteland</ENAMEX> ) I cried because I so
felt for the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. ... It's fun, but it's really sad.' (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson in Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> .)"-- CK
            

            "
'What I mean to do, by evoking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose lives and work I have admired,
is not to dictate the terms of virtue but to invite other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to reciprocal
thoughts about what seems to them to be inescapably good or important, and how
to put that into a life.' (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jedediah Purdy</ENAMEX> on himself, in a recent

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Dialogue</ENAMEX>.')"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Stock</ENAMEX>
            

            " 'One
of the smartest things I did was call a management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>. She gave me this
advice: Stop worrying about yourself and concentrate on how to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX>
a good place for all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to work. That was a transforming moment for
me. ... At the center of everything I did at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX> was honoring creative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.' (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geraldine Laybourne</ENAMEX>, not strictly speaking a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, writing in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> with the help of some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> just to turn out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>
words. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laybourne</ENAMEX> now honors creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxygen Media</ENAMEX> by making sure that
they don't have health insurance so their creativity isn't stifled by taking
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>. And no pensions means no complacency. Refusing to
become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers Guild</ENAMEX> signatory, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxygen Media</ENAMEX> uses only scab <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. No
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>. No benefits, but plenty of honor.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>.
            

            " 'The
reason <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Roses</ENAMEX> has become a classic is that it deals with these
unanswerable questions. And I have a feeling the moviemakers caught that. They
got it from my book like a virus. ... That's what makes it enduring. It deals
with the eternal mysteries of life. Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> love? Why do they hate? How
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> attracted to one another? What breaks up relationships? From my
point of view as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> it came out of my subconscious, but it has found
its way into popular culture.' (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Adler</ENAMEX>)"-- CK
            

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Caribou dung</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
