
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judd</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jeopardy</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Jakob
               
               
                  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liar</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures</ENAMEX>
Entertainment). As expected, no one has much positive to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> drama, but the bad reviews are surprisingly mild. Yes, it's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">awkwardly</ENAMEX> executed and tedious," but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> "does some of his best and most
honest work here"(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> ) as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
brings hope to his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> ghetto by pretending to have good news from a hidden
radio. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' performance is remarkably restrained
and, if nothing else, acknowledge his good intentions: "This is the kind of
bogus production only completely sincere but misguided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> can come up
with" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to see clips from the film.)

            

               
                  Double
               
               
                  Jeopardy
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>).
Plot holes abound in this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fugitive</ENAMEX> knockoff about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashley Judd</ENAMEX>)
framed by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> for his (faked) murder. Once she gets out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, she
can theoretically murder him with impunity, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> protects
her from being tried twice for the same crime. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are harsh on the film's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premise</ENAMEX> and execution, but a few find bright spots in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Judd</ENAMEX>'s beauty and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee Jones</ENAMEX>' gritty turn as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parole officer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> make this "medium-grade
pulp" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ) worth watching.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Visit the Ashley Judd Shrine</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Mumford
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). This "slight, amusing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doodle</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ) directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Kasdan</ENAMEX> is a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Capra</ENAMEX>-style social fable for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). The story follows a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> of questionable credentials
who moves into a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and begins helping out the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">reviewers</ENAMEX> call it quietly affecting, others could barely keep their eyes open.
Many are dismayed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasdan</ENAMEX>'s inability to match his acclaimed early efforts
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Body Heat , The Big Chill</ENAMEX> , and The Accidental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist</ENAMEX> . (Visit the official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> to see stills and clips from the
film.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Secret History</ENAMEX> of Pius
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XII</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cornwell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>). Tempers flare over the validity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornwell</ENAMEX>'s claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Pius</ENAMEX> XII failed to speak out
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> genocide because he was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find the
entire book flawed: "a classic example of what happens when an ill-equipped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> assumes the airs of sober scholarship. ... Errors of fact and
ignorance of context appear on almost every page. ... This is bogus
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholarship</ENAMEX>, filled with nonexistent secrets, aimed to shock" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Others take his claims to heart: "By combining the
painstaking research of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> with his own new documentation,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX> "makes a case ... that is very hard to refute" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V.R. Berghahn</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> writes in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that "nothing I've read suggests he's concocted
anything." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read a point-by-point refutation of this book by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Peter Gumpel</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  An
               
               
                  Affair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investigation</ENAMEX>,
Impeachment, and Trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard A. Posner</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University Press</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>, the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seventh Circuit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX>, is generally hailed for his clearheaded analysis of the legal
aspects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal. It is "by far the most legally sophisticated
account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal" and "brings scholarly rigor to a saga
so far dominated by journalistic accounts" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> ). In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>'s pragmatism
the perfect antidote to the hysteria that surrounded the scandal. But the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Tell</ENAMEX> fumes, calling the book "appalling. ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> feels free to offer conclusions of fact that the public record either
cannot sustain or actually refutes." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

            

               Death
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Scott</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927-1999</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22</TIMEX> after a long career packed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of awards, many of which he refused to accept. Most notably, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> he
turned down the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Actor Oscar</ENAMEX> for his title role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patton</ENAMEX> , calling
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> "a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> meat parade." His roles in movies such as The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strangelove</ENAMEX> and on the stage, including a
performance as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard III</ENAMEX>, earned him recognition as "an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> of
extraordinary range and daring" with an "almost volcanic intensity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel</ENAMEX>
Gussow, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (This site includes a filmography, stills, and an interview with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
