
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.'s Wimp Factor</ENAMEX>

            In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, over the protests of outraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> flew
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the midst of his presidential campaign to supervise the execution of a
retarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>. The message to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, unlike previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, was tough on crime. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, after a
gunman murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> church, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
flew home to urge <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to "pray for love in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s hearts." The message
this time is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, unlike previous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compassionate</ENAMEX>.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> succeeds in projecting such sensitivity, the cure may prove worse than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> used to win elections by calling their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> soft on crime. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, first as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> and then as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
frustrated this tactic by recasting gun control--previously an issue of "big
government"--as an issue of getting tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, who opposes most
federal gun control proposals and signed the law that lets <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> carry
concealed handguns, is in danger of completing this reversal. By fighting crime
with "love," he is coming across not as a gun nut, but as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
tried to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> messages in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> shooting. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is
that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have traditionally argued, culture--particularly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>--is more important than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In remarks replayed endlessly on
television and in the print media, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> blamed the shooting on a "wave of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evil</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>, he surmised, "was acting as a result of evil in his heart.
And I would hope that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> would collectively pray for love in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
hearts." Rather than discuss gun control or prosecution, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s campaign Web
site offered visitors a single quote atop his home page: "This is a terrible
tragedy made worse by the fact it took place in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of hope and love. My
thoughts and prayers are with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation</ENAMEX>."

            
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> tried to project a virtue traditionally scorned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>:
compassion. "It's inexplicable to me how somebody's heart could be so full of
hate that he would walk into a place of worship where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> were seeking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God</ENAMEX>'s grace and love and kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. Rushing home to
"add some comfort to the pain and sorrow," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> regretted that "there's not
much to say" and that "all I could do ... was embrace" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. "It's hard to do anything but just to say, 'I love you,' " he
lamented. Rather than dismiss the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cold-blooded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> called
him a "sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>" who must be "demented."

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> message has curdled the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swaddled</ENAMEX> in hugs, empathy, and spiritual
musings on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>'s "heart," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s appeal to cultural renewal instead of
government intervention comes across more as a plea for love instead of laws.
"We as a society can pass laws and hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> accountable," he told reporters.
"But our hopes and prayers have got to be that there is more love in society."
"I wish I knew the law to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> love one another," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> added. "We can
pass laws, but there needs to be a higher law. And that is, 'Love your neighbor
like you'd like to be loved yourself.' "

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
isn't the only conservative projecting such an oddly mixed message. "Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to understand what a terribly, terribly tragic thing this is,
what a horrible tormented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> this is," lamented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
massacre on "societal elements that create such empty hearts that commit these
crimes," adopted the leftist pose of victimhood, calling for a federal study of
"crimes against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of faith."

            While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> professes reluctance to "politicize" the tragedy, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> have seized the opportunity to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">label Bush</ENAMEX> soft on crime. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> went out of his way to make it harder
to prosecute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> carrying deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and school events,"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> charged. "You can't say you support law enforcement and then refuse to
support law enforcement's attempts to close the gun show loophole. It's time
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to start listening to law enforcement and stop listening to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>."

            Gun
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> have gone further. Speaking on television and in the print
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> massacre, they juxtapose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s "weak" gun laws with the
"tough" restrictions they would prefer. They claim the support of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>" and
the enmity of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>." Mocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s plea that he didn't "know a
governmental law that will put love in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s hearts," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handgun Control</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chairwoman Sarah Brady</ENAMEX> blasted "the cowardice of elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who blame
everything for the carnage--except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, she pointedly
suggested, "must contemplate what its lax gun laws and liberal gun culture have
created."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> seem to be having fun with the notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> as a liberal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reported that after the shooting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "again ruled out the
need for stronger gun controls. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has liberalized gun laws." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> cited speculation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was concerned about "renewed
charges by many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> that he was soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>." On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gang</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> cracked that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was a
little bit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonian</ENAMEX>, flying back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> to feel the pain." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> concluded that "while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was concentrating on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> was concentrating on laws."

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> tried to steer his campaign back to the right. Flanked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, he unveiled a plan to
hire extra <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> who would focus exclusively on gun crimes. Scarcely a
sentence passed his lips without a mention of "toughness." "The best way to
protect our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> is to vigorously enforce the tough laws we have on the
books," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> declared. "We have some very tough laws against gun violence in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and federal law with its mandatory sentences is tough as well. ... Only
with tough enforcement can we win the war against gun violence."

            Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> lost in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> because he was out of touch. They
thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> lost in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> because he was mean and distant. This time, they
were looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who knew how to speak the language of love. Next
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, they may be looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who knows when to stop.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" has also
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">scrutinized , , ,</ENAMEX> , and who have hounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
