
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Sporting Life&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This weekend</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> will jam <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Olympic Stadium</ENAMEX> to share in a timeless
spectacle involving bravery, farm <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Velcro</ENAMEX>. What is it?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 292</ENAMEX>)--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military-Industrial Cineplex</ENAMEX>:
               
            

            

               
                  Porcine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Milius</ENAMEX> praises it as "another link between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> that seems to have broken down over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>." What
is it?
               
            

            "The
dismal failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planet USO</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'institutions</ENAMEX>' are now 'forced' to 'admit' 'women.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Mnookin</ENAMEX>
            

            "Manly
homosexual love. If you don't believe me, watch any <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Milius</ENAMEX>-written
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screenplay</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Conan the Barbarian</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Ricci</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Putting some teeth into the drug war, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>'s right-wing paramilitary death
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squads</ENAMEX> will now be aided by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple</ENAMEX>-cheeked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>. Wolverines!
Wooo!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "Bob
Hope."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Jacobsmeyer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>' Wrap-Up
            

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>: entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and everyone else. Oddly,
if you're an entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, you never meet anyone from the aerospace
industry. That's always struck me as strange. They make death at places like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China Lake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point Magu</ENAMEX>, we sell death at places like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>. They're
conscienceless white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> with money, and so are we. Why don't we hang out? I
don't know, but I'll bet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Didion</ENAMEX> does.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, remember that
debate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Mondale</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> said that the military needed
money for "wardrobe"? Oh, how I laughed. Of course, at the time I was living in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>.

            
               Infotaining
Answer
            

            Producing training material. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>
announced the creation of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Creative Technologies</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> and video-game <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> to create the next generation of military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simulators</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> will then be free to use the technology
they develop to create theme-park rides and special effects. "It's a win-win
for everyone," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Louis Caldera</ENAMEX>.

            It's good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, it's good for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>, and it's good for us. Like when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Hughes</ENAMEX> took all that money for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airplanes</ENAMEX> and shoved it down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Russell</ENAMEX>'s shirt.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Milius</ENAMEX> for his opinion, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conan</ENAMEX> the
Barbarian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scribe</ENAMEX> said it sounded just fine to him.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quiz Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX> sent a cable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>
to secure his support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Green Berets</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Moyers</ENAMEX>
responded that "it sounded like an exciting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> followed up with an
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-page list of the things he would need to make his movie.

            Which of these items did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> really ask for, and which have I just slipped in for fun?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,800,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> and carbines

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">102,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX>

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28,000</NUMEX> trench mortars

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53,000</NUMEX> field and heavy guns

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,000</NUMEX> airplane engines

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition wagons</ENAMEX>

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX> field kitchens

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,150</NUMEX> field bakeries

            

            
               Answer
            

            I didn't add anything to
this list. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> received full military cooperation on his terms and was billed
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,623.64</NUMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            
               Red <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s Note
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> will be the guest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen</ENAMEX> returns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 30</TIMEX>.-- C.K.
            

         
      
   
