
   
   
      
         
            Timor Killers Caught on Tape

            The
Independent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with what it claimed was the first clear,
documented evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> army directed the slaughter in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>. It published transcripts of recordings of two-way radio
conversations between the special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces unit</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kopassus</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>independence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>. Radio conversations between Kopassus
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and militia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> shortly before and after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX> referendum
included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kopassus</ENAMEX> saying, "It is better we wait for the result of the
announcement [of the ballot]. ... Whether we win or lose, that's when we'll
react." Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kopassus</ENAMEX>: "Those white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> [referendum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>] ... should
be put in the river." Militia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> (passing the order to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militiamen</ENAMEX>): "If they want to leave, pull them out [of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>], kill them
and put them in the river." Kopassus: "They need to be stopped." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Militiamen:</ENAMEX>
"It will be done." "I'll wipe them out, all of them." "I'll eat them up."

            On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer of London</ENAMEX> led with an "exclusive" report that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kopassus</ENAMEX> had been secretly trained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> under a
program code-named "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iron Balance</ENAMEX>." Quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> documents obtained by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Timor Action Network</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane Evans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> said the program "was hidden from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> and the public
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> curbed the official schooling of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> after a
massacre in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>." The training of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kopassus</ENAMEX> went ahead nevertheless at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' expense "despite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> awareness of its role in the genocide of about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> after the invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>," the
paper said. It quoted a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> cable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> from an unidentified
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> that the training had been "a
big help to the (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>. They probably killed a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and I
probably have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> on my hands."

            As the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> took a hard line against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, saying that "[i]f the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> lets its
militia puppets fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> should pay a heavy price.
International <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> should halt all aid, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> should bring
maximum pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> to act like the responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> it so often
claims to be." The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX> predicted a strengthening of the power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
military with the anticipated passage in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> of a new state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> bill. Condemning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s reform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> for their lack of
resistance to the bill, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said it would give the military almost
unlimited power in a state of emergency, including the right to jail people
without trial. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> endorses the bill will be
"a sad day for civil society," sounding the death knell for the reform
movement.

            A
commentary in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX> warned that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> could destroy the hitherto
close relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aleksius Jemadu</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lecturer</ENAMEX>
in international relations at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parahyangan Catholic University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bandung</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> might target <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>,
"thus drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> into a conflict much more complicated than it ever
expected. The possibility of an open conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> cannot be ruled
out, particularly if pro-integration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> launch an attack from the western
half of the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>." Noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military is "very
suspicious" about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>'s motivation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> (believing it may have
as much to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Howard</ENAMEX>'s popularity at home as with
humanitarian concerns), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jemadu</ENAMEX> asked, "Does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> have a strategic agenda
which might strengthen its bargaining position vis-a-vis its closest northern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>? Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX>'s fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> is turning out to be a
self-fulfilling prophecy."

            The
same kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX> were expressed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Grattan</ENAMEX> wrote that without a clear exit timetable, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>'s
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> "will be seen through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> prism for years
rather than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>." She said, "The surge of feeling for 'our boys' on their
departure is dangerously fuelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX> sentiment in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> business interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> are being hit by the surge of
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> emotion. And alarmingly, despite the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> is
putting pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> rather than vice versa, some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are starting to talk in old threat-from-the-north language."

            While
remarking that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> had played "a commendably sensible diplomatic role
throughout the latest troubles," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in an editorial that
"[t]he venture has also exposed latent resentment of the potential leadership
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> in the region," particularly from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, which has refused to
take part in the peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> made the
same point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> in an editorial, saying that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (with the
exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> "which accepts all its responsibilities") regard the
intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> as an example of western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neocolonialism</ENAMEX>, but it
argued that the intervention is justified by international justice and, in the
specific case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, by its wish "to benefit from the globalization of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> and from substantial international financial aid." In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bangkok Post</ENAMEX> praised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>'s decision to join the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeeping force</ENAMEX> and described it as a policy of "tough love."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s
reported an improvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> relations because of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>'s decision to raise the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Court of Justice</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX>. It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abel Matutes</ENAMEX> as saying this could bring "a complete solution" to the row
generated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s request for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> to be extradited from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> for
murder, torture, and other human rights violations. It said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> will meet for talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mountaineer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallory</ENAMEX>, who died on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Everest</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX>, may have been the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to
reach the summit after all. A book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that found his body
on the mountain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last May</TIMEX> revealed that he had enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> to do so, and it
also offered another "tantalising clue. ... It is known that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallory</ENAMEX> had
intended to place a photograph of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>, on the summit should he reach
it. No photographs were found on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. 'Where are they,' the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> ask,
'if not at the summit?' " In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> (which is
serializing the book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ghosts of Everest: The Search for Mallory</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jochen Hemmleb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Johnson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Simonson</ENAMEX>) admitted that the evidence is
hardly conclusive but said that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> search expedition will return to
Everest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to look for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallory</ENAMEX>'s fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mountaineer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irvine</ENAMEX> and for the missing camera with which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irvine</ENAMEX> planned to record them both
on the roof of the world.

         
      
   
