
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">290</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Fighting Crime ... With Science</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX>, the list includes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
Pakistanis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cajuns</ENAMEX>. List of what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 289</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Problem":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     Quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wichita</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> said, "This is a terrible, tragic, embarrassing solution to a problem
that did not exist." What is?
                  
               
            

            "The
new state law requiring public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to use
quotation-marks-with-hands gestures whenever they use the words 'evolution,'
'Darwin,' or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>' in class."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Milner</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Pascover</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "The
forced annexation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>, to avoid geographical confusion. But
it's not a problem, since nobody knows anything about geography anymore
anyway."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Thomason</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>'s threat to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Imagine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 months</TIMEX> of that
excruciating white-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> rap! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising excesses don't
seem so bad anymore, do they?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Baisch</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay D.</ENAMEX>
Majors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX> )

            "The
decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas Board of Education</ENAMEX> to define pi as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX>. The resulting
increase in computational speed is expected to raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s average <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>
score by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 0.1415926</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan E. Snow</ENAMEX> )

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MAXIM</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>'
Wrap-Up
            

            What do we think of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>? It's pretty flat, we know that, and it's all in black and white,
as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oz</ENAMEX>. They have tornadoes. It entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> as a free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Cold Blood</ENAMEX> happened there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> and ... um ...
its state fair is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Friday</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX>. But now
I'm cheating by looking in the almanac. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> are so boring that that's
what's comically interesting about them: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peoria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Encino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> is
so boring it's not even funny. Sort of like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>.

            
               Faith-Based
Answer
            

            As many of you knew, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> was talking about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas Board of Education</ENAMEX>, and its decision to excise evolution from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s science curriculum. As another step in its retreat into state-sponsored
superstition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> has also forbidden all references to the Big Bang.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creationism</ENAMEX> is as good a hypothesis as any for how the universe began,"
editorialized the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Topeka</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital-Journal</ENAMEX> . "And we're pretty sure thunder
is caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> doing some sort of loud <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewy</ENAMEX> thing," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> did not
add.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> of the new educational guidelines, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Looy of Answers in Genesis</ENAMEX>, a creationist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, said: "There's no meaning in
life if we're just <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in a struggle for survival. It creates a sense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purposelessness</ENAMEX> and hopelessness, which I think leads to things like pain,
murder and suicide." Which is hanging a lot on the poor old theory of natural
selection. I thought pain, murder, and suicide were caused by television.

            Wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX>, what about that smutty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> show? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the ensemble appears to have a job, and
what is it? "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Geller</ENAMEX>" is a paleontologist. A paleontologist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>! Not
only does he have premarital sex, he believes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX>. If you were from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, it would be almost enough to make you think. And by the way, what kind
of name is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Geller</ENAMEX>"?

            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
Huxley was tired of arguing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who didn't believe in evolution; "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life</ENAMEX>
is too short to occupy oneself with the slaying of the slain more than once,"
said the eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX>. Little did he know.

            
               Parallax
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX> decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> was running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and said so in her
surprisingly-still-syndicated column. He wasn't and he isn't and he won't, but
the idea was intriguing enough to go a couple of news cycles in the legitimate
press and on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>. One remarkable thing didn't come up in the discussions
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>: his age. I think this says nice things about us as a society
and nice things about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s colorist.

            If elected, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> would
be older than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> they took office. Arrange
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> by age at their inauguration or prospective
inauguration.

            Calvin Coolidge

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Harding</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester Arthur</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Polk</ENAMEX>

            
               Common
Denominators
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, ignorant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christian hicks</ENAMEX>, primates,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
