
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">321</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;World Series&quot</ENAMEX>; 

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sao Paulo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX>--what comes next in this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX>? Why?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 320</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Futurific":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
history of the space age," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John E. Pike</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation of American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX>, reacting to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s big event. What
happened?
                  
               
            

            "I got
a pedicure for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. I had no idea of the impact I was
having."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrill Markoe</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>
replaced the faulty <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">O-</ENAMEX>rings in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Quarter</TIMEX> beer <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hooters</ENAMEX>, just down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from FAS
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>
            

            "At
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX>'s request, early-bird specials will be available on all flights to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moon</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX>
            

            "I'm
excited about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Buffy - Angel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">crossover</ENAMEX>, too, but let's not get
too excited."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            I hate the space
program. It's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and circuses without the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>. And with a crappy little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">circus</ENAMEX> that's got, like, maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donkey</ENAMEX> who isn't feeling very well.
Even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s most enthusiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> must admit that the early promise of
this program has been unfulfilled. "The conquest of space has moved ahead with
breath-taking speed since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Age</ENAMEX> began on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 4, 1957</TIMEX>," says
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Book</ENAMEX> , without shame because it's just an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inanimate</ENAMEX> object and can't feel shame, unlike some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space World</ENAMEX>
Book of the future that will know all human emotions and will be perfected
any minute. "On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> launched the first true space
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traveler</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chain-smoking dog</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laika</ENAMEX>, who, after befouling his kennel and
biting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> on the ass, was rocketed aloft in a spacesuit filled with
his own urine," it does not add. I've always favored the alternative
plan--small, unmanned probes, along with a gigantic annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bonfire</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> folded into origami <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cranes</ENAMEX>. A-OK!

            
               I'm

               Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Looking Down on You</ENAMEX>, I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Looking Down Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> high-resolution image of the
Earth taken by a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> was made public.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Imaging Inc.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thornton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, released a
photo taken by a satellite <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400 miles</NUMEX> above <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> The image of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington Monument</ENAMEX> and the surrounding area is as crisp and detailed as some
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> satellite photographs.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration approved private space cameras in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
expect to orbit their own satellites by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. These cameras can resolve
objects as small as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 feet</NUMEX> wide, accurate enough to show a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, although you could make out the cloud of evil roiling around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of mass-death <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson Calls</ENAMEX> for an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End to all This Baptist Bickering</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Randy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>: Lighten up. Baptists have come a long way. They're speaking to one
another in liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> now.

            

               Bail
               -Out Extra
            

            Below, actual lead
sentences that made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> instantly turn the page, or change the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX>, or slip a fresh clip into a cheap and easily obtainable hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> or
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Special</ENAMEX>" purchased within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 feet</NUMEX> of an elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, as
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> goes undercover to ... well, you know--what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX>
used to call "letters we never finished reading" (or something).

            

               "I ..." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.M. Rosenthal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
               

               " 'Complicated' is a word for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tori Amos</ENAMEX> ..." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natasha Stovall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Duque</ENAMEX> loves <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Jeter</ENAMEX> loves the nightlife, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olerud</ENAMEX> loves showtunes." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 14, 1999</TIMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
               

               "When you dial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX>, will you get the help you need? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>
investigates." Promo for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> .-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Heimer</ENAMEX>
               

               "As we head into high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> I find myself thinking often of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers long</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> and a way of life long gone."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail McCarthy</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16, 1999</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonweal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim O'Grady</ENAMEX>
               

               "Attention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> ..." Start of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review of Lulu</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bridge</ENAMEX> .-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good news tonight</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s pro-wrestling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>." Delivered some night
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by an anchor on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">local affiliate</ENAMEX>.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Heimer</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LESLIE GOODMAN-MALAMUTH</ENAMEX>, are the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> is writing for ..."-- Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Goodman</ENAMEX>-Malamuth
               

               "For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year</TIMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> labored to be taken seriously as a
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> studiously ignored him." From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger D. Hodge</ENAMEX>
               

               "Make sure to stay tuned for a live concert featuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Backstreet Boys</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'N Sync</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">98 Degrees</NUMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Fee</ENAMEX>
               

               "Raising a beaker with a balloon inside, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Jacquier</ENAMEX> peers at a wonder
of the world." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 14, 1999</TIMEX>.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
               

               "This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX>, reporting from the eye of
the hurricane."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee J. Nemetz</ENAMEX>
               

            

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metric Tang</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
