
   
   
      
         
            Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust Literary</ENAMEX>?

            
               SUBJECT:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Günter Grass' "Political" Art</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               FROM:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Trevor</ENAMEX>
Butterworth

            
               DATE: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oct 8</ENAMEX>

            Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adorno</ENAMEX> admonished that poetry was
impossible in the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX>, in a different context he also argued that
art was more effectively political the less overt its politics-- pace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brecht</ENAMEX>.

            Now, given the emotional and critical
persuasiveness of both positions, the question of how one might produce art
"adequate" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> is fraught with incommensurability. How can art be
both authentically free and at the same time totalize the experience of
genocide?

            And so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grass</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel Tournier</ENAMEX> in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ogre and D.M. Thomas</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Hotel</ENAMEX>
               , charts an oblique
course as far as historical engagement is concerned (though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> cuts loose
in his shocking denouement).

            If this is, as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grass</ENAMEX> is concerned, a moral
failure of literary process, then Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shulevitz</ENAMEX>, and a notably resentful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heilbrunn</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , need to make sense of their
criticism by showing how art can measure the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> and still be art (and
not history or politics or philosophy).

            (To reply, click here.)

            

               SUBJECT: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shulevitz's Political</ENAMEX> Criticism

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>
               : ""

            
               FROM:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Edroso</ENAMEX>

            
               DATE: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oct 8</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politicization of Nearly Everything</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Literary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX>) proceeds apace. First the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX> attack the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>
for giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lit Prize</ENAMEX> to a commie--all the while admitting that he might in
fact be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> (presumably they'll get around to reading him sometime,
if they can ever get through that big, fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX> book). What's art, after
all, compared to conservative correctness?

            Then Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shulevitz</ENAMEX> gets on <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grass</ENAMEX> for presuming to
use an artistic technique, specifically irony, in the context of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust</ENAMEX>--for what is art compared to a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shulevitz</ENAMEX> doubts Grass
"saved <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> literature." I say anyone who writes a masterpiece does a service
to literature, just as anyone who tries to make a work of art grist for their
political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> does it a disservice.

            (To reply, click here.)


            
               SUBJECT:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               FROM:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Taylor</ENAMEX>

            
               DATE: Thu
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oct 7</ENAMEX>

            I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon Library</ENAMEX> and thus the
promulgator of the analysis of the tape opening that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX> quotes.

            Here's what I noticed about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>: It neglected to mention a principal source of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RN</ENAMEX>'s frustration about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, which is plenty clear in our analysis and the tapes
themselves. Many of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
against her aggressive foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> did not particularly want the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to
support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> against hers.

            Do you or do you not believe this is a legitimate
reason for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> in the middle of a war he inherited to be
frustrated, particularly when he was still signing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30-40</NUMEX> letters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KIA</ENAMEX>? Add that to the fact that he'd gotten <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'68</TIMEX>, and what you have is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> who basically
viewed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> as predominantly liberal, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>, and anti-war.
He didn't just think they were against him; they were against him.

            And that's fine. Blocs of ethnic or religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are frequently against certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, and maybe all those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> get frustrated about it. That's fine, too--except when it's
captured on tape. But here's the bottom line: Words are words, and actions are
actions. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RN</ENAMEX> says "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>" on the tapes, I hear "damn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>," and I
understand it. This is why the points that he saved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> and that his
inner circle included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Safire</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garment</ENAMEX> are more than
aspects of a "some of my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> ..." defense. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> were
politically simpatico! And this was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>! It's not complicated! Also,
find the tape in the new batch where he talks about how impressed he was after
a meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>--then, I believe, a tough young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>.

            Anyway, back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> omission. In a
whole article about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, why leave out the bit about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>? Doesn't he have the right to have the most immediate source of his
frustration even mentioned? Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to think these
feelings sprang from him totally unprovoked?

            Here's what I think: We're all still tiptoeing
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>. We <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">post-Vietnam elites</ENAMEX> all tend to think that Ellsberg
was a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and that the war was immoral. We all tend to think that it was
okay to be for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>' freedom from aggression but to be indifferent toward
that of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Vietnamese</ENAMEX>. And so we still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scapegoat</ENAMEX> RN for all the sins of the
era to avoid having to ask tough questions about what really happened to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indochina</ENAMEX>, and to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> were permitted to
have their way with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whom we'd pledged to protect (and almost succeeded
in protecting). Check out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Sorley</ENAMEX>'s new book about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, for instance.
[Read more about the book in this "."]

            Revisionism about the war is inevitable;
revisionism about the toughest and best <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> will come
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX>. And the tapes won't stop it. More likely, the tapes will fuel it. Maybe
it's a good thing he didn't burn them after all.

            (To reply, click
here.)

            
               SUBJECT:
In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense of the Torah Codes</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
                ""

            
               FROM:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Drosnin</ENAMEX>

            
               DATE: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oct 8</ENAMEX>

            Your article that posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late yesterday</TIMEX> about the
Bible code would not have been published if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, had
taken the time to check out the facts.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">The Bible Code</ENAMEX> , I've spent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past seven years</TIMEX> checking out all the claims and counter-claims. Here are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic facts your article ignores:

            a) The data for the original <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> code experiment
were chosen by an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shlomo Havlin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bar</ENAMEX>-Ilan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, who did not know how the data would affect the outcome of the
experiment. That alone absolutely refutes the new accusation that the data were
"tuned" or "fitted to the tests."

            b) The original <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> code experiment was
replicated by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">codebreaker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Gans</ENAMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 25 years</TIMEX> a
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crypto-analyst</ENAMEX>. He not only re-did the
experiment from scratch, but also confirmed the code using entirely new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>.

            That alone absolutely refutes the new claim that
the results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> experiment can't be replicated. I understand your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s false relief in not having to believe in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> code any longer.
I'm also secular.

            But this new attack by the same old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> does
not let <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wittes</ENAMEX> off the hook. He, in fact, has done what he accuses those who
believe in the code of doing--he has taken on faith the false claims of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>.

            Had he actually checked the facts, he would know
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have not "solved the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> code puzzle"--they told a lie.

            They knew that the esteemed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> who chose the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> had stated in writing that he did not know how the data would affect the
experiment. They knew that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> codebreaker had publicly confirmed that he
replicated the experiment. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> even lied about the results of their
own experiments--which did not "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">debunk" the Bible</ENAMEX> code.

            In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> experiment confirmed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> code. So they ran a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> experiment rigged to fail, and then hid
the positive results of their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> experiment by lumping them together with
the fixed experiment.

            All of us who are not religious think we know that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> code simply cannot be real. When I first heard about it, that was my
entire reply--"I'm not religious."

            But then I learned <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>, obtained a copy of the
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> used by the world-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> who discovered the code,
and worked with it myself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. And then I found in the code a
warning that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX> would be assassinated, and told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> before he was killed.

            I still don't believe in God. I'm still not
religious. But I can assure you that the code is real. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> perhaps
too quickly, too easily embraced the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> code--and has now, like many a
disappointed convert, too quickly, too easily embraced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>.

            I'm surprised that you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> have
followed him without even trying to check out the facts.

            (To reply, click
here.)


            
               SUBJECT:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense of the Torah Codes</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               FROM:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Wittes</ENAMEX>

            
               DATE: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oct 8</ENAMEX>

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Havlin</ENAMEX>'s role in assembling the data
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>'s experiment and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gans</ENAMEX>' work on the codes are discussed at
length in the rebuttal paper. In fact, the central point of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, as I
noted in the article, is that the criteria <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prof.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Havlin</ENAMEX> applied in creating his
list of appellations was insufficiently well-defined before the dataset was
assembled to be scientifically valuable. Far from ignoring this, I described it
as "the core of [the] critique."

            While my article does not discuss Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gans</ENAMEX>'
experiments, that is chiefly because they were never published in a prestigious
peer-reviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> to begin with. The fair-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> will agree that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKay</ENAMEX> paper devastates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gans</ENAMEX> experiments completely.

            It is also false to say that I ever embraced the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bible Code</ENAMEX> or am now a disappointed convert. Rather, I always believed--and
still do--that the codes would, if demonstrated to be real, propel a
scientifically minded person towards <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> Judaism. I have, at the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, also always believed they would ultimately be debunked. Hence, they did
not change my religious convictions at all, though they shook them.

            Consider, by contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Drosnin</ENAMEX>, whose work
constitutes the least scientific and most intellectually shallow end of the
Torah codes discussion. He regards the codes as a proven fact, yet somehow
still professes non-belief. How is it possible that such a future-predicting
code embedded in such an impenetrable form in an ancient document could be the
work of something less than God? How can one believe in the codes and not in
God?

            It is not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-authors</ENAMEX> who "told a
lie." That dishonor, rather, belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drosnin</ENAMEX> himself for publishing a work
that grossly transcends even the now-discredited science on which it was
purportedly based.

            (To reply, click here.)

             

            
               SUBJECT:
The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Math of God</ENAMEX>"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               FROM:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Didaktikos</ENAMEX>

            
               DATE: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oct 8</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> means that you don't have to have proofs of
the existence of God, oh ye of little faith. Anyone whose faith depends upon
mathematical letter sequencing in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> or any other inspired
writing is grasping at straws.

            (To reply, click
here.)

            
               SUBJECT:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Math of God</ENAMEX>"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               FROM:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader</ENAMEX>

            
               DATE: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oct 8</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Wittes</ENAMEX> says that the loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>
codes is a relief. But would it not be sensational to find proof, by way of the
rational mind, for a God with continuing interest in our well-being? 

            (To reply, click here.)

         
      
   
