
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Generation Gap</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelist Hanif Kureishi</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Beautiful Laundrette</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>) has a yen for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambivalence</ENAMEX>, for situations in which no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> has a monopoly on either
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rightness</ENAMEX> or wrongness. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are all right. Or, rather, they're all
wrong. No, they aren't: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right</ENAMEX> and wrong don't comfortably apply. They try to
act as if they're right but suggest by their behavior that they might well be
wrong--akin to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who turns one way at an intersection and then keeps
glancing anxiously at the rearview mirror. To be human is to be pulled in
different directions; the least trustworthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are the ones who seem most
certain.

            This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theorem</ENAMEX> applies especially to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Son the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fanatic</ENAMEX> , directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Udayan Prasad</ENAMEX> from a superbly wry screenplay by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kureishi</ENAMEX> (based on his short story). Its central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--the "my" of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX>--is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parvez</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Om Puri</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> in a bleak industrial city
in the north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. The genial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parvez</ENAMEX> wants nothing more than to make it
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX>, to the point of enduring a steady patter of racist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humiliations</ENAMEX> and drifting into a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> career as a panderer. Nevertheless, he
tells himself that his life has a kind of integrity.

            His grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, Farid
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar Kurtha</ENAMEX>), doesn't see it that way. The angry young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> dumps his
Anglo-Saxon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> and falls in with a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX>, some
of whom he <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> under his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s modest roof. At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parvez</ENAMEX> is
reviled for the decadent culture that he embodies; at work, he's treated as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pet</ENAMEX>, a "little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stellan Skarsgard</ENAMEX>) whom he
supplies with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parvez</ENAMEX> has no status in either Western or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
culture. In his den, he pours himself a glass of single-malt <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Scotch</ENAMEX> and listens
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fats Waller</ENAMEX> and tries to avoid the incinerating glares of his increasingly
traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gopi Desai</ENAMEX>) and the fervent prayers of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. And he finds
himself falling in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettina</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Griffiths</ENAMEX>), an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>
whose compromised purity seems to mirror his own.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M y Son the Fanatic</ENAMEX> is built on incongruities--on
the juxtaposition of fierce <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">piety</ENAMEX> and amiable Western dissolution. The
tensions give it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic tingle</ENAMEX>, but that comedy is rooted in melancholy and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alienation</ENAMEX>. The mix of tones is marvelously embodied in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Om Puri</ENAMEX>, a charismatic,
slightly ravaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puri</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parvez</ENAMEX> begins with a magnetic
confidence in his own foolishness: He's proud of how he grasps for status. In
the movie's prologue, he can hardly contain his delight that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is set to
marry the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief inspector</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose revulsion for this
dark-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> with his cheap camera is manifest in every frozen
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-smile. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kureishi</ENAMEX> could have spun a whole film (and a more commercial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>)
out of this Birdcage opening, but he has already mined that vein in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hilarious</ENAMEX> novel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Buddha of Suburbia</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>). When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parvez</ENAMEX> tells his
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> that he holds himself above his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sir</ENAMEX>, I just joke
with them. A gentleman is my goal."--the tension between how he regards himself
and how the world regards him is heartbreaking. He's in for the comeuppance of
his life.

            But if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s way
is wrong, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s way is dangerously out of touch: It condemns before it
understands. After all, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parvez</ENAMEX> and the call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl Bettina</ENAMEX> are playing by
capitalism's rules, trying to get a foothold in a society that closely guards
access to its more "proper" ladders to the top. That means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farid</ENAMEX>'s moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">absolutisms</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX>' picketing and firebombing of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whorehouse</ENAMEX>--aren't so much wrong as entirely beside the point. Nowhere is this
more evident than in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith</ENAMEX>'s lovely and self-possessed performance, which
transcends every hooker-with-a-heart-of-gold cliché. What she does and
what she is have no connection; she does what she does to get by. The
affection between her and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parvez</ENAMEX> comes from the happy realization that in spite
of their differences, they're on the same (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>--and each has
figured out what the other is truly worth.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M y Son the Fanatic</ENAMEX> isn't entirely pure in its
motives. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parvez</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> remains a remote and unsympathetic figure, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whose
lack of appreciation fully justifies his drift into the arms of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>.
The theme has been much on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kureishi</ENAMEX>'s mind. His most recent novel,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intimacy</ENAMEX> , is a nakedly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">autobiographical</ENAMEX> exploration of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s thoughts
on the eve of his abandonment of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> for a younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. The breadth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kureishi</ENAMEX>'s self-justification in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Intimacy</ENAMEX> is
fairly breathtaking; he really does need more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, more checks on the
central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s point of view. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kureishi</ENAMEX> is much more convincing as a
dramatist than as a monologist.

            Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Son the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fanatic</ENAMEX> isn't an easy sell: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miramax</ENAMEX> picked it up for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> distribution and
sat on it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>, reportedly debating whether to alter its
irresolute ending. It's shocking that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would even consider such a
change, since the film's irresolution is its greatest strength. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kureishi</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hopelessness</ENAMEX> is the kind that leaves you exhilarated, convinced that even if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> on screen haven't found a "right" way, the quest for a right way
is what keeps them--keeps all of us--alive. The punk aesthetic lingers in
Kureishi: The more hopeless the movie gets, the more upbeat it feels.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of all persuasions have been beating their breasts
and warbling for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s new Tarzan cartoon. They're half-right: The
movie is a collision between inspiration and tastelessness, between the
defiantly quirky and the wholesomely homogenized. I hated it in principle--I
hate most modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> cartoons--but adored a good deal of it in practice. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">storyboarding</ENAMEX> frequently borders on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, and few cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have had
the gorgeously dizzy aplomb of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie Driver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>.

            The noxious <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. There's something really icky
about the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> talk. I know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> have spoken <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in
cartoons since cartoons began to speak, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarzan</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
they've done it in a story in which language is a central theme. The daft charm
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Rice Burroughs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>--a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> and human languages are constantly vying for supremacy--doesn't have the
same piquancy when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> talk like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leave It to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaver</ENAMEX> . If we're all the same under the skin (or fur), then what's the
point of the story? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Close</ENAMEX>'s tender mama <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX> has clearly been to
finishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance Henriksen</ENAMEX>'s massive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> must have learned to talk
from watching after-school specials: "I said he could stay," he <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX>, after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby Tarzan</ENAMEX> gets adopted by his missus, "That doesn't make him my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gorilla</ENAMEX>
comic relief comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Donnell</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX>. I'd have welcomed her
self-congratulatory sarcasm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Instinct</ENAMEX> , but here it made my back hair
stand up. You can pretty much ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance</ENAMEX>, but it's
impossible to shut your ears to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, that is, whose songs feature
Afro-Celtic polyrhythms over soft-rock sludge.

            All is forgiven when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarzan</ENAMEX> (the voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldwyn</ENAMEX>) meets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie Driver</ENAMEX>--I mean, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>. When he scoops her up to elude some
angry baboons, the sequence is more electrifying, more dizzyingly vertiginous
than anything in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jurassic Park</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lost World</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>). It gets better
when they stop to chat. He's a likable schnook with a long, skinny chin and a
slightly embarrassed lope. She's all blithe insouciance--a wonderful parody of
proper <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> maidenhood straining to burst its corsets and grab a piece of
jungle hunk. What a voice <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driver</ENAMEX> has! Breathlessly throaty--it only just
manages to contain its own melodic exuberance.

         
      
   
