
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">313</NUMEX> &quot;What's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Smell</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               It was caused by
"a poisonous mix of greed, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>, jingoism, and bad taste," writes Frank
Hannigan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s former executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>? What
happened?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> pm. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 312</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ominous Anomalous":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, God. Which does
not belong? Why?
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is the only one who's been rooting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>
Balk
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX>; I think everybody else is in agreement that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jedediah Purdy</ENAMEX>
would make the perfect first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Anderson</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> has never claimed to have attended a barbecue with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, obviously, because ... oh, wait, that's not what you meant
by 'staff,' is it? Ick, what the hell is wrong with me thinking that? I blame
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, and those scary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX> clones."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gabel</ENAMEX> (similarly: You're all thinking it.)

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Everyone on the list has been, at some point, taken in by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are the only ones who have been taken in
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Scheft</ENAMEX>
            

            "God.
Does not buy clothes at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banana Republic</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Schecter</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wrap-</ENAMEX>
               Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
found common ground in their loathing for professional scold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>--his perpetual disapproval, his sanctimonious speechifying, his
humorless yelping, the way the sunlight turns his hair into an auburn cascade,
the kooky little songs he sings in the shower, his tousled amorous look first
thing in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>, the way his knowing hands, so strong yet so gentle ...
no, wait, sorry ... I was thinking of the affair I've never had with family
values huckster <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>. I get a little mixed up when I miss
breakfast--flapjacks, sausages, prayerful boo-hooing. Most important meal of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eat Well or Burn in Hell: A Child's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Recipe Book of Virtues</ENAMEX> .

            
               Weepy

               Display of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religiosity Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            All but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> are on the list of people
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> believes have forgiven him. Even though he doesn't deserve
it.

            Posing coquettishly for the cameras at the annual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prayer Breakfast</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> said, "I have been profoundly
moved, as few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have, by the pure power of grace, unmerited forgiveness
through grace. Most of all to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, but to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I work
with, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legions</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and to the God in whom I believe, Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Barkin</ENAMEX>. And I'm very grateful to all of you who have had any role in
that."

            A review of the tapes indicates that the president
did not make any overt mention of Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barkin</ENAMEX>. But we know, as few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do,
through the pure power of grace, what he was thinking.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was
surrounded by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phalanx</ENAMEX> of spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wogaman</ENAMEX>. "I don't for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one moment</TIMEX> think that what he's been doing has been
simply for the public relations," said the reverend with unaffected simplicity.
"Camera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX>? Really? Are those things on?" he did not add.

            
               E-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            With various seasonal
festivities fast approaching, why not consider gifts that say, "I like you from
a perspective far to the right of most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>." Online reactionary giving is
as convenient as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, as barbarous as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Inquisition</ENAMEX>--like
Torquemada on some kind of laser <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sled</ENAMEX>. A few suggestions:

            
               Family
Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>
               
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Virtuous Reality</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T-Shirt</ENAMEX>: "Designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Save</ENAMEX>-Sex campaign, this clever logo on a brilliant
red t-shirt is a subtle way to impart the positive message that a virtuous life
is the reality we need to strive for. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> pre-shrunk red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton t-shirt</ENAMEX>."
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>-- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> so seldom sees the word "subtle" and the words "brilliant red
t-shirt" in the same sentence.
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Save-Sex Hold Out</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultimate</ENAMEX>" T-Shirt: "Designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Save</ENAMEX>-Sex campaign, this is a great
shirt for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purple</ENAMEX>, yellow, and green logo on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">white</ENAMEX>, pre-shrunk, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton t-shirt</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>-- You can "hold out for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX>," but remember: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. And married. And denying
everything.
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> Commandment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX>
Covers: "Beautifully designed, these book covers reverently portray the
importance of a higher law in the lives of our school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Allow your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to make a strong yet subtle statement and order a set <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Comes in
sets of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>-- If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> comes home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> determined not to
covet his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>, that will more than make up for his utter ignorance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> and history.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Opinion</ENAMEX>
Books
               , the online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Birch Society</ENAMEX>

            Poster: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Cheers</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Service</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>-- Features pictures of argument-stopping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>,
comical tyrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX>, and not actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Axis</ENAMEX> power Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
            

            Poster: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Experts</ENAMEX>
Agree: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gun Control Works</ENAMEX>!" <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>-- With cartoon bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qaddafi</ENAMEX>, just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX> khaki ads.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peace Is</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Control</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sweatshirt</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>-- Features a scary skull in a blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helmet</ENAMEX>. Available only in Size <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXL</ENAMEX>, showing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birch Society</ENAMEX>'s commitment to
big, fat, superstitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.
            

            Red, white, and blue
"Get the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">refrigerator Magnet</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX>-- <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> they save the
lives of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, then they vaccinate some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>,
and the next thing you know, they're peacefully resolving international
disputes. For the love of God, stop them!
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>
Forum
               
            

            Video: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feminism</ENAMEX> : "What feminism is and why it is destructive." <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21.95</NUMEX>-- I
believe this is the one where a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> get liquored up and ask for
equal pay.
            

            Video: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribute</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Schlafly in Song</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pictures</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>-- Oh, right, like I don't
already have this on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DVD</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign Committee</ENAMEX>
               
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Low Profile Official</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole Campaign Cap</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Embroidered Sanded Twill Low Profile Cap New Shallow</ENAMEX>
Profile. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14.95</NUMEX>-- I'm no fancy campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX>, but I 
               think I see
where they're going wrong with the tone of this thing.
            

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loathing William Bennett</ENAMEX>, punning on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
