
   
   
      
         
            <EM>Veni</EM>, <EM>Vidi</EM>, Veto

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is suing major tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The suit
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">aims 1</ENAMEX>) to penalize the industry for concealing the risks of cigarettes and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
to recover <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of tax dollars spent on smoking-related health care. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> rejected legislation that would have settled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
claims against the industry for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$516 billion</NUMEX>. The industry's spin: The
government can't claim innocence after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of subsidizing tobacco and
promoting overseas sales. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s spin: Even if our hands are dirty,
the industry should pay for the medical costs of its product. The industry
counterspin: Then we should pay nothing, since smoking saves money by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shortening</ENAMEX> lives.

            

               Tension is rising in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
exchanged gunfire with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militiamen</ENAMEX> and renegade <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> are securing the region to make way for relief efforts for refugees
facing disease and starvation. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> spin: This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> could be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cakewalk</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> spin: We brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> for a reason. (See the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> for extensive
coverage of the crisis.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> vetoed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> tax cut. The bill,
narrowly passed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, would have used the projected budget surplus to
eliminate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> in taxes over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>. Both sides have hinted that a
smaller tax reduction would be acceptable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> could
not
afford a return to "the failed policies of the past." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
charged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tax-and-spend philosophy would do just that.

            

               A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was sentenced to death for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> dragging
murder. A unanimous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> condemned avowed racist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Russell</ENAMEX>
Brewer for killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Byrd Jr.</ENAMEX>, a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was dragged alive for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX> behind a pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> before his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> was torn off by a concrete culvert.
Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> was found guilty in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> is awaiting trial.
The prosecution spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> sent a message that not all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> are racists. The defense spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juries</ENAMEX> should evaluate facts, not
send messages.

            

               Hope for more earthquake <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> is fading in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. The
death toll from the initial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.6</NUMEX>-magnitude quake has topped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> and is
expected to rise as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rescuers</ENAMEX> search for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believed to be trapped in
the rubble. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> remain homeless, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, electricity, and
food supplies are cut off on much of the island. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> warned
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> is a sign of things to come: Earthquake damage will increase
everywhere with urban development and population growth. (
                  Slate
               's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> Mother Nature's power.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George C. Scott</ENAMEX> died. He was best known for portraying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Patton</ENAMEX> and for refusing to accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Actor Oscar</ENAMEX> for the
role. Film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Thomson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> was once "the great threat in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> acting--he had such drive and bite, such timing and authority."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> wrote himself into the story as a fictional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. The forthcoming book portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s contemporary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historians</ENAMEX> called the technique dubious. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labeled Morris</ENAMEX> "barking mad ." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> explained that "after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> of deep research I
was, in an almost occult sense, there when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was younger."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> defended his grant of clemency to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX>. He denied <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> allegations that the move was aimed
at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> support for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign. Separately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX> revealed that he had "unequivocally opposed " the offer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clemency</ENAMEX> is about justice, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>' punishments did not fit their
crimes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clemency</ENAMEX> is about security, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>'
release sends the wrong message about terrorism.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is prepared for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX>. The report says
that thanks to preparation by large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and federal and state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, the computer bug will cause few disruptions in most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' lives. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s spin:
Confused computers could cripple basic services. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panicked</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> could wreak havoc on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>.
 

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> is recovering from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX>. The storm
killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 68</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and caused damage worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of millions of</NUMEX>
dollars. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly a third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> remains shut down by flooding, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> now faces <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water pollution</ENAMEX> due to animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carcasses</ENAMEX> and sewage. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s spin: Whew!--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX> was milder than expected. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carolina</ENAMEX> is the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> the
weather reporting industry.)

         
      
   
