
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Cookies</ENAMEX> 101

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iggy's Stooges</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ig</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prizes</ENAMEX>, spoofs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prizes</ENAMEX> that honor both genuine and phony
research, were handed out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Len Fisher</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Bristol</ENAMEX>
won the physics prize for researching the best way to dunk a cookie. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> won the peace prize for a car alarm that stops <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flamethrower</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Standards Institution</ENAMEX> received the literature prize
for its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-page exposition on the proper way to make a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas Board of Education</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado State Board of Education</ENAMEX> shared the
science-education <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> for "mandating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should not believe in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>'s theory of evolution any more than they should believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>'s
theory of gravitation ... or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasteur</ENAMEX>'s theory that germs cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>,"
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> . Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> sent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, award ceremony.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Allah Who</ENAMEX>
Failed
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Kuwait</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmad al-Baghdadi</ENAMEX> was jailed for blasphemy after
writing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX> failed in his mission to convert <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mecca</ENAMEX>'s nonbelievers to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, chair of the political science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, was sentenced
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX> behind bars for offending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> and immediately went on a hunger
strike that sent him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. Upon his release, the professor
apologized for any offense he caused, reports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agence France Presse</ENAMEX>.

            
               A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grade Point</ENAMEX>
Average
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> wants to ditch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A-plus</ENAMEX>. There are "too many of them to
suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> getting them are really doing exceptional work," a
university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> committee
wants to replace the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A-plus</ENAMEX> with an "A with distinction." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teachers</ENAMEX> would still
be able to personally annotate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX>, but it would still only be worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.0</NUMEX>
grade points (compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A-plus</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> oppose the proposed
change. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> says the new grade will allow outstanding work to be
honored while "not disadvantaging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the contest for academic honors,
awards, and prizes which depend significantly on grade point averages." (See

                  Slate
               's "" for an irreverent take on the grade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deflation</ENAMEX>.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gettin' Buggy Wit</ENAMEX>
It
            

            How do
locusts swarm? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC News</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have
determined that locusts attract other locusts with chemical signals to amass
swarms that can strip a field bare within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. Swarming female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locusts</ENAMEX> can
also manipulate the genes in their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> to ensure that their young will want to
join the swarm immediately. (Locusts reared in seclusion are reluctant to
gather.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> hope to isolate the chemical and use it to design
synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compounds</ENAMEX> that will block swarming.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pass</ENAMEX>, and
Cheat
            

            Tutors
may have done schoolwork for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s national
championship college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, according to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>
report. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Tennessee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip Fulmer</ENAMEX> declined to discuss
the allegations, but school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Wade Gilley</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> is reviewing the matter. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> report
is true, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, tutors, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> will be subject to punishment
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s honor code and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> guidelines.

            
               Visions of
Dylan
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poet Laureate Andrew Motion</ENAMEX> has dubbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Visions of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johanna</ENAMEX>" the best song lyrics ever written. Citing "the concentration and
surprise" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan's</ENAMEX> lyrics, as well as the "rasp of his anger," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion</ENAMEX>
rhapsodized over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">songwriter</ENAMEX>'s use of language. Not all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> poets share
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion</ENAMEX>'s taste. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dannie Abse</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Observer</ENAMEX> , "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s]
writing is inferior poetry, and inferior poetry is not really poetry at all."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poet Craig Raine</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenz Hart</ENAMEX> was a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lyricist</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loco</ENAMEX>
Parentis Returnus
               
            

            
Recently amended federal confidentiality laws have prompted such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Delaware</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX> to notify parents
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 21</TIMEX> violate campus rules concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. A
student referendum on notification at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX> produced the highest turnout for a
student election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>: More than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> voted against
it.

            
               All <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hail Marx</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Einstein</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> is the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC News Online</ENAMEX>
poll. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX> placed <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. Rounding out the top
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Newton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Darwin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Aquinas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hawking</ENAMEX>, Immanuel
Kant, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">René Descartes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Clerk Maxwell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedrich Nietzsche</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
Giving
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly Endowment Inc.</ENAMEX>'s recent donation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Indian College Fund</ENAMEX>
is the largest private donation ever made to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.
The money will be spent on improved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> at tribal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> on reservations. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly</ENAMEX> gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic Scholarship</ENAMEX> Fund, and last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> it donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$42 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Negro College Fund</ENAMEX>, making it one of the largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of minority education.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heal</ENAMEX>
Thyselves
            

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> has appointed its first female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine D.</ENAMEX>
DeAngelis, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins University School of</ENAMEX>
Medicine, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> 's editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dismissed George Lundberg</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> after he published a survey of
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' sexual attitudes (sample question: Is oral sex the same as
sex?) that too conveniently coincided with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment
trial. Asked if she was offered guidelines about editing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundberg</ENAMEX>'s dismissal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeAngelis</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , "Editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX> is essential. I have no doubt that editorial freedom will be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">byword</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
