
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">324</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad About Beef</ENAMEX>" 

            
               Fill in the blank
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Gregg</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>, comments on some
recently declassified documents by offering this personal anecdote: "My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residence</ENAMEX> had just been broken into by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> angry about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> quotas.
They tried to burn my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down. And I thought, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'God Almighty</ENAMEX>, if they get
this mad about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>, what will they do when they learn we have _________ here?'
"
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">323</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smooth Talker":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  "We deal in the basics, and all those basics are necessary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">necessities</ENAMEX>," said a smiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, patiently explaining to some CNNfn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would thrive even in an economic downturn. Why was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
smiling?
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honestly</ENAMEX> believes Talk will still be around in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Radosh
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>? No, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saint Johnswort?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Cloutier</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Because he knew he'd never have to answer another question from that bitch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dobbs</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
like to smile also but not when I have to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. Then I frown a
little."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon W. Davis</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>,
what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> do in the privacy of a live broadcast is none
of our business, you know?"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> and its more
appealing counterpart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> (more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> who look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>, more
hints of futility and world weariness, fewer catchy names for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX>--I
believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> has something called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Margin Monkeys"</ENAMEX>) are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> of business
news for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that watches the economy as if it were sports. Both sports
and the stock market are essentially dramatic events, that is, events whose
outcomes are unknown. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanks</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> could win; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> could go up or down. Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> offer an infinite supply of statistics that give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> the
illusion of deeper understanding. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, particularly many retired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their day</TIMEX> by checking the box scores of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s action on
their holdings. These <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> fluctuations make absolutely no difference in
one's financial circumstances, but watching them offers a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>'s pleasure. How
did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> do <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>? And following the market gives that intensified
enjoyment that all sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX> know: It's a lot more exciting to watch when
you've got a little money--or the savings of a lifetime--down on the game. I'd
certainly go to the track a lot more often if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Insana</ENAMEX> were running against a
big, mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.

            
               That's a Good
Thing Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> had just become an elegant,
tasteful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> through the IPO of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart Living Omnimedia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>

            Offered at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18</NUMEX> a share, the stock climbed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/16</NUMEX>, a gain of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">96.9 percent</NUMEX>, raising <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$129.6 million</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            Incidentally, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> maintained the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX>'s usual hard-hitting standards by concluding their conversation this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>: "On a personal note, I'd like to say that for the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> Thanksgivings
we've done your balsamic glazed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">onions</ENAMEX>, and they were fantastic."

            Also going public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wrestling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation Inc.</ENAMEX> closed up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 1/4</NUMEX> after its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17</NUMEX> open.

            Coincidentally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> said, "On a personal
note, I'd like to say that for the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thanksgivings</ENAMEX> we've pummeled each
other into ersatz insensibility, and it was fantastic." Or perhaps he
didn't.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> IPO winner
was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satyam Infoway Ltd.</ENAMEX> closing up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 1/2</NUMEX>, or
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97.2 percent</NUMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 1/2</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had no personal anecdote for sucking up
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satyam</ENAMEX>.

            
               Feelings, Nothing
More Than Extra
            

            I give the
self-assessment; you name the self-assessed.

            
               Feeling
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "I feel really great. Everyone welcomed me back
and has treated me so well."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "I feel OK, I feel comfortable, so we'll just
see what happens really."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "At times I feel as if I am cornered, as if I
can never make an approach."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "I feel good about it."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "I feel so much healthier."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "I feel some frustration that there isn't more
happening in this field."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "I feel it closing in
on me."

            
               Feeler
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonya Harding</ENAMEX> is back on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>, this time as a
pro, after a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five-and-</NUMEX>a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> year layoff for that whole clubbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Kerrigan</ENAMEX>
thing.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> is not looking for another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX> after the death of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, but he's open to the
possibility of a new relationship, although probably not with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonya Harding</ENAMEX>,
whose name didn't actually come up in the interview.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megawati Sukarnoputri</ENAMEX> doesn't feel other
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> welcome an alliance with hers but, if I can read between the
lines--and I can't--worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> wouldn't return her calls even
if she did get up the nerve to phone him.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> feels good about working with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on the budget bill, and encourages you to make up some kind of
sophomoric joke about his yen for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Megawati Sukarnoputri</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonya Harding</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flores</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> pounds. She is among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have responded to "Walk <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX>!" a fitness media blitz that
began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did not participate.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Hammarberg</ENAMEX> (I'm
not sure what he weighs) feels <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> could be using recent political
stability as a chance to make progress on human rights. But is it? No.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank McCourt</ENAMEX> feels
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> is a great career move and a nice place to visit, but after just
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> ...

            
               Signs That the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixties Are Finally Over Ongoing Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All You Need is Love</ENAMEX>" now used in
commercial for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sugar Coated Toxic Waste and Baby Seal Bits</ENAMEX>" breakfast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal</ENAMEX>.
Or perhaps that was just an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> vision I had. Either way, bummer.

            OK, that one I made up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to
find similar but genuine bits of evidence that this magical (and turbulent)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decade</ENAMEX> has ended yet again.

            Replies to run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Necessities</ENAMEX>, in ascending order: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, air,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pornography</ENAMEX>, toilet paper.

         
      
   
