
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tailor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soldier</ENAMEX>, Grandma

            As spy
fever once again gripped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> after the confession of an 87-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> that she had given <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> nuclear secrets to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">l</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ike diamonds</ENAMEX>, it seems, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> are forever."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial: "Any hope of some respite for the world from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brigade</ENAMEX> of 'trench-coats and snoopers,' especially after the collapse of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, have been dashed. The world's
secret service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have apparently merely shifted their emphasis to the
new 'growth area' of industrial spying." It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Marion</ENAMEX>, a former head
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> secret service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, as saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> spying is happy
spying--no ideology is involved."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, however, it was back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> as the press raked over new
revelations of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treachery</ENAMEX>. They came thick and fast, starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, which disclosed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melita Norwood</ENAMEX> (code name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hola</ENAMEX>") had passed
atomic secrets to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> while she worked as a secretary
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tube Alloys</ENAMEX> project, a deliberately anodyne term for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s nuclear
weapons program. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> linked her to the notorious "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> coven"
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male spies</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Philby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Maclean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Burgess</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Blunt</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cairncross</ENAMEX>. "The 'sixth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,' we now know, was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>," it said.

            On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> its sister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> , revealed that a former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland Yard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Symonds</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">64</TIMEX> (code name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scot"</ENAMEX>)--had been paid by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seduce</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruit women</ENAMEX> working for Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symonds</ENAMEX> had been hired
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>, where he fled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> after being named as part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> of
corrupt metropolitan police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> who had taken bribes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> 's spy
scoops: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> ran a "dirty tricks" campaign to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> was murdered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> planned to maim
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballet dancers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf Nureyev</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natalya Makarova</ENAMEX> for defecting to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>; it launched a series of plots against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX>; and it planted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> successive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries-general</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>. All this information was contained in "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitrokhin</ENAMEX> archive"--a vast
haul of documents smuggled out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vasili Mitrokhin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archivist</ENAMEX> who defected to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. His book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Mitrokhin Archive:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the West is being serialized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>.

            The
main question in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press editorials was whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melita Norwood</ENAMEX> should be
prosecuted for her treachery. The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX>
wrestled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> with the logic of applauding the arrest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">83-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> (as the paper had done) while objecting to the
imprisonment of an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">87-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. But it said that "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norwood</ENAMEX>'s betrayal
is more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years old</TIMEX> and was conducted in a paranoid <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War world</ENAMEX> whose
ideological extremism now seems antique and all but incomprehensible."
Furthermore, she "killed nobody" and "was fired by ideological commitment
rather than malevolence." It went on: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memories</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s mass killings and
tortures, by contrast, are all too fresh, and the precedent of his arrest has
international ramifications." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , however,
ridiculed the "predictably forgiving" opinion of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> . "Now that Mrs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norwood</ENAMEX> ... has confessed, without remorse, her
betrayal of her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>'s most brutal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">('Old Joe</ENAMEX>'),
should she be tried, condemned and jailed<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" it asked. "Of course, and the
sooner the better."

            But in
most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press, as around the world, the main story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s capitulation to international pressure by agreeing to allow a
foreign peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. This was generally welcomed, but
with qualifications. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> had responded too slowly.
"Not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">torching</TIMEX> and killing had spread throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> act," it said in an editorial. "As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, crusader for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> values, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologian</ENAMEX> of the just war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, he has been conspicuous
by his silence." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> would arrive
so late in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> that they wouldn't be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firemen</ENAMEX>--just gravediggers.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX> focused on the proposed establishment of
an international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> to investigate "the alleged involvement of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military in very serious human rights violations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>." It
quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Robinson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> for human rights, as saying that
the international community must hold <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> accountable for atrocities
committed there. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX> called the
international outcry against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> justified. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
which has been entrusted with the task of maintaining peace and order, did
virtually nothing as pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> launched a massive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terror</ENAMEX> campaign against their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX>, killing pro-independence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, forcing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> to leave their homes, and destroying
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and other property," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> warned,
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he evil that is done in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> cannot be hidden, at least not for long"
and that "ultimately there will be a calling to account for the rape of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zealand</ENAMEX>, where world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have been discussing the crisis at the
some of the blame on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> should have anticipated the
opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J. Habibie</ENAMEX> would face after the vote for independence in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, disastrously, was allowed to provide the only security
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> after the vote," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s editorial
said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> should have seen the inevitable consequences of this and
ensured an armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> was in place."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, the top story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX>'s latest setbacks
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and local elections, where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Social Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> was thrown out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> in the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thuringia</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> described
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX>'s series of electoral defeats--another is predicted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>--as his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Crucis</ENAMEX> and "a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> social
democracy, the lynchpin of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Left</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, where former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Portillo</ENAMEX> gambled on his political future in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative</ENAMEX>
Party <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by admitting to youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> experiences, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> published an opinion poll showing that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
would accept a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> who had been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> in the past, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> out
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> would accept one who was openly gay."

         
      
   
