
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">264</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$156K</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Problem&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Overheard at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>: "My intention is to do whatever he indicates to me he wants
done with them. He may want them returned. He may want me to destroy them. He
may not care at all." You make the prediction: Who will want whom to do
what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 263</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exchanging Glances":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Despite a recent clash of gunboats, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">freighter</ENAMEX> delivered something to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nampo</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part
of a trade between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. What is being swapped for
what?
               
            

            
"Slaves for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX>. And then the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> supplies the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane sugar</ENAMEX>, and ...
No, wait, hang on. I may have this wrong."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "North
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> gives up its dreams of agrarian reform under collectivism; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>
gives up a phantom economy built on cronyism and kickbacks; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> just gives up."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Pesca</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South</ENAMEX> generously agreed to trade the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> its position in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Wasik</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Episodes of M*A*S*H</ENAMEX> for kimchi. Yes, that is all I know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>.
What of it?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
don't know.  And neither does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lerangis</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            I'd just like to point
out, in case you were planning a satirical musical comedy about the crisis in
question, something you can do to a song from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Side Story</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>,
I've just met a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>!" This you cannot do with "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>" without
offending the rhythm and a sense of human decency. An early version of this
sort of thing that I recall with particular pleasure was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Side Story</ENAMEX> --that being the location of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>.
Khrushchev, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX>, sang, "When you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red</ENAMEX> you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red</ENAMEX> all
the way from your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> party purge to your last power play." As a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX>,
that's where I learned about party purges, and about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khrushchev</ENAMEX> for that
matter. Back then--and is there a more demoralizing phrase<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?-- Mad</ENAMEX> was
prized as the only satirical voice reaching suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX>. Now with
plenty of smart comedy aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman</ENAMEX>
come to mind-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mad</ENAMEX> is as superfluous and weary as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> we
shunted into that nursing home. (Was that us? Certainly not. It was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bastards</ENAMEX>.) In fact, I've just renewed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s subscription.
She seems to enjoy it, and I may yet be in the mood to read a movie parody
called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Drech</ENAMEX>."

            
               Market <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            In exchange for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200,000 tons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fertilizer</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> will discuss family reunions.

            Some conjecture that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigmund Freud</ENAMEX> will rise from
his grave to discuss the equating of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fertilizer</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, of shit with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>, then take in a movie, perhaps that charming <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Notting Hill</ENAMEX> , then
continue being dead. (And by "some" I, of course, mean "me.")

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round of
talks, held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, was largely devoted to trading accusations over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s naval skirmishes and complaining about the accommodations in the
hotel, except for the part about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>.

            
               Discontented
Extra
            

            All the following
remarks could have been made by arrogant senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>, drunk
on their own power probably mixed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX>--and it's kicky summer fun to think
of them that way--but none was. Can you match each with its actual disappointed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>?

            
               The
Disdain:
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "We don't like you; and that's been my motto my
whole life, growing up."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "I was probably too nervous, not much believing
what I can do."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. [It was] "grave and irregular."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. [She has] "a deep feeling of remorse."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "I'm tired of the
divisiveness up here."

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speakers</ENAMEX>:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> A money-hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> wishes its
IPO had yielded bigger bucks and that other online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> would just die or
something.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. Grumpy Knicks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Johnson</ENAMEX> assesses
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX>, and--if I can go out on a limb here, and bear in mind I'm just
speculating--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. Apologetic</ENAMEX> tennis great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martina Hingis</ENAMEX> seems to
resent her absent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, although I've not actually seen her in a clinical
setting.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Crotchety Shimon Peres</ENAMEX> wishes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> police
hadn't shot his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azmi Bishara</ENAMEX>, but he doesn't wish it all that hard.
"I didn't come here to denounce," he said at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lod City Hall</ENAMEX>. "I'm here to enjoy
a lobster dinner, away from the prying eyes of certain pushy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbis</ENAMEX> who ...
whoops!" he didn't add.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Exasperated Jeb Bush</ENAMEX> is pretty sure his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spendthrift</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columba</ENAMEX>, wishes either that she hadn't bought "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19,000</NUMEX> worth
of clothes and jewelry on her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> shopping spree," or wishes that she hadn't
tried to smuggle them through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX>, or wishes that she hadn't got caught.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of those.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F. Disdainful Coke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> sneer at the
misfortunes of ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nah</ENAMEX>, of course they don't. Responsible corporate citizens
every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. (Although I've not actually seen them in a clinical setting.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Cranky Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> is
annoyed that everyone doesn't just agree with him, and he thinks the best
remedy is to mount a futile run for the presidency.

            
               The
Answers:
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-B, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-C, 3-D, 4-E,</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>'s
Ongoing Extra
            

            There's still time to
mock the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greatest Legends List</ENAMEX> of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> by devising a brief
plot summary of a movie in which any equally ranked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>--for instance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirk</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lillian Gish</ENAMEX> are both rated No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>--should have co-starred.

            Inspirational example:

            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> Sunrise
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Boulevard</ENAMEX> --A young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dean</ENAMEX>) falls under the spell of a
disturbingly sexually precocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shirley Temple</ENAMEX>) who lives
alone in her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> with a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> and an ancient tap-dancing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butler</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            
               M*A*S*H was set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
