
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Rating Game</ENAMEX>

            
               X-it
Strategy
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Blame Blockbuster</ENAMEX>, Not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX>") makes good points about the way that the after-market also influences
what can be seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>. But I believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> is partly to blame for
that situation, because it allowed first the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> and then its clone the NC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> to
be described as categories hospitable to hard-core pornography. My hope is that
an A rating would work specifically because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-17</ENAMEX> would be retained, to
give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX> something to feel pious about.

            The current situation
has become impossible. The R rating has been stretched to the bursting point
and now permits material that would have been NC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>. Yet a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kubrick</ENAMEX> film cannot be seen as he intended it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Chicago</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burning Bush</ENAMEX>
            

            I was disappointed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s "" because
it took so many cheap shots and was so internally inconsistent. He first
asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s having an opinion about how one gets to heaven is
tantamount to "condemning most of humanity." Then, in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
efforts to get out of this subject by stating that God decides who goes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heaven</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> mocks him, noting that "we can stipulate that God decides."
Well, which is it--is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "condemning" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by having an opinion, or is he a
weenie for saying that God decides?

            Then, after frying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
for having a view, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idly</ENAMEX> wondering if he is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX>, and criticizing him
for trying to avoid a theological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">quagmire</ENAMEX> in the midst of a political
campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kinsley</ENAMEX> attacks him and others for not sticking to their true views
and also criticizes the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> (to which he was pandering only a few
column inches previously) for caring about what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe about such
issues. Really--it seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> is trying to have his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> and eat it
several times.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
Aeschbacher
            

            
Woodinville, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Road to</ENAMEX>
Hell
            

            Who in the hell cares
whether anyone thinks someone else will go to heaven? (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Go to Hell"</ENAMEX>) Does this belief change one's ability to govern? This should only
matter if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> governing is governing over the place where admission to
same is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s prerogative. As long as the religious belief of the
person governing does not promote or condone acts of violence against those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">governed</ENAMEX>, or in the repression of those who fail to share his/her religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">convictions</ENAMEX>, then the beliefs that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> holds are not a newsworthy
event, or even the public's business. We in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> seem to give too
much weight to things that do not have any bearing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s ability to
lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. I couldn't have cared less if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extramarital</ENAMEX> affair, other than that he spent taxpayer money to get on
television and swear to us repeatedly that it did not happen. His affair has no
bearing on his ability to do his job ... his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dishonesty</ENAMEX> does. If we ever prove
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> has lied to us at our expense, then this will be a factor
that should be weighed in determining his ability to truly lead this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
But otherwise, so long as his religious convictions, no matter how weak or
strong they may be, are not geared toward the outright oppression or
destruction/neglect of those who fail to share his views, they should not
matter, and warrant no scrutiny.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey K.</ENAMEX>
Honor
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>

            
               Closing the
Circle
            

            I shall direct my remarks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen McGarrahan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>").
I, like you, on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4, 1990</TIMEX>, attended the legal execution of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Tafero</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State Prison</ENAMEX>. I, like you, was attending his
execution as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, not for my former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Highway Patrol</ENAMEX>,
but to complete a cycle. A promise to myself, as it were. You see, unlike you,
I was on the scene <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 19, 1976</TIMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Tafero</ENAMEX> shot and
killed state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trooper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip A. Black</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canadian constable Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> was unarmed. I will save you the description of the scene that
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, but it is indelible in my mind, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tafero</ENAMEX>'s execution obviously is in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yours</ENAMEX>. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>, you said, suffered for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven minutes</TIMEX>. I cannot tell you
the length of time it took Black and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> to die. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> was shot through the
eye. Black was shot multiple times and had a stun <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> used on him. Then the two
were left to die on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX>. I thought it more than a little curious that
you did not mention those fine law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in your article.

            I realize the purpose of
your article was to indict the electric chair, as well as to generate sympathy
for the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Tafero</ENAMEX>. Yes, the death penalty involves death.
Unfortunately, it is often the death of a law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> that
initiates the process. I am somewhat surprised that you did not invoke that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-worn liberal word "deterrent" somewhere in your article. But then your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> was not against the use of capital punishment, only the barbaric electric
chair. Well, I'm sorry that I cannot join your indignant outrage. If someone
being electrocuted in the chair, God forbid, happens to get burned or suffer a
nosebleed, so be it. One fact remains above all others; it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Tafero</ENAMEX>'s
choice.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Walston</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fort Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
