
   
   
      
         
            More <EM>Merde</EM>

            The
Mad <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cow War</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is still the most interesting subject in
the international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. It has brought out a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francophobia</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> that has to be read to be believed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, once a
byword for dignity, has a regular feature called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Centre of Attention</ENAMEX>" about
the hot topic of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s column, devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, plumbed
new depths of vulgarity. Beside a photograph of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>, the paper printed
the words: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pity la</ENAMEX> 
               pauvre vache . Less succulent than her
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, she's been good only for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>. Now we find she has been fed
the bodily by-products of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s least soap-conscious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Leaving her as
tasty as a draught from a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestler</ENAMEX>'s jockstrap."

            
Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> denials that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> are fed on human excrement--"No cow in
the world would eat sewage," a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> agriculture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> protested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>--this is the aspect of the dispute that
has captured the imagination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> 's campaign for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>' boycott of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is a
drawing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> with a beret on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and a roll of toilet paper hanging on
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> from its neck. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> expects every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopper</ENAMEX> to do their duty," the
paper proclaimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on its front page--evoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horatio Nelson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of Trafalgar</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> expects that
every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> will do his duty"--but also reflecting the decline in grammatical
standards in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 200 years</TIMEX>. (Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> exhortation to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>--"You must hate a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX> as you hate the devil"--was not quoted
anywhere, but was being widely followed in the spirit.)

            The
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> 's front-page headline, above a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>
halting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> with burning barricades at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Channel</ENAMEX> port of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calais</ENAMEX>,
was "Merde ! What a flaming cheek," and inside in an editorial it said,
"A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> proclaiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> from excrement-fed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> is safe
will only reinforce the commonsense view that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> fed in such a disgusting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> cannot possibly be healthy." So much for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> also
quoted a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> as saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> is an island--it is easier
to blockade than the Continent." He was presumably unaware of a famous prewar
headline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fog</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX>: Continent isolated."

            The
Times headed its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-French</ENAMEX> editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the kind of dreary
play on words that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fleet Street</ENAMEX> currently finds irresistible. "A reasonable
beef," it said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> should eat their words." The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said
in an editorial: "If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> really think they can force
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to buy their produce by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blockading</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calais</ENAMEX>, they had better
prepare for a long and unprofitable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> on the quayside. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]rying to
annoy your target market lacks the flair and subtlety for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
traditionally pride themselves." It also noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> national rugby
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>, currently in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> for that sport's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>, had ordered a meal of
roast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> service at their hotel in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windsor</ENAMEX> with "absolutely no
stipulations as to where it came from." The paper wished the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> "all
the best" in its semifinal on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mass-circulation Sun</ENAMEX> , now reportedly dumping its famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Page-3</ENAMEX> bare-breasted
pinups at the request of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, used the small
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>' protest at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calais</ENAMEX> as the excuse for an attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> for his pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Europeanism</ENAMEX>. "Is THIS what it means to be at the heart
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>?" it asked, beside a photograph of the burning barricade.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come on</ENAMEX>, Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>," it said in an editorial. "Start kicking backsides in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> press, by
contrast, was rather restrained. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> even seemed to support the idea of a
unilateral <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> imports. It said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> had the scientific
justification for such a gesture and that if he had decided to make it (which
he didn't), it "would without doubt have had the merit of calming the enormous
storm of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francophobia</ENAMEX> that is consuming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Isles</ENAMEX> at the moment." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> separately reported that, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is expected to lift its ban on imports of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Roquefort cheese</ENAMEX>, pâté
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of next month</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
