
   
   
      
         
            Ayatollahed You So

            
Security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> quelled student protests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> had
staged protests, thrown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>, and set police <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> on fire. Pro-government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> rallied right back. "" compares the uprising to civil war and the
fall of the Iron Curtain, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neshat</ENAMEX> argues that
revolution is "neither possible nor desirable."

            

               Peace talks broke down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Protestant unionists</ENAMEX>
rejected a plan to implement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s peace accord on the grounds that the
plan requires sharing power with the political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the still-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>. describes the clamor for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> to return the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace</ENAMEX>
Prize they won <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> reports that the post-breakdown finger-pointing is drowning out both sides' weary vows to continue the process.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> pledged to renew the peace process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said he
looked forward to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visit like "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> with a new toy," but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would refrain
from pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> into immediate action. At his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official
meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> promised to implement former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s still-unrealized diplomatic agreements, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> repeated calls to curb <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> settlements. Both meetings were deemed
key steps toward rebuilding relationships <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> had soured. Click to read

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> puncture the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> euphoria.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> asserted its autonomy from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> abandoned its "one
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>" policy, which implied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s sovereignty over and eventual
reunification with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. "Don't underestimate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s firm
determination to uphold national sovereignty, dignity, and territorial
integrity," warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Ministry</ENAMEX> in response. The Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> says the move "alarmed even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>," including
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, which quickly affirmed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> 
               reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> are ready to call what they
think is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">bluff</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> will end their standoff in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>-backed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> militants withdrew from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayan</ENAMEX> stronghold after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> talks
between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> still
refuses to budge. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pakistanis</ENAMEX> spun their pullback as a mutual cease-fire,
but as "" notes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> bragged of "a total military rout." The rest of the
world sighed with relief at what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> 
               called "an end to the latest confrontation between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s newest nuclear powers." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> editorial credits
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with quietly brokering the deal but warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> may
now be drawn into the conflict.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vuk Draskovic</ENAMEX> will try to oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. The hitherto-silent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Draskovic</ENAMEX> called for "massive rallies"
to topple the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 
               cautions that the effort may be sabotaged by a
crackdown from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> or by internecine quarrelling among opposition
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafael Resendez-Ramirez</ENAMEX> surrendered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national</ENAMEX> who
topped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> Most Wanted list and is suspected of killings in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> turned himself in under a plan brokered by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. He had been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apprehended</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for trying to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> illegally, but
had then been released, allegedly because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> had no information on his
record or his warrants.

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> passed compromise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' rights
legislation.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> defeated a plan to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> sue
their HMOs but approved more access to emergency care and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> protested that the reforms would apply to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than one-third</NUMEX> of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">161 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with private insurance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> awards
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> "a clean win on an issue of prime importance to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>" but foresees an election-time brawl. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> we saw what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'compassionate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservativism</ENAMEX>' pretends to be," harrumphed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikulski</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Herbert</ENAMEX> asserts that
managed care has bought <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> votes and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> will die as a
result.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> will forgo federal matching campaign funds. He explained
that being unconstrained by spending limits will give him "strategic
flexibility." "There's a chance I'll be running against somebody who will be
able to jump in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> airplane and travel the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> making promises,"
he said.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX> dropped his presidential bid. He endorsed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Shapiro</ENAMEX> eulogized
Kasich as "one of the most refreshingly outspoken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>" and
concluded that "another voice in the struggle to define the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s agenda is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stilled</ENAMEX>." Other analyses agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasich</ENAMEX> was intimidated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s haul of
money and endorsements, and wondered who might drop out next.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX> quit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> and will run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as an
independent. He castigated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for going soft on gun control
and abortion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will encourage unity by allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> to retain his
committee chairmanship and caucus membership. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> opined on
Face the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Nation</ENAMEX> that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> is doing its best
right now to almost force a fracture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> unveiled rival tax-cut plans. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance Committee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Roth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Del.</ENAMEX>, suggested slicing taxes by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>,
floated a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$850 billion</NUMEX> reduction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> called the cuts "a huge risk
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rangel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> proposal
"a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> that's supposed to appeal to every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>." In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> of supporting "big government 
                  on 
                  autopilot
               " and
argues that the cuts epitomize compassionate conservatism. But deficit-hawk
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Nunn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Rudman</ENAMEX> assert in the same pages that the surplus
should be used to pay down the deficit .

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vatican</ENAMEX> barred an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> from ministering to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. The decree accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeannine Gramick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nugent</ENAMEX> of an "erroneous and dangerous" failure to affirm the "intrinsic evil of
homosexual acts." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that the decree
"effectively ends the careers of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the most
prominent gay rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX>."

            
               A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.9 billion</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> burned by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exploded Chevrolet</ENAMEX> fuel tank. It is one of the largest product liability
awards ever. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> had produced documents demonstrating that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> resisted fireproofing fuel systems because it would cost an extra
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.59</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, who had fought to conceal the memos, called
the argument "absurd." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> clucks that "public trust
in product liability cases tried by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> might well be going down the drain
with these excessive awards ."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> charged an airplane maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> with murder in the Valujet
crash. The indictment blamed the deaths of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s negligence. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time criminal charges have been
brought over an accidental airplane crash in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            
               An
inexpensive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> will help prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> transmission from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> , which sponsored the trial,
predicted that the inexpensive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevirapine</ENAMEX>, will curb infection rates
in poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> is planning to sue the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and TV industries. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> will file
suits
against handgun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">importers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX> to force gun companies
to market their products more carefully. It may also sue TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> for
failing to depict minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in their shows. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kweisi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mfume</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are violating the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications</ENAMEX> Act , which specifies that the
airwaves belong to the public.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> dropped medical supplies to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Pole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> who found a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> in her breast. Weather conditions will delay her evacuation until at
least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnival Cruise Lines</ENAMEX> disclosed rape charges against its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have been accused of sexual assault <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> times in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> span ending
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>. The admission was ordered by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> presiding over a lawsuit by a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> alleging that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> tried to cover up her rape.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> profits doubled. Its stock subsequently jumped to an
all-time peak. Formerly skeptical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> raved about the popular iMacs and
predicted more good news with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s introduction of iMac laptops.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> soccer title. The
game was scoreless and ended in a penalty shootout. More celebrated was the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90,000</NUMEX>-strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, the largest ever for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s sporting event. Former Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Schroeder</ENAMEX> exults in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> "buries
some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> doll influence ," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's jubilant cover
story shouts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is "taking women's sports to the next level ," but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
               Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Vecsey</ENAMEX> wonders whether the
momentum to build a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> can be
sustained. 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> explains the feminist
implications of .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Body</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> will return to the wrestling ring. He will be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wrestling Federation</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 22</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SummerSlam</ENAMEX>" event. "It's
business that is separate from his gubernatorial duties," said an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> will play their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> concert in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>, Ringo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Harrison</ENAMEX> will commemorate the rerelease of the film Yellow
Submarine by playing a concert on a yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX> while floating down a
river in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liverpool</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
