
   
   
      
         
            eBabe

            This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, soft-porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Harris</ENAMEX> began auctioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> of fashion
models on the Internet. His site, ronsangels.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> (named after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the 1970s' babe</TIMEX> show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX> ), invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to "bid on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> from beautiful,
healthy and intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>." Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Seed</ENAMEX>, who recently declared
his intention to clone human beings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> has attracted the attention of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who are "looking into" whether he can be stopped. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> is a creep and that his site is an outrage. What they
don't agree on is why. Here's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have to say about the
auction--and each other.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Egg</ENAMEX> auctions will produce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer babies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> cites his
experience as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeder</ENAMEX> and asks, "We bid for everything else in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>--why not <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>?" Alarmists, agreeing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> "can put you into your
own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer baby</ENAMEX> by selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>," predict that his success will steer "the
future of human breeding" toward "genetic engineering."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Egg</ENAMEX> auctions will fail to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer babies</ENAMEX>. While
fretting about what will happen if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> succeeds, fertility experts
simultaneously debunk that scenario. "Not only is it ethically ludicrous, but
the fact is, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s going to look like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>'s picture," observes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ethicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Annas</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> give <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> reasons. First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of an
ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is just as likely to be ugly as to be pretty.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, everyone carries "recessive" genes, which are invisible in this
generation but may become visible in the next. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> with a small nose can
pass on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> for a big nose. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, even if both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are attractive, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> can combine their features unattractively. For example, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> can
inherit her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s weak nose and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s strong brow.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Egg</ENAMEX> auctions will promote the survival of the fittest.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doomsayers</ENAMEX> predict that once "beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> are available strictly to people
who are willing to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an ungodly</NUMEX> sum for them," the rich will transform
themselves into a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-race</ENAMEX>" reminiscent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>. To this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX>
replies, "It is not our intention to suggest that we make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super society</ENAMEX> of
only beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. This site simply mirrors our current society, in that
beauty usually goes to the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>." But this reply only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> concern
that gradually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">society</ENAMEX> will separate into "genetic haves and have nots."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Egg</ENAMEX> auctions will promote the survival of the unfittest.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> writes that only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with "substantial financial resources" are fit to
give his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>' offspring "a financially secure and stable life." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX>
wonder whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who sell their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> to the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who buy
these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> for the sole purpose of spawning good-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--may produce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> just as dysfunctional as themselves. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calgary Sun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sydney Sharpe</ENAMEX> put it, "Any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> ... who enters into this mephistophelian pact
has a few screws loose. Maybe her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> will, too. Not to mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> who
sign her up."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Egg</ENAMEX> auctions will fail to promote the survival of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unfittest</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, if not most, have had cosmetic surgery. A
model who is perfectly ruthless will conceal this fact when selling her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"angels</ENAMEX>" has already been caught lying about her age.) How does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> know whether his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> have had collagen injections and nose jobs?
"There's no way to know that. You can ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and hope she tells you the
truth," he says. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annas</ENAMEX> concludes that since there's "no way to know how much of
their beauty is a product of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, plastic surgery, a makeup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, or
exercise," only a "naive" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would buy their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> on the basis of the
photographs displayed on the site. "You don't want to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>," he
points out. "You want to see pictures of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>." On this theory,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> produced by the egg auction are likely to be the offspring of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liars</ENAMEX> on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> on the other.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Beauty doesn't convey health. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> casually asserts that
beauty "shows healthiness and longevity." On his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, he writes, " 'Natural
Selection' is choosing genes that are healthy and beautiful." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> question
this assumed equivalence, noting that traits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> find attractive in women these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>--thinness, for example--are often unhealthy. When asked on the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> show how much "medical screening" he has given his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> answered, "None."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Beauty is less meaningful than intelligence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> says
he's not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to market good genes. Others, he notes, have sold
sperm and solicited <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> on the basis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>'s intelligence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX>'
detractors reply that beauty is "superficial" and conveys a "harmful
preoccupation with exterior appearances over intelligence and content of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>." This critique is usually offered by a blow-dried TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>
who, after thanking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> for his time, urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to stay tuned for the
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starlet</ENAMEX> who will join the program after a brief commercial break.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Beauty is less useful than intelligence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> advertises
beauty not as an end but as a means to "success," since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are
physically desirable get more attention, power, and favorable treatment. Having
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chided Harris</ENAMEX> for exalting social advantage over "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> turn
around and adopt his ruthless logic. While conceding that beauty is useful,
they argue that intelligence is a better weapon in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s meritocratic
information economy--and that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> claims his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are "beautiful,
healthy and intelligent," he offers no evidence of brains, such as IQ or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>
scores. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> envisions "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bimbo</ENAMEX> births." A fertility
expert shrugs, "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150,000</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> of a gorgeous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who has an IQ of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>, let them."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. The auction exploits desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> preaches pure
capitalism, saying it's "unfair to put a limit on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s ability to make
money" by auctioning her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>. In turn, fertility <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> accuse
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> of "taking advantage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> trying to conceive" and exploiting
"desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ... susceptible to the dreams he is trying to sell." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> laments, "This is about human need. And human greed."

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. The auction exploits desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late Monday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> had only a handful of bids, and only one was verified as legitimate. On
the other hand, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had asked him to put their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> up for auction.
Gradually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> were the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> described the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> as "struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">actresses</ENAMEX>," reported that they
were unaware of the health risks of donating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, and quoted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> as saying,
"I'd rather do this than do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX> ." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX>' sole
verified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> was "better than
prostitution."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX>
constantly refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> as his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>" and describes them like
cattle--"We have a legitimate bid of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$42,000</NUMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>." He gets a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
percent commission on each winning bid, though he takes no responsibility for
executing financial transactions or medical procedures. "We have no control
over the quality, safety or legality of the items advertised, the truth or
accuracy of the listings, the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> to sell items or the ability
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> to buy items," he stipulates. His role, he explains, is simply to
"find beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, take beautiful photographs of them, [and] put them up on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>." To some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, the mystery isn't, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> suggests, how women
throughout history have exploited their sexual power over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, but how pimps
like him have come away with the profit.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. The auction exploits voyeurs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thinks Harris</ENAMEX> isn't targeting either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX>. He's not serious about
selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . He's just using the sex appeal of his
models and the intriguing perversity of a human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> auction to drum up
publicity and attract Internet traffic to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, from which he can sell
advertising and subscriptions (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24.95</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> to view profiles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>),
hawk his forthcoming book ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naked Power</ENAMEX> ), and direct prurient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to
his various porn sites. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for fertility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> suspects that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ronsangels</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is really aimed at "adolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>."

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. The Internet facilitates monstrous purchases. Technology
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">watchdogs</ENAMEX> call the egg auction another chapter in the cultural slide marked by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jennycam</ENAMEX> (a Web site featuring live video of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> undressing and doing
other normal activities in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>), the promised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webcast</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and
woman losing their virginity together (which turned out to be a hoax), and a
human kidney auction that was conducted and aborted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. "Ever
since the Internet, it seems to snowball more rapidly, this depersonalization
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and selling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>," one fertility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> complains to the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> says the egg auction "just might force an
Internet-obsessed society to finally sit down and ask itself: Where is the
Internet taking us?"

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. The Internet cheats <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of their monstrous purchases.
The only thing worse than buying human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> on the Internet, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, is not getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> you paid for. "When you have large
transactions of this kind conducted over the Internet, there may be fraud," a
computer crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> warns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lori Andrews</ENAMEX>, a reproductive
technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, warns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> that "there's very little that you can do
to prove that these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> actually came from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> that were expected," and
"the Internet just adds ... a layer that it makes it even more difficult to
scrutinize where the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> are coming from."

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Egg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> will reap unintended consequences.
Sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>' application of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>'s theories
to human professional success overlooks the interaction of genetics and human
psychology. To begin with, if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>' auction fails to turn
out as pretty as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> expected, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> may shun the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, or the child
may grow to hate herself for disappointing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. (On the Today
show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> said of this theory, "That's a pretty cynical view of human
nature.") <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> turns out pretty but doesn't want to be a beauty
queen, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> may force her in that direction anyway, thereby stifling her
true talents and preventing her from becoming successful. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s
good looks may attract too much attention of the wrong kind, eventually
destroying her. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> cite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX> as examples.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> don't pass on your genes. In defense
of his auction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Fisher</ENAMEX>'s statement that "having sex
is the most important act of your life. This is how we get our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> to the
next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> seems to have overlooked the crucial words:
"our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>." "The drive to send your own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> is much
stronger than the [drive] to pick out of a sperm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> site," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>
observes. This consideration may not affect single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, but it can be a
decisive turnoff for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>. On this view, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>' mistake is not that he
focuses too much on selfishness, but that he neglects it. He forgets that you
don't care about reproducing unless what you're reproducing is yourself.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. The power of beauty should be transcended, not exploited.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> preaches that the world rewards beauty because it's human nature to
favor those who are pleasant to look at, and therefore the way to have
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is to make sure they're attractive. The most ambitious
response is to attack the whole "prejudice" in favor of beauty. "The standards
of beauty do vary with the culture. And they are social facts, not really
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genetics</ENAMEX> facts," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings Center ethicist Bruce Jennings</ENAMEX>. Therefore, "we
should think about" whether to "accept the existing prejudices and then try to
eugenically manipulate them" or to transcend those prejudices.

            This
critique challenges <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> precepts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>' worldview. First, while pretending
to accept human nature as a given, he violates it by peddling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>' eggs
and encouraging the production of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who will probably never know their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>. Family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>, loyalty, and love are among the best parts of
human nature. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slavish</ENAMEX> catering to physically attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> is among the
worst. If we're going to challenge human nature, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> ask, why not start
with the latter rather than the former?

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> assumes
that the perfection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> want in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> coincides with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX>
perfection. "Every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> is trying to evolve to its most perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," he
writes. What he doesn't seem to understand is that human beings aren't quite
like other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, just as the rest of the world isn't exactly like the
modeling and soft-porn industries of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Humans</ENAMEX> have evolved
to a stage at which our ideas about virtue, perfection, and success have become
more than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. At least, most of us have.

         
      
   
