
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NRA Shoots To Kill</ENAMEX>

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> passed compromise gun control legislation. The
measure requires background checks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>-show sales but reduces the time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have to perform them from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. A tougher measure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resembling</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> legislation was defeated, despite ardent
lobbying by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> . Everyone agrees it's a coup for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX>, which had been taken for dead after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> explained the loss by asserting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> distorted the stricter
measure, claiming it would lead to confiscation and a national gun registry;
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are aware of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>' support for gun
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> but are unwilling to defy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> on the cusp of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election year</TIMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to decide whether to let the Ten
Commandments be displayed in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Proponents</ENAMEX> offered the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> as a response to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detractors</ENAMEX> called it an
unconstitutional violation of the church-state line. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> sincerely believe that this will prevent youth violence. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> sincerely believe that by attributing youth violence to immorality, they can relieve
pressure to pass gun control legislation.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> update: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to end its
occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> agreed to share control of the
airport but still demands its own peacekeeping zone. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is too <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>-friendly to be entrusted with such authority and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> won't resettle in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-controlled zone. The likely compromise: a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> "zone of responsibility" inside a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-controlled area. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s "" for gloating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> press.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> estimated ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> and unearthed a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> torture <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> full of
hideous paraphernalia and photos of suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 33,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> have fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, fearing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanian</ENAMEX> reprisals. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> urged them to trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> and stay. Meanwhile,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 46,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanians</ENAMEX> streamed back in, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s warnings of
land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> approved a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> plan to
bring down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. They claim the plan isn't directed at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> personally.

            

               A former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symbionese Liberation Army</ENAMEX> was
arrested. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> located <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Ann Soliah</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-to-do doctor</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, through tips from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s Most
Wanted . She was indicted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> for allegedly placing pipe bombs under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police cruisers</ENAMEX> (the bombs didn't explode). Her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> expressed
shock, citing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> involvement and her terrific casserole.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> is making Europeans ill. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> products were removed
from store shelves in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> after
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drinkers</ENAMEX> complained of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nausea</ENAMEX> and intestinal trouble. (See "" for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> reaction.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> traced the problem to a preservative used on
shipping pallets and a bad batch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX>, neither of which presents a
serious health threat. Financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say the serious threat is to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>'s
overseas sales, which make up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> of its profits.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> declared his candidacy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. His speech and
accompanying interviews stressed his independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> "the status quo," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
agenda will be "a very successful platform for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> to run from."
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX>
                and the 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
                printed editorials about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
euphoria.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thabo Mbeki</ENAMEX> replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>. This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> handover between democratically
elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> received a unanimously fond farewell . Former
apartheid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> called him "a saintly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," and a conservative white paper
declared that he will be "sorely missed."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> bought a stake in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX>. Their joint online
site will auction antiques, collectibles, and rare books. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spins: 1</ENAMEX>) It's a
revolution in online auctioning! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) No, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX> had already cut a deal with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butterfield & Butterfield</ENAMEX>, another art auction house. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The partnership
between the venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> and the brash startup will be awkward. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> says they're a good match: "We both got started as booksellers.
... It's just that we got started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">251 years earlier</TIMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Jackson</ENAMEX> will coach the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Lakers</ENAMEX>. He'll make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>
million for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. Predictions: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> will work the same magic with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> that he did with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The magic was all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s; no amount of coaching could save <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' underachieving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">egomaniacs</ENAMEX>. Click here for the mostly jubilant local reaction.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> kicked off his presidential campaign in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will do the same <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s declaration marks the earliest start ever to a
presidential campaign. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) No, he's been campaigning for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) So when will
he lay out his positions? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
               's "" on how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> flaunts the courage of his clichés. Click here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's luminous cover profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and
here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's more skeptical version.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> may release a final report criticizing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> says he won't try to indict them
but might publish a damning account of their behavior. The consensus prediction
is that this would jeopardize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s senatorial ambitions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> vows to
plot his course independent of the political consequences, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>
says he's "still on revenge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">autopilot</ENAMEX> ." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Carr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Stewart</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">digest Starr</ENAMEX>'s move--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>'s new book--in "."

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knicks</ENAMEX> reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA Finals</ENAMEX>. They are the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eighth seed</ENAMEX> (i.e., lowest-ranked playoff <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>) ever to
accomplish this feat. They will face the top-seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio Spurs</ENAMEX>. Sports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> debated whether it's a triumph for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Houston</ENAMEX>, a
previous underachiever who scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> points in the decisive game; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gundy</ENAMEX>, who had nearly been fired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the season</TIMEX>; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
whose prestige was already bolstered by cleaner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and lower crime.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> are trying to clone human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">embryos</ENAMEX>. The

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
                reports <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> attempts by private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to grow embryos--a practice banned among federally funded researchers
but allowed in the private sector. The sanguine spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are just
growing stem cells to cure <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>; they're not cloning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. The
pessimistic spin: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> will lead to the other.

         
      
   
