
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=630250921-01071999>Happy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX><SUP><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX></SUP> Birthday<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Hope You Die Soon</ENAMEX></SPAN>

             

            

               
                  New
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story rues the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> revolution. The expected horrors are invoked: the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revolution, the Great Leap Forward</ENAMEX>, the continuing anti-religious brutality of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>. ... As world population reaches <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 billion</NUMEX>, an
editorial calls for more investment in international
family planning. Encouraging smaller family size will boost economic progress
in the developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> are still exploding.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover editorial reiterates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s frequent
warnings that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy is overheated. Rising consumer debt is a bad
sign. Weak commodity demand and a strong dollar are staving off inflation, but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> should pre-emptively raise interest rates before the bubble bursts.
... An article remarks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>'s attempt to market
itself to libertine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. Apartheid-era <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> repressed homosexuals
and suppressed the sex trade. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cape Town promotes</ENAMEX> itself as a gay-friendly
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and welcomes sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1999</TIMEX>
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hagiographic John Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> tribute issue includes excerpts of his writing,
portraits of him with his interviewees, and an over-the-top photo of him bathed
in golden light. The issue is stuffed with tribute ads, including shoemaker
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Cole</ENAMEX>'s: "How do we follow in his footsteps<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" ... A countdown of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> great political moments includes dubious picks, such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Dodgers</ENAMEX>' relocation to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, and predictable ones: D-Day is No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s election is No. 1

            

               
                  Rolling
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 14</TIMEX>
            

            A
sympathetic profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> concludes that he is more sincere and more
dignified than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> refuses to offer
regrets for past <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use and does not coo-coo at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
               
offers a less rosy view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s .) ... A biting narrative exposes
life at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State</ENAMEX> sorority. Despite paeans to sisterhood and philanthropy,
girls join sororities to binge-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>, hook up, and pursue their Mrs. degree.
(For another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX> view, read 
                  Slate
               's sorority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> ".")

            

               
                  New
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 26</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> describes the newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> defense scheme<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">--75-miles</NUMEX>-per<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX> space
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cannonballs</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exoatmospheric Kill Vehicles</ENAMEX>" orbiting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> would be programmed
to collide with warheads. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> step: Build the prototype. ... The cover
essay reflects on hate, describing it as a personal psychological reaction to
idiosyncratic experience. It cannot be outlawed. We can only overcome hate by
refusing to give haters the attention they crave.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover package tweaks <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-wave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>--business-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grads</ENAMEX> lured by lucre rather than a passion for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>. ... Yet another startup saga sketches how a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.B.A.</ENAMEX> student
developed a Web-business idea: He set up a site, which uses an algorithm to
tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> where to take a date, by convincing venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX> to front
money, hiring tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to write code, working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17-hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, and bedecking
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> with inspirational quotes. ... An article alleges that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoys</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> have
pressured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> to obstruct <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s run for the
Reform Party nomination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> is the preferred roadblock, because his
candidacy could attract <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 29</TIMEX>
            

            Fetal
programming determines adult health, according to the cover story . Studies show that low birth-weight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> may
have a high risk of developing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, and prenatal trauma can impede brain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. The link between womb conditions and adult health undermines
studies that suggest <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> has genetic roots. ... An article warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX> might be dwarfed by future
storms. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The past 30 years</TIMEX> of meteorological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">quiescence</ENAMEX> is giving way to a
period of hyperhurricanes because of a change in oceanic conditions and global
warming. (According to "," the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX> on excessive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
consumption.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
27
            

            The
cover excerpt provides a reverent portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul</ENAMEX>
II. The pontiff is credited with inspiring the collapse of communism in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, persuading liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX> that freedom must be girded by public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">morality</ENAMEX>, and opening a dialogue with other religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a

                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>.) ... An article probes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s vulnerability on the firearms
issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s pro-gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> (he barred the prosecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who bring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> that don't specifically forbid <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>-toting) might hurt him in
a nationwide election. ... A profile marvels at the campaign-trail candor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. He recalls his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captors</ENAMEX> as "goddamn gooks," tells gay jokes,
and reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that he once called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX> ugly.

            

               
                  The
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27</TIMEX>
            

            An
essay bewails the absence of "political pizzazz" in presidential campaigning.
Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> is relatively sanguine, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are relatively
lethargic. The public longs for a deft <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX> who doesn't seem prepackaged.
... A profile praises <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garcia Marquez</ENAMEX>'s efforts to heal his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, as he struggles to overcome
lymphatic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>'s most-beloved figure convinced his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> to push leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> toward the peace table and convinced the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>'s hidden hand was necessary.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27</TIMEX>
            

            An
editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skewers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> for betrayal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is
shoe-horning himself into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> solely because of its eligibility
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX> in matching funds. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> bolts, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX> opportunity to define themselves against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s brand of pitchfork
conservatism. ... A review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s new book condemns its defense of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America First</ENAMEX>" foreign policies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan honors Charles Lindbergh</ENAMEX> as a heroic
voice of isolationism and outrageously argues that the West instigated war with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
