
   
   
      
         
            R<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-E-$-P-E-&cent</ENAMEX>;-T

            Once
the terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> had been
agreed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> started to worry about the financial effects
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s participation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segodnya</ENAMEX> pointed out that the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,600</NUMEX>-strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>--along with its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX>-member contingent
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>--will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $500 million</NUMEX> per year--for which "there is no money"
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1999</TIMEX> budget. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> mobilization will
leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chechen war</ENAMEX> in the hands of "untrained drafted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> with broken
weapons.") The "respect" shown to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> summit could also
prove costly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestiya</ENAMEX> said
that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> only pretended that everything was OK in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. ... One thing is to write off a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s debts and quite
another--to write off the debts of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> of elite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>."

            
Regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX>'s decision to write off much Third World debt, as long as the
money is redirected to social programs such as health, poverty reduction, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> education, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> said, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>]conomic good conduct
that requires tightening of belts and good governance is something that the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> World was badly in need of. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has been denied any
further debt relief until it has implemented the necessary reforms should be
enough to convince the Third World debt relief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">G8</ENAMEX> means
business." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Times of India</ENAMEX> struck a contrary note,
however, when it pointed out, "[A]s with all loan write-offs, the move is
unfair to those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that have repaid their loans."

            With
less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> to go before <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> deadline for a breakthrough on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s stalled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Friday Agreement</ENAMEX>"
on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> power-sharing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> are
showing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX> refuses to decommission its
weapons before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, its political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>, are seated in
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>, and since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Unionist leader</ENAMEX> refuses to
call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> to order before the IRA gives up at least some of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>,
the current stalemate seems fairly intractable.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Post</ENAMEX>
                called for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> to apply his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, saying, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t's time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> to assert his
position and power to effect change, demonstrated so clearly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> took a similar tack, observing, "The situation is far from precisely parallel, but it
is still a chastening thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX> is, under
conditions of vastly greater duress, handing in its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> at a rather faster
rate than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provisional</ENAMEX> IRA seems able to arrange." An op-ed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
News suggested that this might not be such a good thing, however. The
piece drew on the experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> (or, at least, one rather
skewed view of that experience) to argue against the disarmament of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX>. "A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> will come," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> argued, "when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> will have to be
protected from new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attacks</ENAMEX> and atrocities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbians</ENAMEX>. At that point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX> will not be able to provide this protection."

            Back
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that returning ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> are targeting gypsies for reprisals. The story says that the gypsies
are perceived to have "sided with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> during the war and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> of
repressive direct rule which preceded it." Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gypsies</ENAMEX> trying to leave
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> are being turned back by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. A "clear sign," according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , "that despite his defeat, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> is
still trying to ethnically engineer the future of the devastated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>." The
"justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> told the paper, "This is a tragic turn of events.
The gypsies were always the most oppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, but they
have been manipulated for so long by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> that it has destroyed much of the
feeling of social solidarity between them and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>."

            An editorial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Times</ENAMEX>
speculates that "pique seems to have figured prominently" in the selection this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend of Turin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, as the site of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter Olympic Games</ENAMEX>. The
paper reports that after scandals surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> venue selections, the
procedure was reformed so that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are
prohibited from visiting potential locations. Instead, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-member selection
panel narrows the field of possible venues to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> final <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX>, with the
final selection being made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2006</TIMEX> games, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>,
was the "clear favorite" of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX>, offering good venues, a "strong
tradition of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> sports," and "the political and economic security that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic Games</ENAMEX> need." However, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Times</ENAMEX> , "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> resent being given a fait accompli and voted against the
recommendation to remind the world just who makes the final choice." Another
"ugly" motive was anger at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claims, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss IOC</ENAMEX> member
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Hodler</ENAMEX> was largely responsible for exposing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> corruption. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> concludes, "Even the mere perception of bias or unfairness undermines
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> ideal. The only question is how far the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> must go to rid
itself of the taint it has acquired. Clearly, it [<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha</NUMEX>]s not yet gone far
enough."

         
      
   
