
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;Stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pressing&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the
Future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homemakers of America</ENAMEX> made a startling announcement. What?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis Management</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  
                     "I didn't even want to talk about chocolate-chip
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cookies</ENAMEX>, really. I shaved my beard and stopped wearing hats." Who said this
about what?
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Famous Amos</ENAMEX>, after being profiled and strip-searched one too many times on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Turnpike</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Ricci</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX>
Shalala, in reference to some new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> crap."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
Hotchkiss
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. I don't know what he was talking about, and I don't really
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>. What matters is that he can win this, and we're backing him all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "This
was the disillusioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> speaking days after performing the miracle of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">loaves</ENAMEX> and fishes. Knowing he had lost his grip on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> when they inquired
what was for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX>, he decided to make a radical change in his
life."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX>
            

            "Queen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>, complaining about just everything, describes the disguise that
enabled her to sneak out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> a day early."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Bodow</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cole</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            By far the most frequent response involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the once and future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX>, or nonbaker, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> begins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her four-day</TIMEX>
"listening tour" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moynihan Farm</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun With Juxtaposition: Which</ENAMEX> is the
more ludicrous expression, "listening tour" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> Farm"?) Unimpressed
with her upstate forays, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>, her likely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, boasts:
"Every time I have gone up there, I have gotten the sense that they like me. I
think they like what I did with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun With Prepositions: Instead of</ENAMEX>
"with" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, substitute "to.") Like him they may, but have any of them
written a tribute as passionate as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Powers</ENAMEX>' love letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morning</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ? (Some sentences omitted.)

            "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]he waits, like the
sentinel of an enchanted world, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> when it's safe to open up a trade
route. Her judgment has not always proven correct, but right now it is
impeccable. [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]hen you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of her magnitude, fashion will always return
to you, hanging its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. [S]he established herself as a mythical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>,
questing but always true to herself. Even at her most spectacularly styled, she
keeps a rough-and-tumble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vaudevillian</ENAMEX> edge. By maintaining an old-fashioned
ethic of showmanship, she seems exceptionally real." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun With Objects</ENAMEX>: Was
this flatulent blather actually about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> or was it perhaps about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX>?
Either way, just nuts, right?)

            
               There Are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX>
Acts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Baking Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wally</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Famous</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amos</ENAMEX> reveals his feelings about the
dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when his cookie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> collapsed.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amos</ENAMEX> started the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX>
borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin Gaye</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Reddy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> as a talent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, revenue reached <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX>. But like many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>, he
was not prepared to manage such a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, after attempts
at restructuring, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 million</NUMEX> and was sold. Under the terms
of the deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amos</ENAMEX> was not even permitted to use his own name for business
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ventures</ENAMEX>. That's when he hit rock bottom.

            Much has improved.
Keebler, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Famous Amos</ENAMEX>, just offered him a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> contract to
promote his old brand, and they are allowing him to use his name for his own
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish Environmentalism</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s Extra
squeezed a few cheap laughs out of a pamphlet for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society for the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advancement of Judaism</ENAMEX>, including their use of the phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Environmentalism</ENAMEX>," for which you were invited to provide even cheaper
definitions. Such as these:

            "What
has the ozone ever done for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "Not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peeing</ENAMEX> in the (indoor) pool at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grossingers</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot Cohen</ENAMEX>
            

            "No,
it's all right, I'll sit in the dark."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have You Ever Known Any Jewish</ENAMEX>
Jons With an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'h' in the Name?</ENAMEX>" Zerolnick
            

            "You
call THIS an environment?!? Feh! I'll show you an environment."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suffering in Silence"-- Alison "The WASP-y Name Is Not My Fault</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> has been planted in your name ..."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX>,
where once dead deserts lay, now flowering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> arise! <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zionism</ENAMEX> IS
environmentalism. Oh, and no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> allowed."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Good News Extra
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Missing Man is Found Alive and Stuck in Mud"</ENAMEX>--headline, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Zerolnick</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headline Haiku</ENAMEX>
            

            'You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX>'
doesn't inspire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academe</ENAMEX>

            
               --Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6, 1999</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> section)

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fields</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claus</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elf</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
