
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Naked and the Dead</ENAMEX>

            Late in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s
final film, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> , there's a harsh bit of piano music by the
Hungarian-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">György Ligeti</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> high note plinking over and over,
first slow, then hard and fast and cruelly untranscendent. The camera,
meanwhile, rests on the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Harford</ENAMEX>, who's only just comprehending the horror of what he has witnessed
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous 24 hours</TIMEX>--the bestial evil under the waltzing façade of
civilization. (The early part of the movie is scored with waltzes.) This moment
is meant to be soul-churning for both the character and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harford</ENAMEX> is played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX>, who is not, to put it gently, a thoughtful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruise</ENAMEX>'s brow is preternaturally low, and when he tries to simulate
brain activity he looks like a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Neanderthal</ENAMEX> contemplating his Cro-Magnon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s presentation of fire: What this orange snake make finger feel
hot? That the emotional climax of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s last movie is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX>
screwing up his face and feigning a tragic awareness while a piano goes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plink</ENAMEX> ... plink ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">plink-plink-plinkplinkPLINK</ENAMEX> is enough to make you
cry, but not the way the filmmaker intended. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Lear</ENAMEX> we
must ask, "Is this the promis'd end?"

            It is certainly the end
toward which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX> labored. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> reportedly discovered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schnitzler's 1926 Traumnovelle</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dream Novella</ENAMEX> , although it has
been translated as other things) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX>, spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> on the
updated and Americanized but otherwise faithful script (he shares the credit
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederic Raphael</ENAMEX>), and shot and reshot it for an eyes-wide-opening period
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only</NUMEX> after principal photography was finished did he
replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Jason Leigh</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sydney Pollack</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Richardson</ENAMEX>.) Eyes 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wide Shut</ENAMEX> , for better or worse, is the
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kubrick</ENAMEX> wanted to make--the fever dream that haunted him and that he
trusted would haunt us, too. But as usual with late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kubrick</ENAMEX>, the aspirations
seem more haunting than the plinking. The movie is a somnolent load of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wank</ENAMEX>.

            It's easy to see what drew the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnitzler</ENAMEX>'s
narrative. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> yields to a best-repressed impulse (the urge to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unfaithful</ENAMEX> to his true love) and gets launched on a dark odyssey, which
culminates in his near death and a vision of society's most ferociously
psychosexual underpinnings--civilization and its discontents and all that. The
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> sexual obsession with an epochal fear of sex: It says, "Don't go
there, you won't like what you see." The ingenuous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harford</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alice</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX>), attend a lavish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> party thrown by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ziegler</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollack</ENAMEX>), in which both are sexually propositioned. After a bout of jealous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">banter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> declares a smug faith in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fidelity</ENAMEX>, whereupon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX>--who has been smoking dope and quietly simmering--wallops him with the
news that she once came this close to abandoning him and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> she locked eyes with at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort hotel</ENAMEX>.

            His domestic stability
more precarious than he ever dreamed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harford</ENAMEX> is eaten at by fantasies of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>, and emerges from his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> into a kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walpurgisnacht</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>) of a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> blurts out a
wish to leave her fiance for him. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vinessa Shaw</ENAMEX>) picks him up. He
visits a costume shop in which the voluble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rade Servedzija</ENAMEX>)
discovers his pubescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leelee Sobieski</ENAMEX>) in flagrante with a pair of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. The film's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centerpiece</ENAMEX> is a sequence in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> perilously
crashes an ornately choreographed orgy in which the rich and powerful wear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cloaks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian</ENAMEX> masks and ogle long-legged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as they're marshaled and
disrobed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>. That he isn't supposed to be there dawns on him about
the time the masks turn his way and the conversation stops.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schnitzler</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Traumnovelle</ENAMEX> when he was
partially deaf and had withdrawn from the world, he chose to set the novella a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quarter-century</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, at the fabled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Viennese</ENAMEX> fin de siècle , when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> was spinning out NC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>-ish interpretations of dreams (he and Schnitzler
were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schnitzler</ENAMEX> himself was attempting to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casanova</ENAMEX>'s
record for the most orgasms with the most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steeped</ENAMEX> in Expressionism
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strindberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Dream Play</ENAMEX> had been mounted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few years</TIMEX>
earlier), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traumnovelle</ENAMEX> has a paranoid dream logic that feels inexorable
and a tone of breathless intimacy that smoothes out many of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">absurdities</ENAMEX>.

            That tone would have
been a snap for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Killing</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>), Lolita
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strangelove</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>), and a stretch after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>), when his storytelling acquired an all-purpose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lugubriousness</ENAMEX>. But by the end of his life <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kubrick</ENAMEX> had little stretch left: He
didn't extend himself to fit his material, he contracted his material to fit
his turgid tempos. That wins him points as an auteur but not as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>--someone who at least needs to make a show of finding his subject more
involving than his own voice. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX> can't manage to
get past his sour detachment and enter into the movie. He keeps the characters
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>'s length: When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> treats a half-naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who has overdosed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ziegler</ENAMEX>'s commodious commode, the shot is another of those fisheye specials
that makes the space seem cavernous yet oppressive; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kubrick</ENAMEX> seems more alert to
the color scheme--the towel that covers her breasts matches the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">turquoise</ENAMEX> of
the shower--than to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s suffering (which will later be of more than
passing significance). 

            How many takes did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> into to get
performances this flamboyantly bogus? The early scenes are the most maladroit.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandor Szavost</ENAMEX>) who whirls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> around on the dance floor while
purring suave come-ons is like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX> parody, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giggly</ENAMEX> responses (she's supposed to be drunk) recall <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie Griffith</ENAMEX> at her
most airheaded. The pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> who try to pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harford</ENAMEX> have dialogue
so stilted that it could have been written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>. The unease Kubrick
generates is a little like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet's</ENAMEX>: You can't tell if everyone sounds so phony
because they're all part of a scheme to hoodwink the protagonists or because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX> has forgotten how human beings talk. Or maybe it's all a--woo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">woo</ENAMEX>--dream.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> has
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">timeless</ENAMEX> feel, and I don't mean that as a compliment: It supposedly takes
place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> in the present, but it's estranged from any period I
recognize. Who are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kidman</ENAMEX>, who act as if no
one has ever made a pass at them and are so deeply traumatized by their
newfound knowledge of sexual fantasies--the kind that mainstream culture
absorbed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX>? Where do these heroically
self-sacrificing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> come from? Who are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aristocrats</ENAMEX> whose limos
take them to secret masked orgies in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX>? Even dream plays
need some grounding in the real world. There might have been a way to
make the movie work if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> hadn't been so abstracted, so generic.
But in an evocative (if self-serving) piece in The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX> notes that his original script was ultimately "blanched of all the
duplicity that made it alive" for him, that at every turn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX> took out
details of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> in pursuit of an underlying archetype. I don't know how
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> whose central theme is the loss of humanity can be so uninterested
in the minutiae of human speech and behavior.

            Posthumous tributes have emphasized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s
unkempt-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-teddy-bear warmth and blamed the myth that he was "cold" on
entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> determined to make him pay for his (sensible)
decision to remove himself from their orbit. But the coldness that has become
synonymous with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s name has little to do with his life, and everything
to do with the clinical distance he maintained from his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stripping</ENAMEX> (to a waltz) that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidman</ENAMEX> does in the first frames of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide</ENAMEX>
Shut serves only to display her high, tight buttocks and long thighs--the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of many high, tight buttocks and long thighs in the movie--and has
nothing to do with who she is. Where's the drama in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s (and our)
realization that she's fundamentally unknowable when she has been photographed
from the outset as a blank, leggy doll?

            The movie's lone masterful sequence is the one that
features a batch of blank, leggy dolls, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> are
hidden behind expressive masks. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cruise</ENAMEX> moves past the fornicating satyrs and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satyrettes</ENAMEX> to the euphonious dronings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jocelyn Plook</ENAMEX>'s music, one feels
Kubrick, at last, is in his element. He doesn't need to force his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> to
caricature their behavior in the name of some "archetypal" truth because those
masks are already so marvelously archetypal. The most vivid moments in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s films in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 30 years</TIMEX> have come when he has turned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s
faces into masks: Think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm McDowell</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Clockwork Orange</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nicholson</ENAMEX> in The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shining</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent</ENAMEX>
D'Onofrio in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Full Metal Jacket</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>). Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kubrick</ENAMEX> would have made
nothing but masterpieces if he'd put big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> or Venetian masks on all
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>. You can stare at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruise</ENAMEX>'s mask as he takes in the orgy and swear
you see the wheels turning in his head. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> thinking is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s most
startling special effect.

         
      
   
