
   
   
      
         
            
<P><SPAN class=760110315-12101999><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Sikorski</ENAMEX></SPAN></P>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Captain's</ENAMEX> log: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">0430 hours</TIMEX>, underway in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX>, steaming northeasterly along the southern coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>. The
phone ringing in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> awakens me; it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conning officer</ENAMEX> on the bridge
making a report of a vessel that we have in sight approximately <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12 miles</NUMEX> away.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conning officer</ENAMEX> is guided by my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing Orders</ENAMEX>, which is a compendium of
actions to take when I'm not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>. As directed, she is notifying me
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> is on a head-on collision course with us and we need to
maneuver to pass clear of each other. Her recommendation to turn to starboard
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 degrees</NUMEX> conforms with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Navigational Rules</ENAMEX>; I agree and ask
her to watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> until it is well past and clear. At sea, this scenario
is repeated numerous times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. Safe navigation between <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> is based
upon simple mathematics ... add the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vectors</ENAMEX> representing each <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> and
speed to determine if we are trying to occupy the same piece of ocean;
henceforth known as a collision. We have several technically sophisticated
computers that actually calculate the "closest point of approach" between our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conning officer</ENAMEX> uses some common sense to verify the
computer solutions with what is actually happening. I have the final call on
all maneuvers to safely pass clear of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0630 hours</TIMEX>: My morning wake-up call and workout.
Since it is <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Columbus Day</ENAMEX>, we are in "holiday routine"; no reveille. Weather
remains very fair; it's already <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">66 degrees</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">light northeasterly</NUMEX> winds;
barometer is holding steady; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seawater</ENAMEX> temperature is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">65 degrees</NUMEX>. We are
all very excited that the weather is turning much warmer; it's a far cry from
the howling gale we encountered as we exited the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strait of</ENAMEX> Magellan <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly two</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45 to 50</NUMEX> knots, the wind <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrieked</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> and was
actually tearing off the tops of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25-to-30-foot</NUMEX> seas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seawater</ENAMEX>
temperature was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">36 degrees</NUMEX>! We beat ourselves up trying to work our way north;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> was rolling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30</NUMEX> plus degrees. All kinds of things broke free, including
a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> of free weights in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hangar</ENAMEX> and our <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12-foot</NUMEX> wardroom dining
table. We came through a bit battered, but thankfully no one was hurt.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0730 hours</TIMEX>: A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> collision-avoidance report
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conning officer</ENAMEX>; another large merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> trying to occupy the same
piece of ocean.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0800 hours</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, and lots of good
conversation. Since we are on a rather long trek up the eastern coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, the routine has settled down somewhat from the hectic pace of the
previous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>. At the top of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every hour</TIMEX>, the bridge calls down to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineering Control Center</ENAMEX> to record the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seawater</ENAMEX> temperature from an engine
room gauge. To liven things up a bit, the engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> watch has calculated and
reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seawater</ENAMEX> temperatures in units other than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Fahrenheit</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelvin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rankin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celsius</ENAMEX>--the bridge didn't think it was too funny. In a similar vein,
several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> have braved the elements by appearing at our daily
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-hands gatherings on the flight deck without coats; only to be outdone by a
petty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who wore shorts through the frigid <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strait of</ENAMEX> Magellan!

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1100 hours</TIMEX>: Voyage planning; calculating distances
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> consumption rates to finalize port calls off the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern</ENAMEX> coast of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200 hours</TIMEX>: Observed following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX>:
Received ship's position report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">navigator</ENAMEX>. Current position is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
degrees <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19 minutes</TIMEX> South latitude and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">047 degrees</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">52 minutes</TIMEX> West longitude
(<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 1,700 miles</NUMEX> south of the equator). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conning officer</ENAMEX> reports that all
small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition</ENAMEX>, and pyrotechnics have been inspected. Traditional eight
bells are struck.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1245 hours</TIMEX>: Made a round of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>. Clouds are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thickening</ENAMEX>; looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>. We are making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> knots on a northeasterly heading;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seawater</ENAMEX> has become bluer and has risen to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">67 degrees</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineering</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> is
operating well; temperature between the main diesel engines--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elwood</ENAMEX>--is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">98 degrees</NUMEX>; in the high southern latitudes the temperature was
barely <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 degrees</NUMEX>. The evaporator is supplying us with enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to keep up
with our consumption. Bilges beneath the operating machinery are dry and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1300-1600 hours</TIMEX>: Shuffled paperwork; reviewed
reports and signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> logs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crew</ENAMEX> is enjoying a day of rest
watching movies and playing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morale Committee</ENAMEX>-sponsored spades
tournament.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1700 hours</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ate</ENAMEX> dinner in the wardroom.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2120 hours</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrote Night Orders</ENAMEX> outlining
supplemental instructions for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> watches to follow.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2300 hours</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Engineer officer</ENAMEX> and I won our first
round of the spades tournament.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0000 hours</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steaming</ENAMEX> under a canopy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>,
gently swaying to the ocean swells; glowing lights on a distant shore. Another
day at sea is complete.

         
      
   
