
   
   
      
         
            Chat

            Join us for the
exclusive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>-only 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chat</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of 
                  Slate
               , as he gives us a look at the coming elections.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> will discuss the impact of the Internet on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' campaigns and how
elections may never be the same.

            
               A little
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>:
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> formed 
                  Slate
                in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1996</TIMEX>. Previously, he was
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Republic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> , for which he continues to act as a substitute
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX>. He is a contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> and
has also been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> survey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Economist</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> your calendars now,
because coming up every other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:00 p.m. PT</TIMEX>, you can chat
with other notable 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>, and
opinion-makers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo Howard</ENAMEX> (Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>.

            

               Got a question for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>? Click here to post it in "The
Fray." We'll compile the best ones, and he'll answer them--as well as take live
questions--during the chat at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 pm PT</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 29</TIMEX>.
            

            To
read 
                  Slate
               , click here .

            Only

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> have access to 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'
               s exclusive
chats, occurring every other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m. PT</TIMEX>. To subscribe,
click here. To renew your subscription, click here.

         
      
   
