
   
   
      
         
            Being <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>

            When
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> brag about their "dialogue with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,"
as they inevitably do, what they really mean, of course, is their "monologue at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." They orate, you write a check. This is not conversation,
it is a sales pitch. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s idea of give and take is you give, I
take.) Even the much-vaunted campaign Web sites allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> no more
engagement than sending an e-mail off into the inky void.

            But it
is an Internet axiom that there are no one-way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netizens</ENAMEX>, a
"national conversation" requires actual discussion. There are plenty of Web
sites that will feed you political information--see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>'s "" for the
best--but where can you go on the Net to debate, bicker, blab, argue, spar,
kvetch, or just plain gossip about the presidential campaign? Where can you
play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cybergabber</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX>?

            The
first stop is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usenet</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of political newsgroups are gearing up for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alt</ENAMEX>.politics.election is the most fertile of these
bulletin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>, but other heated campaign confabs can be found at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alt</ENAMEX>.politics.<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republicans</ENAMEX>, alt.politics.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal</ENAMEX>, alt.politics, alt.politics.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">usa,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alt</ENAMEX>.politics.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>, us.politics, alt.current-events.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clinton</ENAMEX>.whitewater, and
others. (If you're not used to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usenet</ENAMEX>, you can access the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Deja</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            
Newsgroupies aren't yet fixated on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, so to find campaign chat you'll have
to bypass endless threads about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waco</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, and
Masonic conspiracies. But once you do find it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usenet</ENAMEX> campaign talk is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tonic</ENAMEX>. At their best, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> spin off both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Frankenesque</ENAMEX> quips and
high-minded colloquies about campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">alt</TIMEX>.politics, for example,
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple of dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> drilling down on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
health-care proposal. Meanwhile, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Athanaric</ENAMEX>" capped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an alt</TIMEX>.politics.<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republicans</ENAMEX>
debate on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> use with an endorsement of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">powderhead</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>: "Stoners ... just sit around hitting the bong, watching
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, and sending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> out to bring back some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bell</ENAMEX>. Real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cokehead</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> would be running around getting things done. You can't sit
still and be lethargic after doing a fat rail! I'm for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> here." (It must be
admitted that there is a lot more quipping than wonking in these debates.)

            The
newsgroupies are wonderfully vitriolic. Many of the discussions are flame wars,
and almost all are uncivil. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> are the clear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">champions</ENAMEX>: A thread
titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> shoot <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the back" is easily trumped by
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> believe in raping their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>.") But the intimacy of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsgroups</ENAMEX> frequently borders on claustrophobia. You'll see the same names and
the same harangues over and over if you stay too long in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usenet</ENAMEX>
attracts more than its share of obsessives (most are garden-variety Waco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conspiracists</ENAMEX> or anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loonies</ENAMEX>). Many threads that begin by analyzing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign end by denouncing the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vice Criminal" and the "First</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rapist</ENAMEX>."

            For
less rant and more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> to the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Webzines</ENAMEX>.

                  Slate
               'sown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, "," always has several active campaign threads,
usually pegged to "Ballot
Box " or "Frame
Game " columns. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Fray</ENAMEX> is linked to specific ,
campaign-related articles, it tends to stick to the election and not meander
off into conspiracy land. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> also has lively campaign chat in its
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Table Talk</ENAMEX> "
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>: It tends to be more conversational but less focused than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Fray</ENAMEX> (he
says unbiasedly).

            The
portal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are trying to grab a share of the campaign palaver, too. Yahoo!
hosts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several dozen</NUMEX> political discussion "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>." Most claim only a handful of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>), but some of the larger ones are
quite lively, especially "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fear</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loathing on Campaign 2K</ENAMEX> " and "Campaign
Techniques ," where they were debating whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> should ever
make campaign promises when I visited. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSN</ENAMEX> offers a similar array of
Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> , though they are far less active. Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and MSNBC
are chockablock with political bulletin boards, though they too are tepid.

            Sadly,
otherwise abundant political sites such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Junkie</ENAMEX> don't
embrace conversation. Only Primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diner</ENAMEX> has a forum worthy of the name. I learned more
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons of the front-loaded primary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> from the prattlers
at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Primary Diner</ENAMEX> than I have from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> watching.

            When
you tire of the staidness and bipartisanship of the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBSs</ENAMEX>, invade the
free-fire zones of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FreeRepublic</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucianne</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
               . These are the spawning grounds of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vast Right-Wing Conspiracy</ENAMEX>. FreeRepublic gained a modest name for itself
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal as a haven for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> haters, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucianne</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is
the queendom of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doyenne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucianne</ENAMEX> and FreeRepublic
serve presidential chat laced with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arsenic</ENAMEX>. Specially targeted: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> for
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flaccidness</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for enviro-kookiness. (These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are
proudly conservative, except when it comes to intellectual property law. They
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reprint</ENAMEX> articles--or huge chunks of articles--from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> without
seeking copyright permission.)

            You
can also conduct your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> debates purely by e-mail on a politics listserv. The
listserv I'm on--subscribe by sending the message "sub politics [your name]" to
listserv@aloo.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">netaxs</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>--has not
yet focused on the campaign, but will as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> beckon. (You
can search for political listservs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-Soft .
Please tell us if you find a great <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.)

            The
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are beginning to acknowledge all this online campaign
talk, if only halfheartedly. Most of them have participated in live chats at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. (Read the transcripts of the better <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> chats here . Look for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allpolitics</ENAMEX> section toward the bottom of the page.) But the chats are basic Q
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatters</ENAMEX> ask routine questions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate types</ENAMEX> back a canned
response. It's too bad the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' lone exposure to Internet talk is so
denatured, so polite, and so very dull. They could learn something--not much,
perhaps, but something--from the lively, nasty online discussions they're
missing.

         
      
   
