
   
   
      
         
            Chance and Consequences

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run Lola Run</ENAMEX> should, by rights, have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commas</ENAMEX> in its title, but commas would be false to its tempo, which is
alternately whooshing and staccato. !!!(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">RunLo//laRUN)//</ENAMEX>!!! would be
closer to the mark. This gimmicky <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> thriller, poised to be a crossover
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smash</ENAMEX>, is that rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>: a good "music video" movie. That is, it's
both fractured and fluid, with a helter-skelter syntax and a ceaselessly
infectious backbeat. Beyond that, it's a blast.

            The premise is both
simple and spherical. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">radish-haired Lola</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franka Potente</ENAMEX>) gets a panicky
call from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moritz Bleibtreu</ENAMEX>), who's in a phone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX>: Why didn't
she join him at the site of his big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> deal? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souped-up</ENAMEX>, black-and-white
flashbacks illustrate her absence and his anguish<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Her motorbike</ENAMEX> was stolen,
she couldn't pick him up, he left a bag of drug money on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
will kill him if he doesn't come up with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100,000 marks</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>. The camera
rides in on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lola</ENAMEX>'s mouth as she shrieks at the prospect of losing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Zoom
in on the clock<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">: 20 minutes to noon</TIMEX>. The phone arcs through the air. As Lola
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dashes by</ENAMEX>, the camera revolves around her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, then swoops in on a TV
screen where a cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lola</ENAMEX> is flying down a circular staircase past a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s barking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and out into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, where she's live-action again
and ready to run for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>'s life. I've left out maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> shots, and
it's still just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first five minutes</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Mitchell</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run Lola Run</ENAMEX> as
"a video game that even resets itself at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of each</TIMEX> round." He means that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lola</ENAMEX>'s race against the clock concludes and then begins again, the story told
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with different permutations and wildly different outcomes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
always die, but never the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: It depends on how fast the cartoon Lola
makes it down those circular stairs. In one go-round she's tripped and forced
to hobble, which means she doesn't bump into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with the baby <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriage</ENAMEX>,
which means she doesn't arrive at her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to catch the
exchange between him and his pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, which means she doesn't stop her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> from robbing a supermarket, which means ... This is the other extreme
from those <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens or Hardy</ENAMEX> novels in which someone's fate depends on his or
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>; here, who lives or dies is a matter of a chance <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-second</TIMEX> or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> glance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who cross <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lola</ENAMEX>'s path are frozen in the frame, their
futures telescoped in rapid-fire black-and-white snapshots: In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> variation, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lola</ENAMEX> bumps ends up destitute and prematurely dead; in another, she
wins the lottery. All because of where her path crossed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lola</ENAMEX>'s run.

            If you watch a lot of
Star 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trek</ENAMEX> spinoffs, you're no stranger to time loops, temporal
fluxes, and the rippling consequences of chance--all staples of post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
Hawking pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sci-fi</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run Lola Run</ENAMEX> is more than the sum of its
gimmicks: It has a real worldview. The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Tykwer</ENAMEX>, seems
determined to kiss off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sturm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">und</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drang</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of German
culture. His running, red-haired riot grrrl <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> for openness, crazed
optimism, and a belief in endless possibilities--all of them underlined by
multiple angles, split screens, slow and fast motion, and blizzards of
hyperbolic imagery. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lola</ENAMEX> can breathe life back into her injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, whose
illicit love affair is viewed as if it were a fuzzy video on a tired afternoon
soap opera. She can charge through a flock of nuns (take that, Catholicism!),
rob a huge bank (take that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capitalism</ENAMEX>!), and stop a roulette wheel with her
glass-shattering scream (take that, Chance!). She can goof something up and
then replay the sequence until she gets it right, taking the narrative into her
own hands. The movie could be dismissed as all adrenaline-swamped pyrotechnics,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adrenaline</ENAMEX> can be its own justification: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run Lola Run</ENAMEX> , it makes
stuff happen big-time.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O scar Wilde</ENAMEX>'s comedies are doubtless long-winded, but
their wind blows in from a high peak: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' formulations are bracing,
and their epigrams have a sting. In the new, all-star adaptation of An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ideal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Husband</ENAMEX> , one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s richest plays, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Parker</ENAMEX> has
practically pared the speeches down to their topic sentences. The movie is
diverting enough--it's good fun--but much of the genius is gone with the
wind.

            The plot is ever
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contemporary</ENAMEX>. Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Chiltern</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Northam</ENAMEX>) is esteemed by the world and
revered by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cate Blanchett</ENAMEX>). He is that rare thing, a public
figure with an unblemished past. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s protagonists all have dark
secrets, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiltern</ENAMEX>'s turns out to be a doozy. His fortune rests on a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-decades-old piece of insider trading involving a successful international
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">canal</ENAMEX> scheme. An incriminating missive has fallen into the hands of an
unscrupulous fortune <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX>, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheveley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianne Moore</ENAMEX>), who's happy to
destroy it if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiltern</ENAMEX> trashes his high ideals and throws his support to a
real-estate scam in which his blackmailer is heavily invested. Exposure would
be devastating to both his political and marital future, but how can he violate
his principles? Help arrives from an odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goring</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Everett</ENAMEX>),
a rich, indolent bounder and somewhat halting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiltern</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabel</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie Driver</ENAMEX>). An ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX> of Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheveley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goring</ENAMEX> can match her in
Machiavellian wiles. But can he help to repair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX>'s shattered faith?

            Reviewing An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ideal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Husband</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1895</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bernard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> wrote that "the modern note is struck in Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Chiltern</ENAMEX>'s assertion
of the individuality and courage of his wrongdoing as against the mechanical
idealism of his stupidly good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and in his bitter criticism of love that is
only the reward of merit." This idea is probably more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shavian</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibsenite</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Wildean</ENAMEX>, but the larger point is clear: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> was more concerned with
exploding the notion of an "ideal" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> than with punishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiltern</ENAMEX>'s sin,
and in showing that part of becoming human is learning to forgive others'
lapses. That "modern" note is largely absent from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX>'s adaptation, in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">soulful center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blanchett</ENAMEX>'s performance is radiant in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forthrightness</ENAMEX>. She's so good, you don't want her illusions to be dashed. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suspense</ENAMEX> is that of a conventional melodrama: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Chiltern</ENAMEX> defy Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheveley</ENAMEX>
in the name of truth? And will the shiny-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> get to see him do
it?

            At his best, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> brings out the waltzingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">malicious undercurrents in Wilde</ENAMEX>'s "polite" intercourse, and his camera is at
just the right distance to catch the anxious flickers of individuality under
the socially mandated poses. That tension is superbly embodied in Julianne
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, who issues poisoned ultimatums from behind a smile frozen firmly in
place and an erect <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriage</ENAMEX> that carries only subtle traces of the warped inner
being. She and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northam</ENAMEX> have scenes of deliciously controlled viciousness.
Almost as good are her scenes with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Everett</ENAMEX>, who can't quite transcend his
languid self-love enough to make us believe that he once had a thing for her.
He's less credible yet making cow eyes at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie Driver</ENAMEX>, whose tomboyish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gumption</ENAMEX> is often charming but more often strange.

            The schlock-waltz score (at times bordering on
calliope music) by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Mole</ENAMEX> is one of the most grating ever written: It has
a way of making the lines seem facetious. Was the hope that middlebrows would
be seduced by its jaunty sentimentality and highbrows take it as ironic? It's
hard to know what is meant as irony. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX> transposes one scene to the inside
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>--where, of all things, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Importance of Being Earnest</ENAMEX> is
having its legendary premiere. Quite a tribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>, except that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> now talks over the lines of another set and pays
no attention to the action on stage. The result is not a fugue but an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impertinence</ENAMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">would Wilde</ENAMEX> have made of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so indifferent to both
Earnest and his own famous curtain speech (here delivered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culkin</ENAMEX>)? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX>'s "tribute" ends up making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> seem both prolix and
irrelevant. Was that the intention? To make his own adaptation seem more
savvy?

         
      
   
