
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">284</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Gamy&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>,
speaking on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sperling</ENAMEX> said it reminded him of the game "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Twister</ENAMEX>." What?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 283</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Storm Warnings":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     The current issue of a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> lists these warning
signs: stain, unusual odor, the sound of broken glass or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX>. What
publication, what danger? (Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O'Grady</ENAMEX>.)
                     
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosmopolitan ; another 'Rate Your Man in Bed</ENAMEX>' quiz."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia V. Bastani</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Car and Driver</ENAMEX> ; how to tell when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Expedition</ENAMEX> has hit another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Festiva</ENAMEX>. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedans</ENAMEX> can become wedged in the suspension and cause damage, you
know."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cole</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Reiness</ENAMEX> )

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
new Starbucks-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> joint venture, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> ; frankly, I think they're
overstating the dangers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folgers Crystals</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Catholicism Today</ENAMEX> ; advising its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> how to stay clear of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa</ENAMEX>'s miracle 'misfires.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ballard</ENAMEX>
            

            "If I
remember, this was the last issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> . I got as far as
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> before I nodded off and toppled a glassful of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prune juice</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rug</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Gaffen</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Before the Battle</ENAMEX>, Mother," one of the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular</ENAMEX> songs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a million</NUMEX> copies in sheet music, an
interesting thing to contemplate (or call for at a karaoke <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>) as we await the
debut of Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> (as I understand it, an abbreviated form of the
original title<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, Talk Is Cheap</ENAMEX> ) and the resumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>-mocking.

            It's as if we were monologue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> for a
late-night talk show who knew that tomorrow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> would rise from the
dead, recant his resignation, resume the presidency, and start having sex with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joey Buttafuoco</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humbling</ENAMEX>. It's not often that life gives
you a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> chance to do pretty much what you did when you had your first
chance.

            Some of you might feel
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trafalgar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yamamoto</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giap</ENAMEX>
before <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tet</ENAMEX>. Are you worthy? Judging by the magazine savvy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s responses,
I face <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> with confidence, eager to see you react to the premiere issue
of Talk (as I understand it, an abbreviated form of the original title
All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk, No Action</ENAMEX> ), proud to be among we few, we happy few, we band of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quizzers</ENAMEX>.

            
               First-Class
Answer
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Life</ENAMEX> , the in-house <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service</ENAMEX>.

            Signs that an unmarked package contains hazardous
material--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAZMAT</ENAMEX>.

            A photo accompanying an article in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>-August
issue shows a letter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> holding a parcel that is smoking, presumably
another danger sign.

            The article proudly notes that the postal service
was in no way responsible for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> crash of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valujet</ENAMEX> Flight 592 in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> Everglades.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> has never been a contributing factor to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> crash," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>'s aviation mail security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlton</ENAMEX>, with barely a hint of disappointment. "And that's an impressive record
considering we could have mail on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56,000</NUMEX> flights a day!"

            Not all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAZMAT</ENAMEX> is taboo.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> will carry "nail polish, household cleaning supplies, dry ice
... some infectious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> and clinical specimens" if they are properly
packed and labeled so as to pose no threat to health or safety of postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> or the mail-reading public.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Cloutier</ENAMEX> Signs
In
            

            END CONSTRUCTION

            Street sign or protest sign?

            And then we sing:

            END CONSTRUCTION!

            END CONSTRUCTION!

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ENDCONSTRUCTIONENDCONSTRUCTION</ENAMEX>!

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Word on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Charybdis/Caribdis</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Newman</ENAMEX> was right. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charybdis</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
spelling and became the preferred English spelling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> spelling
cannot be precisely rendered in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> characters because not all the letters in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> alphabet have exact analogs.

            For a very brief
discussion, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spelling</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> Names, which also explains that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> might prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Kharybdis</ENAMEX> as a truer transliteration of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger "Cogito Ergo Spud</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Think Therefore I Yam</ENAMEX>)" Hipp
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monkey News</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Which of these recent headlines and its
accompanying lead is an actual news story, and which is my way to give you a
few moments of amusement and some pointed social commentary because I like you
and just want you to be happy?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HONG KONG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BANS MONKEY FEEDING</ENAMEX>
Stifled by traffic and smog <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> know the value of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> for peace and quiet. That is, except for the wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX> ...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. NYC OFFERS <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 MILLION</NUMEX> TAX ABATEMENT TO
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MONKEY</ENAMEX>
Citing similar offers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ernst</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX>, and noting that
"This is a very wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> who will create a lot of jobs, you stupid
bastards," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> announced ...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">FIVE</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEOPLE ARRESTED FOR POACHING YUNNAN GOLDEN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MONKEYS</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been given jail sentences of varying lengths by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deqing County</ENAMEX> in southwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yunnan Province</ENAMEX> for poaching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yunnan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yunnan</ENAMEX> golden <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> is under state protection,
similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant Panda</ENAMEX> ...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">YOUNG GEORGE W. DRANK HEAVILY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STRANGLED</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MONKEY</ENAMEX>
Describing a troubled phase of his early life that he says ultimately brought
him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> recalled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> binge that ended with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corpse of Pepe</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rhesus monkey</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Zoo</ENAMEX>, floating face down in
...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ANGRY MONKEY BITES STEWARDESS</ENAMEX> IN LATEST CASE OF
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">AIR RAGE</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> up with long lines, cramped seats, indifferent service, and third-rate
movies with the hot parts edited out, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ChiChi</ENAMEX> ...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BANGLADESH POLICE CAPTURE DRUG-DEALING</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MONKEYS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bangladeshi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> said on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> they had captured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX> trained to
deliver <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dhaka</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BANGLADESH COPS RESCUE DRUG MONKEYS</ENAMEX>
(Same story, different spin.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> say they have rescued <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">spider monkeys</ENAMEX>
who had been trained to sell contraband <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> by recognizing the colors of
different currency.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REPUBLICAN TAX CUTS TO BENEFIT WEALTHY</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MONKEYS</ENAMEX>
Brushing aside the warnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> and the
widely accepted research of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Goodall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> pushed ahead with
...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTAH ZOO CITES</ENAMEX> FAMILY
VALUES, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ORDERS MONKEY PANTS</ENAMEX>
While it may be an ordinary fact of life that is practiced nearly universally,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masturbation</ENAMEX> is not ...

            
               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 3, 6</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> are
actual stories.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> , assorted
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">aviation alerts.</ENAMEX>

            
               Schedule Note
            

            There will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two quizzes this week</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, so I'll have time to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> alphabetize its mailing lists.

         
      
   
