
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">262</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder Bread</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engler</ENAMEX> says it "strengthens <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, stabilizes neighborhoods, builds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, enhances self-sufficiency, and promotes personal well-being." What
does?
            

            
               (Q uestion
courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Terns</ENAMEX>. )
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 261</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rules":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pages of rules are these: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> must
smile and wear makeup at all times, any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> caught chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> gets an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fine</ENAMEX>, and then there's the draconian Rule <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>--"if any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> gets three
complaints, she must immediately resign." Rules governing
what?
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Poker</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Oder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomason</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "The
utopian society described on the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">New Barbie</ENAMEX> box."--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
Carlin
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> wonders why its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> never does
well."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay D. Majors</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Schatz</ENAMEX> )

            "This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sucks</ENAMEX>. I thought working on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liddy</ENAMEX>'s campaign would be better than working on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s. I quit."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer Gabel</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Bryton</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Wilkes</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dee Lacey</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Framson</ENAMEX> , and Cebra
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> )

            "Oh
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, I've got that list. I can't remember if it came from the tenure committee
or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> where I used to lap dance."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Comical misogyny, like that underpinning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
question, comes in a variety of forms, none more impressive than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man</ENAMEX>
Show , a beer-fueled, bikini-clad exercise in frat-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> reassurance that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">debuts</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>.

            With a self-congratulatory smirk, the show presents
the most bullying reactionary ideas as if they were progressive . It's
the naughtiness of the privileged that runs something like this: Everyone says
it's wrong to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> kittens with cinder blocks. Well, I'm no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convention</ENAMEX>, I just beat the hell out of them. I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX>, and only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prude</ENAMEX>
would complain. This bit of logical high jinks can justify anything from racism
to the flat tax.

            Offering up loutish claptrap used to require a
different sort of justification. The old method was to insist that it was
"satire." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the line would run that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man Show</ENAMEX> is not the
thing but is a parody of the thing. (The thing being the social ideas of Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> around the time he was eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> off the belly of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hooker</ENAMEX> and
slapping around his girlfriends. Still a lively topic in philosophical circles,
apparently.) But satire requires a critical stance, while <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man Show</ENAMEX>
requires jokes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women drivers</ENAMEX> and farting <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX>.

            This justification devolved into the light irony
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>: Our show may be rubbish, but we know it's rubbish. Through a process
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alchemy</ENAMEX>, self-awareness transforms rubbish into lucrative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonrubbish</ENAMEX>.

            The most modern and
least demanding defense relies on the personal virtue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>. I'm a
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, therefore anything that I do is, by definition, good. Thus, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man Show</ENAMEX> , produced by a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> (and I know him, he's a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>) is
OK, but if, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> had produced it, it would be vile. It's Borges
logic. It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvinism</ENAMEX>, with enormous breasts, bouncing on a trampoline.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientation Week</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            These are the rules for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> working for one
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar owner</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabukicho</ENAMEX>, or "entertainment zone." Rule <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>,
incidentally, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, "When a customer sings karaoke, please, everyone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clap</ENAMEX>."

            Lately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> are finding it hard to compete with vibrant immigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> are taking business from us in every area--in prostitution,
in gambling, in fencing, in stolen goods," said one yakuza to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Kristof</ENAMEX>. "The difference between us is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yakuza</ENAMEX> think of long-term business relationships, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> thinks just of the short term. Their only goal is money, money,
money."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Becalms a Legend Most?</ENAMEX>" Extra
            

            In yet another spasm of millennial list making, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Film Institute</ENAMEX> ranks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">50 Legends</ENAMEX>." If only the
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> and the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> had made movies together! Well, actually
but few other equally ranked pairs ever worked together. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are
invited to rectify that.

            From the list, available on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s Web
site, choose a pair other than No. 1 (or No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Cooper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stanwyck</ENAMEX> often appeared together) and come up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> -style plot
summary of a movie in which they might have co-starred. Entries are due by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, June 27</TIMEX>; results will run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX>: 

            

               No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">C'mon Get Happy</ENAMEX> --A happy-go-lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Astaire</ENAMEX>)
tries to cheer up a neurasthenic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greta Garbo</ENAMEX>) by teaching her
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cha-cha</ENAMEX>.

               No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Acres</ENAMEX> --A taciturn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Fonda</ENAMEX>) forces his
beautiful but leery young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX>) to live a simple life on a
farm. Later remade for television, but as a comedy.

               No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guess Who's Coming to Seder</ENAMEX>? --A <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX>) brings his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlene Dietrich</ENAMEX>) home from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> to meet his
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

               No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great Dominatrix</ENAMEX> --The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tramp</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX>) sneaks into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of a wealthy young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Crawford</ENAMEX>) for shelter, plays
whimsically with her silver serving set, and is beaten nearly to death with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">fireplace poker</ENAMEX> when she discovers him. Later remade <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">as Boudou Saved From</ENAMEX>
Spanking .

               No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old York</ENAMEX> --A brooding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olivier</ENAMEX>) is fascinated, against his better judgment, by a wisecracking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginger Rogers</ENAMEX>) who scoots around his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX> hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby backward</ENAMEX> on
heels humming to herself with her arms splayed.

            

            Click
here for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s list of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Greatest American Screen Legends</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>, displacing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> for Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sexist Public Figure</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, displacing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Sexist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
