
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> and Porn</SPAN></SPAN>

             

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 14</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story assails the widening health gap between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> and poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who die before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 5</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98 percent</NUMEX> live in the
developing world. Alliances between nongovernmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> could catalyze research into the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> that plague poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.
... An article endorses an antitrust crackdown on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s competition authority has concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> abused its dominant
market position by preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> from selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX>. ... A
profile of porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Hirsch</ENAMEX> says that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vivid Video</ENAMEX> dominates <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicone Valley</ENAMEX> because he recreated the studio system
that used to govern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. Vivid cornered the market on porn queens by
signing them to package contracts, promoting them heavily, and sending them on
incredibly lucrative strip-club tours.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 30</TIMEX>
            

            A
piece blasts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> for ginning up controversy
over "endocrine disrupters," man-made <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> that allegedly disrupt human
reproduction even in trace amounts. The research into endocrine disrupters has
been wildly distorted, and there is no compelling evidence of the most
spectacular claim: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> have lowered sperm counts. This hasn't
stopped <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> from using endocrine disrupters to raise money and grab
attention. ... The cover story on the creepy marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> is largely ruled by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mira Markovic</ENAMEX>, a fervent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>.
Both believe that they alone stand against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> world domination.
... An article describes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DigiPen Institute of Technology</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
college sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> learn nothing but video-game
programming. The best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> drop out and take high-paying jobs with game
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 15</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story asks: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Lost Russia?</ENAMEX>" Some blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
blind support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> loans or
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s insistence on economic "shock therapy" for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s deterioration. In
fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> was never <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s to lose: It has declined because of the
corrosive legacy of communism on civil society. ... An article attacks
the insular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>'s latest book typifies the
"lie-free, alcohol-free, womanizing-free" standards of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. The
moralistic reaction of the press to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s foibles demonstrates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s
elitist insularity.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
                
               and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX>
Project takes both covers; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's package is meatier. Both

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                and 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
                concur that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horror vérité flick</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> will prompt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> to imitate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> 's guerilla
marketing tactics: They include an amazing Internet site, fake "missing"
posters for the film's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, and leaked previews. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX> movie will have the highest profit margin in film history. Both mags
rehash now-familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> trivia: The filmmakers sent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
into the woods for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> with cameras and only a thin plotline for
direction, then spooked their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> with nighttime raids. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
reports that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> refuse to believe that the story is
fictional.

            
               Time wonders how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will handle "hard to place"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> when the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> welfare limit comes up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. Persistent
welfare cases don't get jobs because of mental illness, substance abuse,
transportation obstacles, child-care difficulties, and simple lack of interest.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> think more job training could help. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> concede that some
safety net may be necessary.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> notes that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> promotes religious understanding
and meditation, he opposes abortion, contraception, and homosexual acts.
... An essay on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> argues that he epitomizes the
malaise of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> disassociated from the bonds of fraternity and patriarchy
that shaped their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>' lives.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16-23</TIMEX>
            

            A
double issue examines life in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">A.D. The Islamic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> empires were
world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX>, but the conversion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magyars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christianity</ENAMEX> was setting the stage for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s ascent. A piece hints that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China</ENAMEX> lost the massive technological
advantage it held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> because its mandarin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> imposed too many
regulations. An article says that if you were alive in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>, you probably
would have been a miserable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX>. ... A story says that there is still virtually no evidence linking
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> bombed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to
chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> production or terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> in charge
of the bombing never consulted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> who could have told them that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> was legit.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> reprises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> antitrust trial. The software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> belatedly
realized the importance of courting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and the press, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> charm offensive is too late: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has already been tarred as a
bully in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of public opinion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> feels so embattled that he
can't contain his anger or make rational choices about how to settle
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s no-win predicament. ... A piece speculates about the IPO
potential of online pornographers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of pussy.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is preparing to go
public. Despite huge profits, many e-pornographers have a hard time finding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> willing to represent them. ... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar Goodman</ENAMEX>
suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> elected the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> it deserves. The former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob-lawyer</ENAMEX> is
crowd-pleasing, casino-friendly, and proud of his colorful past, just like the
city he serves. ... An item condemns the indictment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spiteful</ENAMEX> and politically motivated.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover
story joins the chorus against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> straw poll and attacks the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caucus</ENAMEX>, too. The straw poll is bogus because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> pay their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>' participation fees and the horserace-hungry media overblows its
significance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is a poor bellwether, because it is disproportionately
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>, white, rural, and conservative. ... An article details
the desperation among the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-string <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> sent out a
press release to announce that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX> was writing an item about his
campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> allegedly attempted to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temps</ENAMEX> to vote for him and is
offering straw-poll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> free balloon rides and face-painting for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
