
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Giuliani Was Spared</ENAMEX>

            
Although the election of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdurrahman Wahid</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> came too late to be reported in any of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s papers, the
ballot process was seen as giving hope for democracy. An op-ed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
Post of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> said that "despite all the mess, the killing, the
corruption and deceit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> is engaging in a more open and competitive
political process than ever before." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>
said in an editorial that the ballot by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> marked "a crucial turning
point" for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> since it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s first contested presidential
election.

            
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most popular presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Megawati Sukarnoputri</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s national <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that if she failed to win, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> economy could be halted by strikes and popular unrest. This was a
warning made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zen Mulani</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, in a briefing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> and presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>. He
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and capital markets are expected to be the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> of
industrial action. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Howard</ENAMEX> for publicly backing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Megawati</ENAMEX>'s candidature on the eve of the vote.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> would be better served if he kept his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> on who should lead
another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>," it said.

            In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX>
condemned as "disgraceful" the treatment meted out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei</ENAMEX>
Jingsheng, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> seized and held him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> as he tried to unfurl
a banner in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> as they processed in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> carriage up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckingham Palace</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
state visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. "This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is increasingly seen by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> as an
accomplice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. Noting that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> had let it be known in advance that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> would pay a
penalty if it tolerated public protest during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s visit, it commented, "The
Government may have been right to invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, but it
should not kowtow to repressive demands." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei</ENAMEX> himself told the press: "We think
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> behavior is without reason. We thought it was only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> that
freedom of expression was forbidden." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> operated a policy of "zero tolerance" toward all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> except
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> who were allowed to practice their spiritual
exercises opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Izvestiya</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> noted an alarming new tendency in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>:
In the absence of effective enforcement of property rights, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> simply grab
what they think should be theirs. It gave the example of the Barrikady
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agricultural cooperative</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Volgograd</ENAMEX> region, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant shareholders</ENAMEX>,
claiming a combine harvester and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> as their own, seized them from
a neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. "This is how bloody slaughters have started in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX>
history, leading in the end to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> revolutions and the placing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
outside the civilized world for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire 20 th century</TIMEX>," the paper
said.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> Times
ran a comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yulia Latynina</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on a rise in the approval ratings of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> successes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chechen war</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> is bound to slump again in the polls, though, because
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> will lose the war. "To win it requires money that is not in the budget,
sober-mindedness that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> don't have, and a readiness to fight to
the end that too frequently is absent in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. It is funny to think
that our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>--in which 'surgical strikes' are useless because enlisted men
shake the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX> out of the bombs and sell it--could consider fighting a country
in which war is considered the one worthy male occupation."

            The
Independent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX> isn't the only thing
being sold by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military. It said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">navy</ENAMEX> is selling off the
kamikaze <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX> it trained to blow up enemy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> by carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> to them.
"There is a general disposal of surplus military equipment, old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>,
armoured personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bulldozers</ENAMEX>, which the impoverished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
military no longer needs or can maintain," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            The
Independent also reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dar es Salaam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>, that the death of
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julius Nyerere</ENAMEX> is generating "the biggest outpouring of
collective grief that southern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> has ever seen." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> is
among world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> due to attend his funeral there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> amid "a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48-hour</TIMEX>
non-stop orgy of tears for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baba wa Taifa</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>." The paper
described a tearful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> on television singing "You did more in your life than
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the sea." This included running the economy into the ground
and at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point having more political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, but his
work in the cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">emancipation</ENAMEX> was celebrated in a poem by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaunda</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zambia</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
quoted from the poem: "I am sure you know of all those successes ... in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Namibia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>. Why then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius</ENAMEX>, do you leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burundi</ENAMEX> unfinished<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaunda</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that he would present another poem to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nyerere</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led its front page with a report
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' refusal to include funds to implement the Wye
agreement in the foreign aid bill it approved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> "could throw a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>
wrench" into both a final-status agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and a deal
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had specifically pledged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> in
aid to evacuate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, relocate industries, and establish military
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. It added that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>
remains confident that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million dollars</NUMEX> of aid slated for this year
will eventually be approved because "Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> say they do not
object to the aid in principle--it is merely a tool in their power struggle
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>."

            A
strange development occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> referendum campaign on
the abolition of the monarchy. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX>
reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckingham Palace</ENAMEX> Web site had quietly changed its
description of the queen's constitutional position in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> from "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
state" to "sovereign." This apparently delighted many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> monarchists
who have been countering the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>" slogan with
the bizarre claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> already has an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor-general</ENAMEX>, the queen's representative there. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckingham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace</ENAMEX>, while claiming to be aloof from the campaign, admitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that it made the change to its Web site--calling it "an
appropriate amendment"--but wouldn't say why. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> said monarchist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Howard</ENAMEX> was under suspicion and linked the change to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monarchists</ENAMEX>' strategy of pretending the queen doesn't exist or, at any rate,
doesn't matter. The latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> opinion poll has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> each.

            It
will only be known after the vote of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6</TIMEX> if the queen will go the way of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> just discovered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have discovered a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> the
size of a small gray <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kangaroo</ENAMEX> and have curiously named it "Qantassaurus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intrepidus</ENAMEX>" after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qantas</ENAMEX>. They say it is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115 million</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and should contribute to the paleontological debate about whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX> were warm-blooded or cold-blooded.

            A piece of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
art which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> has fortunately been spared is
My Bed , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracey Emin</ENAMEX>, one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> short-listed for the annual
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner Prize</ENAMEX>. Featuring prominently in an exhibition at the Tate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, it is said to be the bed in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> spent a week
contemplating suicide after breaking up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the bed "is covered in urine-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">stained</NUMEX> sheets
and torn pillows and is surrounded by the detritus of her sojourn. This
includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-smoked cigarettes, condoms, packets of contraceptive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>, empty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">vodka</ENAMEX> bottles, a pregnancy testing kit, sanitary towels, nylons and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pairs
of her dirty knickers." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> compared the exhibit to
"unprocessed sewage" and said that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emin</ENAMEX> wins the prize, as she very well
might, "her victory will testify not to the vitality of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> art but to a
campaign of promotion so brazen that it has left even the cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> art
world awestruck."

         
      
   
