
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bullet Points</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> will omit evolution from its statewide science
curriculum. Individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> will now decide whether to teach it or
not. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> predicts that the decision will discourage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> from teaching it, encourage creationists to introduce their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">textbooks</ENAMEX>, and leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> unprepared for college science <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> surrendered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buford Furrow</ENAMEX>, a neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>,
had sprayed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community center</ENAMEX> with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uzi</ENAMEX>, injuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>.
He also allegedly shot and killed a letter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>. He told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> "he
wanted this to be a wake-up call to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variously</ENAMEX> tied the incident to recent spates of workplace shootings, school
violence, and hate crimes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> cited a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>'s warnings that ethnic slurs can lead to
violence, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX> blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> for allowing civil liberties <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> to limit their
monitoring of hate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post focused on gun control, accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> of neglect and empty
rhetoric.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> fired his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> again. He
replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Stepashin</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>, his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX>. Yeltsin swore that he would stick with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> through
the presidential elections in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> wrote that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> "invites parody when his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> desperately needs stability," and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> quipped that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> changes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> changing
shirts." "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Papers</ENAMEX>" to his drinking, his background as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
party hack, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s failed transition to democracy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> stock
market slid, and the ruble fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>.

            

               A tornado ripped through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and injuring
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Weather Service</ENAMEX> pointed out how unusual it is
for a big tornado to strike an urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> .

            

               An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> jet shot down a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all 16</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> claimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> had been in
its airspace. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> worries about future "volatile
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confrontations"</ENAMEX> (read: nuclear warfare), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
bets the clash will aid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s upcoming elections. Read
"" for more on the conflict.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> announced that it may resume supporting the Tailhook
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> severed its ties <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX> after reports
of sexual abuse at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s convention. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>'s disclosure of tentative plans is intended to test public opinion for
restoring the relationship.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> will wrap up his investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' alleged
misdeeds with a final report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. He told the Today
show that the purpose of this report, unlike his last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, is to summarize his
findings, not to assert wrongdoing .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, will support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> had figured that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> would turn his back on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> as a payback for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prot√</ENAMEX>©g√©, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Lazio</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, will run anyway, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> said his candidacy is
doomed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> attributed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>'s halfhearted endorsement to
"pressure from national <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to head off a fratricidal battle
that could only help" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            

               An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was caught smuggling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hiett</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> presides over all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
has been pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> to be more aggressive in its anti-drug campaign.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , changed the
subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>'s problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> and civil war.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> slashed its long-distance rates. It will offer weeknight
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> calling for a flat rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cents</NUMEX> per minute. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post marvels at the fall in long-distance rates since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1984</TIMEX>
breakup of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ma Bell</ENAMEX> but warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to check for hidden fees.

            

               
                  
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> approved the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> tax-cut
plan.
                  
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rangel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
preparing to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scrooge</ENAMEX> for vetoing this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>-in-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> package of tax cuts." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> says that
"only high-flying G.O.P. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and special interests" really want the cuts,
and that they're "designed to please the hard right and force a confrontation
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, comparing the negotiations to those
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> welfare bill, signaled that he will accept a compromise plan. In
"," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> explains how the tax cut became a "tax scheme."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> was confirmed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>. His nomination had been held up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 months</TIMEX>, first on
ethics questions and then because of spats between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> gained little for their stonewalling, and the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> relays that the holdup made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> feel even more
snubbed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Chemical</ENAMEX> will buy rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Carbide</ENAMEX>. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> predicts the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX>, the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
