
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">328</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wieners&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times as
likely to do it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> as on any other <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. Do what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">327</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Haider Go Seek":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jörg Haider</ENAMEX> led his far-right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Party</ENAMEX> to a
stunning second-place finish in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>'s national elections; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> from
now, he's coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. To do what?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To</ENAMEX>
celebrate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX> on yet another stunning second-place finish
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lott</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Shuger</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            "Find
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>. Wacky high jinks ensue. Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchwald</ENAMEX> has already filed a
lawsuit."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> )

            "Buy a
ton of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy corn</ENAMEX> in the half-price <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> sales."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>
Markoe
            

            "I
guess I should be paying more attention to this charter revision thing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">huh?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Check</ENAMEX>
out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Waldheim</ENAMEX>'s old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>; see if the swastika <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX>
carved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> is still there."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Surdyk</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            This question generated,
by far, a record number of "similarlies" all focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s
politics. Unavoidable, I suppose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cartoons</ENAMEX>, sitcoms, and political campaigns
conjure up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> with a single, instantly recognizable characteristic.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Daffy Duck</ENAMEX> is, well, daffy; Phoebe from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> is, OK, well she's daffy
too; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is ... OK, never mind. But to sustain him as a viable
comic foil through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next November</TIMEX>, we'll need to observe him in a more
particular and nuanced way, or pray that he develops webbed feet, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phoebe</ENAMEX>,
and a quirky sex appeal, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daffy</ENAMEX>. There's something about that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>. I
wonder if he's ever considered joining a new political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            
               Is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Hard To Run in</ENAMEX>
Those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackboots Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jörg Haider</ENAMEX> will be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Nov.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, to run in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New York City marathon</ENAMEX>. He will be wearing number <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5777</TIMEX>.
Despite protests, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race officials</ENAMEX> have declined either to eject <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haider</ENAMEX> or to
reroute the event to keep him out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hasidic</ENAMEX> neighborhood in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>.

            Although it is, of
course, impossible to know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> will deal with this potentially
volatile confrontation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> has already praised the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> for their
wisdom, restraint, and all around good looks in handling the situation, and
dismissed those who disagree as "publicity-seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX>." Or perhaps he
hasn't.

            
               Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pandering</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catering</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Under the slogan,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another Great Reason To Be a Woman</ENAMEX>" (feel free to make up your own jokes about
some of those other reasons), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxygen Media</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcy Carsey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Werner</ENAMEX>, and Caryn
Mandabach, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Laybourne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX>) has launched its Web site and announced the shows
it will start airing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX> on television (a box consisting of a cathode ray
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tube</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receiver</ENAMEX> and ... oh, screw it). Some actual highlights along with some
actual snarky remarks.

            

               Inhale, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 a.m.</TIMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High-energy yoga?</ENAMEX>" Isn't that a contradiction? Well, no. We just won't stand
for doing anything the same old way.-- It's yoga with attitude. No, wait:
It's yoga for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new millennium</TIMEX>. It's yoga, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cajun</ENAMEX>-style. Wait, wait, come back
...
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Oxygen</ENAMEX>.Comedy, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6-8 p.m.</TIMEX>
"It all starts off with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> unorthodox game shows including our take on the
classic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I've Got a Secret</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Retread</ENAMEX> game shows? OK, as it turns
out, we WILL stand for doing some things the same old way.
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pure Oxygen</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8-10 p.m.</TIMEX>
At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pure Oxygen</ENAMEX>, we talk with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, not at them, in a fluid production style
that breaks down the wall between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> and the on-air
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">personalities.</ENAMEX>-- If you've ever broken down the wall between yourself and a
union stage hand, I'm not sure you'd cheerfully do it again.
               

               Exhale With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candice Bergen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-F</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10-11 p.m.</TIMEX>
Whew! Was that a day or what? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to take a deep breath, reflect,
relax and get inspired with our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> hour-long conversation (not a talk
show) between a celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and the most interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the
day.-- And those leather things she's wearing on her feet? Not
shoes.
               

               shE-commerce, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weekends</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.-2 p.m.</TIMEX>
OK, we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. We shop. Thank God for the Internet!-- This may seem sexist,
but it's not: It's gurrrll power, like at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX>.
               

               WeSweat, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weekends</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4-6 p.m.</TIMEX>
Whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> sports, rock climbing or just strutting around the block,
there's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> burning inside every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Oxygen celebrates that spirit
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WeSweat</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> weekend block.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strutting</ENAMEX>: I believe that's a
demonstration sport in the next <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>. And incidentally, doesn't the suck-up
form require it to be shE sweat?
               

               X-Chromosome, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sat.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30-9 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30-8 p.m.</TIMEX>
Breaking the rules and mining hot new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things Oxygen does
best--collide head-on in an explosive new animation series for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.-- I
believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Lee Gifford</ENAMEX> said the same thing about working conditions in her
factory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala</ENAMEX>.
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pyjama Party</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sat.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.-12 a.m.</TIMEX>
Think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>, but don't think too hard--this is
fun!-- This is the listing that made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan B. Anthony</ENAMEX> burst the confines of
her coffin, drive down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> to purchase an inexpensive and easily
obtainable handgun, take the red-eye to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, and clean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. (Not a talk
show.)
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Goes Online</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-part series
She's the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in television. An accomplished entertainer and
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>. Nothing gets in her way. Nothing, that is, except the
computer.-- And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next season</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">24-parter</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> learns to set her
VCR.
               

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Soul kissing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> ... in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX>!

         
      
   
