
   
   
      
         
            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet Mr. Kettle</ENAMEX>

            
               Hyperlinked
Hypocrisy
            

            I write this with regard to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dispatch</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>"). Frankly, I would have responded directly to him if he were a
little more open to the cyberworld and had provided an address of any kind to
respond to. He says cyberculture brings out the worst in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (Well, there's
no convincing him otherwise if he's not accepting debate on the issue.) Then he
launches into a tirade about the arrogance and ignorance of the "Chatroom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poseur</ENAMEX>" based on a single e-mail he received questioning his honesty as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist-columnist</ENAMEX>.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> wants to be an objective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fine</ENAMEX>, but he enters with too many preconceptions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> e-mail messages and one
trip to a chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> (by his own admission) may give him room to give his
initial reactions, but not to cast judgment on an entire culture. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>
writes, "I'm not unwilling to listen to criticism, but a critique clothed in
such an invincible armor of arrogance and ignorance is, well, typical of
cyberchat rhetoric."

            You don't think your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">respondent</ENAMEX> had any real logic or an equitable argument, but your posting has
even less. You take potshots at him in public as he did to you in private (you
called him a dimwit). That's hypocritical.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan O'Brien</ENAMEX>
            

            
Meriden, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> replies:
                
               This letter, while
unusually lucid for e-mail, is based on a misconception: While I've only
visited a chat room once, I've read numerous transcripts, excerpts, printouts,
etc. Enough to characterize the typical snide tone. I should point out that I
omitted the name of the respondent I critiqued.
            

            
               Down on
Dowd
            

            What on earth makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>") think that the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cognoscenti</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> like the recent work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> any better then
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> do? The last line I heard from a cognoscente
was "Isn't it too bad about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Maureen?</ENAMEX>" and that was some time ago. What seems to
have happened is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> has been playing to a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-phobes at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> who laugh and applaud wildly as her
reputation sinks at about equal speed in all major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> at once.

            And what makes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> think he knows all about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' "chilly business deal" either? Surely a kinder and sadder story
can be whittled from the same evidence, to wit: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, a blue-stocking
in love with a glamorpuss, had too eagerly bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's</ENAMEX> Gladstone-like tales
of helping troubled young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to find peace: enough so anyway to make a
potential laughingstock of herself by repeating them on television, and enough
also to give Bill some terrible legal advice in the specific matter of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>.
Surely a chilly business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> would at least have known about a case that
was about to go on legal record and would never have urged her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to
brazen it out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> and start the whole miserable ball
rolling.

            At any rate, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
was finally cornered by the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> and forced to blurt the truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
was revealed to be not just a wronged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> but a lousy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>--and she was
most gratifyingly furious. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s rage <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> was surely one of the most
authentic sights ever shown on television, prompting the thought that, unlike
the absurd <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp, both Clintons</ENAMEX> really are us, in our various phases--and
incidentally that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> may be the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> in my lifetime (which goes
back a bit) that one can even imagine being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with. And since then, she
has played her part just fine, establishing herself as a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> and not
just "standing by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s "failed feminist," but standing by her
family, like a grown-up--a condition that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> herself curiously never seems to
get any closer to as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> go by. In a column airily damning the whole
younger generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>, she makes it clear that she has probably never
raised a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> herself and worried herself sick about how it would turn out;
and in another, gleefully jumping on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX> after he was fired
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S. News</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX> , she indicates that job tenure has
not been a problem either. Good job tenure, that is--because in yet another
column, she sneers at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Davidson</ENAMEX> for working on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Woman</ENAMEX> . Why can't the silly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> get a perfect job like hers? So long as
the pet's patriarchs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> continue to give her unlimited freedom
to write exactly what they like to hear, she is sitting pretty--though not,
perhaps, in an ideal position to judge anyone else anywhere.

            -- Wilfrid
Sheed
            

            Sag
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>

            P.S.:
I have it on the word of a neutral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in a position to know, that in her
famous bake-off with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> undoubtedly made her own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>
from her own recipe, and they were excellent. No big deal, of course--these
things happen all the time in real life. But both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> might
like to stick it in their stereotypes anyway and smoke it for a while,
preferably in silence.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX> Don't Kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">People Kill People</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Easterbrook</ENAMEX> really needs to educate himself
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>"). Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I know that own a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX> live and work in rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, where they need the off-road and carrying capability of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX>. Now,
those who live in the suburbs who don't use an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX> except for pure street
driving may be the ones to whom you're referring. I own a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep Cherokee</ENAMEX>. Yes,
it does consume more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> than an econo-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. But it is a justification I have
accepted in order to get the performance that I need to earn a living. Much of
my time is spent working in the field as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX>. I do a lot of off-road
work where four-wheel drive is an absolute. There really is no option for me
but to own a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX>. I am proud to say that I am one of the few who use these
vehicles for how they were really intended to be used.

            You, on the other hand, are part of a growing
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that like to target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the basis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>. Your
petty antics of coal-raking put those of us who are sincere and considerate SUV
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> at risk. You are generating waves that are being heard in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
where laws may be drafted that make it harder for someone to own a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX>.

            I and the many of us
that are the responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SUV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> would appreciate it if you would take your
brow-bashing energy and channel it not to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX> but to those who abuse the
privilege of driving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and gun control, it's not the gun that
needs to be removed from society, it's the ass behind the trigger.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Mallow</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cocoa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
