
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s Debate Bait

            For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year</TIMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> labored to be taken seriously as a
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> studiously ignored him. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last weekend</TIMEX>, after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> surged past him in the fund-raising contest and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> polls,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> turned and opened fire. At an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa Democratic Party</ENAMEX> dinner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">challenged Bradley</ENAMEX> to debate him once a week. "How about it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">taunted</ENAMEX>, looking straight at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>. "If the answer is yes, stand up and wave
your hand." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> sat on his hands, and the press reported excitedly that the
momentum in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> had shifted. The debate challenge has changed
the game by advancing several of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s strategic objectives.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. 
               Kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s momentum. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has bled
money and support, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has gained on him. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, when one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> makes this kind of "run," the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> calls a timeout to defuse
the hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s momentum and ruin its rhythm before the game gets out of hand.
Since the strategy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> had mapped out before the game has already been
defeated and discarded, he has nothing to lose by tearing up his schedule to
make room for debates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s game plan, however, has been highly effective,
and he has much to lose by being derailed from it. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> ignores the
challenge, it has supplanted his message as the campaign's hot story. Every
headline coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> dinner focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s challenge and ignored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s good speech.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. 
               Reverse the expectations game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has suffered
from being perceived as the spoiled, stagnant front-runner. He wants (as

                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> has ) to restyle himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>.
And what does an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> do? He dares the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> to debate him. The
debate challenge helps persuade the media to cast <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in this unlikely role.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> gave a "scrappy" speech in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and "offered himself as a feisty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underdog</ENAMEX>," reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> may no longer have the
luxury of trying to be above politics--and repeated debates."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. 
               Change the subject from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> to issues. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has appealed for support on the basis of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has
appealed for support on the basis of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and life story. So far,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s biography has trumped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s issues. Debates, which are organized
around issues rather than personal history, would force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
game. Since polls show that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> don't know his
positions on the issues, he stands to lose some of his support by having to
spell out his views. By pushing the contest in this direction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s challenge
has already poisoned media coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. "The inability of many New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s positions on major issues could loom as
a vulnerability," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Make 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> address losing issues. Every candidate
has issues on which he expects to win votes and issues on which he expects to
lose votes. The rule is to talk about your winning issues and avoid your losing
issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s winning issues are campaign reform, health care, and gun
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> wants to make him talk about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> losing issues: Reaganomics
(which hurts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> because he voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> budget
cuts), vouchers (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s past support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> voucher programs offends
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who think vouchers threaten
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s past opposition to ethanol subsidies
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irks Iowans</ENAMEX>, who count on these subsidies to prop up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s inconsistency on the ethanol question, click .)
This is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> specifically dared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to debate him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agriculture</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can answer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s criticisms--in interviews, he has
already begun to do so--but politically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> loses votes and momentum just
by having to address these troublesome issues instead of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Recast 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">depicted Gore</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stiff</ENAMEX>, imperial, and out of touch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has played along,
calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> "timid" and associating him with "entrenched power." By daring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to debate him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> confounds this characterization. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s refrain in
his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> speech--"stay and fight"--excited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s "call to arms" conveyed "passion" and "suggested
focus and purpose." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> sprang to life
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, delivering one of his feistiest performances of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>." A
Times headline ventured, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notion</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">New</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore Begins</ENAMEX> to Take
Root."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Recast 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coward</ENAMEX>. For the preceding
reasons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has no strategic interest in debating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. He didn't budge
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> urged him to stand and accept the challenge, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
brushed it aside, saying there would be "plenty of debates" down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. But
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> keeps declining the challenge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will turn the "timidity"
argument against him. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, with increasing explicitness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> of "walking away from the fight" by voting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> budget,
opposing farm subsidies, and retiring from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> took full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s surrogates have accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> of "quitting" and
"running" from battles. The media smell a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>. "By refusing to engage,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> opens himself up to being portrayed as a risk-averse, aloof <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>
who does not have the mettle ... to fight emphatically for the nomination,"
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . "Will he hold up as a high-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>," asked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , or "will he be seen as just another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who has ... gone
wobbly on his party on crucial fights?"

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. 
               Seize the high ground. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley dismisses Gore</ENAMEX>'s
criticisms as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">darts</ENAMEX>." "I am simply not going to get into dealing with the
darts that are being thrown," he says. "I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to
have a positive vision of the future." This rebuttal might have worked, but the
debate challenge has thwarted it and has jeopardized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s posture as a
straight-talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX>. Questioning your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s courage looks cynical,
but calling for debates looks noble. Conversely, refusing to answer your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s insults looks noble, but refusing to answer a debate challenge looks
cynical. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is using his debate challenge as moral cover for his attacks on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are turning their scrutiny on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
"defensiveness" instead.

            In his
speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> handed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> the perfect metaphor to make this point: <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> run derby between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Sosa</ENAMEX>. "Why can't it be Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> to be
the best we can be?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> asked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> proceeded to hit this pitch out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX>, telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> that if the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sluggers</ENAMEX> had "stayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dugout</ENAMEX>" and
"didn't step up to the plate, they wouldn't hit many home runs." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> headline made clear who had won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
Asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to Step Up to Debate Plate."

            You
have to feel sorry for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. Having ignored him throughout the campaign,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has decided--at a moment oozing with political expediency--to reverse
course, demand an open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, and cast himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are playing along, hoping to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> on the fight. In an interview with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> showdown, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> again ducked the debate
question, declining to "lay all the cards out on the table" just because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
suddenly finds it convenient. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> knows he'd be an idiot
to debate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. And the last thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can afford is to look like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
