
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in the Doghouse

            A
worldwide chorus of outrage greeted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>'s refusal to ratify the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> was
a rare dissenter. In a rather limp editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, it described <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lugar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CTBT</ENAMEX>, as "a scholarly, moderate, highly respected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX>" whose views should be taken seriously. "The instruments for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of the evil of nuclear proliferation must be effective," it said. "It
is such questions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote has rightly raised." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> also ran an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Perle</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> assistant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense, attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> for trying
to influence the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote through an article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
"Why didn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> congratulate its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX>]
on their wise and timely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>?" he asked. "I suspect that one reason is that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> have actually read the treaty and understand how deeply flawed it
is, how unlikely it is to stop nuclear proliferation or even nuclear testing,
and how it has the potential to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with an unsafe,
unreliable nuclear deterrent. ... In domestic affairs, no-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> would seriously
propose that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> come together and sign agreements under
which they accept the same set of restraints on their freedom of action."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers were otherwise unanimous in their condemnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. In
the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , foreign affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Woollacott</ENAMEX>
said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> "sent out a dismal message--of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">selfishness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foolishness</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> readiness to put her
own safety <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, whatever the consequences for the rest of us." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>
editorial said the vote was "a serious blow to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s political and moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>" and that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, by exploiting the opportunity to
inflict a very public defeat on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame-duck President</ENAMEX>, have done their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
and their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, a grave disservice."

            The
Independent
ran an article jointly authored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harald Muller</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Research Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, who said the vote was "deplorable" and reflected a situation in which
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> policy is increasingly being shaped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with isolationist, or,
even worse, a supremacist agenda. They want to expand military programs, weaken
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and run the world by flaunting power." An op-ed
piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX>
Times said the vote underlined "the extent to which international
considerations have been pushed to the fringes of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics. The broad
consensus about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> responsibilities in the world has fractured."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> 's
main front-page headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America Reopens the Nuclear Arms Race</ENAMEX>,"
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial that "in the essential area of nuclear
nonproliferation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has set the worst possible example." It
concluded, "The world's greatest power will from now on be less credible on the
international scene." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
Figaro , in a signed editorial by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Rousselin</ENAMEX>, used exactly the
same phrase as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX> when it called the vote "an unprecedented
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snub</ENAMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--"un camouflet sans précédent "</ENAMEX>--to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s credibility is now damaged, perhaps irredeemably, as he
embarks on his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will easily
remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' virulent campaign against our nuclear tests in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rousselin</ENAMEX> wrote. "At that time, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> defended the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CTBT</ENAMEX> to get himself re-elected. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has no lessons to give
anybody." In a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
that he is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of a "blind, reactionary and inward-looking
party." The Frankfurter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> said the vote was a rejection of security
through international cooperation. "That, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s decision, is what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> should be thinking about most."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> put some of the blame on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for
not resigning over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> crisis. "This terrible defeat, more so
for all of us than for the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, was exactly what was feared might
happen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days of 1998</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was forced to admit in public to his
own pathetic errors as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and to his own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">unforgivable</ENAMEX> lies as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
and therefore had to undergo the indignity of a public trial over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
affair. ... The price for his survival in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has been paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and been
paid by the rest of the world."

            In one
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nuclear powers on the subcontinent, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> said in
an editorial that it is now "absolutely certain" that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
nor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will ratify the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CTBT</ENAMEX>. It said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s credibility abroad has
suffered a very serious setback, not only because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> decision but
also because of "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> military ignoring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> advice on restoring the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> process in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
