
   
   
      
         
             Praise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord, Pass the Ammo</ENAMEX>

            Addressing a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God Not Guns</ENAMEX>" rally of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> near
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> offered this
explanation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, killings: "I got an e-mail this morning
that said it all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> writes, 'Dear God: Why didn't you stop the
shootings at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>?' And God writes, 'Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>: I would have, but I
wasn't allowed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.' "

            The view among
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> is that adolescent violence is inevitable given the decline of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>. Indeed, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s'</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decisions on school
prayer, displays of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX> were common. And back then, crime was
much less prevalent than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. So, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted to undo the "damage" by
allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to mandate the posting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and
other public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>.

            In social science terms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> believe there is a
correlation between the influence of religion and obedience to the law. The Ten
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commandments</ENAMEX> prohibit murder, so exposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to them could tend to
discourage lethal violence. The absence of religious faith and norms, on the
other hand, might incline someone toward homicide. The argument has particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> in the context of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> asked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> if they
believed in God, and when they answered affirmatively, shot them dead.

            The correlation is not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">implausible</ENAMEX>, but a correlation is not the same thing as a cause. If we were to
discover that none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> in the various school shootings were in the
habit of eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pancakes</ENAMEX> for breakfast, we would have established a
correlation. But no one would argue that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> killed because they didn't
eat enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pancakes</ENAMEX>--much less that the answer to school violence is a national
campaign to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pancakes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. Once you find a correlation
between A and B, you still have to demonstrate that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> causes the other.

            In this instance, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are claiming to
have found a cause without even showing a correlation. Why not? Maybe because
they can't. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is the most religious of all the industrialized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Forty-four percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> once a week, compared
with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>. Yet violent crime is not less common in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>--it's more common. The murder rate here is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times higher than the
rate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times higher than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times higher than in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times higher than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, where Christianity has
almost no adherents, has less violent crime than almost any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. There are
a few advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that have high rates of church attendance and low rates
of violent crime--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>--but they're the exceptions.

            Within the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
there is no evidence that a God-fearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> equals a law-abiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bible Belt</ENAMEX> has more than its share of both praying and killing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX>
has the highest churchgoing rate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but its murder rate is more
than twice the national average. The same pattern generally holds in the rest
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>-toting state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has a murder rate triple
that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, which is "ungodly" enough to have elected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> openly gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the very symbol of godless depravity, is
perfectly average when it comes to extralegal slaughter. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> slugabeds are more common than anywhere else in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>,
murder is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38 percent</NUMEX> less common.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have also failed to notice that the
school shootings have not occurred in hotbeds of secular humanism--say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX>; or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>--but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dobson</ENAMEX> would be proud to call home. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
Paducah, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonesboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>, are not
exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madalyn Murray O</ENAMEX>'Hair <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Littleton</ENAMEX> was fertile ground for
evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>.

            If there is any apparent correlation between the
prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> devotion and law-abiding conduct, it's the opposite of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> claimed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religion</ENAMEX> and violence seem to go hand in hand.
That doesn't mean faith actually causes murder. But it does suggest that when
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> contemplate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX>, they should pay more attention to
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX>, which prohibits false <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
