
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tale</ENAMEX>

            There had been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> of success, of rapid
growth fueled by the money of international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> anxious to get in on a
good thing. But then, with startling suddenness, things went sour. The leader
admitted that some bad investments had been made and that even good investments
had been financed with too much debt and too little equity. But much of the
problem, he insisted, was other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s fault: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who pulled out their
money at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> whiff of difficulty, forcing a sudden financial
restructuring that aggravated the losses; hedge funds that, seeing his
weakness, speculated against him. And so, to the shock of many, he suddenly
changed the rules, imposing new restrictions on the ability of short-term
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to withdraw funds. "If we had been smart," he declared, "we would
have tied up these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> for a long, long time when we were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> of the world
rather than excrement."

            No, this isn't another
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiery prime minister</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> in question
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Robertson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of--yes--a hedge fund, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Management</ENAMEX>, until
recently the largest such fund in the world. In its heyday in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $20 billion</NUMEX> under management, considerably more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Fund</ENAMEX>, and was reputed to be even more aggressive than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum</ENAMEX> in making plays against troubled economies. Notably, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX> was perhaps
the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the yen "carry trade"--borrowing yen and investing the
proceeds in dollars--and its short position in the yen put it in a position to
benefit from troubles throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. But when the yen abruptly strengthened
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few months of 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX> lost heavily--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2 billion</NUMEX> on one
day in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> began pulling out. The losses continued in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>--from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January to the end of September</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX>, compared with
a gain of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> for the average S&P 500 stock. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of September</TIMEX>,
between losses and withdrawals, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX> was down to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a mere $8 billion</NUMEX> under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. And a furious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>, blaming flighty <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> for
aggravating the problem, announced that henceforth the privilege of quarterly
withdrawals would be revoked. (As my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> declared, after reading news reports
on the move, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Robertson</ENAMEX> just imposed capital controls!")

            Of course, everyone makes mistakes, although Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>'s difficulties may inspire a bit more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Schadenfreude</ENAMEX> than your
ordinary, average business disaster. The large, loud, tough-talking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robertson</ENAMEX>
has none of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX>' intellectual veneer or social graces; he might have been
deliberately cast to play the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ugly American</ENAMEX>. And while he does not
share <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX>' ambition to be seen as a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher-speculator</ENAMEX>, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prominence</ENAMEX> does constitute a sort of bully pulpit--with the operative word
perhaps being "bully"--from which he has not hesitated to lecture <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> on
their failings. The irony of his current situation no doubt pleases many.

            But the really
interesting thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>'s problems is the way they highlight the key
role played in the recent travails of the world economy by hedge funds--or, to
use the terminology preferred by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>, "highly leveraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>." (Yes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLIs</ENAMEX>. In the world of international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>--everything seems to
have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-letter abbreviation--TLA?) Never mind the allegations of
conspiracy, the claims that hedge funds profit from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> when they are
down. Where hedge funds really get important is when they don't make
profits, when they themselves are in trouble. Indeed, the troubles of hedge
funds played a remarkably large role in the financial instability of the world
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>.

            The reason for this crucial role is that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> a
handful of highly leveraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> became key, even dominant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in a
number of financial markets. In the international arena, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX> and a few other
funds became the key conduit, via the carry trade, for the export of capital
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>--that is, hedge funds came to play a central role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of
yen for dollars. In the domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> arena, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term Capital Management</ENAMEX>
became a key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchaser</ENAMEX> of a number of crucial if slightly obscure financial
instruments such as commercial-mortgage-backed securities. Exactly how central
these hedge funds had become was not clear until they got into trouble. But
then it turned out that without them the markets could barely function.

            Why were these funds so
important? Even the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 billion</NUMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX> managed at its peak is not a large
sum in the world financial scheme of things (the total wealth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> alone is in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of trillions</NUMEX>). And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term Capital Management</ENAMEX>,
which nearly brought down the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> financial system, had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $5 billion</NUMEX>
under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. What was different about hedge funds was, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, their
ability and willingness to leverage up the money they managed--in effect, to
use their limited wealth to buy or short-sell much larger values of assets on
margin; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, their willingness to play outside the mainstream markets.
Hedge funds were never important in the market for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stock or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bills; but when it came to the secondary market in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> mortgages or
the forward market in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">baht</ENAMEX>, it was a different story.

            Underlying the ability and willingness of hedge funds to
take huge positions in obscure markets was the belief, both by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX> and by
the hedge fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> themselves, that they had special expertise. In the
case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term Capital Management</ENAMEX>, that expertise was technical: The
sophisticated financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> implemented on their computers were supposed to
allow them to diversify away risks. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum</ENAMEX>, it was
more a cult of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> believed in the ability of Messrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX> to outsmart markets--and so did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX>. Indeed, you
probably can't become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of a really large hedge fund unless you have
a slightly irrational faith in your own judgment; when success depends on being
able to convince other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to let you take huge risks with their money, it
is not the paranoid but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">megalomaniac</ENAMEX> who survive. That is, until reality
catches up with them.

            When reality did catch
up, it had unanticipated consequences both for the funds and for markets. Look,
for example, at what happened to that yen carry trade <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX> and
other funds had borrowed heavily in yen, betting on a decline in the yen
against the dollar. When the yen started to rise instead, they suffered losses.
Since the funds were already leveraged to the hilt, this reduction in their
capital forced them to reduce their exposure, which meant paying off some of
those yen borrowings. But that created a fresh demand for yen and supply of
dollars in the foreign exchange market, which led to more losses, forcing even
more repayment, pushing the yen still higher. The result in a short period of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> was a drastic appreciation of the yen and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in losses
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX>. A similar process of self-reinforcing movement in asset prices when
Long-Term <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Management</ENAMEX> got into trouble drove interest rates on virtually
everything except the most plain-vanilla of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> securities to dizzying
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">heights</ENAMEX>, or in some cases led markets simply to close up shop. And more was at
stake in these asset-market collapses than the money of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hedge</ENAMEX>-fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>:
The sharp rise in the yen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> threatened to send <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> into a
deflationary spiral, the drying up of liquidity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> briefly
seemed to threaten a general financial collapse.

            Which is why, in a perverse way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX>'s current problems
are good news--for they take place against a background of a generally calmer
world, one that has learned to live with a greatly reduced role for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
such as Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX> are still around, but they are no longer
as central to the world financial picture as they were--which means that the
particular sort of vicious circles that brought the world to the brink a year
ago are less likely to happen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            Some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in the financial industry think
that hedge funds were not just a , but the source of instability
in the late crisis. In that case, the clipping of those funds' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX> is a
fundamental change in the situation. The world is really a much safer place now
than it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>. I think this is a bit too optimistic; there are
unfortunately many other ways for a global financial system to get into trouble
(and the yen, as it happens, is once again dangerously overvalued). But
anything that makes the new global economy a bit more stable is to be
welcomed.

         
      
   
