
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impeachment Redux</ENAMEX>

            Pop
Quiz:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Why were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>'s
cell phone records important?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
What was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorton-Lieberman</ENAMEX> plan and what happened to it?

            I'll wager that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) you don't know the answers; and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) you don't care. And that is the news. (If you are genuinely curious about
the answers, click .)

            An anniversary passed strangely and happily without
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six months ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was impeached. During the
Flytrap hullabaloo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> promised that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would spend years
pondering the meaning of this impeachment. They could not have been more wrong.
It's been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> since impeachment and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX> since acquittal, but it
might as well be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> for all that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has thought about it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't gossip about it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> don't poll about it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> don't
pund about it, the torrent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nexis</ENAMEX> articles has dried to a trickle, and even
the mythical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is devoid of impeachment talk.

            "Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> I
have been talking to say they haven't thought about it at all. They had an
active desire to rid their memory of it. The level of traumatic amnesia is
quite remarkable," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Baker</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political scientist</ENAMEX>
who studies impeachment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> followed the increasingly typical pattern of the
modern media event. It was exaggerated beyond reason while it was unfolding.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> overdosed on it. As soon as it ended, the sand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> washed away,
supplanted by the next big thing. (See also: the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. Supposedly the
defining event of the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War world</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> brouhaha disappeared
moments after the fighting stopped and left no lasting impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
politics.)

            Impeachment may be
forgotten, but it's not gone. It lingers sourly but not in quite the ways
anyone expected. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> consensus predictions about how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> would
change <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics: It would make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX> and murder
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> at the polls in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s approval
ratings remain high, and he has been able to prosecute a war almost
single-handedly. And <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have all but surrendered the idea that
impeachment can be a campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>. They fund-raised off impeachment
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Kennedy</ENAMEX> has abandoned his plan to make impeachment the
centerpiece of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> campaigns. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are not so focused on
impeachment that they would come into the voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booths</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX> and
say, 'Aha, he was for impeachment,' and vote against him," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pollster Mark Mellman</ENAMEX>.

            Impeachment continues to distort politics, but not as
itself. It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masked Impeachment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sublimated Impeachment</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, seething with rage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lech in chief</ENAMEX>, are the most potent
example. They didn't trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> much before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. Now they don't trust
him at all, and they yearn to nail him once and for all. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
crisis, which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> privately called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s war," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> opposition to
intervention stemmed as much from a desire to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as from any
principle. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> effort to undermine the war was a continuation
of impeachment," sniffs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Houser</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> also bears some
responsibility for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s paralysis. The personal rancor fomented by
impeachment blocks bipartisan cooperation. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> remain at each other's throats. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, still
furious at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s indictment of him, doesn't work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, who want to run against the do-nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, are
happy to stall major legislation. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impeachment</ENAMEX>, of course, is hardly the sole
cause of paralysis. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are content to delay big legislation till
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s presidential inauguration. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> intruded during the few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> when major bills could have been considered. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> is so
thin and fractured that passing contentious legislation was almost certainly
impossible, even if there had been time.)

            Impeachment has also frozen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> but for a less
ominous reason. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, which finished impeachment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> lost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first two months</TIMEX> of its current session to the trial. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">massively</ENAMEX> delayed planning and bill-writing, a traffic jam that still has not
cleared.

            Impeachment is twisting
the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, born to suffer for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sins, is
bearing the cross for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Kohut</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pew Research Center</ENAMEX> cites
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s poor ratings in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-to-heads against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> as evidence that the veep is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fatigue." And the only discernible reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> clone in both middle-road policy and stump awkwardness--is polling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> is that he is independent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal
machine.

            Impeachment so haunts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> that he has designed his entire
campaign around neutralizing it. Had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> never occurred, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> surely would
be running on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> economic boom. Instead, he has placed family
values and personal morality at the heart of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, and the first act of
his campaign was to schedule a series of interviews in which he denounced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential campaign is being
shaped by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>word as well. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rage benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in
the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> they represent. But anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonism</ENAMEX> is not a tenable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> strategy. Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have anointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> because he is mercifully
disconnected from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who can preach the
winning message of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> (morality good, lechery bad) but isn't associated
with the screeching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">impeachers</ENAMEX> who are so unpopular nationwide.

            Impeachment may be, in the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
Zogby, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Unmentionable</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> will make it a hidden foundation
of their strategy, will imply and suggest and insinuate. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will hint
at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> immorality, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will poke at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> obsessive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nuttiness</ENAMEX>. The points will be scored obliquely, but almost no one will risk the
word itself.

         
      
   
