
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Perils of E-</ENAMEX>Fund Raising

            The
pitch arrived by e-mail, and it was a direct appeal for money.

            It
appeared to come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Draper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX>, whose
e-mail would be eagerly read by anyone interested in the financing of
technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. But this message wasn't about funding technology: It was
about funding the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            "Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friend</ENAMEX>," it began, "Please send <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> and call <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to join us in
support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." The e-solicitation, dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 4</TIMEX>,
gave out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Draper</ENAMEX>'s office phone number at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Draper Fisher Jurvetson</ENAMEX>,
his e-mail address, and a place for checks to be sent.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Contributors</ENAMEX> who raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>, the e-mail said, could "be listed as a cohost
and be invited to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIP</ENAMEX> photo reception" at an event in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redwood City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 30</TIMEX>. The final line said: "P.S. Forward this e-mail on to your address
list and get some viral marketing going."

            Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> did, but at least a few questioned whether this was an authorized
request for money, or a hoax. "Obviously, someone is out to get him," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VirtualFund</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, shortly after receiving
the e-mail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Draper</ENAMEX> would be flooded by angry
complaints from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "who don't know who he is and who think he really did
spam them."

            In
fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Draper</ENAMEX> did spam them. "The e-mail was real," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Draper</ENAMEX> later confirmed. "I'm
happy about it because I happen to think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> is the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for the
job."

            
Welcome to the murky world of e-mail fund raising.

            As
more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and more political campaigns get on the Internet, e-mail is
replacing many of the campaign tasks traditionally handled through telephone
and direct mail. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">About $3 billion</NUMEX> will be spent on all political direct mail in
the current <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> electoral cycle, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Faucheaux</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaigns & Elections</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. In many cases, direct mail
represents a campaign's single largest expenditure (although presidential
campaigns have a different spending mix, because of their lopsided use of TV
advertising).

            As a
fund-raising device, e-mail has powerful advantages over direct mail. For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">starters</ENAMEX>, it's essentially free. It's also self-replicating: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> enthusiastic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> can easily send e-mail along to dozens of others, without the
campaign having to rent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an additional</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> list.

            But as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Draper</ENAMEX> incident shows, the process can also create some unexpected
headaches. A traditional direct mail solicitation usually contains legal
reassurances that the solicitation is authorized (and the cost of postage makes
an unauthorized mailing an expensive proposition), which some e-mail
solicitations currently lack. Also, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> do not screen their e-mail
address books politically, meaning that a solicitation sent out to all a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> may well end up in the hands of someone who doesn't want
it--which could turn into a public relations problem.

            That's
what happened when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Perkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Herring</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, sent out an invitation to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> luncheon as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Draper</ENAMEX>. He used a
list from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Eye</ENAMEX>, one of the e-mail newsletters that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Herring</ENAMEX>
publishes. Using a pun on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Herring</ENAMEX> 's name, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins</ENAMEX>' note appeared to
imply that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> donation would enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' relationship to the
publication. "If you want to be a really big <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fish</ENAMEX>, you can become a cohost of
this event by committing to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>, which will get you into a special VIP
reception with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>," the e-mail said.

            The
message confused some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Eye</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Red Herring</ENAMEX> rapidly
began a damage control campaign. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins</ENAMEX> did not respond to several requests
for an interview.) First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> took the position that the e-mail
pitch mistakenly went out under the guise of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Eye</ENAMEX> editorial product, when
in fact it was a paid political advertisement.

            A few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins</ENAMEX> sent out a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Eye</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>, apologizing for
the blurring of journalistic and political lines. "As you know, I have strong
political ties to presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, however these are not
the opinions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Herring Communications</ENAMEX> nor do they influence the
journalistic ethics of any of the editorial properties of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Herring</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins</ENAMEX> wrote. "I apologize for the miscommunication and hope
it did not cause any irritation or confusion."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins</ENAMEX> has said that he will personally pay the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900</NUMEX> cost of the list rental
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Herring Communications</ENAMEX> (which to some degree is the same as paying
himself, since he is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shareholder</ENAMEX>). Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins</ENAMEX> told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> that he would record the expense as an in-kind
contribution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>. His apology e-mail, however, did not mention
this contribution, and as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 21</TIMEX>, it had yet to show up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
campaign's online daily roster of campaign donations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> did not
respond to a request for comment.

            
Perhaps to avoid such sticky situations, some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> are
steering clear of the e-fund-raising path--at least for now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>'
campaign accepts donations through its Web site and sends out thank you notes via e-mail to those
who contribute online--but that's all. "We haven't done any e-mail fund raising
at all," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Gettler</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> campaign, "and we don't
have any plans to do so. We believe our Internet presence is good enough." Of
course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> is spending significant sums of his own money on the
presidential campaign, making his fund-raising urgency arguably lower than that
of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            Ultimately, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaigns & Elections ' Faucheaux</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> will become
accustomed to unwanted e-mail solicitations, just as it is to political junk
mail. "As long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> are comfortable with it being there, I don't see that
[e-mail solicitations] have any particular problems," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faucheaux</ENAMEX> said.
"Remember: It's really in an experimental stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>."

         
      
   
