
   
   
      
         
            Taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulse Online</ENAMEX> 

            The
landslide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a recent TIME</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> poll on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> was a shocker.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>' choice for the presidential nomination was none other than ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>.

            That's
the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> who's wallowing near the bottom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> field by
almost every measure--including most polls. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIME</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>'s straw poll allowed
anyone, not just registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, to cast a ballot and to do so as many times
as they wished. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s Web site linked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> to the poll, and
he pulled in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the vote.

            While
this unscientific survey is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s version of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just</NUMEX>-for-fun <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">900</ENAMEX>-number
telephone polls, there's concern among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> that the public has trouble
distinguishing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> poll from another on the Web. In fact, the news media has
picked up on some of these pseudopolls, and in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> instance reported
on the poll as if it were credible. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> straw poll on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> found <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amazingly</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> cited the results as
evidence that the political "nutty season" had begun.

            The
confusion surrounding online polls is adding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> to the biggest debate now
raging among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX>: Is it time for the Internet to replace the telephone as
the polling technology of choice?

            
Already, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris Poll Online</ENAMEX> has chronicled the upcoming presidential
contest by assembling a pool of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 million</NUMEX> Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and surveying
demographically adjusted samples of that pool <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
efforts have attracted wide interest, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>' methods have prompted concern
that Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are not representative of the national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>: They're
too white, too male, too young, and too wealthy.

            "Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> think you should not let it out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> yet," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election 2000</TIMEX>. "But Internet polling is going to
happen."

            
Meanwhile, media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> and well-established polling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup Organization</ENAMEX> say they are staying away from Internet polling--for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.

            "I
will be doing what I normally do: blocks of nationally representative telephone
surveys," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Frankovic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of surveys for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX>. She admits
she's intrigued by the flexibility of Internet polls and the potential for
sharing visual materials with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> online. But she notes that the Net
still poses problems for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX>. "You can't just randomly sample Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. You're not supposed to send unsolicited e-mail. And there is a truly
nonrepresentative nature to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actively engaged on the Internet." Most
disturbing of all, she says, is the underrepresentation of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over-65</TIMEX> age
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, which, studies show, votes in high numbers.

            At the
same time, there are new efforts underway to perfect the use of the Net as a
polling technology. InterSurvey, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> recently started by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>
University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>, pulls a random sample the old-fashioned way--through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX>-digit phone dialing--and then equips <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panel members</ENAMEX> with Internet-access
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">devices</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WebTVs</ENAMEX>, so they can respond to Web-based surveys. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>,
which is backed by venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>, has thus avoided
much of the criticism leveled at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its sampling</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">InterSurvey</ENAMEX> is also
in talks with several campaigns and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> about work on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
election.

            When
pollsters talk about a "representative sample" they mean a sampling that
accurately reflects the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> at large. The most widely used method is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX>-digit dialing, in which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first six</TIMEX> digits of a telephone number are
selected to allow for every region to be well represented, while the remaining
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> digits are dialed at random.

            One
problem with online polling is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> can't e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at random.
E-mail addresses follow no standard format. There's no central phone book for
all e-mail addresses. And some Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> block spam to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>.

            
Technology has always influenced the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> do their job. Starting in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1960s</NUMEX>, the phone replaced door-to-door polling as the preferred means of
taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s pulse. That was only after phone use became ubiquitous. But
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Commerce</ENAMEX> study found <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 26 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> had
Internet access, though more recent private studies estimate that share to be
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 38 percent</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen NetRatings</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jupiter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX>, for one, is waiting until Net use becomes more widespread before
embracing online polling. "We will continue to consider it," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Ludwig</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">research director</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX>. He says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> might use
the Internet "at some point, if the penetration gets up to where it is with the
telephone or television."

            A
recent study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mediamark Research</ENAMEX> bears out assertions that Net <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> aren't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> at large. Some of the findings: Fifty-two
percent are male, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX> are between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages of 18 and 34</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX> have
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> household incomes exceeding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88 percent</NUMEX> are white. The
comparable figures for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> at large: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent</NUMEX> are male, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX>
are in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18-to-34</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age bracket</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> have a household income above
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84 percent</NUMEX> are white.

            
Research, asserts that weighting the data--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> plans to do--won't
compensate for the differences in any meaningful way. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> notes
that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> the online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> Poll accurately called <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> and
gubernatorial races, while traditional polls miscalled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
races.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traugott</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> need to look deeper at the data from online
polls. "The question is not whether you called the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>; it's the
margin of victory between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. In the Web surveys, they got the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX> you would expect. The results were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">pro-Republican</ENAMEX>. Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are from a
higher socio-economic status; they're better educated, and they're more likely
to identify with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>."

            Will
candidates embrace Internet polling? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Gage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Market Strategies</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, the polling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that's working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>,
says his opinion of the Net's potential has shifted. "I began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> thinking
the Internet would be used in storing, retrieving, and distributing
information," he says. "More and more, I've come to realize that you can have
selected panels of suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who you know have <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> Internet access,
and you can talk to them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> about what they've seen." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gage</ENAMEX> says the
potential lies in testing advertising, keeping tabs on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, and getting
instantaneous reactions from events like debates.

         
      
   
