
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Issue, Take 2</ENAMEX>

            A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month ago</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> had begun to delete the word
"abortion" from his comments about abortion, substituting the phrase "the life
issue." By talking about "the life issue," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> signals to pro-lifers that
he's one of them, while concealing from pro-choicers that he's no longer one of
them.

            Here's
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> said about abortion in his speech at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> straw poll last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>:

            
               Now, the issue of life
is one of the most emotional and heartfelt in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Like you, I am pro-life
and believe in the life amendment. But many in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> don't share our goal,
but that doesn't mean we put our principles aside. The highest form of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statesmanship</ENAMEX> is to find ways to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> towards our goal. And I believe
that if we move forward with persistence, patience, engaging in a dialogue, we
can change the hearts and minds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. And I believe that if
we do persist, the time will come--I have faith that the time will come when
once again life will be held sacred in our hearts, in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, and, yes, in our <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>.
            

            And
here's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> said about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who fudge their positions:

            
               If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> won't
tell you where he stands, that means he either doesn't know where he stands or
he doesn't want you to know where he stands, and either one is not good for you
or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
            

            So,
let's try again. Where do you stand on abortion, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
