
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray of Light</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  A note from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraymaster</ENAMEX>: Welcome to the first installment of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fray</ENAMEX>," a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> column featuring the sharpest posts from our new reader
feedback forum. If you'd like to comment on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> article, we
encourage you to do so in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>," and if it's especially good, we'll
excerpt it here (though we may edit it for length). You might also get a reply:
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Slate writers</ENAMEX> visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX> to read the posts about their stories,
and some respond there. (For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>, our poetry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, will
be participating in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray's "Poem</ENAMEX> "
topic at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 p.m. PST</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 29</TIMEX>.)--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Brus</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SUBJECT: Love Diary</ENAMEX>
... but it's not edgy enough

            
               FROM: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Juntunen</ENAMEX>

            

               DATE
               : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thu</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept 9</TIMEX>

            This is purely an opinion. I really like reading
the diary feature. But I see the writing of high
achievers, but I'm not seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are on the edge. For example, you had
a great feature on a real estate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. But she was a very successful real
estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. Likewise, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> was a very successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            Now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> diaries, the possibility of disaster always loomed. Could we read the
diaries of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who is a little closer to the edge?

            (To respond, click
here .)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SUBJECT: Tabloids</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baloney Sandwiches</ENAMEX>

            
               FROM: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>

            
               DATE: Fri <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept</TIMEX>
10

            I would like to take a moment to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabloids</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>, and challenge anyone to make a different observation.

            My job takes me to dozens of grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, which
distribute a great number of these offensive babble-on-ion manuscripts, and
where a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> read them in the break <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Not once in my
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37 years</TIMEX> have I heard anyone admit that they believe in the content.

            Why read this crap,
then? Well, why read any type of fiction? I believe it is because there is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for rape, murder, hurricane, political treachery-types-of-reading, and a
time to just amuse yourself while you're scarfing down a baloney
sandwich-type-of reading.

            (To respond, click
here .)

            
               SUBJECT: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Response</ENAMEX>
from the author

            
               FROM: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
Mendelsohn

            
               DATE: Mon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept</TIMEX>
13

            Thank you to everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fray</ENAMEX> who's taken the
time to comment on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s "" ["<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enquiring Minds</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovakia</ENAMEX>"].

            I've enjoyed all your comments immensely,
especially Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heaney</ENAMEX>'s suggestions that I am "used to wallowing in this
type of pigslop" and that I should return my fee for writing the column. As to
the former, while I'll confess that my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is a huge mess, I'll have to
steadfastly disagree that it's quite reached the pigpen level; the latter I'll
just politely overlook.

            There seems to be a huge misunderstanding
underlying many of your posts, though, and I'd like to clear it up. "Enquiring
Minds in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovakia</ENAMEX>" is not meant to be an essay on the socio-cultural
implications of the use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> in a Slovakian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classroom</ENAMEX>. Nor is it a serious critique (or celebration for that matter) of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloids</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> gossip column lazily cribbed from the pages of other
magazines. The article you saw was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX>, a
lighthearted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> column I write for 
                  Slate
                that sums up--and
pokes fun at--what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket tabloids</ENAMEX> have been writing about for the
previous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>. (Get it? We're trying to have a little fun here.)

            I'm sorry to disappoint all of you who've
complained that I haven't done anything but sum up what's in the tabloids, but
that's precisely what I'm here to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>. I don't do any independent
investigation of the veracity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> stories, I just let them speak for
themselves, in all their ludicrous glory--hopefully in a way that's as amusing
as the tabs themselves. (But that's why I'm not at all surprised that the
poster calling him or herself "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too Embarrassed I Read This Crap</ENAMEX> " didn't find "rumpology" in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>.)

            You can read back issues of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX>," which
might help give a little perspective, by clicking here . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next month</TIMEX>'s column, covering the best (and
worst) of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , will be
online around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 5</TIMEX> or so.

            Thanks again for all
your insight.

            All best,

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Mendelsohn</ENAMEX>

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">respond,</ENAMEX> click here .)

            
               SUBJECT: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
speech

            
               FROM: maureen

            
               DATE: Tues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept</TIMEX>
14

            Sure, "a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smile</ENAMEX>, the pleasure of helping someone in need, friendship," etc., etc., may be
both hard to measure and extremely corny, but let's not get carried away. There
is no doubt that those things are all indirectly but absolutely affected by
those who govern, via economic and social policy. If elected, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> might
even use (unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>) the bully pulpit to remind us of the critical
importance of those intangibles in creating responsible and compassionate adult
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. It is more than empty rhetoric.

            (To respond, click
here .)

            
               SUBJECT: you think
this is a joke<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>!

            
               FROM: outraged

            
               DATE: Thu <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>

            A few things to say about the ["<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trippin</ENAMEX>' at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNC</ENAMEX>"]:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. If you don't have an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, say <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis</ENAMEX>, why on earth do you expect to feel any effects from a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> which is
intended to treat said <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>? Side effects, sure, but I would doubt any
primary effects would be felt.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Depression</ENAMEX> is a serious illness. Why must you
treat anti-depressants as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> toys?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. If you think herbal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> are necessarily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">safer</ENAMEX> or have less side effects than commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>, where do you
think those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX> came from in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place? Many, if not most,
common <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> were originally a substance that occurred in nature, such as
various plant extracts.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Ever heard of a self-fulfilling prophecy? Or the
placebo effect? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> could conceivably have convinced him/herself that
because a product is supposed to make one feel less depressed (and therefore
happier??!!), he/she will therefore feel better. The mind is a powerful thing,
and sometimes may be as effective or even more effective in treating a physical
or mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malady</ENAMEX>, than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX> (herbal or otherwise).

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Anti-depressants are not meant to make one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">happier</ENAMEX> , per se, but rather to make one feel normal and better able to
deal with everyday details that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take for granted. (I suffered
clinical depression for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>; I know.) So why should it be a big
surprise if a non-depressed individual does not notice any effects from taking
an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anti-depressant medication</ENAMEX>?? Put another way, anti-depressants don't make
you happy, they just help lift you to a plateau from which you are able to seek
your own happiness, whatever that may consist of.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Severe <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> is
not a joke. Why must the treatment of this illness always become one? Don't
treat it so lightly unless you've been there.

            (To respond, click here .)

         
      
   
