
   
   
      
         
            Where <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are All the Online Ads</ENAMEX>?

            After
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of dullness, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> presidential primary now looks like a
contest. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> preening and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> backpedaling, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX>
Party is enjoying its widest media exposure since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>'s '92 run.

            
Normally, presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> try to build on momentum created in the "free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>" by purchasing ads. Some campaigns, notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s, have jumped
into the ad game--but not on the Web. So where are the online ads?

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> was supposed to be the time that political advertising
splashed across the Web. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> virtue of virtual ads, said political and
advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, is the cost relative to a typical TV spot. Also, online
ads can be more compelling than print or radio spots. Moreover, because the Net
is a distinct medium, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> could experiment online with targeted ads that
might not suit other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.

            So
far, though, that's all theoretical: As well as can be determined, no major
party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has yet run a Web advertisement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>-based ad-tracking
firm AdRelevance
(which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was bought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Metrix</ENAMEX>) is trying to measure Web traffic
for all presidential advertising in this race. "We've seen nothing to date,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Ryan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AdRelevance</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of media research.

            That's
not because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have avoided advertising altogether. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 26</TIMEX>,
for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign conspicuously took out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-page print ads
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> , major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dailies</ENAMEX> in the crucial early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also
offer Web sites, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign apparently saw no value in extending
the ad campaign into cyberspace. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Howard</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, said, "As
far as I know, we have not purchased space on any Web sites, whether they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> running the ads in print version, or otherwise."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AdRelevance's Ryan</ENAMEX> says that, at least at this stage of the presidential cycle,
campaigns seem to be clinging to more traditional promotional channels. "I
don't think [the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>] will start [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>] advertising until after the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas season</TIMEX> when they start their television campaigns," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> said. "There
is also the likelihood that some may not advertise on the Web at all."

            One
source close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> had
tentative plans to advertise online in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> as far back as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>. But
the plans were shelved when it became too time-consuming to coordinate the
campaign's online messages with its offline messages.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> said that the campaign is interested in online advertising, citing
an arrangement back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RealNetworks</ENAMEX> for a Web ad that announced the
Internet availability of the audio of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s announcement speech. Any further
details, he said, were "not something we're willing to talk about at this time.
We tend not to talk about our advertising strategy until we do the ads, because
we don't want our competition to know."

         
      
   
