
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX> <STRONG><EM>Slate</EM></STRONG>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX> <STRONG><EM>Slate</EM></STRONG>

            A few housekeeping
announcements:

            

               Access to the "
                     Slate
                   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archives"</ENAMEX> (formerly known as "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compost</ENAMEX>") is now free to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonsubscribers</ENAMEX>. Find past

                     Slate
                   articles by using the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Search</ENAMEX> 
                     Slate
                   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archives</ENAMEX>"
function at the bottom of each page or by going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archives</ENAMEX> page (also
accessible in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utilities</ENAMEX>" drop-down menu). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archives</ENAMEX> page features,
among other delights, a virtual reality function that allows you to imagine
that it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any week</TIMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1996</TIMEX>, re-create the 
                     Slate
                   Table of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contents</ENAMEX>, and relive the excitement of that particular moment. Or, for those of
you who didn't read 
                     Slate
                   for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 10 months</TIMEX> or so we were
charging for access to almost all content, this is a handy way to catch
up.


               While we're giving stuff away, we also have a new free e-mail service:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> delivery (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days a week</TIMEX>) of 
                     Slate
                  's home page, featuring
descriptions of and links to every 
                     Slate
                   <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> that is new that
day. If your e-mail program accepts mail sent in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTML</ENAMEX>, you'll get the actual
home page. If not, you can ask for an all-text version. Click here to sign up.
(Other e-mail services, including <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> delivery of
our all-text edition, 
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                  , are still services for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> only.)


               Check out our new "
                     
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Store</ENAMEX>
                     ." We
don't just sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> T-shirts and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> mugs. In fact, we don't sell
that stuff at all (though we will within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>). But if you want to pick
up a last-minute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes-Benz</ENAMEX>, this is the place to do it. Also books,
chocolates, and other essentials of life.

               

               
                  
                     Slate
                   is now available on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PalmPilots</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows CE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">devices</ENAMEX>,
through the good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AvantGo</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. It's a great way to keep up with the
world and impress your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with how busy you are. We offer a variety of

                     Slate
                   features, including <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>, for these hand-held
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gizmos</ENAMEX>. You need to register (it's free), which you can do here and then subscribe to
the 
                     Slate
                   options you want (yes, yes, that's free too), which
you can do right here .
Then you'll no longer need to waste those valuable <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> spent waiting for
the elevator.


               But it's hard to read a hand-held computer while on the treadmill at the
health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> or while driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>--or, for that matter, while at your grown-up
computer. For that you need 
                     Slate
                   by audio. A link on the page
(look near the top left of the page or click here for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s audio edition) will bring you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> national newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summary</ENAMEX> (read aloud by a voice far more mellifluous than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>'s own). You'll
need <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Windows Media Player</ENAMEX> software (which you may already have if you've
installed the latest version of Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>). If you don't have it,
there's a link on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> page for that, too, or click here .
Free, free, yes, of course, free.


               To hear 
                     Slate
                   by audio on devices other than your computer,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows CE</ENAMEX> hand-held machines, you'll need to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Audible</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> . This is a site that offers audio
versions of a wide variety of printed material, including selections from

                     Slate
                  . They also offer their own listening gizmo, which you can
leave on your dashboard and get downloaded audio over your car radio (or
through headphones). The 
                     Slate
                   selections include <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moneybox</ENAMEX>." To get them through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audible</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, you must
subscribe. And no, this one is not free. It's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.95</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$49.95</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.
But --<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> to 
                     Slate
                   itself can get an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audible</ENAMEX>
subscription for free. A 
                     Slate
                   
                  subscription costs just
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Do the math. It doesn't take a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PalmPilot</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
