
   
   
      
         
            <EM><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Daddy</ENAMEX></EM><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Day</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Daddy</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandler</ENAMEX>'s latest film immature, irresponsible, and only marginally funny. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moviegoers</ENAMEX> couldn't have cared less: The film beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> for the No. 1
spot at the box office and had the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest opening ever for a comedy
(behind the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Spy Who Shagged Me</ENAMEX> ). Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">premise: A thirtysomething</ENAMEX> slacker adopts a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to demonstrate his maturity
to his wary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>. Since it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandler</ENAMEX> film (he shares a writing credit),
this "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>" teaches his young charge how to pee in public, spit, and trip
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rollerbladers</ENAMEX> and tells him that the only thing better than drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoo-Hoo</ENAMEX> is
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokin</ENAMEX>' dope." Like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> is
not impressed: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Daddy</ENAMEX> should be reported to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>." It's not as funny as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Waterboy</ENAMEX> , it's not as sweet as The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wedding Singer</ENAMEX> , and it fails at its only real goal: It "doesn't generate a
lot of big laughs" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here for info
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandler</ENAMEX>'s earlier films.)

            

               
                  An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ideal Husband</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Everett</ENAMEX>
turns in a "brilliant comic performance" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ) as an idle and decadent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX> in this adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s play, but the rest of the film gets mediocre notices. The chief
complaints: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s sharp edge has been dulled--it's "likable" and
"handsome" but "diluted" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the
story "unfolds with all the urgency of a dainty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> napkin" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the plot, a blackmail scheme with many moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quandaries</ENAMEX> to resolve, ends too tidily and happily for its own good. (For loads
of dreamy photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Everett</ENAMEX>, check out this fan
site.)

            

               
                  Return With Honor
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean Releasing</ENAMEX>). This documentary
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> who were held as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POWs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> wins
excellent marks from most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>: "engrossing and chilling" says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kauffmann</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Republic ; Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's Gleiberman
says, "You emerge shaken, with your perceptions--of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and of war in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>--permanently enlarged." A few carp about the film's cloying, overt
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">patriotism</ENAMEX>--and the avoidance of the politics and protests that surrounded the
war--with the most vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissenters</ENAMEX> saying it "restart[s] the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne-ing</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael Atkinson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). For most, though, the
stories, told by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 20</NUMEX> captured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airmen</ENAMEX>, speak eloquently and powerfully.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read about the film's opening <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Air</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Museum</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Who's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gish Jen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jen</ENAMEX> switches
from novels (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promised Land</ENAMEX> ) to stories, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are impressed. The collection covers the same ground as her two
previous books--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> and biracial experience in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--and she
covers it with "equal measures of pathos and wry fun ... the collection, at its
considerable best, finds words for all the high and low notes of the raucous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> anthem" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Thompson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> is less enamored than most, noting that
a few of the stories "appear to be studies for [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jen</ENAMEX>'s] earlier novels and stand
somewhat shakily on their own." (Read the first
story courtesy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker Evans</ENAMEX>
               ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James R. Mellow</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Books</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mellow</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Book Award</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, died before completing this long
biography of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>--making it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> example
(after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX>'s True at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Light</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ellison</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juneteenth</ENAMEX> ) of an unfinished work by a deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> published before
proper completion. The biography reveals fascinating details about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' life
and provides a new insight into his art, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say it gets weighted down
by superfluous material the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> would likely have removed had he finished
the book, resulting in a somewhat "exasperating" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tome</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Loke</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Even worse, the ending, which details <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' final
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and death from drinking, is still in the form of unfinished notes by
Mellow. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to see a sampling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' photographs.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgments</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Movie
            

            

               
                  My <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Son the Fanatic</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> love this
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> film directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Udayan Prasad</ENAMEX> about the life and dreams of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">downtrodden Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> in the north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. Their only quibble:
It's more of an extended character study than a full-fledged drama.

            
               Music
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric</ENAMEX>
Honey
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luscious Jackson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMD/Capitol</ENAMEX>). Solid reviews for the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> album. Riding on the success of their breakout
Fever <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Fever Out</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), they've turned in another smooth 'n' mellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">album</ENAMEX>, but this one is "a more eclectic mix of hip-hop, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop</ENAMEX> and rock sounds
wrapped around sensual vocals" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tad Hendrickson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMJ</ENAMEX> ).

         
      
   
