
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Witch Way Should They Go</ENAMEX>?

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I read you often and now need advice. My son
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> are getting married soon, and I have serious questions about
the ceremony. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> and very successful. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> and is a very
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intelligent</ENAMEX>, successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. They have been together <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, living
together for the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. The problem is not their relationship, but my son
and his intended are both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witches</ENAMEX>--that's right, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witches</ENAMEX>--and they are having a
"handfasting," a witchcraft wedding ceremony. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I are devout
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>, and it seems that going to a pagan ceremony goes against all our
religious beliefs. Even one of the elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parish</ENAMEX> said it would be
against God to attend such an event, though a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> said as long as we
didn't take part in the ceremony, it would be OK.
            

            
               I know my son
doesn't believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Satan</ENAMEX> or evil. He's a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, and I'm proud of him.
He has even allowed me to read the ceremony that will be performed. Actually,
it's just about the most beautiful ceremony I've ever read, but I'm very
confused. Should I possibly go against my faith to support my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> by attending
a pagan rite, or should I alienate my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> because of my own religious beliefs?
Any advice would be appreciated.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Cha</ENAMEX>,

            Oh, my, talk about
dilemmas ... your cauldron runneth over. Prudie, however, feels comfortable
with the assessment of the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>, and you should, too. Since you're
not participating in the actual ceremony and found nothing objectionable in the
text, you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> should not deny this lovely son your presence. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes you appreciate the reversed roles in this situation: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usually</ENAMEX>, it's
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, matrimonially

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Your advice to "" struck me as amazing. From
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> use, the rule among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> seems to be nothing spoken
in the "sit-downs," banal comments of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot</ENAMEX> enough for you?" variety at the
"stand-ups," and pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trifles</ENAMEX> at the washstands.
            

            
               By the way, an old
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro</ENAMEX> once told me never to discuss anything of importance in a
bathroom or an elevator. I once was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> elevator with the other
side's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, who hadn't yet been introduced to me, who spent the ride down
discussing strategy with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>!
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faithfully</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Front</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Eyes</ENAMEX>,

            Thank you for one of the
better letters inviting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to reconsider. Please read on.

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I enjoy your column
and often think your advice is excellent and daring. Except in the case of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wondering</ENAMEX>, too." I suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> was napping when she answered that one. I,
myself, not being shy, wouldn't mind a friendly chat while in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> stalls
but many would. Some would feel embarrassed at simply being identified and
addressed in a compromising position. Others would feel tense, and conversation
might interfere with the reason they are there. Not to mention that some people
go there to sit and be quiet and have a small private break. Addressing someone
by name, after identifying them by their shoes while they are sitting on the
commode, seems downright rude to me.
            

            

               --Privacy Please
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Pri</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has finished her nap and wishes to
acknowledge that the flub-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> was visiting her when she answered that
letter. Persuaded by several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, she now wishes to reverse herself and begs
the pardon of anyone who's had to suffer chitchat during a private moment
simply because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> said it was OK.

            An interesting sidelight
to bathroom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kremlinology</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> tradition articulated in the
preceding letter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> do not have such a rigid convention, but they weighed
in, as well, with pleas for silence when nature calls.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, correctively

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>, and my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boyfriend</ENAMEX> and I are expecting our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX> is terribly embarrassed by the fact that we are not married. (But we've
been living together for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years</TIMEX>.) I was brought up with the
values that you got engaged, got married, and then started a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. For some
reason, I was blessed with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> much sooner than planned. What can I say
or do to convey to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> that this is a blessing and not a
tragic event? Please help. Thank you very much.
            

            

               --Confused
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Con</ENAMEX>,

            For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, you can tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>'s mother
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> is on time; the wedding is late. (Was this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, by any chance,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> when they decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingrid Bergman</ENAMEX> should be kept out
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>? If you have no idea what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> is talking about, ask your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.)

            In any case, your
attitude about the blessed event is most pleasing, and your relationship sounds
solid. To assuage social convention, however, and to validate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s
suggested retort, perhaps you and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>-to-be might consider legally tying
the knot ... and perhaps before the little bundle of joy requires a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitter</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, expectantly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Prude,</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               I was ensconced in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manly</ENAMEX> game of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">collegiate football</ENAMEX>-watching when I overheard the womenfolk
discussing proper breast-feeding etiquette. When asked, I indicated that as
long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX> is hidden under a blanket with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, I don't mind.
However, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> goes "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX>" and everything is out in the
open, I feel a bit squeamish. There was no consensus amongst the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> (one
turned up the volume on the game so he didn't have to deal with the whole
thing). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were mixed in their opinions. So what is appropriate when
breast- feeding in public? Thanks.
            

            

               --~jeff
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear ~jef,</ENAMEX>

            Though there is
disagreement on the subject, good sense and good taste would seem to dictate
that this perfectly normal function can be carried out in public with as little
obviousness as is feasible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is not sure about a total blanket tent for
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and breast, but an attempt at decorous draping would seem the thing
to strive for.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, discreetly

         
      
   
