
   
   
      
         
            What Did You Do in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Junior</ENAMEX>?

            The
draft issue is back. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> avoided <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> by being admitted to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air National Guard</ENAMEX> with unusual speed. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That same day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> presented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s side of the story. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> use his connections
to dodge the draft? That depends on the standards by which his conduct should
be measured, which in turn are the subject of a vigorous spin war.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morality</ENAMEX> vs. legality. The moral argument against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> who
joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard</ENAMEX> to avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> is that they jumped the line--that they used
their connections to leapfrog ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard applicants</ENAMEX>, leaving those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> to be drafted into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> to die in their place. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
focused its story on the alleged unfairness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "quick" admission but
concedes that "there is no evidence of illegality or regulations broken to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accommodate Bush</ENAMEX>'s entry and rise in the service."

            Since
the moral question is tricky but the legal question is open and shut, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> want to focus on the latter. So far, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are obliging them.
"If [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>] didn't do anything illegal or didn't break any regulations, how
important or serious is this allegation<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Serrano</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> piece, replied
that "it's serious in the sense that others probably had to go into the regular
service because of the favoritism that he got." But that answer didn't cut it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> concluded that "no rules or laws were broken," and even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s fiercest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, confined the issue to whether "anything
illegal was done."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preference</ENAMEX> vs. qualification. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> constantly compares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
experience to that of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard applicants</ENAMEX>. "Although getting into the state
units was difficult for most others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was soon in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard</ENAMEX>," says the
Times . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> got a "special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> making him an instant second
lieutenant" and "was able to jump into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> ranks without the
exceptional credentials many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer candidates</ENAMEX> possessed." The
News adds that in the pilot aptitude section of the written test for
pilot trainees, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> scored "in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th percentile</NUMEX>, the lowest
allowed for would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fliers</ENAMEX>." In short, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s merits and treatment are
examined relative to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>', his story looks fishy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
response is to shift the analysis from a relative to an absolute standard, from
whether others were more qualified or more slowly admitted to whether he met
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guard</ENAMEX>'s minimum "qualifications." "I met all the criteria, I met all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">qualifications</ENAMEX>," he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who asked about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> used the same term: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> found him absolutely
qualified to be commissioned."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
Treatment vs. string-pulling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> want the story to be about how
he was treated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wants the story to be about whether he pulled strings.
That's because if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>, you can get special
treatment just by introducing yourself. You don't have to pull strings. The
Times says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "received favorable treatment," and "doors were opened"
for him. Note the passive voice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> found "no sign that political
influence helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> along," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> adds, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX> who
supervised Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and approved his admission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard</ENAMEX> said they were
never contacted by anyone on Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s behalf." For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, that ends the
discussion. "The favoritism was all on the side of the military reaching out to
him rather than anything he or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> did," observed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hume</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> agreed: "I am sure he got preferential treatment. But what is he
supposed to do? [Say] 'My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>?' " No strings, no
story.

            The
question <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are too coarse to contemplate is whether there's a zone
between passive innocence and active manipulation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to whom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> applied for admission told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> mentioned his father
right away: "He said he wanted to fly just like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s spokesman
pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, "because of his circumstances, made an ideal subject for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> publicity." In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> knew the deck was stacked in his
favor. All he did was play the cards.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Location</ENAMEX> vs. job title. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> flew fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> served as
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s location sounds more manly, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s job
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> looks better. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s location, warning that
he "will be asked to explain how he did not come to serve in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s least
popular war." To underscore the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> comparison, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
notes that one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s rivals, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, "has joked that as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Vietnam</ENAMEX> he slept more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">soundly</ENAMEX> knowing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was
defending the shores of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> from invasion." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> sympathizer, suggested that the
difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is that one "went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>" and one "did
not."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> with which to combat this characterization. Since pundits
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, they find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s portrayal of his journalism as military
service somewhat preposterous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> served "as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, not as a combatant,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">observed Fortune</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Birnbaum</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
"went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, but as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, not as an infantryman," agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> also points out that
he tried to volunteer for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard</ENAMEX> program that sent several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> indicates that he was rejected because he was clearly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unqualified</ENAMEX>. Whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> deserves admiration for volunteering or deserves
suspicion because he knew he would be rejected can be debated.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s most
effective point is that he was, as he told reporters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4</TIMEX>, "a fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> never had to fight, but he did fly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter jets</ENAMEX>, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter pilot</ENAMEX>"
sounds a lot better than "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
How you served vs. whether you served. Investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> assume that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard</ENAMEX> service should be compared to an
alternative scenario in which he served in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wants to highlight a
different alternative--dodging the draft and ducking military service
altogether--against which the course he chose looks better. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, he told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Chronicle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, "[y]our options either were to avoid
the draft or sign up, and I signed up." After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story broke this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> told reporters, "I asked to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>," "I served my
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," and "I'm very proud of my service."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
has several decisive advantages on this question. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of his generation
know someone who avoided the draft in a less respectable way than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> younger than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> know little of the military and therefore
tend to be impressed that he served at all rather than concerned with how he
served. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, overshadows the campaign as a
constant reminder of the contrast between serving and not serving. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> used
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Officers Training Corps</ENAMEX> to escape the draft, then backed out and
never served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROTC</ENAMEX>. Against this background, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guard</ENAMEX> service looks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noble</ENAMEX>. "A lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did not do nearly as much as he did," argued
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> . "He did something honorable. At least he
actually joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, agreed:
"Here is a fellow that went and flew <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> and learned to be a pilot and
was prepared to go, if he had to go. That is a lot."

            Who's
winning the war over the draft? Since the talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> that it's a "non-story," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Round 1</ENAMEX> goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. But the contest
between the pro- and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> spins is less interesting than the reality that
lies between them. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> who flew with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
that their service was "a non-threatening way to do your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, get paid
well for some long shifts, and feel good about your own involvement. ... It was
a cushy way to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriot</ENAMEX>." Perhaps the story worth telling about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
military service is not whether it was cushy or patriotic, but how it was
both.

         
      
   
