
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">318</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Non, Je Ne Regrette Rien&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "You won't hear
any apologies from me," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Ostroff</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>. "Anyone who continues to maintain that there was some mistake here
doesn't understand the way science proceeds." What isn't Ostroff apologizing
for?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 317</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">She's Still Got It":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           "We are quite the best <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. In my lifetime all the problems have come from mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and all
the solutions have come from the English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of the world," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> in her first speech at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX> conference since
stepping down as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Thatcher</ENAMEX> was inspired to speak by
a particular cause. What?
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            
"Raising money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot Leisuredome</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX>
            

            "Oh,
when will the western <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> rappers make peace with the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">rappers?</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National If English Was Good Enough for Our Lord Jesus Christ, It's Good</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enough for Me Day</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Basial</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic</ENAMEX>, Not an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> . (She was dictating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreword</ENAMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Chen</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony D. Stone</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Renbaum , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Akawie</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PinochetAid</ENAMEX> concert."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy Christianson</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>
present us with contrasting retirement strategies--pathetic senility and
rancorous immortality, each in its way a grotesque form of self-parody. We
always knew they had it in them. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> era chose
other retirement plans. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duvalier</ENAMEX> went with exile to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX> went with
prison, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brezhnev</ENAMEX>, I believe, is now a privately owned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cement</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> near
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sverdlovsk</ENAMEX>. What none of them ever does is die in a hideous automobile
accident. This defies all probabilities. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> has been in a car
crash. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty thousand</NUMEX> of us die that way <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. Either each powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retiree</ENAMEX> is transported in some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titanium</ENAMEX> case or that satanic pact is
still in effect even after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Either way, great benefits.

            
               Stand

               by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Man Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady T.</ENAMEX> was shaken from her slumber by the plight
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>.

            "Make no mistake, revenge by the left, not justice
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> case is all about,'' she declared to a
packed hall in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blackpool</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> conference.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>," she said--choosing his honorific
with the same care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> uses when calling its own pet war criminal "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dr.</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>--"is, in truth, on trial not for anything complained in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baltazar Garzon</ENAMEX>'s indictment but for defeating communism. "

            "What the left cannot forgive is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>
undoubtedly saved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> and helped save <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>,'' she said. "That, and
the torture and murder of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, but mostly that," she did not
add.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has
ruled that the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> can be extradited to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloutier</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco-Prussian Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Sure, all the world's
problems come from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, but who is able to produce funnier problems, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>? At last, science can decide. Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alta Vista</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>, I've double-translated a passage from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tsu</ENAMEX>-tech
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inti-Mist" Family Bidet</ENAMEX> Web site into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> then back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>:

            

               Sit Of heating: A seat of heating eliminates "the frosted contact" usually
tested when to rest on a seat of toilet cooled by the cold of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>. You
will be astonished and satisfied the comfortable comfort of the seat of toilet
of heating <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">by Bidet of Inti-Mist</ENAMEX>.

            

            The same passages,
translated into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> then back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>:

            

               Lively seat: A lively seat eliminates the "icy note" normally experienced,
when sitting on a toilet seat to showers of the winter cooled down. They are
surprised at cozy the comfort of the lively toilet seat intimatist bidet and
please.

            

            
               Who is funnier? Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Ongoing

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bail-Out Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who writes about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> ..." Boom.
Right there. That's where I snapped off my radio, in the opening phrase of a
piece by some twinkly gasbag on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>'s annoying <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sunday Edition</ENAMEX> .

            Certain phrases are so potent and evocative they
inspire you to hurl the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, or hurl yourself across the
room to switch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, or hurl the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to ... not that I'd
ever do that.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to submit similar
examples--from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, or broadcast news--of what <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> used to call "letters we never finished reading" (or something like
that).

            Best examples to run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            Anglo-French hostility.

         
      
   
