
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vines</ENAMEX> of Tarzan

            
               What's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrong With</ENAMEX>
Being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Momma</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lind</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>") needs to get a grip. It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>'
movie, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, and it is as true to the original text as it can be in our
politically correct times. A more "feminized" society is not the repressed,
horrible existence Lind portrays--why are less violence, less aggression, less
machismo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">less extremist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwinism</ENAMEX>, and greater sensitivity bad things? Let's
face it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> took their "survival of the fittest" theory out of
hand and the result was far from pretty.

            And anyway, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who
knows how to treat his mother well is way sexier than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who thinks he's too
cool and manly to care for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lind</ENAMEX> is grumpy because he wouldn't
look quite so hot in a loincloth by conventional standards of beauty.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Stanton Euclid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>

            
               Book
Clubbing
            

            Might I respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alterman</ENAMEX>'s sarcastic remark (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>") that I "graciously declined" to reply to a
column by him in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> attacking my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diarist</ENAMEX>"
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale University Press</ENAMEX> and its series on communism? For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time--the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was in a letters <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alterman</ENAMEX> has somehow
inferred that my silence connoted acquiescence with his article. Since Alterman
did not point out any factual inaccuracies in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Diarist</ENAMEX> and since he defended
the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> were sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gulag legally</ENAMEX>, I thought his article
too trivial and silly to merit a response. But because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alterman</ENAMEX> ungraciously
persists in depicting me as having repudiated my own article, I feel obliged,
for what it's worth, to note that I think it holds up perfectly well.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Heilbrunn</ENAMEX> Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Alterman</ENAMEX>
replies: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Heilbrunn</ENAMEX> has messed up yet again. I intended no sarcasm in
crediting him with sensibly refusing to defend what was clearly a shoddy and
indefensible piece of work. I thought he was showing some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heilbrunn</ENAMEX> calls my
objections to his Diarist "trivial" and "silly." Let's say he's right. Why,
then, did conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Klehr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Earl Haynes</ENAMEX> feel a need
to condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heilbrunn</ENAMEX> as well in letters published in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> 's own letters
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX>? Why did the equally conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gid Powers</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heilbrunn</ENAMEX>'s
accusations against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> "absurd" and existing "only in the minds of the
pathologically suspicious" on the same page? Why did even the venerated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anti-Stalinist historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Conquest</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heilbrunn</ENAMEX>'s article "unfair" and
"exaggerated"? Why did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale University Press</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ryden</ENAMEX>,
insist in a letter to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Editor-in-Chief Martin Peretz</ENAMEX> has admitted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heilbrunn</ENAMEX>'s piece is unfounded
and should not have been published." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peretz</ENAMEX> denies this.) Are the criticisms
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Klehr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Earl Haynes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Conquest</ENAMEX>--and if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryden</ENAMEX> is to be
believed--even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heilbrunn</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty Peretz</ENAMEX>, among many others, all too
"trivial" and "silly" to merit a response as well? Or was a strategic silence
really the right response for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heilbrunn</ENAMEX> after all?
            

            
               Criticizing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo Critics</ENAMEX>
            

            Thank you for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s brilliant analysis
("") of the war. As a lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, who feels that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> defamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the presidency, I was amazed that all
the major conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> were against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
action. After all, the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> had sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> for humanitarian reasons, and yet the operation was largely a
failure.

            I believe the prevailing
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> opinion was largely generated from an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> feeling,
particularly after a failed attempt at removing him from office. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commentator</ENAMEX> said that we should have provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX> with
weapons but not sent our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. Imagine if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had adopted this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isolationist</ENAMEX> policy during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. The face of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> might look quite a
bit different.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Spiegel</ENAMEX> Los Angeles

            
               Retire the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Policeman</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> showed more than a little bias in
the piece about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> condemnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
actions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>").

            What were we really doing bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>? Maybe
extending the ideas of a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World Order</ENAMEX>" in which hard-working <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are
expected to pay the price not only of our freedom, but of the freedom of the
whole world. We had no business in any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> actions; there was no real
possibility of this expanding throughout the region as everyone in the
administration was spouting. It didn't concern our energy supply--not much oil
comes out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. They were not a direct threat to our national security.
They were not a world threat such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. So
what were we really doing there?

            And what of the
atrocities? Were they going on before the bombing started? Do we have proof of
that? Maybe these atrocities began from the outrage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbians</ENAMEX> knowing
that their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> were getting bombed, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> being killed.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary W. Meadows Spring</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley Barks</ENAMEX>
Back
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley Jr.</ENAMEX> read a 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club</ENAMEX>" about his latest
novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Redhunter: A Novel Based on the Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> , and decided enough was enough. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clubbers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
Alterman, had called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>'s book "a lumbering, themeless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pudding</ENAMEX> of a novel
that forces one's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">eyelids</ENAMEX> shut like an invisible vise." The other, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
Radosh, had described it as "heavy and plodding, without any real juice to it."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> weighed in, defending his work against all charges aesthetic,
historical, and ideological, and quoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> writing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>'s own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> , who deemed the book "wonderfully readable ... a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">witty</ENAMEX>, fast-moving yarn." Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> has asked 
                  Slate
               
to run the following excerpt from the book, so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for
themselves. We are delighted to oblige. Click for the excerpt.

         
      
   
