
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">279</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worlds Collide&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Federal attorneys
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern District of New York</ENAMEX> arrested and indicted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a
case that touched on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hasidim</ENAMEX>, and squirrels. What's the
connection?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 278</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest Rate</ENAMEX>":
Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carleton S. Fiorina</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>, the newly announced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard company</ENAMEX>, meets the press: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My ________</ENAMEX> is
interesting but really not the subject of the story here."
               
            

            
"Ability to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> 
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Damned One-Note Media</ENAMEX>!"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Inability to distinguish 'profits' from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'losses</NUMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tullis</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Dinner with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Van Dussen</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Sexual discrimination lawsuit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Nikonovich-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kahn</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner Actives</ENAMEX> sports bra, which will go on sale at major sporting goods
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 26</TIMEX>, with a suggested retail price of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welty</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Wing</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            But of course it's not
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carleton Fiorina</ENAMEX> to say what the subject of the story is; that's the job of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. Or, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrity</ENAMEX>'s press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. You'll find your experience with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> less
frustrating if you accept the idea that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> is there to tell not your
story but his or hers. It is, no doubt, irritating to be misquoted, but at
least you retain the moral high ground and a sense of yourself as wise and
well-spoken, albeit misunderstood. What's completely intolerable is to be
accurately quoted and seen--even by yourself--to be no better than you actually
are. It is a deeply demoralizing experience for anyone who lacks adequate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">powers</ENAMEX> of self-deception and photo approval.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egalitarian Utopia</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            "My gender is interesting but really not the
subject of the story here."

            "I hope that we are at a point that everyone has
figured out that there is not a glass ceiling," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiorina</ENAMEX> added. Well, maybe.
But, while she is undoubtedly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">terrifically</ENAMEX> capable and successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>,
her new job will make her the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> ever to head a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> included in the
Dow Jones industrial average and one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> to run a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> listed on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> 500.

            The former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 billion</NUMEX> global
service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider division</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiorina</ENAMEX> is a surprising
choice in other ways, too. She is young, she is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
has traditionally found its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in-house, she brings a marketing and sales
background to the engineering culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H-P</ENAMEX>, and her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name seems utterly
unrelated to her surname.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carly</ENAMEX> was quite simply
the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H-P</ENAMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Platt</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>. "And to look fabulous doing it," he did not add.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>'s
Pom-Pom-Shaking Follow-Up
            

            How ironic. I was a cheerleader in high school, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Webb</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> as we won the national championship in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>.

            Goooooooooooooo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Quiz!!

            
               Good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>--Or Not,
Depending--Extra
            

            "An investigation into
the size of male sex organs reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> are generally better
endowed than heterosexuals. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> say they surveyed data gathered on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,172</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and found penis sizes to be larger in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> than heterosexuals
based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> measurement standards. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> say an earlier study also
shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> differ, on average, from heterosexuals in genital size.
A survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">126</NUMEX> homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had larger penises on the average than a similar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">86</NUMEX> heterosexuals."--from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The List</ENAMEX>, a service of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wired Strategies</ENAMEX>.
Subscribe free by e-mailing join-THELIST@wiredstrategies.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thanks to Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ongoing Domain Name</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GlobalEconomy</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is already registered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SatelliteTV</ENAMEX>.

            Dollar-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A-Day</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is already registered by Execulink
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>. FiftyCents-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A-Day</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is available.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to submit a similar set (a
pair will do)--a domain name that is already taken along with an amusing and
available alternative.

            You can check the availability of domain names at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eHost</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com/domain_reg/</ENAMEX>index.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>.

            Replies due by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Ambiguous name, attractive ass.

         
      
   
