
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">256</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Artifacts or Fiction</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               The list includes
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> shredder (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Shark 200</ENAMEX> personal security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shredder</ENAMEX>), a leather picture
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frame</ENAMEX> (without picture), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jockey®</ENAMEX> shorts (athletic midway
pouch brief). List of what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 255</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sorry, Right Number":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parris Glendening</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances</ENAMEX>,
released a statement that began: "Early <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, we received a call that
every parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dreads</ENAMEX>." What did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> say?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>? I've decided to major in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Rogers</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>? I'm gay. And now for the bad news ..."-- L
               arry Amoros
(similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darren Thorneycroft</ENAMEX> )

            "The
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> called upon them to sacrifice their eldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, as a sign of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>. They later learned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> was making a prank call."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
Considine
            

            "We've
traced the call ... it's coming from inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, the good news: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX> was nearby."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            The most feared (in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">good-natured</ENAMEX>, humorous way) teen news--other than the startlingly high number
of "your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> was killed in a car crash" (in a lighthearted, frolicsome
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>)--was this: Your adolescent is enjoying sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. This is a tricky
territory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who enjoy sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and liberal politics. How do you
forbid the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to practice what you, er, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>? The hypocrisy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buster</ENAMEX>?
Age-appropriate. There are many things that are permitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>--e.g.
driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>--that are not wrong in themselves, just wrong for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 5-year-old</TIMEX>.
Once you get your adolescent to endorse this idea (and to forget that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Juliet</ENAMEX>
was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just 14</NUMEX>), you've won. The rest is just arguing over what age is the
threshold for each activity. Some suggestions:

            

               Drinking--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>, in accordance with the law of the land

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dating--16</ENAMEX>, in accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' senile reminiscence

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Own Monkey--12</ENAMEX>, or whenever old enough to operate electro-stick

               Own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erotic Life</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>, if attending college out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>, if living at
home

               Own Seat on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>, or old enough to serve Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Todd Whitman</ENAMEX>'s relentless ambition

            

            
               Slurred
Answer
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glendenings</ENAMEX> that their
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond</ENAMEX>, had just been arrested for drunken driving, in a
parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30 a.m.</TIMEX> Most piquant detail: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Glendening</ENAMEX>'s assumption
that this is a universal experience.

            After giving the little
miscreant a sound thrashing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will throw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond</ENAMEX> out
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and disinherit him, or, if you choose to believe the pronouncement
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> befuddled by grief: "We will offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond</ENAMEX> our unconditional and
abiding love, support and guidance."

            
               Augmented
Quotation Extra
            

            (Each
final sentence added by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.)

            "... I
particularly want to congratulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX>. And that boozy old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> who piloted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon Valdez</ENAMEX> --I'm sending him a bouquet of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">daffodils</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>, reacting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louima</ENAMEX> verdicts.

            "...
It was such a surprise that we couldn't believe it at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. How on God's green
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX> could he think this makes the cops look good?"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Ghiorso</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Laboratory</ENAMEX>, commenting on the discovery of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new chemical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>.

            "...
We feel this will go a long way in carrying out our responsibilities to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. And we hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX> makes good use of his time on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater Owners</ENAMEX>, announcing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> will now have to present fake photo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDs</ENAMEX> to get into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-rated movies.

            "...
All I have to do is say I am going to see Star Wars ' and then sneak into
the movies I really want to see. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kartozian</ENAMEX> is as goofy as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McSweeny</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>, who has so
little respect for phony-baloney gestures that he won't even bother to purchase
a fake <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ID</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>.

            "...
He acknowledged his mistake but also said, 'Don't forget, I'm a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-time
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.B.A.</ENAMEX> All-Star,' which for every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year-old</TIMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Dream</ENAMEX>. That, and
having sex indoors."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Coen Gilbert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> sneakers,
sympathizing with company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latrell Sprewell</ENAMEX>.

            "...
All of this depends on Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s accepting the terms of the military
technical agreement, and abiding by it. He really congratulated the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cops</ENAMEX>?!!"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, assessing progress in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> talks.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Madden</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headline Haiku</ENAMEX>
            

            Haven for illicit
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-digit dialing is
the death knell.
Move into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia Inquirer</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3, 1999</TIMEX>

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology</ENAMEX> section
only)

            
               Common
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denominator</ENAMEX>, Unrun
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> interns, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burbank</ENAMEX>, prunes.

            
               Common
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denominator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, I need my old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> back.

         
      
   
