
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX> Shenanigans

            A
scandal rocked the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> monarchy when it was revealed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that
much-respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert II</ENAMEX> has an illegitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> working as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. The revelation, made in a new biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Paola</ENAMEX> by
a precocious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flemish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Daneels</ENAMEX>, shook the image of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> family famed for its moral rectitude. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Soir</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in an editorial that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belgians</ENAMEX> is "the incarnation of a unifying morality and of
proclaimed virtue." He presides over what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgians</ENAMEX> regard as "the ideal family
... even the incarnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> concluded that if the
king casts more light on the matter (he has so far refused to comment), the
long-term consequence might be no more than to make him seem more like an
ordinary mortal. Another leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Meuse</ENAMEX> , expressed
regret that "the last symbol of a united <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> is sinking into the
bedclothes," but in general the press was less condemnatory of the king's
adultery than of the intrusion into his private life. Because of this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libre</ENAMEX> refused to publish the name of his illegitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, Delphine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boel</ENAMEX>.

            The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> splashed the story on its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, together with a large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photograph of Boel</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>, seated on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her artistic creations, a multicolored
papier-mâché chair. It said she is the product of an affair between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>, now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> aristocrat--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baroness Sybille de Selys</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longchamps</ENAMEX>--during an early, troubled period in his marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Paola</ENAMEX>.
Boel was raised by the baroness and her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">industrialist</ENAMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> refused to accept her as part of the royal
family. She now lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Notting Hill</ENAMEX> but has gone into hiding since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> press descended on the fashionable west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> district <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. The
Times quoted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> opposite her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> as saying, "I
see her going out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most days</TIMEX> in quite wild clothes, like patchwork trousers.
She's often spattered in paint."

            The
Daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with a boycott by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> throne, of a banquet hosted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>, because of his "contempt for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s human
rights record." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the rebellious gesture will cause new tensions
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>. Although a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> said later that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> intended no snub to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> but was bound
by an earlier engagement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> was "motivated by his
admiration for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>, whom he has met at least twice in defiance of
Government policy." It reported that the exiled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> paid a private
visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> country estate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months ago</TIMEX>.

            In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> favorably compared
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>' behavior with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, who "was much in attendance on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Downing Street</ENAMEX> lunch given by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX>, then at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Museum</ENAMEX> exhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tang</ENAMEX> treasures sponsored by
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">flagship</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> has chosen to
flatter an odious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> in the hope of making a fortune from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
market. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX>, at whose family Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> constantly snipes,
has decided that supping once with the devil is enough" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> attended an
earlier banquet for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> at which his mother, the queen, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> also said that a special report on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> that the
Times had been due to publish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> had been postponed until after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s state visit.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Guardian</ENAMEX> united <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX>
in condemning the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> for its treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. "The right to assemble and the right of free speech remain
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the most fundamental rights in a democratic society," it said in an
editorial. "Yet little knots of human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> have been manhandled and
herded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Police</ENAMEX> in a desperate attempt to keep them out of
sight and hearing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said that one of
these manhandled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> ought to bring a civil action against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>,
so as at least to identify "which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> was in charge and from whom he
received his instructions." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> visited
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
decided to extend the same privileges to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> lamas and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> that it
allows to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, including tax breaks and the
right of access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>.

            The
election of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Megawati Sukarnoputri</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdurrahman Wahid</ENAMEX> was widely welcomed around the world as improving
the prospects for order and democracy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> said peace
should return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> now that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>" had the vice
presidency. "Once little more than a symbolic position, the post must be
regarded as pivotal, given the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year term</TIMEX> of office and the poor health of
Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wahid</ENAMEX>, said sometimes to fall asleep in mid-conversation." But it said the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> faced a difficult task in reducing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s political role.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Megawati</ENAMEX>'s appointment
"offers her bruised and fragile <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> its best hope of consolidating its
infant democracy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX> , however, reported that "massive protests" have
been taking place in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX>, who withdrew from the election after losing a confidence vote. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Sulawesi</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> was born, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> took over the local radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX> and broadcast demands for eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> to secede and become an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> published an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>, who denied that her new
magazine<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, Talk</ENAMEX> , is failing. "I have the tremendous security of knowing
that our business picture is very strong and that takes a lot of stress off,"
she said. "All my stress now is getting the product accepted, getting it
better." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Publisher Ron Galotti</ENAMEX> said Talk had "probably the most
successful launch in the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>" and had sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1 million</NUMEX>
copies of its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. He also said advertising revenue--464
pages sold for just under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 million</NUMEX>--is "way ahead of budget." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> said,
"At this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> plan. No-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> expects it to make a profit
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. We are on plan and on budget."

         
      
   
