
   
   
      
         
            Do Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates</ENAMEX> Use the Internet?

            Every
presidential candidacy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is represented by an official Web site. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
to read 
                  Slate
               's survey of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>.) But what of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> themselves? They all give lip service to the idea of the
information revolution, and especially to the quantities of cash it's pumping
into the economy. But do they know how to use personal computers? Do
they send and receive e-mail? Do they surf the Web? How regularly do they do
so? How long have they been doing so?

            Net
Election's crack research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> sent a brief e-mail questionnaire on Web
literacy to all the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. With a touch of naive optimism, we
imagined that our reporting would be complete once we'd tracked down e-mail
addresses for each of these campaigns and shipped our questionnaires off. The
idea was that the campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> , if not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> themselves,
would immediately download our questionnaire, hit "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reply</ENAMEX>," answer its not
terribly demanding questions on the spot, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> back the answers within
moments. To encourage a prompt response, we assured all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> that we
didn't intend to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> harshly those who displayed poor Web literacy,
since--let's face it--computer skills rank fairly low on the list of the things
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> needs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> in order to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Alas,</ENAMEX>
even in an age where "just-in-time inventories" are believed by some to have
eliminated economic recessions, political campaigns lack the ability--or
perhaps the inclination--to respond quickly to electronic queries. In fact,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> presidential campaigns--those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>--sent e-mails back. Of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> campaign produced a
truly "frictionless" response (that is, responded to our questionnaire before
we started making the inevitable round of follow-up phone calls to campaign
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>), though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s e-mailed responses, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes'</ENAMEX>, were
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s own words. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> we spoke with directly
about his Internet use was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, who said he'd been checking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> to track how the controversy surrounding the historical speculation in
his new book A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic</ENAMEX>, Not an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> was affecting sales.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Predictably</ENAMEX>, it's helping.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s campaign, though very cordial
when we phoned, never got back to us with answers.

            If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> are to be believed, there is no such thing as a presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who doesn't use e-mail (though we didn't bother asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cybill Shepherd</ENAMEX>, all of whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidacies</ENAMEX> remain extremely
hypothetical; and while we sent an e-mail to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX>, we lacked the
initiative to try to reach him by phone). On the other hand, it's fairly common
for a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> not to use e-mail in connection with his campaign.
(Presumably this is because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s e-mail address, once known by the
entire campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and by political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, would be spam bait.)

            Here
are the survey results (click on the graphic for an enlargement):

         
      
   
