
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999>Why It's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Not So Bad To Be Canadian</ENAMEX></SPAN></SPAN>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX>
24
            

            The
cover story concludes that technology has probably
given birth to a "new economy," though there is no statistical proof of it.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s productivity growth spurt has been concentrated in the
computer industry, anecdotal evidence suggests that technology increases the
flexibility of capital in all industries. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>'s assessment
of "new paradigm" economics.) ... A survey postulates that it is not necessarily bad to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> has universal health care, low inflation, low interest rates,
and strong economic growth. On the downside, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s economy is weaker than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>', and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> have an inferiority complex about their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  
                     
                        New
                     
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover package debates how to divide the surplus. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> argues for public investment in research, infrastructure, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, based on the premise that the information revolution, not deficit
reduction and low interest rates, undergirds our prosperity. Another piece,
which embraces the notion that smaller deficits and lower interests rates have
midwifed prosperity, proposes shoring up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, and
saving the surplus. Some minor tax relief, such as an increase in the earned
income tax credit, is also appropriate, as is boosting education and
infrastructure investment. A final article calls for "monumental tax cuts" to
restore faith in individualism, abolish the tax code's dispiriting
progressivity, and pare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> down so it can't do much.

            

               
                  
                     
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
                     , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1999</TIMEX>
               
            

            The
jokes in the unfortunately timed "political humor issue" fall hideously flat.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guest editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Stiller</ENAMEX> joshes about banishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> and is
photographed making off with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John-John</ENAMEX>'s sports equipment. ...
A mock interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky Martin</ENAMEX> suggests that he is a secret policy wonk: He
reads the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> and loves to expostulate on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX>
sugar-cane subsidies and "la domestic policy loca." ... In a
real profile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Bono</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, defends herself from charges of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promiscuity</ENAMEX>. "If I had had an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, I would have ended up
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX>," she retorts.

            
               
                  
                     
                        New
                     
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 25</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story worries about the implications of a gender-selection technology.
The experimental "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Microsort</ENAMEX>" process separates <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> chromosomes
(which create <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>) from those carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> chromosomes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> impregnate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with embryos of the favored gender. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ethicists</ENAMEX> fear that the technique
will further institutionalize sex discrimination. ... An article warns
that all computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are unsafe and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> will reap
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> from lawsuits prompted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> fiascoes.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1999</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story maps a political agenda to engage the apathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Generation X:</ENAMEX>
fiscal restraint, investment in education and training, and class-based
affirmative action. ... An article recommends a cup of "shade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>."
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>," grown in high-yield rows, doesn't taste as good. "Sustainable
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>," grown in the shade amid other vegetation, is better for the
environment and a great way to differentiate java in an overcrowded market.
... A piece claims world population will fall in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 50 years</TIMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two decades</TIMEX>, global fertility has dropped by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> per woman
and industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have fallen below the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>-per-woman
replacement rate. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on population
trends.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26</TIMEX>
            

            Special editions mourn the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">passing of JFK Jr.</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> junked copies of its original edition to
put out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX> special.) All are packed with full-page photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> in
various stages of his public life. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> has fresh shots of an anguished
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethel</ENAMEX> and a plaintive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rory Kennedy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weeklies</ENAMEX> embrace the myth of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>. 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> family of pain."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> says the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX> "seemed almost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ordained</ENAMEX>."

            The cookie-cutter profiles note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was a
mediocre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> but had a perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6-0</ENAMEX> conviction record as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. He
became a devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> , which seems likely to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> in his
absence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> says he met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Bessette</ENAMEX> jogging in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says they met at a charity ball, but all agree it was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">storybook</ENAMEX> romance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX> actively explored a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> run before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> expressed interest. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was afraid to
fly with him, preferring to travel with a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> or drive herself.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> both declare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX> was not reckless like
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> questions whether it was foolhardy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> to fly solo over the ocean. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to
find out why 
                  Slate
                recommends against flying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>
by yourself.)

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> reassesses what turned the tide in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. Though
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> damaged civil infrastructure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> remained basically intact.
Only the belief that ground war was imminent led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cave</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> 
               report distinguishes among different types of memory loss.
Forgetting names is not a cause for alarm, but forgetting how to prepare dinner
indicates loss of "executive functioning," which signals the onset of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> article
dismisses the hysteria over rationed health care. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> percent of
treatment decisions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are approved by managed-care plans and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> states
already offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> some protections against insurance plans.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover
story chastises the "ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ax</ENAMEX>-grinders" for exploiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
victory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blowhards</ENAMEX>" falsely claimed that the game
demonstrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are the same as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Since female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are weaker and
slower their play is more offense-oriented and therefore more exciting to
watch. (Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> politics .) ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> salutes the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the first moon walk by
calling the space shuttle program a flop and the international space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> a
disaster. These programs have produced no significant scientific discoveries.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should cut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> funding and let free enterprise flourish in space.

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26</TIMEX>
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profile of New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Sulzberger Jr.</ENAMEX>
concludes that he has shepherded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> through profound changes while
maintaining its integrity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sulzberger</ENAMEX> created new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>, introduced color to
the front page, enlivened the editorial page, and promoted minority viewpoints.
His greatest challenge: bringing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> to the Internet without
sacrificing quality. ... A dispatch mocks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Allen</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moguls</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun Valley</ENAMEX>. The media elite socialize during raft trips and water
fights and vie for a place in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> Annie Leibovitz portrait. ...
An item reveals that although an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> deputy proposed indicting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>, including former ethics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Dash</ENAMEX>,
dismissed the idea as meritless.

         
      
   
