
   
   
      
         
            Personal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Invaders</ENAMEX>

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>, I am more
touchy-feely than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>. To most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in my own age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, this is
considered normal. (And I guess even to most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in other age
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.) However, I am aware that one of my better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> is just too reserved
for this invasion of his personal space. Despite resolving not to make him feel
like he's being assaulted, I often forget myself when we are together and
realize too late that I'm either sitting too close or talking too close or
worse, being a hug-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               He tolerates this,
though it clearly makes him nervous. He is tremendously enjoyable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and
I am accustomed to viewing affectionate gestures as rewarding someone for this.
Could you offer me some helpful suggestions for being, well, more
prudent?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affectionately</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               Recidivist Hugger
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Re</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> sees from your e-mail address that you are
female (unless, of course, you've hopped on someone else's machine) and
believes that touching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> is mostly a feminine trait. In any case, this is
what the situation looks like from here: You have the habit of getting close
and touching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>; you are aware that in some instances this is regarded as
an invasion of someone's personal space; you and the reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">touchee</ENAMEX> are good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>; you would like to bag your habit of "rewarding" him with physical
contact, but sometimes you just can't help yourself.

            The key, it seems to
Prudie, is that you are close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and that he tolerates it--though
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uncomfortably</ENAMEX>--while you want to accommodate his comfort zone. Why don't you
annex humor and honesty to this dilemma and deal with it openly? Say to your
chum something like: "I have this lunatic habit of touching my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and I
also tend to get too close. I know this is not comfortable for you, so the next
time you feel crowded, just say, 'Down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, down.' " Well, you get the drift.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of you should decide on a code phrase that suits you, and in time,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> predicts, there will be no discomfort at all--on either side.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, spaciously

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               You display a wide
range of knowledge, so let me run something by you I have not seen you deal
with before: have you any ideas about making some serious money--fast? I hope
you can help. I'm in a bind.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BPL</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear B,

            Your question is
actually the bailiwick of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, the one who
started this column. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, no kind of economics is within this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purview</ENAMEX>. Just from reading the financial section, however (as close as Prudie
gets to monetary information), one suggestion for you might be to get on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>'s bad side. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to do really well.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, killingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years ago</TIMEX> in
college I had a brief fling with a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has remained a dear and close
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>. We never repeated our physical intimacy. Now he has finally (!)
married, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, fascinated by his long-term friendship with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX>, persistently asks if I ever slept with him. I have tried every trick
in the book to keep from answering her truthfully, from "Why in the world would
you need to know that?" to "It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> ... how can I possibly remember?!"
But she won't give up. How can I answer her without answering her? How can I
get her to drop the subject? I'd like us all to remain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
refuses to satisfy her curiosity as well. I don't want to come right out and
say, "It's none of your business what happened between your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and me when
we were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>," and I guess I am looking for a nice way to say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MYOB</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perplexed</ENAMEX> in Pendleton
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Perp</ENAMEX>,

            You tried the nice way of saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MYOB</ENAMEX> (which is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landers</ENAMEX>' wonderful shorthand for "mind your own business"), and it didn't work.
I refer to your quip about it being the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX>, and how could you be expected to
remember anything ? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thought was to suggest that you tell
the proverbial "little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">white</ENAMEX> lie" to make the subject go away. Then she decided
that white lies, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">turquoise</ENAMEX>, for that matter, should not be encouraged ...
that there must be a better way than dishonesty, no matter how admirable one's
intent. For this reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> asked an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> who is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divinity School</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>.

            His position was that lying is unethical, therefore
it is important to consider how not to answer rather than compromising
one's integrity. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is that a sexual relationship might be
going on (that is, a present-tense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>) or is merely curious about the
past, this is a question she must ask her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> directly
involved. The proper communication is with the relevant person--her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>. If
this rather thick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> persists in her questioning, you might say: "I never
answer questions about the personal lives of my close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Please do not
ask me to violate my friendships by pursuing this line of inquiry. This is a
boundary I care about." Such an approach protects the confidentiality you share
with your old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and directs the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> (her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>) allowing you to know you have behaved in a morally ethical manner.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>--who did not
attend divinity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of hard knocks--would like to point out
that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">elm</ENAMEX> disease would figure out
that there might, indeed, have been a little experimentation of the sexual sort
and quit already with the interrogation. This, however, is an altogether
different problem. Good luck to you, and my compliments for wishing to do the
right thing.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, privately

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Though it is not on
a par with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> spying, I nevertheless have been reading about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Hefner</ENAMEX>, the geezer in pajamas who founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> around the time
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. As I understand it, he is currently occupied, very
publicly, and supposedly romantically, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> whose names are like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Handy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dandy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX> ... or something like that. How would you categorize
this behavior, and what do you think it's about?
            

            

               --Really Confused
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Real</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pathetic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>.

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opportunists</ENAMEX>, I mean, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, are named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brande</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandy</ENAMEX> ... or
something like that.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, disdainfully

         
      
   
