
   
   
      
         
             More <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Booze You Can Use</ENAMEX>

            When we last heard from them, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the

                  Slate
                beer-testing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> were coping with lagers and trying to see
if they could taste the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3-to-1</NUMEX> price difference between the most- and
least-expensive brands. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a wrap-up of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round of beer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tasting</ENAMEX>.) The answer was: They found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> beer they really liked, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adams Boston Lager</ENAMEX> , and one they really hated, imported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Grolsch</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>. Both were expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grolsch</ENAMEX> was the most expensive in the
test--and otherwise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX> had a hard time telling beers apart. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, as noted in the original article, all hold day jobs at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, mainly as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, and coders for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX>.

            The point of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> test was not to find the
difference between cheap and expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> but instead to compare a variety
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">top-of-the-line beers</ENAMEX>. Was there one kind the tasters preferred
consistently? Could they detect any of the subtleties of brewing style and
provenance that microbrew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> pay such attention to when choosing some
Doppelbock over a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream ale</ENAMEX>?

            Since the tasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> had left the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round
grumbling that cheap lagers were not a fair test of their abilities, this
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round of testing was advertised to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> as a reward. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> in
Round <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> would be a fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. A microbrew. A "craft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>." A prestigious
import. These were the kinds of beer the panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> said they liked--and the
ones they said they were most familiar with. One aspect of the reward was that
they would presumably enjoy the actual testing more--fewer rueful beer
descriptions along the lines of "urine" or "get it away!" were expected than in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round. The other aspect of anticipated reward was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX>'
unspoken but obvious assumption that this time they would "do better" on the
test. Intellectual vanity being what it is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had fought for and won
jobs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and who still must fight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every six months</TIMEX> for primacy on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX>-ranking scale (which determines--gasp!--how many new stock options
they receive) would assume that their skill as tasters was on trial, just as
much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> was. Of course they were right, which is what made this round
as amusing to administer as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one had been.

            Here is what happened
and what it meant:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. 
               Procedure. This was
similar in most ways to the experimental approach of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX>
who showed up were a subset of the original <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12</NUMEX>. The missing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dropped out
with excuses of "my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is sick" (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>) and "meeting is running long"
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>).

            As before, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tester</ENAMEX> found before him on a table
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> red plastic cups, labeled A through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX> Each cup held <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 ounces</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A-to-J</ENAMEX> labeling scheme was the same for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX>. Instead of
saltines for palate-cleansing, this time we had popcorn and nuts. As they
began, the tasters were given these and only these clues:

            

               that the flight included one "holdover" <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> from the previous round
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX>);

               that it included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> import (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bass</ENAMEX>);

               that it included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> macrobrew ,
specifically, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the vast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (Michelob
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hefeweizen</ENAMEX>).

            

            After sampling all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>, the tasters rated them as
follows:

            

               
                  Overall quality points, from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>, reflecting their
personal, subjective fondness for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>.

               
                  Descriptions of and comments about each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beer</ENAMEX>'s taste--"smooth and nutty," "too strong," etc. If the first ranking was a
measure of how good each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> was, this was an attempt to explain what made it
good.

               
                  Best 
                  and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worst</ENAMEX> , one of each from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

               
                  Name 
                  that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>! The tasters were told that some of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hefeweizens</ENAMEX>, some might be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPAs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> pale <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ales</ENAMEX>), some might
be bitters, and so on. They were asked to put each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> in its proper
category--and to name a specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brewery</ENAMEX> and brand if they could. The idea here
was to test the veteran beer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">drinkers</ENAMEX>' claim to recognize the distinctive
tastes of famous brands. (To see all the grids for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>, click .)

            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. 
               Philosophy. The first
round of testing was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All Lager</TIMEX>. This <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round was All Fancy, and Mainly Not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lager</ENAMEX>. As several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> (for instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of Best American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beers</ENAMEX> ) have helpfully pointed out, the definition of lager provided last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> was not exactly "accurate." If you want to stay within the realm of
textbook definitions, a lager is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> brewed a particular way--slowly, at
cool temperatures, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> that settles on the bottom of the vat. This is in
contrast with an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ale</ENAMEX>, which is brewed faster, warmer, and with the yeast on
top. By this same reasoning, lagers don't have to be light-colored,
weak-flavored, and watery, as mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lagers</ENAMEX> are. In principle,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lagers</ENAMEX> can be dark, fierce, manly. Therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> suggest, it
was wrong to impugn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wicked</ENAMEX> for deceptive
labeling, in presenting their tawnier, more flavorful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> as lagers too.

            To this the beer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> must say: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX>-learning is fine in its place. But let's be realistic.
Actual drinking experience teaches the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> beer consumer that a) all cheap
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beers</ENAMEX> are lagers; and b) most lagers are light-colored and weak. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> test
was designed to evaluate low-end <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> and therefore had to be lager-centric.
This one is designed to test fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>--but in the spirit of open-mindedness
and technical accuracy, it includes a few "strong" lagers too.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.

               Materials. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> test <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> were chosen with several goals in mind:

            

               To cover at least a modest range of fancy beer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX>--extra special bitter,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> pale <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hefeweizen</ENAMEX>, and so on.

               To include both imported and domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>. Among the domestic microbrews,
there's an obvious skew toward <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX>. But as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> would put it, that's a feature not a bug. These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> all came from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway</ENAMEX> nearest the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, "main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, and
microbrews are supposed to be local.

               To include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> holdover from the previous test, as a scientific control on
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tasters</ENAMEX>' preferences. This was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> , runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.

               To include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>-scale <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brewery</ENAMEX>, to see
if the tasters liked it better or worse than the cute little microbrews. This
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelob Hefeweizen</ENAMEX> , from the pride of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX>.

            

            Click for pricing information and pre-quaffing
evaluations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers tasted</ENAMEX> were:

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>
Analysis.
            

            
               a) 
               Best and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worst</ENAMEX>. Compared
to the lager test, we would expect the range of "best" choices to be more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">varied</ENAMEX>, since all the tested <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> were supposed to be good. This expectation
was most dramatically borne out in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best and Worst</ENAMEX>" rankings.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> tasters cast a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worst</ENAMEX> votes
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.5</NUMEX> Best votes. (Tester No. 1 turned in a sheet with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">selections</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more than his theoretical quota. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tester No. 4</ENAMEX> listed a Best
and a Best-minus, which counted as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a vote.)

             The results were clearest at the bottom: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
Worsts for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pyramid Hefeweizen</ENAMEX> , even though most comments about the beer
were more or less respectful. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bitter</ENAMEX>, drinkable.") But at the top and middle
the situation was muddier:

             

            There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> Bests
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Full Sail ESB</ENAMEX> , which most of the tasters later said they weren't
familiar with, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redhook IPA</ENAMEX> , which all the tasters knew. But
each of these also got a Worst vote, and most of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> had a mixed
reading. So far, the tasters are meeting expectations, finding something to
like in nearly all these fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>.

            
               b) 
               Overall preference
points. Here the complications increase. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">loser</ENAMEX> was again apparent:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pyramid Hefeweizen</ENAMEX> came in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last</TIMEX> on rating points, as it had in the
Best/<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worst derby</ENAMEX>. But the amazing dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> was Michelob
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hefeweizen</ENAMEX> . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> elements of surprise here, in ascending order of
unexpectedness, are:

            

               This best-liked beer belonged to the same category, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hefeweizen</ENAMEX>, as the
least-liked product, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pyramid</ENAMEX>.

               This was also the only outright <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX> product in the
contest (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redhooks</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> A-B free). It is safe to say that all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tasters</ENAMEX> would have said beforehand that they would rank an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> macrobrew
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX> last of all.

               Although it clearly won on overall preference points, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelob Hefeweizen</ENAMEX>
was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> not to have received a single "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best</ENAMEX>" vote.

            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> anomalies can be written off as
testament to the power of a blind taste test. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> suggests an important
difference in concepts of "bestness." Sometimes a product seems to be the best
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> simply because it's the most unusual or distinctive. This is why
very high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wine Spectator</ENAMEX> ratings often go to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> that mainly taste
odd. But another kind of bestness involves an unobtrusive, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>-in day-out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptability</ENAMEX>. That seems to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michelob Hefe</ENAMEX> 's achievement here: no
one's first choice, but high on everyone's list. Let's go to the charts:

            This table shows how the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> performed on "raw
score"--that is, without the advanced statistical adjustment of throwing out
the highest and lowest score each beer received.

             

            Next, we have "corrected average preference points,"
throwing out the high and low marks for each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. The result is basically the
same:

             

            It is worth noting the
fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> on these charts. Here it ends up with a score of less
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>. These were the numbers awarded by the very same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tasters</ENAMEX> who gave it a
corrected preference rating of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83.33</NUMEX> the last time around--and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best</ENAMEX>" votes,
vs. one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best</ENAMEX> (and one Worst) this time. The shift in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bests</ENAMEX> is understandable
and demonstrates the importance of picking your competition. The severe drop in
preference points illustrates more acutely the ancient principle of being a big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> in a small pond. These same tasters thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> was objectively
much better when it was surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmidt's</ENAMEX>.

            
               c) 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value</ENAMEX> rankings. Last
time this calculation led to what the colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> would call a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bouleversement</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the cheapest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX>, which had been in the
lower ranks on overall preference points, came out at the top on
value-for-money ratings, because it was so cheap. The big surprise now is that
the highest-rated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> was also the cheapest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelob Hefe</ENAMEX> ,
so the value calculation turned into a rout:

             

            
               Pyramid

               Hefeweizen was expensive on top of being unpopular, so its position at
the bottom was hammered home--but not as painfully as that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bass</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ale</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bass</ENAMEX> had been in the respectable lower middle class of the
preference rankings, so its disappointing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Val</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-u-meter</NUMEX> showing mainly reflects
the fact that it was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> not on "sale" and therefore by far the
costliest entry in the experiment.

            
               d) 
               Taster skill. As members
of the tasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> began to suspect, they themselves were being judged while
they judged the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the tasters, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, decided to live dangerously
and give specific brands and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">breweries</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Samples A</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX> This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was
the only panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> whose job does not involve designing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX>--and
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> to identify <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or more</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers accurately</ENAMEX> and specifically.
(He spotted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redhook IPA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redhook ESB</ENAMEX>.) The fact that the beers correctly
identified were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most popular microbrews in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> area suggests
that familiarity is the main ingredient in knowing your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>.

            Many others were simply lost. Barely half the
tasters, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>, recognized that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelob Hefeweizen</ENAMEX> 
               was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hefeweizen</ENAMEX>. Before the test, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> would have said that picking out a
Hefe was easy, because of its cloudy look and wheaty flavor. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> tasters
thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPA</ENAMEX> ; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redhook</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPA</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hefeweizen</ENAMEX>. In fairness, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX> identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pyramid</ENAMEX>
Hefeweizen as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hefe</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> recognized Full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sail ESB</ENAMEX> as a bitter.
Much in the fashion of blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> describing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>, here is a how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">testers</ENAMEX> handled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams Boston Lager</ENAMEX> :

             

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
Implications 
               and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions for Future Research</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> does
not always answer questions; often, it raises many new ones. This excursion
into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> science mainly raises the question: What kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are we?

            If we are Gradgrind-like empiricists, living our
life for "welfare maximization" as described in introductory econ. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courses</ENAMEX>, the
conclusion is obvious. We learned from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> experiment to buy
either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> (when we wanted maximum lager enjoyment per bottle)
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX> (for maximum taste and snob appeal per dollar). From this
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round we see an even more efficient possibility: Buy Michelob
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hefeweizen</ENAMEX> and nothing else, since on the basis of this test it's the best
liked and the cheapest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. By the way, if there is a single company
whose achievements the testing panel honored, it would be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX> . From its brewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> came <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the double-crown
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> of the taste tests: plain old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX> , the Taste<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-o-meter</NUMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Snob</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-o-meter victor</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelob Hefeweizen</ENAMEX> , the
preference-point and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Val</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-u-meter</NUMEX> winner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time</TIMEX>.

            But, of course, there is another possibility: that
what is excluded in a blind taste test is in fact what we want, and are happy
to pay for, when we sit down with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. The complicated label, the fancy
bottle, the exotic concept that this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> has traveled from some far-off corner
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohemia</ENAMEX> or even the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>--all this may be cheap at the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.25</NUMEX>-per-pint cost difference between the cheapest and the most expensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beers</ENAMEX>. In elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, we all endured a standard science experiment: If
you shut your eyes and pinch your nose closed, can you tell any difference in
the taste of a slice of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carrot</ENAMEX>, of pear? You can't--but that doesn't
mean that from then on you should close your eyes, hold your nose, and chew a
cheap carrot when you feel like having some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>. There is a time and place
for carrots, but also for juicy <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pears</ENAMEX>. There is a time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX>, but also for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> Sail "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equinox</ENAMEX>."

            For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> who want to continue this work at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, here are a few suggestions for further research:

            

               Tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX> ahead of time what beers they will be drinking. Ask them
to rank the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>, based on how well they like them. Then compare
the list with the "revealed preferences" that come from the blind test.

               As a variation, show them the list ahead of time and ask them to pick out
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> they know they love and the one they know they hate. Then compare this
with the "after" list.

               If you're going to test imported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lagers</ENAMEX>, try <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corona</ENAMEX> rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grolsch</ENAMEX>.

               Remember to stay strictly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>'s role. Don't take the test
yourself.

            

         
      
   
