
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">311</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch Treatment&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Beatrix</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> reopens one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX>'s
most popular tourist attractions after extensive renovations. What
attraction?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 310</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Insight Out":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     "I'm saying we really do have to recognize that it's
going to be difficult and take a while for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to get this stuff," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoshanna Sofaer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baruch College</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the federal
government. "And for a significant percentage, they're never going to get it
because they're cognitively impaired, they're too frail, or they just don't
have the energy to invest in understanding these things." Who's never going to
understand what?
                  
               
            

            
"Convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> will never understand how their former best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> gets to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> while they rot in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>
prison."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>; how he, too, can qualify for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX>
mortgage."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dogs</ENAMEX>
are never going to understand quantum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX>. It's sad, in a way. If they
could, they'd know whether to bother with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schrodinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> or not."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jedediah Purdy</ENAMEX>; why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> giggle when they hear the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jedediah</ENAMEX>. Especially
in combination with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdy</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roche</ENAMEX> had a
similar answer.)

            
"Frankly, I think that even if you missed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The West Wing</ENAMEX> , it
should be pretty easy to catch on."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Anecdotal
Wrap-Up
            

            I'll tell you what I don't understand--why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoshanna Sofaer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baruch College</ENAMEX> sounds so cranky. (Needs a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sabbatical</ENAMEX>?) Or why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Needs</ENAMEX> term limits? Of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 30 seconds</TIMEX>?) makes it
harder for ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to join in a class action suit but easier for giant
oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to pump free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> from public land and sell it at a profit,
probably to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Needs</ENAMEX>--oh where to begin? With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX>'s sentimental
nonsense about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>? OK. There!) to fuel those big turbines to
illuminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> for the telecasting of semi-popular tripe on the public
airwaves at vast profits, for the entertainment of bored oil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> out in
some once-magnificent national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. (Need a good book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> with a series of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> appearances, maybe starting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>? She's full of
understanding. And slogans.)

            You know who would
understand? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX>. Pretty obvious to him. But even a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> weighed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 350</NUMEX> pounds and had to be braced up with a special
cast iron frame, even he can't understand why love is a crime, the sort of
crime spelled out in a restraining order from some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> (NEEDS HIS GODDAMNED
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">HEAD EXAMINED</ENAMEX>!!!!) who is oh so ready to ignore everything <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> says and
just believe everything some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> says even when she is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> !
Hypothetically speaking. Answer me that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoshanna Sofaer</ENAMEX> of Baruch
College! Where's all your governmental advice now?

            
               Learn

               Fast or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            Older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> don't understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and its
alternatives.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Neuman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Family Foundation</ENAMEX>
says many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d</ENAMEX>]on't understand the rules that govern their care."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollster Michael Perry</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are "very angry
over how confusing the program is."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Archer</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Rights Center</ENAMEX>, disagrees, "It's all incredibly complicated, not only
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> but for everyone, including me." Or perhaps she agrees. It's very
confusing.

            And so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> is launching "the biggest peacetime
education program the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has ever undertaken." Features
include:

            

               a handbook being mailed to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">39 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>

               a toll-free info line: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">633-4227</ENAMEX>

               a Web site [<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">medicare</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>]

               outreach efforts with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> local and national groups

               the advice and snippy comments of Shoshanna Sofaer

               Geezer, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stupid Healthcare Baboon</ENAMEX>, a lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mascot</ENAMEX> who'll
travel to nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and explain that what seems like a cold and heartless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is really great, once you grasp it. Or maybe I've misunderstood this
last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and it doesn't actually exist. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoshanna</ENAMEX>?

            

            

               Opprobrium 
               Extra
            

            I give the expression of
disdain; you tell me who said it about what, and then tell me your bankcard PIN
code.

            
               The 
               Slurs
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "Sick stuff"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> and offensive"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "I'm embarrassed about it"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "Is wrong, is embarrassing, is outrageous"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "He has corrupted all of those around him"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">= Hitler</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "An insulting
mess"

            
               The 
               Targets
            

            A. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> doesn't like some art he
hasn't seen. His response: cut off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s finances.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Mayor Giuliani</ENAMEX> also detests an article in a
student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>: He had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> jailed. Wait, sorry, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiite Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> who jailed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>; I keep confusing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX> and New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Morgan Entrekin</ENAMEX> is sorry he nearly published
another of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Mackay</ENAMEX>'s possibly plagiarized biographies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Entrekin</ENAMEX> has
destroyed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all 7,500</NUMEX> copies of the suspiciously prolific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul Jones</ENAMEX>
bio, by my count his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">925 th</NUMEX> book.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nita Lowey</ENAMEX> says, "To be the
biggest deadbeat at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> ..."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Professionally disapproving William Bennett</ENAMEX>
doesn't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to give the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson Lecture</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment of the Humanities</ENAMEX>. And so he won't.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Demonstrators</ENAMEX> in wheelchairs don't think
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX> should hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Singer</ENAMEX>, but they will.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G. New York Times</ENAMEX>
TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caryn James</ENAMEX> doesn't enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Sorkin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Wing</ENAMEX> .

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            The pleasantly varied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> responses defy easy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">categorizing</ENAMEX>. So you're all dismissed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> early.

         
      
   
