
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999>The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Godfather of Compassionate Conservatism</ENAMEX></SPAN></SPAN>

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12</TIMEX>
            

            In a
cover book excerpt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ashes author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank McCourt</ENAMEX> recounts his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> as a public-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>. McCourt captured the imagination of his
rambunctious class by having them transcribe essays written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a
generation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>. ... An article introduces the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of
compassionate conservatism, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>-turned-evangelical-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin Olasky</ENAMEX>, who penned a book arguing that faith-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> could
supplant the welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. He now chairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s religion-policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>. To practice what he preached, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olasky</ENAMEX> opened an ex-con <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> and
adopted a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover package debates whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETS</ENAMEX> plan to adjust
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores on the basis of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s socio-economic and racial background
threatens meritocracy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece argues that "striver" scoring is a rational
statistical tool for achieving the worthy goal of admitting more non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> to elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>. An opposing opinion claims striver scoring would
entrench the fallacy that "demography is destiny." ... A piece assesses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s foreign policy,
arguing that he covers up his ignorance of foreign affairs by deferring to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Condoleezza Rice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scowcroft</ENAMEX>. The neorealist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bushites</ENAMEX> believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should
intervene abroad only to protect vital national interests. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>'s tutors opposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and support constructive engagement with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
Nation
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20</TIMEX>
            

            A
special issue focuses on new ideas for drug reform. An article redefines drug abuse as a public health problem.
Treatment on demand and the abolition of criminal penalties for nonviolent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> is the solution. ... A piece deems drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> a cheap and
promising approach to rehabilitating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>. Nonviolent drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> can
avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> sentences by undergoing treatment and monitoring. ... A
pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is promoting a prescription alternative to medical
marijuana, according to a story . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marinol</ENAMEX> controls <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nausea</ENAMEX> and appetite loss, the same
symptoms that lead <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to smoke pot. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s minions are
loudly opposing marijuana legalization to improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>'s sales.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Prospect
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1999</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story condemns the increasing use of convict labor by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. Among
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> employed by private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for a fraction of the
minimum wage are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>'s reservation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s software boxers.
Prison employment circumvents labor laws and hurts regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover excerpt from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>'s much-ballyhooed book says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have been emasculated by feminism and the new economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> should learn to
replace media-manufactured masculine ideals that emphasize appearance and
dominance with ungendered ideals of social responsibility and liberty.
... A profile slaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> for hypocrisy. He
fund-raises madly while assailing the role of money in politics, and he attacks
finger-in-the-wind politics even though he spent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times more on polling
than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> during his last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign. ... In an
interview , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> laments <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commercialism</ENAMEX> and
gripes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> butchered his soon-to-be released <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">For Love of the</ENAMEX>
Game . (
                  Slate
                predicted it would be a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story , rehashing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s discovery that smart <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
can be genetically engineered, predicts that the bioengineering of human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> will soon be possible. ... A profile crowns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris Rock</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Funniest Man in America</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comedian</ENAMEX> is making his mark with middlebrow movies, smart standup specials, and
his own eclectic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> show. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX> is taking his stereotype-bending routine global
by staging his next standup special in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">à la Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rumble</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jungle</ENAMEX>." ... A piece cringes at the new trend of body modification--or
"bod-mod"--in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> mutilate themselves by searing their skin and
splitting their tongues.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
13
            

            The
cover story reviews the latest research on how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> think.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neuroscience</ENAMEX> suggests that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third month</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> are mature enough to
reason and process language. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Psychologists</ENAMEX> warn against overstimulating babies'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brains</ENAMEX>, but that has not slowed the boom in lapware--educational software for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-month-olds</TIMEX>. ... An item reports that high-end preschools now offer <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and
theater classes. For <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> get daily progress reports while
their toddlers are served <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX> for lunch.

            

               
                  The
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> explodes the fallacy of safe sex. Sex with a condom does not prevent
transmission of the papilloma virus, the most common sexually transmitted
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Papilloma causes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cervical cancer</ENAMEX>,
and pap smears miss <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 40 percent</NUMEX> of infections. New <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> tests may help
detect the virus, but there is no treatment. A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> is needed. ... A
profile of comedy icon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Pryor</ENAMEX> salutes his transgressive artistry. Unlike
earlier black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pryor</ENAMEX> never tried to ingratiate himself with white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> or cloak his rage.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story argues that the complementary campaign platforms
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> represent a coherent governing philosophy for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wants to revive citizenship through energetic local government
and strengthened neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> promises to fight cynicism
by reforming campaign finance and embracing a broader role for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> abroad.
... An article cudgels the claim that there is a farm crisis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agriculture</ENAMEX> is triumphant, growing more than ever and growing it more cheaply.
Even though free-market farming kills family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> cannot afford to
prop up unprofitable agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
