
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer Scandal</ENAMEX>

            Did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> commit adultery with a campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>? Rumors to that effect have
circulated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> gossip column asked, "What presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is praying that a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> doesn't go public with her claim
that he's been having an affair with a twentysomething <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>? Many on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">married Republican</ENAMEX>'s campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> are already jumping <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>." National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotline</ENAMEX> broadcast that teaser, and radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Imus</ENAMEX> linked
it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> about the rumors
and published his denial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. At a news conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> denied
that he had violated his marital vows or inappropriately touched anyone, and he
challenged the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> on hand to produce evidence or a specific,
on-the-record allegation that he had done so.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> had the evidence, they could have produced it. If not, they could
have closed their notebooks and walked away. Instead, they interrogated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> in front of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> TV cameras and wrote articles suggesting
that whether or not he had had an affair, he was wrong to have left open the
possibility that anyone might have thought he had done anything wrong. The
scandal isn't that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> committed adultery. The scandal is that without
proving that charge or even making it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have found ways to spin
lesser, derivative, and empty insinuations about him into a national story.
Let's examine the charges against him.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> committed 
               "the appearance of impropriety."
Unable to produce allegations of impropriety, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> in
accusatory tones whether he had "met behind closed doors" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa McClard</ENAMEX> (answer: yes), and whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> had told him "that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are asking questions [about it] and it's making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uncomfortable."
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> challenged a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> to define the alleged "inappropriate
behavior," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> replied, "That you were seen too often with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> on
your campaign, who is described to me as being <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 years old</TIMEX> and blond." Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> of being "ambiguous, because you're not really telling
us ... can you understand the perception that you may have had an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">affair?</ENAMEX>" How
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> could refute such perceptions, questions, and discomfort was equally
ambiguous.

            Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alleged Bauer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Jarvis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim McDonald</ENAMEX>, finally
went on the record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarvis</ENAMEX> said he had no proof of a sexual
relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClard</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald</ENAMEX> said he believed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s
denial of such a relationship. Rather than conclude that there was no story,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> published an article, headlined
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ex-Aides to Bauer Speak Out</ENAMEX>," which paraphrased the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s
meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McClard</ENAMEX> "looked" inappropriate and "lent themselves to gossip and
rumor." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarvis</ENAMEX> as saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> "has no business creating
that kind of appearance of impropriety."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The 
               appearance of impropriety by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
conservative is itself improper. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> pressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> about
his closed-door meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McClard</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX> doesn't do it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> doesn't do it. So [among] the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who you are close to, actually,
there is a sensitivity about meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> behind closed doors. I'm
not saying there should be one. I don't think there should. But there is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarvis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald</ENAMEX> "said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> behind closed doors with her and traveled alone with her, violating
the strict rules they believe govern conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in
their dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>." By framing the issue as "sensitivity," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> avoided taking responsibility for deeming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s closed-door
meetings an important issue.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> 
               appeared to ignore allegations of the appearance
of impropriety. "Is it possible," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>, "that you may
have been engaging in behavior that was perfectly innocent [but] in the minds
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who work for you and respected you was inappropriate, and that
perhaps you--as it was put by someone to me--you appeared a little arrogant in
refusing to recognize, according to them, their complaints?" In other words,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s offense is that he dismissed a perception he knew to be false.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> 
               is covering up allegations of the appearance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impropriety</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> had told him they were
"uncomfortable" about the appearance of his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McClard</ENAMEX>. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asked whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> had told him, "I wish you
wouldn't behave this way with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> challenged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
to explain the meaning of "behave this way," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> admitted, "I don't
know."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
denied that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> had alleged actual impropriety: "No one leaving my
campaign has said, 'Gary, I am leaving your campaign because I believe you're
having an affair.' " He also denied that any perception of impropriety could be
justified: "I cannot imagine that anybody in a campaign would object to me
having a meeting behind closed doors with a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , seizing on the latter remark, reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarvis</ENAMEX> "sharply
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disputed Bauer</ENAMEX>." The sad truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarvis</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , was that "people
have confronted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX> about the appearance of impropriety." Similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarvis</ENAMEX> as saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> just went on national
television and refused to tell the truth." And what was that truth? That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarvis</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> had quit the campaign because of their "concerns about the
relationship"--whatever that means.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> 
               improperly failed to confront the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who
apparently alleged the appearance of impropriety. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would think," one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reporter lectured Bauer</ENAMEX>, "when you found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> appeared to be [the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>] campaign, that you would go directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of that campaign and
say, 'Is this happening? Are you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing this?' " Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> chimed
in, "For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who are not presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, if somebody was spreading
rumors like that about them, I think the first instinct would be to go to the
suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> and say, 'Are you doing this? And if so, please stop it.' Why
didn't you do that?"

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> 
               failed to disprove the possibility of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impropriety</ENAMEX>. Unable to formulate a precise allegation, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> whether his behavior with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McClard</ENAMEX> had been "flirtatious or in any way
different from how you interact with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>" (answer: no). When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
challenged another questioner to explain what he meant by "inappropriate
behavior," the questioner replied, "How specific do you want to get? I'm not
sure I understand what you want." Responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s assertion that he had
never violated his wedding vows, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> cracked, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
said that too." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> "would not go much
further than indicating he was faithful to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>." The collective
implication is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s denials must have been couched to protect some
unspecified kind of dalliance.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Every 
               a
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">llegation</ENAMEX> is a political
fact. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Horse</ENAMEX>-race journalism ignores whether charges are true and focuses
instead on whether they're damaging. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> was,
"Don't you just give this story more momentum by doing this?" Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
asked, "How do you think your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> are going to respond to all this?" The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , too scrupulous to say whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> had done anything wrong or
even whether the perception that he might have done so would hurt him
politically, found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political scientist</ENAMEX> who "warned that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> could be
fatally wounded, in political terms, by the dispute" and another who "said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> could help himself by saying, 'I wish I wouldn't have put myself in this
kind of situation, I'm sorry and I apologize.' " Whether the "situation" was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misdeed</ENAMEX> or a perception was left unexplained. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that "the real news was the wall-to-wall
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">throng</ENAMEX>" at the news conference.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> 
               showed bad judgment by letting the allegations of
an appearance of impropriety become a political problem. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>, "A lot of us have heard this rumor. But to be quite
honest, I think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> are never going to mention it and
probably didn't take it very seriously. But you've now elevated it to a point
that it will be on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news. And a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, when they are
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> introduced to you ... it will be for that--for denying an affair. What
does that say about your political judgment?" Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>
published the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s derisive story about the press conference, titled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>: I am not a slut!"

            The
problem isn't that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are malicious or are out to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>. I know and
like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who asked some of the most loaded questions
at the press conference. The problem is that they can't resist a hot story. A
sex scandal on the religious right, no matter how flimsy, seems too good to
pass up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> think they have to ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> question or advance the
story, never mind which way it's going. The campaign is in overdrive, their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prey</ENAMEX> stands before them, and the heat of the moment carries them away. They
wonder whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> is strong enough to resist the urge. They should ask
the same question of themselves.

         
      
   
