
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Brinkley</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Brinkley</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> death circus. Before the crash, the boyish, gap-toothed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brinkley</ENAMEX> was
known primarily as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Beschloss</ENAMEX>-in-waiting, a telegenic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fielding</ENAMEX> calls from the cable news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Orleans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> has parlayed a contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editorship</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> and a
friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> into a job as a necropublicist. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between Saturday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brinkley</ENAMEX> appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition , Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Morning America , Dateline , Today</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX>),
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX>). He also penned columns about his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and was quoted everywhere else
ink touches paper.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , Brinkley
cut a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> for a week of exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> commentary, but
then agreed to provide it pro bono. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> are reportedly so
annoyed about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s death punditry that they have dropped him from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masthead</ENAMEX>.

            Even amid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s staggering hyperbole,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s emotional profligacy has distinguished him. He is, as he rarely
fails to remind his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38 years old</TIMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, a vegetarian like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, and a Sagittarius like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>. That identification with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
accounts in part for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s tenuous proposition: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s death is
the signal event of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, the moment <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gen X</ENAMEX> lost its innocence. In the
opening paragraph of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> opined: "It's as
if suddenly, an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s optimism is deflated, and all that is left
is the limp reality of growing old." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s death may have affected his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend Brinkley</ENAMEX> this way. I am not sure anyone else outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s circle
was so moved.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> has also
mounted his thanatic pulpit to tell and retell anecdotes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decency</ENAMEX>: how he declined an honorary doctorate because he felt he didn't
deserve it, how his racial compassion sparked him to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX> in jail.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> has grown comfortable enough with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>-family talk that he no
longer limits himself to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his second Today</TIMEX> jaunt, he
opined about would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rory Kennedy</ENAMEX>: "It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> and the feminist
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rory Kennedy</ENAMEX> that I think is her greatest contribution to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
life.")

            It's a historical truth, handed down from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Antony</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX>, that celebrity death is a fabulous marketing
opportunity, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brinkley</ENAMEX> is not cynical about his prolific <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> comments.
"I have been in a deep, deep depression, and my way of responding was to be
proactive," he says. "I could have shut up about this and not done anything,
but I really believe that this is someone who matters ."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s belief that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> is someone who matters--matters enough for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two op</NUMEX>-eds and countless TV
an appropriate eulogist for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> because they shared a vision of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
culture and politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s worthy democratic instincts inspired him to use
entertainment to teach politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s worthy democratic instincts inspire
him to use entertainment to teach history. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s case, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy's</ENAMEX>,
the results have been both inspiring and awkward.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> (who is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>--that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
history prof <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Brinkley</ENAMEX>) stands at the intersection of academia, serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, and TV punditry. He is striving for a place in the pantheon of
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Ambrose</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger</ENAMEX>. Brinkley
abhors the narrow academic history that has dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. He scorns
scholarly monographs and favors a democratic, populist history. As history grew
more and more abstruse in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> ceded the role of
public intellectual to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> wants to take it back. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
himself admired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s approach enough that, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brinkley</ENAMEX>, he had
been trying to land Brinkley an appointment at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy School</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> first came to
prominence as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neo-beatnik</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> that the best way to
learn history is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, he led <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from Hofstra
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> (where he then taught) on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-week</TIMEX> history road trip, from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Route 66</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Kesey</ENAMEX>'s farm to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX>. He
turned this "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Majic Bus</ENAMEX>" trip into a popular book. He now guides a civil-rights
bus journey for inner-city high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every spring</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majic Bus</ENAMEX> also
inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-Span</ENAMEX> to start sending its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majic Bus</ENAMEX> illustrates both the charms and flaws of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s notion of public history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> is the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> freshmen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX>, because he is a kind of Überfreshman himself, wildly enthusiastic and
infatuated with popular culture. He believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kerouac</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> literature. He quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramones</ENAMEX> lyrics. He
loves the word "troubadour." He refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Reed</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Reed</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majic Bus</ENAMEX> is full of passages like this: "How could I be a great bop
wanderer, a mystic in search of ecstasy, a hobo scribbler of haiku and jazz
poems, somehow discovering, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerouacian</ENAMEX> terms, how to 'dig' life in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">divine world to the fullest?</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> is a cheerleader
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. Everything is a celebration. He likes to cite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerouac</ENAMEX>'s
"I am not anti-anything" (except "racists" and certain big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>). The
civil rights movement was great. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beats</ENAMEX> were cool. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> is amazing. He even
wrote a kindly biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>. Brinkley skirts the arguments against
his rosy vision. When his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majic Bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> encountered a couple of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">belligerent Buchananites</ENAMEX> spouting nativist claptrap, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s immediate
reaction was to treat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loonies</ENAMEX> and hustle his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> back onto the
bus. His <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is conflict-free. Here, too, he resembles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, who was a
cheerleader for politics, publishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that detached politics from
ideology.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majic Bus</ENAMEX> brought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> minor fame. Blessed with
preternatural gregariousness, good humor, and a love of attention, he's been
tireless about pursuing both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> and the cause of popular history ever
since. "The word that is used around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug is 'operator</ENAMEX>.' That is said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scornfully</ENAMEX> or dismissively," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brinkley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrose</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tapped Brinkley</ENAMEX> to succeed him as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Orleans</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisenhower Center</ENAMEX>. "He is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>, and I think that's wonderful.
He's entrepreneurial and enthusiastic. It's very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>."

            It's hard to find anyone
who knows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brinkley</ENAMEX> and dislikes him. It's also hard to find anyone who knows
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> and doesn't worry about his obsession with fame. "His name-dropping is
almost pathological," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. In my conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>, he
touched on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> he knows. His writing is full
of sentences that begin something like, "As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cage</ENAMEX> once asked me ..."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> worked assiduously to join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beschloss</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kearns Goodwin</ENAMEX> on the air. "TV is the most important medium for conveying
history. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> not to reach out smacks of elitism," he says. He will
happily decorate any TV or radio story with a veneer of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history.
Recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> have seen him comment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> bombing, ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Independence Day</ENAMEX>, impeachment, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, to name a
few topics.

            Meanwhile, he has pursued
a writing career that would fell a less industrious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Kennedy</ENAMEX> pieces appeared, Brinkley
published a sweet article in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> about a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-year</TIMEX>
correspondence between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan club</ENAMEX>. Brinkley
publishes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heritage</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>. His work ranges from routine commentaries on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s
political news to celebrity puff profiles. He writes more journalism than most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hacks</ENAMEX>, and certainly a lot more good journalism than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>. At the
same time, he has managed to write or co-write <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> books in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past seven</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> full-scale biographies and a lively <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX>-page history of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s oeuvre demonstrates his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endearing</ENAMEX> himself to all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: He has done books with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX>, the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment figure</ENAMEX>; with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX>; and
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>.) He is currently working on a profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, a biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX>, and a biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ford</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s sunniness and ardor are appealing, but his
public history has its shortcomings. His idols, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambrose</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlesinger</ENAMEX>, have
won the admiration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> and the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> has won the public
but has not wowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>. Some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' dismay is simply
jealousy of his entrepreneurship, but some is more substantive. His books read
like good journalism--and that's no insult--but they are not great history. "He
has made no analytical contribution at all," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> Ivy League <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> who
professes to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brinkley</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger</ENAMEX> went on television to mourn the
death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Brinkley</ENAMEX> goes on television to mourn
the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> This is why his
ambition to be a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> may falter. A public intellectual resists
the frivolous. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> does not resist the frivolous. As his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> Ambrose
says, "I wish he would spend less time on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> and more time on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
