
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Year for the Roses</ENAMEX>?

            Early in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Beauty , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester Burnham</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Spacey</ENAMEX>), a weary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for a media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, masturbates in the shower while informing us in voice-over that we're
witnessing the highlight of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX>. He peers through tired eyes out the window
at his manicured suburban tract-house lawn, where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX> (Annette
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bening</ENAMEX>)--whose gardening clogs, he points out, are color-coordinated with the
handles of her shears--<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">snips roses</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> beauties) and twitters about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miracle-Gro</ENAMEX> to a gay yuppie (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Bakula</ENAMEX>) on the other side of a white picket
fence. "I have lost something," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester</ENAMEX>. "I'm not exactly sure what it is
but I know I didn't always feel this ... sedated." Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX> doesn't
realize that snipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX> are garden-variety symbols of castration, or he'd
know what he has lost. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Beauty are about to
give <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX> his roses back. At a high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> game, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX> is
transfixed by a blonde <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheerleader</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mena Suvari</ENAMEX>), who is twirling
alongside his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thora Burch</ENAMEX>). Ambient noise falls away, the crowd
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disappears</ENAMEX>, and there she is, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX>'s angel, writhing in slow motion--just for
him. She opens her jacket (she's naked underneath) and red rose petals drift
out. Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX> envisions her on a bed of red petals, then immersed in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bath</ENAMEX> of red petals. Back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, he's soon
pumping iron, smoking pot, and telling off his frigid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and faceless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>,
convinced that whatever he has lost he's getting back, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>.

            The movie is convinced,
too--which is odd, since the fantasy of an underage cheerleader making a
middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s wilted <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses bloom</ENAMEX> is a tad ... primitive. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Beauty doesn't feel primitive. It feels lustrously hip and aware,
and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are making big claims for it. The script, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Ball</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> and former sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, carries an invigorating blast of
counterculture righteousness, along with the kind of pithily vicious marital
bickering that makes some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> (especially male) say, "Yeah! Tell that bitch
off!" More important, it has a vein of metaphysical yearning, which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Mendes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> brilliantly. A hotshot <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> theater director
(his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabaret</ENAMEX> revival is still on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendes</ENAMEX> gives
the film a patina of New Age lyricism and layer upon layer of visual irony. The
movie's surface is velvety and immaculate--until the action is abruptly viewed
through the video camera of the teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voyeur</ENAMEX> next door (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wes Bentley</ENAMEX>), and
the graininess of the video image (along with the plangent music) suggests how
unstable the molecules that constitute our "reality" really are. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendes</ENAMEX> can
distend the real into the surreal with imperceptible puffs. Aided by his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cinematographer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad Hall</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tariq Anwar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Greenbury</ENAMEX>, he
creates an entrancing vision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> on the verge of a
meltdown.

            A merican 
               Beauty is so wittily written and
gorgeously directed that you might think you're seeing something
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archetypal</ENAMEX>--maybe even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great American Movie</ENAMEX>. But when you stop and smell
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX> ... Well, that scent isn't Miracle-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gro</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairpin</ENAMEX> turns from farce
to melodrama, from satire to bathos, are fresh and deftly navigated, but almost
every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the underlying attitudes is smug and easy: from the corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flunky</ENAMEX> named "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX>" to the interchangeable gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> (they're both called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim"</ENAMEX>) to the brutally homophobic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> next door, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-Marine colonel</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Cooper</ENAMEX>) who has reduced his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (the normally exuberant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allison Janney</ENAMEX>)
to a catatonic mummy and his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bentley</ENAMEX>), to a life of subterranean
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deception</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX>'s idea of bliss is watching an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>
military picture on television: How's that for subtle?) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX>,
is even more stridently caricatured. A real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> who fails to sell a
big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> (her only potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are blank-faced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, and surly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX>), she wears a mask of perky efficiency and
insists on listening to Muzak while she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> eat her
"nutritious yet savory" dinners. It's amazing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ball</ENAMEX> get away
with recycling so many stale and reactionary ideas under the all-purpose rubric
of "black comedy."

            But it's also possible
that those ideas have rarely been presented so seductively. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several months ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Menaker</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
                in contemporary film in which the
protagonist attempts to break through our cultural and technological
anesthetization into "the real." That's the theme here, too, and it's
extraordinarily potent, at times even heartbreaking. The symbols, however, have
been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cunningly</ENAMEX> reversed. In movies like sex, lies, and videotape (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>),
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> has to put away the video camera to "get real"; in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Beauty , it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricky Fitts</ENAMEX>, the damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stoner videomaker</ENAMEX> next door, who sees
beauty where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonartists</ENAMEX> see only horror or nothingness. In the film's most
self-consciously poetic set piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricky</ENAMEX> shows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX>'s dour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>--in
whom he recognizes a kindred spirit--a video of a plastic bag fluttering up,
down, and around on invisible currents of wind. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky</ENAMEX> speaks of glimpsing in
the bag's trajectory an "entire life behind things"--a "benevolent force" that
holds the universe together. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>, who likes to train his lenses on
dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, sells wildly expensive marijuana to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX>
and somehow passes on this notion of "beauty." By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX> is mouthing
the same sentiments and has acquired the same deadpan radiance. That must be
some really good shit they're smoking.

            It's not the druggy philosophizing, however, that makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Beauty an emotional workout. It's that the caricatures are
grounded in sympathy instead of derision. Everyone on screen is in serious
pain. The manipulative sexpot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>, who taunts her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> with the idea
of seducing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, acts chiefly out of a terror of appearing ordinary. As the
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martinet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX> goes against the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX>, turning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitts</ENAMEX> into a
sour bulldog whose capaciously baggy eyes are moist with sadness over his
inability to reach out. (When he stands helplessly in the rain at the end, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deluge</ENAMEX> completes him.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX> is so shrill as to constitute a
libel on the female sex, but there isn't a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bening</ENAMEX> sends the woman
up. She doesn't transcend the part, she fills it to the brim, anatomizes it.
You can't hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is trying so hard--to appear
confident, composed, in control. When she fails to sell that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, she closes
the shades and lets go with a naked wail--it's the sound of a vacuum crying to
be filled--then furiously slaps herself while sputtering, "Shut up--you're
weak--shut up. " Then she breathes, regains her go-get-'em poise, replaces
her mask. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX> isn't a complicated dramatic construction, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bening</ENAMEX> gives
her a primal force. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> who packs more psychological detail into a
single gesture than others get into whole scenes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bening</ENAMEX> was barreling down the
road to greatness before she hit a speed bump called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>. It's a joy to
observe her--both here and in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Dreams</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>)--back at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full throttle</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Beauty is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spacey</ENAMEX>'s movie, though.
He gives it--how weird to write this about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spacey</ENAMEX>, who made his name playing
flamboyantly self-involved psychopaths--a heart. Early on, he lets his face and
posture go slack and his eyes blurry. He mugs like crazy, telegraphing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX>'s
"loserness." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spacey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> is for mugging in character. He makes us
believe that it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX> who's caricaturing himself , and that bitter
edge paves the way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s later, more comfortably Spacey-like
scenes of insult and mockery. He even makes us take <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX>'s final, improbably
rhapsodic moments straight.

            But do the filmmakers
take them straight? If I read it correctly, the movie is saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> is unjust and absurd and loveless--full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so afraid of seeming
ordinary that they lose their capacity to see. It's saying that our only hope
is to cultivate a kind of stoned aesthetic detachment whereby even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with
his brains blown out becomes an object of beauty and a signpost to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher</ENAMEX>
Power. But to scrutinize a freshly dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and not ask how it got that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>--or if there's anyone nearby with a gun who might want to add to the body
count--strikes me as either moronic or insane or both. The kind of detachment
the movie is peddling isn't artistic, it isn't life--it's nihilism at its most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fatuous</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Beauty is New Age <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nihilism</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX> older than he was as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crash Davis</ENAMEX>,
the over-the-hill minor-league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bull Durham</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>), but he can
still get away with playing a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballplayer</ENAMEX>. He moves and acts like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity jock</ENAMEX>, and he can make his narcissistic self-containment look as if
he's keeping something in reserve--to protect his "instrument," as it were. In
For <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love of the Game</ENAMEX> , he's a 40ish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit Tigers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> having his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last hurrah</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has been sold and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> don't necessarily want
him back. For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about half an hour</TIMEX>, it's a great sports movie. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner</ENAMEX> stands on
the mound shaking off the signals of his longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John C. Reilly</ENAMEX>); he
forces himself to tune out the huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yankee Stadium</ENAMEX> crowd (the background blurs
before our eyes and the sound drops out); and he mutters darkly at a succession
of batters, some old nemeses, some old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX>.

            He also thinks about his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>-based
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Preston</ENAMEX>), who tearfully told him that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> that things
were absolutely over and she was moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. There's an appealing
flashback to how they met (he stopped to fix her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> while on the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX>
Stadium), then it's back to the game for more nail-biting at bats. But pretty
soon the relationship flashbacks start coming thick and fast, and the balance
of the movie shifts to whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX> can commit to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> can commit
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX> or whether his only commitment could ever be to the ball and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diamond</ENAMEX> and the game.

            Maybe it's because I'm a baseball nut that I hated
to leave the mound. But maybe it's also because the relationships scenes are
soft-focus, generic, and woozily drawn-out, whereas the stuff in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> is
sharply edited and full of texture. The rhythms of the game feel right; the
rhythms of the romance feel embarrassingly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlequin</ENAMEX>, and the picture drags on
for over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>. I can't believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Raimi</ENAMEX> ( The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>
Dead , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s A Simple Plan ) thought that all those scenes
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preston</ENAMEX> staring into space while the piano plinks would end up
in the final cut, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raimi</ENAMEX> apparently gave up control of the final cut for the
sake of making his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, real mainstream picture. He might as well have stuck
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> over the plate and said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bean me</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
