
   
   
      
         
            Beavers on Probation

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Beaver</ENAMEX>
She-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Men</ENAMEX>
            

            
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ottawa Citizen</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s national animal is sexually
confused. A research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Guelph</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ontario</ENAMEX>
Veterinary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> recently dissected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> male beavers that were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> to
Spencerville, just south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s capital, and found that they all had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uteruses</ENAMEX>. They found the same curious biology in the majority of beavers from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other locations as well. The finding wasn't such a surprise to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, whose routine post-mortems in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> have turned up a
very high percentage of such "pseudo-hermaphrodite" beavers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Fisher</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of biomedical sciences at the veterinary college, believes that the
development of a uterus is a normal part of a male beaver's genetics and
embryology: But "I wouldn't bet the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> on that," he says. "I'd bet a cup of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>."

            
               Smart
Banking
            

            Is it
too soon to prepare for a glut of academically inclined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>? The
newly opened "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notables' Sperm Bank</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu</ENAMEX> accepts donations only from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> who are under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 60</TIMEX>, have no history of congenital diseases,
and are at the very least an associate professor. Of course, as the
Independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bangladesh</ENAMEX> points out, it has yet to be scientifically
proved that "intellectual quality can be enhanced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> breeding
techniques." But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>, new data should be available.

            
               Shoot the
Loon
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon Fraser University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Columbia</ENAMEX> is urging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX>
to ditch the "loonie," as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s dollar is fondly called, and join a
monetary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. A report, co-authored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard G. Harris</ENAMEX> and
Queen's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas J. Courchene</ENAMEX>, argues that such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> would
be economically advantageous for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. But what about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s national
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">pride?</ENAMEX> "All the hang-ups that we now have about our paper money are going to
... go the same way as the buggy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX> and typewriters," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Canada</ENAMEX> aren't biting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Independent</ENAMEX>
reports. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> has found one supportive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, however: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX> who
believe that the currency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> would ease <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>'s own transition to
sovereignty.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kangaroo</ENAMEX>
Saviors
            

            A
computer science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> has designed a "marsupial" to help search-and-rescue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in times of crisis. The robot, designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Murphy</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of South Florida</ENAMEX>,
has a pouchlike cavity inside of which a smaller "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>" robot is stored.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> robots work as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> carries a load of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> equipment and battery power into the search site, then deploys
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to poke through the debris and rubble for evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
for a video clip of the "launch" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> robot.) The robot system is
safer than dispatching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human rescuers</ENAMEX> and, when space is tight, more
effective.

            
               Probation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX>
            

            Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of University Professors</ENAMEX> has censured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> that do
wrong to their faculties. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s additions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of shame are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson and Wales University</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Marty College</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAUP</ENAMEX> charged <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX> with wrongful termination for not renewing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">one-year appointments</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> teaching in a doctoral program in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">educational</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Marty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> allegedly violated the
due-process rights and academic freedom of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, who had been
trying to revive a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAUP</ENAMEX>, when they fired him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAUP</ENAMEX> censure matter? Some say the mark is "a serious stigma,
others call it a joke," reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> . Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> do their best to reform after receiving
the citation. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, a record number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>) were able to
persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAUP</ENAMEX> that they had cleaned up their act and should be removed from
the list; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> still remain under censure.

            
               School's Out,
Forever?
            

            
Despite achieving their primary goals, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are still on strike.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nearly three months ago</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> at the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autonomous University of Mexico</ENAMEX> proposed a raise in student tuition from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
cents to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $150</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> closed down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> with a strike,
affecting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">267,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>. So why are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> still
occupying the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>'s major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have escalated their demands to include the rollback of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a
dozen changes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> has imposed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, including limits on
the number of years <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have to earn degrees and tougher enrollment
standards. With negotiations at a stalemate and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> vacations removing the
motivation for an immediate solution, both sides appear to be settling in.

            

               Cybercheating
            

            The
Scotsman reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> is withholding exam results from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> computer
science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> determines whether or not they used
the Internet to cheat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graders</ENAMEX> became suspicious that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were sharing
answers via e-mail and using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX> to search for information when
they noticed similarities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' work--some to the point of being
identical. Although the incident has raised questions about whether electronic
cheating is commonplace, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> asserts that "there is
no evidence this is a more serious and widespread problem."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mau Mauing Goes to</ENAMEX>
College
            

            
Following a bloody assault by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obafemi Awolowo University</ENAMEX>,
Ile-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ife</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are calling for the dismissal of a top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>, who they hold responsible for lax campus security. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attackers</ENAMEX> belong to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> secret society that
functions like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>, retaliating against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> who oppose
them. The melee left at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> dead and incensed fears that
cult-related violence is rising on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s university <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>. The student
union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has promised a continued boycott of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> until campus
security is improved and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice chancellor</ENAMEX> dismissed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>, which
have been blamed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of rapes, murders, assaults, and arson attacks over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, are widely considered to be the most serious problem facing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>'s
largest university system.

            
               Packing
            

            
According to a study conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard School of Public</ENAMEX>
Health, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 400,000</NUMEX> undergraduates in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> own a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handgun</ENAMEX>. The study also shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> handgun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> fit the profile of
the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>: white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> or in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> areas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> also reports
from the study that it points to a "worrisome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>" between gun
possession and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> drinking. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Weschler</ENAMEX>, one of the report's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>,
warns, however, against overreacting to the study: "We're not pointing to
hordes of drunken college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> running across campus armed," he said. "I
don't want to give that impression."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
Threat
            

            Top
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> are worried that repercussions from the alleged
theft of nuclear secrets will hamper the recruitment of talented <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . Since the
charges in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> gathered a rich harvest of nuclear secrets from
ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has slowed the visa approval
process, making academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> more difficult. In addition, low
morale is evident among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, since suspicions
abound in the workplace. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahwey Chu</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the Asian-American
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Laboratories</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, commented, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it would take a
brave lab <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> to hire someone with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> name."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> Who
Thawed Their Work Destroyed
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>'s power outage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early July</TIMEX> may have damaged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of experiments
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> were conducting at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">upper Manhattan</ENAMEX>. The backup generators designed to power the various machinery
and refrigerator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> failed. Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are trying to determine
the extent of the loss.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comings</ENAMEX> and
Goings
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Fish</ENAMEX>, formerly of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of liberal arts and sciences
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, has lured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more high-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> to join his ranks--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transsexual</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre McCloskey</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Iowa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX>
Graff, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of English and education at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elsewhere</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> has finally lured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">provocative criminologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John J. DiIulio Jr.</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiIulio</ENAMEX> will take
his endowed chair in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Humanities</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> has announced its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999-2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> will
investigate a range of subjects including techno music and globalization,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">avarice</ENAMEX> in the late middle ages and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> and
foreign affairs.

         
      
   
