
   
   
      
         
            Bad <I>Instinct</I>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hideous</ENAMEX> <I><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX></I>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Instinct
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> skewer this
psychodrama starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primatologist</ENAMEX> who clubs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> park
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rangers</ENAMEX> to death while living in the wild with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gooding Jr.</ENAMEX> as the hotshot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> assigned to draw out his story. The
plot rips off the familiar <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> mind games of The 
               Silence of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> and adds up to nothing more than "a greatest-hits collection of
plot devices and emotional cues from such films as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gorillas in the Mist</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest "</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to watch the trailer, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in

                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  Limbo
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Entertainment</ENAMEX>). Good reviews for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sayles</ENAMEX>' ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lone Star</ENAMEX> ) latest drama: "moving and empathetic ... Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> are more
instinctively caring, or provide for more moments of grace between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). The film, set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, follows
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loners</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Elizabeth Mastrantonio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Strathairn</ENAMEX>) who
engage in a tentative romance. Halfway through the film, the plot suddenly
turns into a survivalist action adventure. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say this transition
is rough but ultimately forgive the film: "If this oddly structured film feels
like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> short stories stuck together, there is enough solid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX> joining them
that they resonate off one another deeply" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> dissents, calling
the film "an earnest, dogged, squarely rendered wisp of a movie." (For more on
Sayles, this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX> has a biography, filmography, and news.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Social Club</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artisan Entertainment</ENAMEX>). Wim
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wenders'</ENAMEX> documentary about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of the same name gets
consistent raves. Not only are the live performances transcendent ("the music,
in its acoustic beauty and power, jumps off the screen," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Watrous</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ), the scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> are spectacular, and the story
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>' recent professional rebirth is gripping. Many of the performers
are in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">70s</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80s</ENAMEX> and had not played music for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--one was working
shining shoes, another hadn't had his own instrument for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a decade</TIMEX>--until
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ry Cooder</ENAMEX> brought them together to record and perform. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to buy the album that won them a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammy</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Brief <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Interviews With Hideous Men</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Foster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little, Brown</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> collection of stories is roundly seen
as a disappointment. Hailed as one of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> when he published the immense novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Infinite Jest</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> irks the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> with this collection, which is mainly a series of sketches describing
extremely unpleasant and misogynistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Though a few stories are on par with
his earlier work, most reviews find the collection riddled with
self-referential tics and self-consciousness. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> comes down the hardest, turning in a scathing review in which
she calls the book "an airless, tedious production" that "represents a sharp
falling off in ambition, nuance and vision from Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>'s previous works of
fiction." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read 
                  Slate
               's recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club</ENAMEX>" on Brief
Interviews .)

            

               
                  Juneteenth
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ellison</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Callahan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). "Uneven" is the word used most often to describe
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s posthumous <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> novel, which he had been working on for 40 years
before he died. Pared down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">384</NUMEX> pages from the sprawling, unfinished,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX>-page manuscript by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Callahan</ENAMEX>, the
novel leaves many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> wondering about the enormous amount of material not
included and whether the novel can even truly be called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s book. Ellison
envisioned a multi-voiced symphonic saga about race in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, but Callahan
reduced it to a single linear story with a few central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--notably
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">omitting</ENAMEX> excerpts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX> had published, such as the story "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flambé</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> say that sections are on par with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invisible Man</ENAMEX> --especially
the set pieces, dialogue, and riffs--but the novel as a whole doesn't match up:
It "provides the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> with intimations of the grand vision animating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year</TIMEX> project, but it also feels disappointingly provisional and
incomplete" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> found the novel more satisfying than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. Click to read his
review.)

            

               Music
            

            
               Death: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torme</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925-1999</TIMEX>). The jazz, swing, and pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> died of a stroke
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday at the age of 73</TIMEX>. Nicknamed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Velvet Fog</ENAMEX>" for his smooth voice,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torme</ENAMEX> "sang with a geniality that seemed ingrained and a voice that was
incapable of making an unpleasant sound" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
He was most famous for his scat improvisations and enjoyed a renaissance in the
1990s, when, after a lifetime of performing, he was discovered by a younger
generation interested in lounge music. Never a true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX>, he managed to
succeed mainly because he continued to perform and his voice miraculously
seemed to improve with age. He was also a songwriter, and his most famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">composition</ENAMEX> was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Christmas Song</ENAMEX>"--better known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chestnuts Roasting</ENAMEX> on an
Open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fire</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to see a listing of his albums.)

         
      
   
