
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=350300619-12101999><SPAN class=350300619-12101999>Weak <EM>Hearts</EM>, Potent <EM>Pu-239</EM></SPAN></SPAN>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  Hearts
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sydney Pollack</ENAMEX> directs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Scott Thomas</ENAMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> who discover, after a plane crash kills their respective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>, that their loved ones were having an affair together. In their grief,
they start an affair. Despite the strength of the star power, the reviews are
uniformly weak: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he movie ... sputters and sprawls, breathtakingly unaware
of how ponderous it is" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The
problem? The relationship that blossoms between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Thomas</ENAMEX> is
unrealistic and boring, "the sexual equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Easy Listening"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
Maslin, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and here to find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Thomas</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  Don't Cry
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> Searchlight
Pictures). Outstanding reviews for this independent film based on the life of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teena Brandon</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who passed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and was raped and murdered
when her secret got out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> can't say enough good things about the film:
It is "audacious, accomplished" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel Levy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> ), "a delicately
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conceived</ENAMEX>, fearless film" that is like "a long tragic poem" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ), "one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s best" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maslin</ENAMEX> calls it a "stunning debut
feature" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly Peirce</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Owen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary Swank</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">90210 veteran</ENAMEX> who plays
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>, "extraordinary." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> the trailer on the official site, and an article in 
                  Slate
                on how well
the film reflects the facts of the actual story.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Superstar</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). "If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superstar</ENAMEX>
were meatloaf--and that would be an improvement--the recipe would be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 pounds</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread crumbs</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 ounces</NUMEX> sirloin. Make that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chuck</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> agree with this assessment, saying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> sketch featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shannon</ENAMEX> as nerdy, horny,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tortured Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolgirl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Katherine Gallagher</ENAMEX>--with a signature
pratfall that exposes her large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">white underpants</ENAMEX>--does not translate well to
the big screen. The biggest problem: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is "so sad and helpless, so
hard to like, so impossible to empathize with, that watching it feels like an
act of unkindness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). A few concede that
the film is "amusing if uneven" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Harvey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> ), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX> gives the film a decidedly upbeat review: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> works
because <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shannon</ENAMEX> so precisely gets the dank weirdness of the truly alone. And
because she shows her underpants a lot." Reading further, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> questions his
motives when he describes her thus: "her legs askew, her too-tiny schoolgirl
kilt aflutter and the little white delta of her panties flapping before the
world, we sense someone profoundly disturbed yet poignant at the same time."
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon</ENAMEX> and here
to listen to an audio clip of her in character.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Pu
               
               
                  -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">239</NUMEX> and Other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian Fantasies</ENAMEX>: A Novella
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stories</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Kalfus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milkweed Editions</ENAMEX>). Strong reviews for this
collection of stories set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Russia</ENAMEX>: These "crafty, nerve-rattling tales
are among the most unusual and interesting now being written" ( Kirkus
Reviews ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Characters</ENAMEX> range from a nuclear reactor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> who tries to
steal and sell the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plutonium</ENAMEX> of the title in order to support his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> after
he gets radiation poisoning, to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who is convinced there is a link between
her onset of puberty and the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>. The only sour note comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , who writes in an otherwise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laudatory</ENAMEX> review that "a surplus of sobriety may account for what weaknesses
the collection has." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  The
               
               
                  Fragile
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine Inch</ENAMEX> Nails
(Nothing/Interscope). Excellent reviews and a debut at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billboard</ENAMEX> 's pop chart (it then dove down to No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Reznor</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> offering in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. The double album is "a musical treasure trove.
... Hard rock simply doesn't get any smarter, harder, or more ambitious than
this" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim DeRogatis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). What sets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reznor</ENAMEX> (who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> under the name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine Inch Nails</ENAMEX>) apart from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">techno</ENAMEX>/goth-rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>?
His knack for pop hooks and appealing beats in the midst of all the aural
chaos: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]hen you listen up close you get engrossed in the buried sonic twists
and turns; when you turn it up loud Reznor bangs your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Sheffield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> the video
from the album on the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine Inch Nails</ENAMEX> Web site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Garth</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> in ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life of Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaines</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMD/Capitol</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> shocks the world by
putting out a pop album under the fictional persona of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Gaines</ENAMEX>, giving
himself a radical makeover complete with soul patch, eye makeup and, most
startling of all, no cowboy hat: "[H]e looks a bit like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Reznor</ENAMEX> crossed
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who eats a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese steaks</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher John Farley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). The music, though, is anything but shocking. It's "drab,
anonymous pop" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hilburn</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ) with a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babyface</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&B</ENAMEX> numbers thrown in for good measure. The consensus: "It's
neither a great pop album nor a great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> album" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Mansfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> ). (Visit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garth Central</ENAMEX> to find out more about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alter ego</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
