
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey Shakes</ENAMEX> and Breaks

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> everywhere led on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s ruinous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> earthquake, where the
latest tallies show <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 6,300</NUMEX> dead and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 20,000</NUMEX> injured. Most
reports noted that although strict building codes have been in effect in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Istanbul</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>, the regulations are often ignored. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> said
that "shoddy construction work, cheap building materials and a reckless
disregard for safety," almost certainly caused so many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> to crumble.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> noted that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> has long been ... a land of ruins," but
recommended that just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uses the latest techniques to
protect monuments such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hagia Sophia</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX> from seismic turbulence,
so should it "apply the same rigorous standards to its more mundane buildings
for it is upon them and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> that its future depends."

            Many
papers quoted the headline from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s best-selling newspaper
Hurriyet : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murderers</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo of Spain</ENAMEX> said: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adjacent</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that are
completely destroyed there are others that are totally undamaged. How can this
be? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> criticized the poor quality of many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that have gone up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> in the area affected by
the earthquake, a region that has experienced heavy industrial development.
This undoubtedly amounts to criminal irresponsibility. Even more so,
considering that they knew they were building on an active fault line that has
caused <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of devastating earthquakes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent decades</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX>
couldn't have put up such fragile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> had not
permitted it." An editorial in the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lib√</ENAMEX>©ration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
agreed, pointing out that the "the outcome in seismic catastrophes has less to
do with poverty than with negligence."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> won't be voting for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 28</TIMEX>, because the
official screening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> approved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> for the
position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.R. Nathan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75</TIMEX>, was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to meet their eligibility
requirements of senior government or business experience and personal
integrity. According to the Straits Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong Teng Cheong</ENAMEX>, the
incumbent and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s first elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was chosen by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>), wanted to seek re-election, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> declined to support him for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX> because it felt "there was a
strong likelihood that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s health would affect the discharge of his
official duties in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> maintains that the selection was a deliberate effort to ensure
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> would come from one of its non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX> is of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> descent, while the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX>, are from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>, which accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IHT</ENAMEX> said, "With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>'s giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, riven by ethnic conflict, and its northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, about to hold elections in which the political supremacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>
majority will again be an underlying issue, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wants to
re-emphasize its commitment to racial equality as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> of political
stability and economic growth."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s ethnic hot spots was the subject of an editorial in the Straits
Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that the north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sumatran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of Aceh
"long a festering sore on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> body politic, is now an open wound."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been killed and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around 140,000 displaced</NUMEX> from their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military stepped up its campaign against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Aceh Movement</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ST</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acehnese</ENAMEX> separatism is
fuelled by popular anger against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> for taking more than it returns to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX>-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>, and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acehnese</ENAMEX> insistence that they are an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
enclave distinct from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Javanese</ENAMEX> who dominate the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Separatists</ENAMEX> intensified their campaign in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> president
announced that there would be a referendum on autonomy or independence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>, but the Straits Times observed, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amputation</ENAMEX> is out because Aceh
is unquestionably a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, unlike the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony East</ENAMEX>
Timor it invaded and then annexed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>." The editorial concluded that the
"carnage will stop only when reconciliation begins," but as a story in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> noted, the fighting is currently intensifying, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> armed forces threatening to order a state of emergency in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
Post of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> fretted about the situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has shrunk from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000 to 50,000</NUMEX> as a result of
post-conflict <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX> persecution. An editorial said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> thought it was fighting for a
multi-ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. Instead, it seems about to inherit a long-term <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> per
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">cent Albanian</ENAMEX> protectorate, ethnically cleansed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleansing</ENAMEX>, who can be as cruel as their former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tormentors</ENAMEX> when given a chance."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> concluded, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosovars</ENAMEX> are better off than under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> control,
but there is no peaceful solution in sight."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that heavy metal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Led Zeppelin</ENAMEX> are the most
bootlegged musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Phonographic Industry</ENAMEX>'s
anti-piracy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">384</NUMEX> titles by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in its collection, compared with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">320</NUMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">317</NUMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stones</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">301</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> (the
subject of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Browser"</ENAMEX> column on "the bootleg fallacy"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenth</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BPI</ENAMEX>'s list,
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jimi Hendrix</ENAMEX>--who hasn't done many live concerts since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
