
   
   
      
         
            Raising a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stink</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cologne</ENAMEX>

            Food
was fundamental in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>. An item in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer Sunday</ENAMEX> reported that world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> meeting at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cologne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, designated genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> as one of
the "greatest threats facing the planet"--along with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and the millennium
bug. The topic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> food has been widely debated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> but is seldom
raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, where, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> , "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 70</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million acres</NUMEX> of modified soya <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>, tomatos, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX> are now grown."
(For more on national attitudes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> foods, see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX> 's
cover story.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
featured a long piece about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> crops in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and reported that a group of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cologne</ENAMEX> to protest what they see as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto Co.</ENAMEX>'s
attempts to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> dependent on genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton crops</ENAMEX>.
Meanwhile, all over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> there were reports of increasing consumer anxiety
about the safety of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX> to cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict was not forgotten, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> around the continent encouraged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to maintain a stiff spine regarding the demilitarization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation Army</ENAMEX>--a matter apparently resolved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spanish</ENAMEX>
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX>, which has not been a military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> during the
campaign, cannot now be its political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. As just one of the parts of the
conflict, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> should subject itself to the authority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFOR</ENAMEX> and disarm
itself." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tagesspiegel of Berlin</ENAMEX> said, "It is understandable that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> wants to remain armed in case of possible <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> attacks in the future. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> in its military movements can't consider that during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these critical days</TIMEX>,
as they work to prevent a security vacuum with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> withdrawal. ... If the
principles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are to be believably achieved and the chance of a
multiethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, at least at the starting point, is to be retained, then the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> must also let itself be disarmed."

            Also
on the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
counseled against analogy creep. It said, "There have been rather too many
emotive analogies drawn with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Nazi Holocaust</ENAMEX>, which are in danger of
clouding the truth rather than illuminating it. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language</ENAMEX> is important and,
although the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> state pursued a policy of vilification, expulsion and
murder against the ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>, it did not amount to genocide. ... If
there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> dead in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> that is a terrible crime, but it is not the
same as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> that were once feared. There is a parallel
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s ambition for a racially pure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s
ethnically homogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Serbia</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> was not working towards a
Final Solution; he did not aspire to world domination; he did not espouse an
ideology of eugenics."

            
Returning to a still-unresolved earlier conflict, an editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> came out in support of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Dutch</ENAMEX> proposal designed to ease the West's "economic stranglehold" on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> observed, although it was "[r]ecently overshadowed by
the conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>," for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> now the West has used "tough sanctions
and low-intensity bombing, which has taken place on average once every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>" to battle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, without "having the required effect."
The new proposal would set strict conditions under which the West would lift
the economic embargo and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would be allowed to bid on contracts
to rebuild "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s shattered oil industry." According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> , "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t is now time to break the deadlock by pushing forward with
this humane proposal." Nevertheless, the plan was denounced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX>,
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Jumhouriya</ENAMEX> said, "The vicious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
draft has even exceeded the unjust and cruel resolutions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>
Council against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>."

            In
other media matters, intervention by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Party</ENAMEX> has delayed
conservative newspaper magnate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad Black</ENAMEX>'s elevation to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> who owns <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> , and most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>, had been advised
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that he would be able to accept a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lordship</ENAMEX>, for which he
was nominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hague</ENAMEX>, if he took out dual
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. With the intervention of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> received a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> passport, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> before the honors
were announced, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottawa</ENAMEX> reversed its position and declared that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX> law
prevents <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> from receiving peerages. Black told his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> flagship
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
Post that "as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> I find the conduct of our government
slightly embarrassing." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX> ,  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> 's main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, said that
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> legal reforms should make the peerage possible and noted
rather archly that "[t]he prestige of a noble title is now within Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grasp</ENAMEX>, but ... he must wait, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the autumn</TIMEX>, before the prize is securely
his. The delay should not, however, prove too trying. Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX> has, after all,
been anticipating the pleasure of a peerage for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a decade</TIMEX>."

            The
last <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> royal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding of the millennium</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s marriage of Queen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>'s youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophie Rhys-Jones</ENAMEX>--was the occasion for the
recently installed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official ode. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Motion</ENAMEX>'s poem
"Epithalamium" (read it here--free registration for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> site
required) was described as "safe" and "traditional" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> ,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.G. Ballard</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , "The poem proves that it's
time to discontinue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poet Laureate</ENAMEX> in the hope that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX>
Family will follow soon after."

         
      
   
