
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> Canada

            It's about time. Those of us who work on
international monetary theory have been wondering for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX> would get his richly deserved <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Memorial Prize</ENAMEX> in Economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sciences</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX>'s work is so central to that field, so "seminal"--an overused
term that really applies here--that on many disputed issues his ideas are the
basis for both sides of the debate. But a layperson might be confused
about exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mundell</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> are really about.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page, rather pathetically, has declared this a
"supply-side" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>. No surprise there: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bartley</ENAMEX>'s attempts to
claim intellectual vindication have become increasingly desperate in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. With <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> and counting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> expansion making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> fat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>" look positively shabby, and with supply-side <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jude Wanniski</ENAMEX> looking loonier by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> will
take anything it can get. (Since when does Bartley care about what some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedes</ENAMEX>
think, anyway?) For what it is worth, the citation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>
doesn't mention anything <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX> has written since he was adopted as mascot by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartley et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 25 years ago</TIMEX>. It is the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mundell</ENAMEX>, whose theories still
dominate the textbooks, who earned the prize.

            So if it isn't a supply-side <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>, what is it? Well, how
about regarding it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Nobel</ENAMEX>?

            I'm not sure why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> policy issues are
universally regarded as being dull--why the winning entry in the old
competition for most boring headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worthwhile Canadian Initiative</ENAMEX>," still
seems so funny (yes, I think it's funny, too). Maybe it has something to do
with the way they talk, eh? But when it comes to international monetary
matters, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> has often been a very interesting case--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that defies
the trends, that demonstrates by example the hollowness of the conventional
wisdom of the moment. Right now, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s ability to thrive with
an independent dollar is the best single argument I know against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">europhiles</ENAMEX> who insist that their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> must join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Monetary Union</ENAMEX>
or die. And when the young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mundell</ENAMEX> did his most
influential work, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX>, it was arguably the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> difference
that inspired him to think outside the box.

            Here's what the world
looked like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>: Almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> had fixed exchange rates with their
currencies pegged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar. International movements of capital were
sharply limited, partly by government regulations, partly by the memory of
defaults and expropriations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX>. And most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> who thought about
the international monetary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> took it for granted, explicitly or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">implicitly</ENAMEX>, that this was the way things would continue to work for the
foreseeable future.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> was different. Controlling the movement of
capital across that long border with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had never been
practical; and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> felt less nervous about putting their money in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> than anywhere else. Given those uncontrolled movements of capital,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> could not fix its exchange rate without giving up all control over its
own monetary policy. Unwilling to become a monetary ward of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve</ENAMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949 to 1962</TIMEX> Canada made the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost</NUMEX> unique decision to let its
currency float against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, high capital mobility and a
fluctuating exchange rate are the norm, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> they seemed
outrageous--or would have seemed outrageous, if anyone but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> had
been involved.

            And so perhaps it was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> case that led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX> to ask, in one of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most famous
contributions, how monetary and fiscal policy would work in an economy in which
capital flowed freely in and out in response to any difference between interest
rates at home and abroad. His answer was that it depended on what that country
did with the exchange rate. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> insisted on keeping the value of its
currency in terms of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>' monies constant, monetary policy would
become entirely impotent. Only by letting the exchange rate float would
monetary policy regain its effectiveness.

            Later <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX> would broaden this initial insight by
proposing the concept of the "impossible trinity"; free capital movement, a
fixed exchange rate, and an effective monetary policy. The point is that you
can't have it all: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> must pick <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. It can fix its
exchange rate without emasculating its central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, but only by maintaining
controls on capital flows (like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>); it can leave capital movement
free but retain monetary autonomy, but only by letting the exchange rate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fluctuate</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>--or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>); or it can choose to leave capital free and
stabilize the currency, but only by abandoning any ability to adjust interest
rates to fight inflation or recession (like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argentina</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, or for that matter
most of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>).

            And what choice should a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>--where capital controls were not a serious option--make?
Should it explicitly or implicitly give up on having its own currency and go on
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar standard, or were the risks of a fluctuating <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar-dollar</NUMEX> rate a
price worth paying for the ability to actively stabilize the domestic economy?
The debate over how to define an "optimum currency area" is an endless <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX> set its terms, suggesting in particular that a key feature of such an
area would typically be high internal mobility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, that is, the
willingness and ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to move from slumping to booming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>.
(This is a criterion, incidentally, that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>--whose single-currency regime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mundell now</ENAMEX> enthusiastically supports--manifestly does not satisfy.)

            It's hard to appreciate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> just how novel both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX>'s
statement of the issues and the way he tried to resolve them were at the time.
But if you look at the international monetary literature when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mundell</ENAMEX> was in
his glory days, you get the impression that he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 or 20 years</TIMEX> ahead of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contemporaries</ENAMEX>. They were still thinking in terms of a controlled world, a
world where money moved where and when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> told it to move. He was
thinking in terms of a world where money moved freely and massively to wherever
it could earn the highest return. At the time, only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, thanks to its giant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neighbor</ENAMEX>, lived in anything like the world he envisaged; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we all do. And
if you look at any major textbook in international economics--such as the
perennial best seller by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Obstfeld</ENAMEX>--you still find that the
monetary <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the book is very largely based on the papers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mundell</ENAMEX> wrote in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1960s</TIMEX>.

            So who is this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> that the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> thinks is on its side? Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> do change their styles and
their views as they get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">older</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX> changed more than most. Those seminal
early papers were crisp and minimalist; they looked forward with remarkable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prescience</ENAMEX> to the wild and woolly, out-of-control world of modern international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macroeconomics</ENAMEX>. By contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX>'s writings since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX> have been
discursive, one might almost say rambling, and often reveal a sort of hankering
for the lost certainties of the gold standard. (And yes, he has said a few
things that can, with some effort, be construed as support for supply-side
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX>.) The precocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> anticipated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>; the elder statesman
has hearkened back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>.

            So you can take your pick as to which Mundell you
prefer; but the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> basically honored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mundell</ENAMEX> the younger, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> who was iconoclastic enough to imagine that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, of all places,
was the economy of the future--and was right.

         
      
   
