
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pond</ENAMEX>

            In the
absence of any major international story to dominate the press, newspapers
around the world tended to focus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on domestic issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday</ENAMEX> stories
were big in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> reported vast traffic congestion in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">peninsula</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> fatalities on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX> gave dramatic front-page treatment to the heat wave in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
describing its effects as a "massacre." Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> quoted the pope as
advocating vacations in monasteries and convents. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Salzburg Festival</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
have imposed a ban on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under-16s</TIMEX> attending an "erotic" edited version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s tragedies. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12-hour</TIMEX> theatrical marathon in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> is titled
Schlachten! ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Battles</ENAMEX>! ) and is said to include scenes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masturbation</ENAMEX> and oral sex.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, a flood of interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> heralded the launch of her new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearst</ENAMEX>-Miramax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>, Talk . In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> article, amid many cravenly
anonymous predictions of disaster, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> of 
                  Slate
               
warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not to bet on her failing. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> ,
Talk 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Galotti</ENAMEX> says, "You can never, never underestimate the fundamental level
of interest there is in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>," by which he presumably meant the opposite. Brown
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">herself</ENAMEX> said that during her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last six months</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> she had
"begun to miss the theatricality of photography, to be able to use pictures in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> that were really free and uninhibited" and that she "wanted to create a
new form for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> without the institutional history of any publication
before me, or on my mind."

            The
piece described the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue of Talk as more closely resembling "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postmodern</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> magazine or <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Paris Match</ENAMEX> than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> retread." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> said Talk was printed on thin paper
to have "a roll-it-up-and-put-it-in-your-pocket, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> feeling." The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said Talk has "a strangely dated feel." It said,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> wants to give Talk the feel of the best 1950s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCalls</ENAMEX> and Look , as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Paris Match</ENAMEX> . Those magazines
have all been widely admired, but it is a long time since they were considered
at the forefront of the market."

            In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helena de Bertodano</ENAMEX> said that her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> had been "tense"
because a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX>, an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a cut-glass <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> accent" had
insisted on sitting in on their conversation but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> subsequently
arranged a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> meeting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>. "I'm sorry about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>,"
she said when they reconvened. "It was embarrassing. ... I didn't expect it."
On the hostility she was said to have generated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> said: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs bark</ENAMEX> and
the caravan moves on, right? That's just life at the top of the media world."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> acknowledged a link between her departure from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and the death of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> beforehand: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]he kept
telling me that I didn't have enough fun. I think she was right and I just felt
this job would be tremendous fun." What if <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk fails?</ENAMEX> "It won't," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brown</ENAMEX>
said. "Already the commercial signs are such that it won't." Asked where she
sees herself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>' time, she replied: "Sitting in a café in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. This
is definitely the last big roll of the dice as far as I'm concerned."

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> led with Talk 's first scoop--its interview with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> blaming her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s infidelities on a "weakness" caused by
childhood abuse. The same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> carried on its front page an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who manages the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H. Gates Foundation</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates Sr.</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> will announce a number of new funding programs during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> that will go a long way toward its ultimate aim of becoming the largest
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is going to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> all his life because
of his wealth," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates Sr.</ENAMEX> said. "But I'm optimistic now that we have put to
rest any criticism on the basis of his not being sufficiently generous. We've
pretty much drowned that out."

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> led with the news that the brain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iris Murdoch</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> who died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, is to be
used by research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> to help find a cure for the disease. Her widower,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Bayley</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> long ago expressed a wish for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to
be given to science. "We were both happy about it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when she could be
happy about anything," he said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> revelation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> Sir
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Jackson</ENAMEX>, refused an order by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO Supreme</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX>
forcibly to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from occupying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> when the war
ended. "I'm not going to start the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> for you," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> was
quoted as saying.

            The
Mail on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX> have
purchased a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-story, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">southeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> suburb of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulwich</ENAMEX>, where they are thinking of sending their
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connor</ENAMEX>, to one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s most prestigious private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulwich College</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also ran a feature on a "svelte and clearly
self-assured" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Woodward</ENAMEX>, who posed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> for the women's magazine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Claire</ENAMEX> against the background of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>,
who was convicted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> of the manslaughter of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">-month-old Matthew Eappen</ENAMEX>,
is studying law at a university in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and maintains a close friendship with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Scheck</ENAMEX> (he defended both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>), who
sometimes takes her out to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> in fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and in whom she
confides "about all her problems," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

         
      
   
