
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">273</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Fun With Ambiguity&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Here's a headline
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Swerve and Sharp Elbow Cost a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hotfoot the Stage</ENAMEX>." What's the lead?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 272</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Old Ways":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> did something
that no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has done since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> did it on vacation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>.
What?
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "Told
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickes</ENAMEX> to stop giving so many crazy ideas to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">goddammit</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            "Had
sex with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'00</NUMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gammons</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Packed the selection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> for a new dime design."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Bodow</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> reviews the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> section of his legacy checklist: 'Cheat on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>' ...
been there. 'Get into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> war' ... done that. 'Die in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unimpressive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> can be elected' ... Maybe I'll just visit an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">impoverished Indian</ENAMEX> reservation."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Visited an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> reservation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> followed immediately behind,
handing out <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smallpox</ENAMEX>-infected blankets and bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">President Attends World Cup Final, Enjoys Two</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scoreless Hours</ENAMEX>." That's the headline that didn't run in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s papers,
suggesting that, contrary to many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> responses, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s portrayal as
prancing national satyr is ended. Further evidence: At the end of the match,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandi Chastain</ENAMEX> tore off her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> did not go to a split-screen shot
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> drooling. Which was only fair, because he seemed to be
salivating less over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s new golden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> than over his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> tub of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fried</ENAMEX> something or other--popcorn? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clams</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuahuas</ENAMEX>?

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s coverage of the big game is portentous,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s place in history is as the fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> we first elected: Every time
they cut to him, he was eating junk food. There was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> beside him--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service?--who poked him in the ribs whenever he was on camera; his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goofy</ENAMEX> stare
would flit from his trough of nachos to the playing field. Apparently
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> of the future will learn anecdotes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fries</ENAMEX>,
like those heartwarming stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taft</ENAMEX>'s giant bathtub. Filled with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chili</ENAMEX>.

            There are, incidentally,
no known photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> with any sort of junk food. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> are
determined that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> statue in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> will depict him eating a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">burrito</ENAMEX>.

            
               Is That a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pocket of</ENAMEX>
Poverty, or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are You Just Glad To See Me Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            As a part of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty '99 Road Tour</ENAMEX>--and the
tour jackets, incidentally, are way cool--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oglala</ENAMEX> Lakota
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sioux Indian</ENAMEX> reservation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pine Ridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D.</ENAMEX>, making him the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to
set foot on a reservation since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> visited some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cherokee</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 60 years ago</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s determination to eradicate poverty is
consonant with the welfare "reforms" he championed so vigorously, his
determination to raise the minimum wage so high that it's nearly possible to
live on it, and his commitment to do something or other for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who lack health insurance.

            Here's the slogan that's
not emblazoned on the back of those jackets: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Casino Gambling--Is</ENAMEX> There
Anything <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Can't Do?</ENAMEX>"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MyTwinn™ Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            A perverse practice played for laughs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Powers: The Spy Who Shagged Me</ENAMEX> and for terror in voodoo cults is now a
freakish gift for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>: You can buy a tiny duplicate of yourself. Or
someone you love. Or, presumably, hate.

            For <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$134.95</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MyTwinn</ENAMEX> "artisans" will make a
posable, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23-inch</NUMEX> doll that bears a frightening resemblance to your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>.

            To order, send a photo and fill out a questionnaire
that's pretty much a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Identikit</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> pictures of eyeballs in
assorted colors; circle the one closest to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s. There are, however,
only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> choices on the skin tone chart, from "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain</ENAMEX>," to a suspiciously
light "dark brown." There are also hair and eyebrow charts and a sketch of a
face upon which you draw birthmarks, moles, and freckles. "Pierced ears, cleft
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chins</ENAMEX> or dimples are not currently available."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MyTwinn</ENAMEX> dolls are created to be more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-like
than doll-like, which makes them more fun to play with. They are soft cuddly
and durable; and they become a treasured keepsake for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>." Isn't this the
sort of thing no longer available in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX>?

            The other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> here is to make you a steady
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> for doll-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> outfits at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $50 to $100</NUMEX>. The catalog,
filled with photographs of overly cute little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and their grotesque
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">simulacra</ENAMEX>--identically dressed!--is deeply disturbing. Deeply. I'm not kidding.
Deeply.

            Near the end of the catalog are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MyTwinn Boys</ENAMEX>.
Not for the fainthearted. And, in a chilling retroactive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorian Gray</ENAMEX> bargain,
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">randmothers</ENAMEX> can also have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MyTwinn</ENAMEX> doll made to resemble them when they
were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-12 years old</TIMEX>." And alive.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MyTwinn</ENAMEX> workshop is
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramsey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, same thing. Read more about it and order a
catalog of your own, if you've got the guts, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mytwinn</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good News</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> Should Pick
This <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">His Running-Mate</ENAMEX>."--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richmond Times-Dispatch</ENAMEX>
headline over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Wattenberg</ENAMEX>'s column on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lieberman</ENAMEX>

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Sex on wheels.

         
      
   
