
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">272</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;The Old Ways&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did something that no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has done since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> did it on
vacation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>. What?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 271</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stop the Pressing":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Future Homemakers of America</ENAMEX>
made a startling announcement. What?
                     
                  
               
            

            "We're
leaving you for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia Hamm</ENAMEX>. Make your own goddamned dinner."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> pulled strings to join in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'68</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Thomason</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Shakle</ENAMEX>
            

            "We're
not wearing any underwear!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsey Brock</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> has been shot!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "Fuck
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gravy</ENAMEX>; let's go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arby's</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Just because an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> drops off the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> or the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Post</ENAMEX> doesn't mean it has ceased to exist. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fraternities</ENAMEX>, drum and bugle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> croquet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> with a deep
bronze suntan hungry for a thick steak with a fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> on top and a cigarette
to settle the digestion! Is that a reactionary bastion, a pathetic anachronism,
or something truer, something with enough confidence to survive without media
ratification. As that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife club</ENAMEX> thing turns out--reactionary bastion. But
I admit that when a drum and bugle corps marches by playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Wars theme, I get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> in my throat. Then I vomit into the gutter, and
after that I'm OK.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Whine</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
Bottles Answer
            

            They're changing their name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family,</ENAMEX> Career and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Leaders of America</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHA</ENAMEX> was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX> to teach teen-age girls
how to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>-to-be. Much has changed since then, and
teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are now a quaint relic of a bygone day, or perhaps it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that are the quaint relics. But there is a relic and, by God, it had
better be quaint.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> began
admitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, who now are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45,000</NUMEX> out of a total membership of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">220,000</NUMEX>. Its
current mission is to teach career development, community service, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>,
and balancing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and career.

            
               All Talk No Action
Extra
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> subscription solicitations have been
mailed out by Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, marking the official return of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>,
as welcome a development as the renewal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bald eagle</ENAMEX> hunting. Impressively
vacuous, the Talk mailer is short on specifics--it mentions neither a
single forthcoming article nor any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>--so we can only speculate about the
magazine itself. But judging by the mailer, Talk will be good, not bad;
exciting, not dull; the sort of thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are interested in, rather than
something they ignore.

            And, judging by that
mailer, Talk will be much, much more:

            
               Will There <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Be Lots of Adverb-Adjective</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pairs</ENAMEX>?
            

            Yes. "Interestingly
different. Refreshingly provocative" Reversing these duos would have given a
whole other impression. "Differently interesting" sounds like naked pictures of
someone in a wheelchair; "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Provocatively Refreshing</ENAMEX>" implies an overly
aggressive breath <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mint</ENAMEX>. Avoiding this error bodes well for Talk .

            
               Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Expect Clapped-Out</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neologisms</ENAMEX>?
            

            Yes: "spinmeisters,"
"digerati." I'm not "intellectually adventurous, provocative, funny,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wide-ranging</ENAMEX>, or visually engaging," but if it were "spinerati" and
"digemeisters," wouldn't you be more likely to subscribe? But there's still
time to correct this before the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue "closes."

            
               Anything for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader Who Enjoys</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meaningless Dichotomies</ENAMEX>?
            

            Yes. "It makes elite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subjects</ENAMEX> accessible. And accessible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects elite</ENAMEX>."--I'm pretty sure the
former involves a hidden camera in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX>'s shower, and the latter
involves some animal (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>? a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>?) wearing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX> and a velvet cape.
"You'll discover the extraordinary side of the ordinary and the usual side of
the unique." I have no idea what this means. But I'm sure they do up at
Talk , and I'm eager to learn. That must be what they mean by
"provocative."

            
               What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Reminders That This Year Is</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>?
            

            Yes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> in a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-page pamphlet, including "new millennium" and "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">new century</TIMEX>," but no
mention of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> giving way to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 o'clock</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. We'll have to wait and
see. But I can't wait! Or see! My eyes! My eyes! I joke. It's my quick and
agile wit (see below).

            
               Any Mention of That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>?
            

            Just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, part of the
"spectrum of society--from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>." So there's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to improve
here, and I'm confident they will.

            
               Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Look Forward to Shameless</ENAMEX> Pandering
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader</ENAMEX>?
            

            You mean, like this:
"Only a select few will receive this exclusive invitation. Why you? Because
you're ... Someone with a curious nature, an acute sense of style, a level of
sophistication that matches our own, and a quick and agile wit. Someone who is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years</TIMEX> young <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>!" (Except for that last bit, which I added on account of
my, wadda ya call it, quick and agile wit. )

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX>'s Ongoing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to submit actual
quotations that sound dirty and adolescent enough to be dialogue in his future
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>. While sophisticated double-entendres are permitted, single-entendres
are preferred. Perhaps this example will stimulate a response, if you know what
I mean:

            "I'm here to say I hope
she will go all the way. I will go all the way with her."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endorses Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 7, 1999</TIMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Madden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good News</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kids Turn</ENAMEX>
Innocent<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-Looking Cigars Into Stogies Laced With Marijuana</ENAMEX>"--headline, some
paper in south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX>

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homewreckers of America</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
