
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sibling Rivalry</ENAMEX>

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               A recent inquiry regarding replacing the has
prompted me to seek your assistance. I asked my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 20</TIMEX>, to be
my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOH</ENAMEX>. But she is making the planning of my wedding a nightmare. I had thought
it would be a kind gesture if I asked her to pick out the dresses for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bridesmaids</ENAMEX>. We visited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> bridal salons, and she made a veritable scene in
each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. She was unspeakably ugly to both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and me, as well as the
staff (swearing, sarcasm, and just plain rudeness). I was deeply embarrassed,
and she apparently doesn't understand that this is not going to be "her
day."
            

            
               I asked her to help
address envelopes and other little things that need doing, and she refused:
"Not in the mood." The icing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> is that when she asked if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOH</ENAMEX> is
supposed to make a toast at the reception and I said it was traditional, she
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flat-out</ENAMEX> refused. Both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and I have tried speaking with her, but that
just unleashed foul behavior. I am sick of her antics and fed up with her. I
realize that asking her to relinquish the "title" may jeopardize our
relationship, but I don't understand her behavior at all.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.H.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear T.</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does. The little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is competitive with
you, and there's a chance she wishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> and bridesmaid roles were
reversed. Acting out in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and "foul behavior" are indicative of emotional
problems, deep hostility, and no self-control. By all means withdraw the
"title," and tell her you do not wish to burden her with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOH</ENAMEX> chores, nor do you
wish to have your dream day spoiled. There is not a reason in the world that
you should have to tolerate this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. In fact, suggest that she
not attend the wedding. You need not be the victim of her neuroses.

            As for "jeopardizing the
relationship," with all due respect, it sounds as if it's already on life
support. Just because she is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> doesn't mean she gets to behave less
well than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. Sometimes a relative is just an annoying person courtesy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DNA (</ENAMEX>or, if you're religious, a punishment from God).

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, proactively

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               My question also
concerns , but this time in an office setting, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> with many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>.
If you think you recognize the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stall</ENAMEX> next door and you
have a question or a comment, should you start talking?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wondering</ENAMEX>, too
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Won</ENAMEX>,

            If this is a same-sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bathroom</ENAMEX>, not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ally</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McBeal</ENAMEX> unisex setup, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would say it's OK. (She is
not exactly sure why, though.) Do begin, however, by verifying it's the person
you think it is so that you are not having a conversation with the wrong pair
of shoes. You might also want to edit your conversation for whoever else might
be listening. This would entail, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> guesses, checking for more shoes.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, loquaciously

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I thought your
response to the about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telemarketers</ENAMEX> was wonderfully done. Would you run for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? Better yet, would you spearhead a tasteful anti-telemarketing
crusade? I am thinking of an Internet movement. Can you imagine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> answering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telemarketers</ENAMEX> by singing one line of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant</ENAMEX>" and
then hanging up?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear D.</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> cannot run for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> because she is having such fun working at 
                  Slate
               . She
is, also, alas, out of the crusade business. Your idea, however, about singing
and hanging up is now being read by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, so telemarketers
beware.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, melodically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Thanks for all your
good advice. Here's my problem: I broke off a relationship with a delightful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who lives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. We were together for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly four years</TIMEX>.
I'm starting my own business and just don't want to be in a committed
relationship right now--but I would like for us to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. He is having a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal of trouble letting go of the more physical aspects of our past and
spends a lot of time begging for "just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time." How can I make it clear
to him that breaking up means losing that physical connection? He's prone to
pouting, and it's driving me nuts.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thanks</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TOO MUCH LOVE IN VT.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear TOO,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is going to give
you the exact language. This is what you say: "The last time was the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>." And if you have broken up, how is it that you are subject to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pouting</ENAMEX>? By the way, it seems quite clear that your current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>/former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beau</ENAMEX> is not looking to be "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>."

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, definitely

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               When taking my seat
in a crowded movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, do I say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Excuse me</ENAMEX>" to those already seated
before, while, or after I step on their feet?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Smith</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear R.</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie always says it before.

         
      
   
