
   
   
      
         
             Flight Stimulator

            The deaths of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bessette</ENAMEX>
sisters have inspired myriad debates over the safety of private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, as well
as a lot of criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s decision to brave <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> sky over ocean
in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piper Saratoga</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II HP</ENAMEX>. Obviously, it's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s role to
prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from taking the sort of risks they think makes life worth
living. But should <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> be spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of millions of dollars</NUMEX> each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> encouraging the risky business of private air travel?

            How risky? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> times
more likely to be involved in an accident and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">225</NUMEX> times more likely to suffer a
fatal crash than a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six hundred</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died in
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> crashes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, but only one died on an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airliner</ENAMEX>. Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> continues to subsidize general aviation--the
catchall category that covers everything from single-engine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cessnas</ENAMEX> piloted by
weekend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hobbyists</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Learjets</ENAMEX> carrying corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX>. Partly due to all this
government largess, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has more private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> than
all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> combined.

            The biggest direct
subsidy is the air traffic control system. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Golaszewski</ENAMEX> of
the consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRA Inc.</ENAMEX>, general aviation imposes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1 billion</NUMEX> a year
in air traffic control costs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX>, but the
fuel taxes levied on general aviation cover <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about one-third</NUMEX> of that. The
shortfall is covered by the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> federal tax on commercial airline
tickets. Also, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> has furnished <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.7 billion</NUMEX> in grants to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> aviation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> to pay for construction and improvement and has given
federally owned land to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX> analyst <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Utt</ENAMEX>
points out that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>, which serve <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of
commercial air <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>, get less federal money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,233</NUMEX>
smaller ones that cater almost exclusively to private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fliers</ENAMEX>.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> go down, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> conducts costly
search-and-rescue missions. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of light-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> crashes can expect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> trying to recover their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> under the gaze of TV
news cameras, but the bulk of the efforts deployed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> accident was
not out of the ordinary. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About 400 to 500</TIMEX> search-and-rescue operations for
missing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> are undertaken by the federal government <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, nearly all
of them private. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Nearly $370 million</NUMEX> is spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> on all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> federal
search-and-rescue missions. The amount spent on general aviation search and
rescue is not broken out as a separate category.)

            Additionally, all private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> accidents, whether
they involve a fatality or not, require a costly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Transportation Safety</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> conducted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,907</NUMEX> such investigations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> doesn't detail its costs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Air Patrol</ENAMEX> also
gets money to help find downed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>.

            Other inducements to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> aviation include easy access to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>. Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>
frequently find themselves trapped in holding patterns over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
biggest and busiest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> as corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">turboprops</ENAMEX> carrying a few people
land. Increased landing fees and less generous treatment have reduced general
aviation traffic at big hubs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, but they haven't eliminated it.
At <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O'Hare International</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 6 percent</NUMEX> of all landings are private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>'. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles International</ENAMEX>, the figure is close to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>.

            All those corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> highlight another reality, which
is that general aviation benefits from the abuse of the business tax deduction.
Deep in their hearts, the captains of industry know that corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> are a
rip-off: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX> once christened his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> jet "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Indefensible</ENAMEX>."
Legal fees and photocopying expenses, of course, are just as deductible as the
cost of owning and flying a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. So why doesn't anyone worry about
their being abused? Because traveling on a cushy corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>, quite unlike
consulting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, inevitably involves a large component of personal
pleasure and comfort--like staying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons</ENAMEX> instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott</ENAMEX>.
The extra expense required to avoid the sweaty traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> may yield
nothing in terms of higher productivity or profits, but with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> footing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of the cost, top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> may find the perk too tempting to resist.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX> was pretty normal for a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>--a
hard-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">charger</ENAMEX> who fell in love with the freedom, excitement, and romance of
private aviation. But like most of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fliers</ENAMEX>, he had the resources to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> his pricey hobby without imposing so much on earthbound mortals. While
we're free to second-guess his decision to fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>, maybe we
should be pondering another question: Why were the rest of us paying him to do
it?

         
      
   
