
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crime of Wine</ENAMEX>

            As Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> spin into the financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stratosphere</ENAMEX>, Wall Street and the business press speak with awe of the
revolutionary implications of the Web. Issue after issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">detail</ENAMEX> in awe-struck tones the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> (sometimes even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> ) raised by Net <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
A new staple is the interview with the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> (call him the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> will ask meekly, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chopra</ENAMEX>, what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> do you think will be
affected by the Internet?" To which the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> sighs, pauses, and explains,
"The real question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>, is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> will not be affected.
Frankly, I can't think of a single <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>."

            Well, I can--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> business might well
end up being one of the few areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life undisturbed by the great
Internet revolution. The buying and selling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> across state borders is
still illegal in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, where I live. It's a pity
because the wine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> is perfectly suited to e-commerce. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> could
possibly stock even <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>-odd <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wineries</ENAMEX>, not to mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">vineyards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>.
It would be a godsend if wine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> could do a Web search for bottles of, say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cloudy Bay Sauvignon Blanc</ENAMEX>, a hard-to-find <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16</NUMEX> world-class white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zealand</ENAMEX>. In my mind's eye, I see myself using a search engine similar to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Book Exchange</ENAMEX>,
which allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to track down secondhand books at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> across
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North America</ENAMEX>. I can just see myself clicking the mouse to comparison <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and
then score a bottle from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> store, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> outlet.

            I'd settle for being
able to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> from mainstream Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-800-WINE-SHOP</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wine</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
(which used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virtual Vineyards</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--most of them in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>--have completely legalized such acts of capitalism between consenting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. The laws regulating direct <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> sales were rarely enforced until
recently, but a new zeal is in the air. Buying a single bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">out-of-state</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-degree felony in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and is
punishable with fines of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $2,000</NUMEX> and jail time. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the parched</TIMEX> state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, has introduced a bill that would allow
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to prosecute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX>. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> was moved to federalize
this crime precisely because new technologies like the Internet make it easier
to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> nationally (horrors!). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Scarborough</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, introduced a
similar bill in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>--which passed by a hefty margin.

            At the risk of making a one-way trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rikers Island</ENAMEX> ("I
must take the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth</ENAMEX> about my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> purchases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>"), I spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks this summer</TIMEX> surfing the Web for vino. Some wine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> keep their lists
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">online</ENAMEX>, but none of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Lehamn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zachy's</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrell's</ENAMEX>--do. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> wine lists I browsed were so outdated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
percent of the wine I wanted to order was out of stock. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
wine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX> I spoke to said that the Internet isn't having much effect on his
business because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from most big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> can't use it to order <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>. If
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> buying was uniformly decriminalized and there was a genuine
nationwide market, on the other hand, the system would be more creative and
efficient.

            I had better luck ordering from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corkscrew</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K&L Wine Merchants</ENAMEX> (a widely
known and well-regarded place) of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wine</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, an
online-only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Napa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are pretty well run but, again, they
simply don't compare with those selling books, CDs, clothes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> wares.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> were shipped to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, one of the enlightened
places where e-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> are legal. Precisely how I obtained the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> is a matter
of "don't ask, don't tell."

            I deliberately chose
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> that could travel badly--delicate white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Champagne</ENAMEX>, Pinot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grigio</ENAMEX>--and also some harder-to-find <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sangioveses</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> were received in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> of ordering.
They were all very well packed in special thermacol <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine molds</ENAMEX>. As a result,
almost miraculously, most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> held up even though they were shipped in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> degree weather. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Champagne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billecart-Salmon</ENAMEX>'s special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K&L</ENAMEX> bottling,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26.99</NUMEX>) went slightly off (losing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> and gaining acidity); the cheaper white
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pont de Brion Blanc</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13.99</NUMEX>), was a decent steely <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sauvignon Blanc</ENAMEX>
that stood up to the trip nicely. The more expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chateau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>-Haut-Lafite
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22.95</NUMEX>) was superb, delicate, flowery, and yet crisp. But in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or two it
began fading; signs of jet lag. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sangioveses</ENAMEX> were the most pleasant
surprise--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaffer</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virtual Vineyards</ENAMEX> special bottling (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13</NUMEX>): Both
were delicious, with the pointed flavors of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chianti</ENAMEX> and the ripeness of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s clime mixed together. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Chianti</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> are going to be
the next trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX> winemaking.

            Back to the puritans. Why do the new prohibitionists oppose
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>? They claim <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, like most new legislation in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, it has been passed for the benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> need to
ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> are not provided with unfettered access to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>
explained. He trots out the usual anecdote masquerading as evidence--a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> once ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> off the Internet. In fact, there is little
danger that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> are going to order unusual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> from distant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wineries</ENAMEX>,
wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> for them to arrive, arrange to have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> out of the house
when they do, and then ... what? Throw a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claret keg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Alcohol</ENAMEX> has received exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> complaint of an Internet sale to a
minor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it's for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">21 st Amendment</ENAMEX>, which repealed prohibition, allows
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to regulate the transportation of "intoxicating liquors." Indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>'s bill is titled "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">21 st Amendment Enforcement Act</ENAMEX>." But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">protections of the 21 st Amendment</ENAMEX> are actually quite thin. The
language of most state laws would seem to violate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>'s interstate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commerce</ENAMEX> clause, which facilitated the creation of a national economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX>
are increasingly coming to this view. At the very least, it means that the
restrictions do not have the halo of constitutional protection.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">21 st Amendment</ENAMEX>'s intent was to give the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> the power to prosecute the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>'s involvement in the liquor trade. But
because much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>'s interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> died with the repeal of
prohibition, what keeps these laws alive is politics. Liquor regulation is a
case study in the manipulation of politics by powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobbies</ENAMEX>. The regulations
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> are maintained and strengthened because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesalers</ENAMEX>, and
large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wineries</ENAMEX> benefit from them, and they are organized and politically
powerful. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobbies</ENAMEX> have been effective at working with
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cranks</ENAMEX> to regulate the minutiae of the wine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> can't sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> are
illegal, but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> oversized bottles are illegal. And so on. (The single
most bizarre law, which banned giving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, has recently
been repealed.)

            Those who lose out are small and up-and-coming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wineries</ENAMEX>, specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who would have more
choice and lower prices. The entire setup has an anti-competitive,
anti-entrepreneurial flavor that rewards political lobbying rather than good
business practices. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> seems to recognize this when he says, "If there
is a problem with the system we need to fix the system, not break the laws."
For the moment, however, the fix is in for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
