
   
   
      
         
             Playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heavy</ENAMEX>

            Blame it all on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calista Flockhart</ENAMEX>. Having
apparently grown tired of obsessing over just how skeletal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ally</ENAMEX>
McBeal 
               Über -<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waif</ENAMEX> has become, the tabs take a different tack: They
bare their fangs and become positively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCarthyesque</ENAMEX> in their zeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebs</ENAMEX> who've become the least bit unsvelte. Fat jokes are the order of the
day--the meaner, the better.

            Where to begin? With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's snippy
caption for a photo of "tubby" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX> "nearly blocking an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Hampton</ENAMEX>
street"? Or with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's complaint that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winslet</ENAMEX> "ballooned up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the minute</TIMEX> she got off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and loosened up her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corsets</ENAMEX>"? (The story goes on to say that she put on all of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> pounds, for the
record.) How about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's report that at the bash to celebrate her
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> appearance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> "hit the buffet table
like a toothy tornado"? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> explains, is in the midst of
a "frantic food frenzy"; the paper even provides a helpful restaurant diary
that details where she has been spotted and just what she has indulged in.
Sample entry: "She wolfed down a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> oz. goblet of sugary hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper East Side</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Serendipity 3</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> also
claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX>--who has gained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> pounds of her own, according to the
Star --fears that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chastity Bono</ENAMEX>, is "eating herself into an
early grave." "I've seen her eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> out of the carton," a source
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confides</ENAMEX>. (If this is a warning sign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> fears for the health of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.) And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's hit list goes on.
"Pudgy" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> is said to have put on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> pounds. An intrepid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> interviews a vacationing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy Ramsey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of
JonBenet, while swimming in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> and observes that she has "obviously
put on weight." And, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> cover story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX> has
"pack[ed] on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">47 lbs.</TIMEX>--& DOESN'T CARE!"

            The good news for all those who've been nailed by the
tabloid fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> has the secrets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s "love diet," a seaweed-rich plan that has helped the "bloated blimp"
with "enough ballast to sink the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> " become a shadow of his former
self. Can it be coincidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> claims it was a "wacky seaweed
therapy" that helped "hefty and hippy" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophie Rhys-Jones</ENAMEX> drop <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 pounds</NUMEX> before
her recent wedding to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Price Edward</ENAMEX>? Furthering the maritime theme,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Myers</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
pounds on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon salad</ENAMEX> diet."

            When they're not
obsessing about who's eating what (check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's scintillating
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-page photo spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>' favorite breakfast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>), the tabloids
take time to remember that it's wedding season. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX> wedding intrigue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dominates</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> raising the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> may
be gay--perhaps forgetting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a week earlier</TIMEX>, it had him confessing that
he was actually in love with his late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>. But
there's no rest for the weary in tabloidland. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week</TIMEX> after the royal wedding,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> had already reported that the honeymoon was "over"
and that cracks were "already showing" in the marriage.

            At the wedding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courteney Cox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Arquette</ENAMEX>--who'll
be getting the requisite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gucci</ENAMEX> nipple rings to celebrate, according to the
Star --the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> says that "no one was paying more attention" than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX>, because they are preparing to take the plunge
themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> will have to take a number. Among those the tabs
say are eager to walk down the aisle are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demi Moore</ENAMEX> and new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beau Oliver</ENAMEX>
Whitcomb, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie Driver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Brolin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Graham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Burns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camilla Parker Bowles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariah Carey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Miguel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Bratt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Douglas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enquirer</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Fonda</ENAMEX> is "stocking up on bridal
magazines," while country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Yoakam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> for her engagement ring,
despite a concurrent report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> that a "heartsick" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonda</ENAMEX> "can't
find Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Right</ENAMEX>."

            So much love is in the
air that a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> are flying back into their former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>'
arms--or at least trying to. And naturally, at the forefront of this wave of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity reconciliations</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Lee</ENAMEX>. According to the
Star , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> are thinking of getting remarried the old-fashioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>: on pay-per-view TV, complete with a video montage of their "non-explicit
romantic moments together."

            Perhaps inspired by action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Claude Van Damme</ENAMEX>, who
recently retied the knot with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladys Portugues</ENAMEX> (making her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> No. 3
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 5</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa-Marie Presley</ENAMEX> is "desperately pleading" with ex-husband
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> to get back together, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> . "I'll treat his
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> adorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> as my own," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa-Marie</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying, in the
unmistakably stilted syntax of tabloidese. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , on the other hand,
has Presley busily planning her wedding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Watson</ENAMEX>, although at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> will reportedly be at the altar: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> is said to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> of honor.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Andrew</ENAMEX> must be
unfazed by how "chunky" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> says his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Ferguson</ENAMEX>, has
become, because they are also talking remarriage, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> . And when she's not worrying that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is about to keel
over, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX> has been rekindling her romance with her ex <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Camilletti</ENAMEX>,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , which also reteams <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Leon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> with her ex <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> might want to check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , which claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth</ENAMEX> could
be the next to jump on that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gucci</ENAMEX> nipple ring bandwagon.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> stretches the reconciliation theme to new
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">heights</ENAMEX> with a story suggesting that the "fates" are trying to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> back to his ex <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daryl Hannah</ENAMEX>. The evidence? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah</ENAMEX> was recently
spotted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> wearing a hat with a star on it, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was
photographed elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Apple</ENAMEX> wearing a T-shirt with--are you sitting
down?--the "same celestial sign." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> notes conspiratorially that
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Bessette-Kennedy</ENAMEX>, was "nowhere in sight."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> we definitely don't expect to see
reconciling anytime soon is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cybill Shepherd</ENAMEX> and her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> runs what it says is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>'s "open letter" to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepherd</ENAMEX>, in which he pleads with her to "open [her] heart and do what's right"
by repaying him the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> she reportedly owes him. Confidential to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>: You
might have had a better chance of getting your money had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> not
run a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World Exclusive</ENAMEX>" interview in which you're quoted disclosing
"titillating details" about your ex's sexual fantasies and happy<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-hour</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proclivities</ENAMEX>. Keeping Tabs would never presume to speak for Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepherd</ENAMEX>, of
course. It's just a sneaking suspicion.

         
      
   
