
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Witty and Benign Companion&quot</ENAMEX>;

            In an
interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of
continuing to lie to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but reserved his harshest words for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s only stated regret was that he
didn't do enough to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> publishing the most salacious material in his
report. He deplored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' decision to authorize publication of the
unexpurgated evidence instead of "screening and winnowing" it first. "I wish I
had done more to say to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>: be careful," he said. Some of the most
sensitive evidence he gathered has never been made public, he said; and "had
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> seen fit to tell the truth, we would have been spared the
intrusive nature of the details." But he said that much of the information
published was vital to the credibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s testimony.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
complained that even now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has "admitted no offences,
other than to have the inappropriate relationship, which is not a matter of
interest to federal law. To the contrary: he has very vigorously stated that he
at no time committed any federal offences." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> said that "in one of the most
unfortunate episodes of the entire drama" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made the decision, when his
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> came to light in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1998</TIMEX>, that he was not going
to tell the truth. He was advised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> "that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
would readily forgive an adulterous relationship, but they would not be
forgiving of offences against the justice system. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> informed
him, 'Well, we will just have to win, then.' Thus, instead of telling the
truth, admitting the facts and seeking forgiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, he
launched a campaign designed to erode confidence in the duly appointed system
of justice."

            Asked
if he regretted the personal distress suffered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> replied:
"She--as an obviously highly intelligent young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>, a professional, a college
graduate--made a most unfortunate judgment, and that was that she would commit
federal crimes in order to obstruct the judicial process in the form of a
sexual harassment action [the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case]. Not only that: she importuned
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, to likewise engage in federal crimes. That was
serious business. She did it not on the spur of the moment; she did it over a
considerable period of time. She knowingly went to one of the most powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, who in turn guided her to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> to prepare
what she knew to be a perjurious affidavit. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> should not blink at those kinds
of offences." Because of her decision "not to be readily forthcoming," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
had "put the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> of a wretched and miserable <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX>
news cycle," he said. "Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> did not co-operate until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1998</TIMEX>. This
could have been over in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>." The enduring lesson of the whole affair,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> said, was that "we in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> take the law seriously and that
we are all accountable."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that was vigorously anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
throughout the scandal, sponsored a lecture by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>
was much taken with him. "The grimly bespectacled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> is only the public
face," he wrote. "In private, he is a witty and benign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>. He enjoys a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martini</ENAMEX> and is relaxed on the subject of sex: by no means the prudish
teetotaller portrayed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best legal minds of his
generation, he speaks in perfectly grammatical sentences, with the same
exhaustive precision as his celebrated report."

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s Burden," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s virtues are largely being ignored in the election
campaign because of his "intense and inevitable association with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--to whom some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 per cent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> believe that Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'too</ENAMEX> close' for their comfort." If he is to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination, "he must emerge as something more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s
favoured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> secured the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of change. In this respect, at least, Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has lessons to learn
from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>."

            But
the main focus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>,
whose speech at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party Conference</ENAMEX> promising to end the class
war, create equality of opportunity, and purge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> forever of "the forces
of conservatism" generated many editorials. His "vision of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> more like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> is laudable," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said, "but he will have to
pursue it with a passion and defend it with care." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> ,
however, called it a "strangely nerve-wracked speech, at once
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">belligerent</ENAMEX> and insecure, that seemed to reveal an inner uncertainty about what
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> is trying to achieve, and why." The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said the
speech was "as accomplished as any speech Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> has given," but the
Independent
said "real radicalism needs substance, not just a collection of good tunes."
The Financial Times
praised his radical rhetoric, but also said he failed to explain "how all this
translates into hard-edged policies."

            
Another FT editorial said the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> is breaking in corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> changing "in ways that would have seemed impossible <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>." It concluded, "As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> continue to posture in much the
same old familiar ways, the economy is at last beginning to be restructured
from the bottom up." But in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> dwelt on the human cost of this, reporting a rapid rise in the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> diagnosed as psychotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depressives</ENAMEX>. "The trigger
for their slide into mental illness is constant anxiety in the workplace," it
said. "Many are alarmed by the prospect that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s restructuring
drive will single them out." Some of them check into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> psychiatric clinic
at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> in order to find the strength to go to work on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX>, when
important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> meetings are often held, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> added.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led its
front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a report
that the change of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has ended efforts by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> mobsters
to establish ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. Such ties had been
"ripening" under the premiership of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, it said, quoting police
and intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, but were broken after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> won the
election.

         
      
   
