
   
   
      
         
            Candidates Who Don't Care

            Part of the appeal of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is that they don't seem to want it all that
badly. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> for the myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cincinnatus</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who
accepts power only reluctantly.

            Of course no one really runs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> out of
humility. Our election process is so arduous, and the odds of triumph are so
low, that no one would endure it except out of some combination of
self-obsession and self-delusion. Certainly the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> (except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>) aren't motivated by ideology. They may have positions--they certainly
have position papers--and they may even have beliefs, but these can't be what
they're in it for.

            Still, seeming not to want it desperately is
useful, and especially important to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s case, it's
part of his jovial laid-back image. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> further along, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bushes</ENAMEX> are
either actually getting less patrician or they're getting better at faking it.
No self-conscious babbling about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork rinds</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. He</ENAMEX>'s just a regular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fella</ENAMEX> who'd rather watch <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> on the tube than discuss policy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX>. It's
"Message: I don't care" turned into a plus.

            For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, the appeal
is almost exactly the opposite. He gives his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> the impression of
being almost too thoughtful to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> of yore, he is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of ideas (although, also like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX>, it is more the idea of ideas than
any particular ideas themselves). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> didn't run, though his party
begged him to, because his inner clock wasn't ready. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, whose clock
is always ready, ran and won. I think this speaks well for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and poorly
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, but many disagree. They feel it shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is not just
another scheming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol</ENAMEX>. Because he's not desperate to win, and because he's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thoughtful</ENAMEX>, he can speak the truth.

            These amorphous impressions are important to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> important truth neither he nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is emphasizing at the
moment--and neither is the press, for obvious reasons--is that they are
remarkably similar. Both are moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> (though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is feinting
left at the moment). Both are former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>. Both are in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50s</TIMEX>. Both are
tall and regarded as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stiff</ENAMEX> and dull. Both are from privileged backgrounds,
which both--in honor of another bit of democratic sentimentality--are trying to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disown</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> by emphasizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> aspect over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> aspect of
his childhood as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> by making a big deal about growing up
in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where--as he doesn't emphasize--his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bank</ENAMEX>). Both also have had privileged political careers, floating into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> or lineage, and both seem better suited to being selected
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of admiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> than to the grungy business of running for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> must treasure
and promote the idea that he is the no-bullshit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> running against "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>," as he always refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. A reputation for honesty is
useful, if not essential, to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>--especially in this post-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
election--but for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> it's vital. If he's not the truth-teller, he's got
little to offer. With that in mind, what do you make of the following exchange
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Live</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KING</ENAMEX>:
OK. The switch on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>, which you once called highway robbery, was this
political for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>?

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX>: You know, I represented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, tried to do the best job I could.
The ethanol subsidy meant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> paid higher tax for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>. It also meant that it was more difficult for us to meet our clean air
standards. That's why I oppose it. I also didn't like the fact that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX>
of the benefit went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. I didn't support corporate welfare.

            And
that was when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. I am now running
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Part of running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is getting to know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in a depth that you didn't before.
Agricultural economics I didn't know much about.

            I spent
a lot of time talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. And the problem and crisis
in the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> is real. And I sat with enough of them to know that the
ethanol part of their overall cost statement was an important part, and
therefore, I believe that it was a reasonable thing to do.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KING</ENAMEX>:
Were you wrong when you went that way as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>?

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX>: I was not wrong as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, and I'm not wrong as a
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. When you run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, you've got to think of the
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, not just your own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethanol</ENAMEX> is a ludicrous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> made out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX>, at a cost far
higher than the petroleum it replaces, produced with a huge government tax
subsidy, which started during the energy crisis a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter-century ago</TIMEX> and has
long since become a classic case study of stupid policy entrenched by special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interests</ENAMEX> (in this case <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer Daniels</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midland</ENAMEX>, the company
responsible for the fabulous discovery that if you tell the government what to
do in commercials on every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> talk show, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> apparently is
powerless to resist).

            It's not just that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> subsidy until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>. Tax policy is one of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> on which he is regarded as being especially philosophical, and his
philosophy is that a simple code with lower overall rates is better than a
complicated one filled with special treatment for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or another.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s biggest accomplishment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> tax
reform that embodied this philosophy.

            The honest answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>'s question--did he
flip-flop because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses--would be "yes." It's hard to imagine
any other reason, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> offers none that is believable, or even coherent.
Giving him maximum interpretive generosity, what he does say is sort of a
baroque variation on "yes." He's saying: "As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, I pandered to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, I will pander to every special interest in
this great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." This raises the difficult philosophical question, Does a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pol</ENAMEX> deserve credit for being an honest hack? It's a tempting proposition.
Trouble is, the need to pretend you're not just pandering acts as a restraint
on all but the most cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panderers</ENAMEX>. We don't want our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> to think they can
win points by saying, "Sure I voted with the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>--do you know how
much their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX> gave me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>?"

            Anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s answer
was not really honest, even in this cynical sense. In fact, it was the opposite
of honest. The truth is that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> he was serving the interests of the
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, while as a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> he has
abandoned the national interest in favor of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
he has no coherent response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s very good follow-up about whether he was
wrong before he flipped. Even though he now claims the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> subsidy is good
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, it was still "right" for him to oppose it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> because
it didn't benefit his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX> ignoring the good of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> except to the extent that it coincided with the good of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, and
he believes every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> is "right" to do the same. (Unless he's running for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, presumably, in which case he is permitted to consider the interests
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>.)

            A 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colleague</ENAMEX> asks, quite reasonably: How
should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> have answered the question? Start with the assumption that you
can't become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> under our unique constitutional system without giving
special pleasure to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, including the thrill of being paid by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>. What should the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> do when asked
about it? It's bad enough that we may have depleted our inventory of potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> by ruling out anyone who lies about sex. Do we really want to go
further and disqualify anyone who lies about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>?

            Maybe it's not disqualifying, but yes: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
lie was a bad one. It was a betrayal of his own long-standing beliefs on an
important policy matter. It was brazen, in front of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> on national
television. And yet it was embroidered with just enough art and obfuscation
that he can't pretend it was a just verbal wink. He wants to con us.

            So what should a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s position have
done? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things, it seems to me. One is to have answered the question
honestly and hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> reward him on the hoary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> principle that ya
gotta love a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who admits he's full of crap. It might work. And I wouldn't be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indignant</ENAMEX> if a sufficiently abject confession was tarted up with a bit of "...
and that's why we need campaign finance reform."

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> really should have done, though, is
stick to his true beliefs, so the question of why he flipped would never have
arisen. Maybe it's true you can't be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> without supporting the ethanol
subsidy. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> doesn't want to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> all that badly. Or has he
forgotten that?

         
      
   
