
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=630250921-01071999><ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke Problem</ENAMEX></SPAN>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 8</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
anniversary argues that the hardest part of its economic liberalization is to
come. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> can only save itself from its current stagnation by fixing its
banking system, addressing environmental hazards, controlling government debt,
and democratizing. ... An article condemns "positive discrimination" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Well-educated blacks</ENAMEX> are "mercilessly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-hunted" for high-paying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX>, while uneducated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> suffer from high unemployment and poor public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. ... A piece says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> is being destroyed by drug
trafficking. A trans-shipment haven for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, the island <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is
in an economic tailspin, drug violence is rampant, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> patrols the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beaches</ENAMEX>, and tourism is stagnant.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18</TIMEX>
            

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Lane</ENAMEX> and the appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beinart</ENAMEX> to replace him are not mentioned. ... A cover profile of financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suze Orman</ENAMEX>, author of
the best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The 9 Steps to Financial Freedom</ENAMEX> , argues that her
simplistic philosophy--be thrifty--is good advice in an age of escalating
consumer debt. ... An article applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s call for a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">21 st Century Teacher Corps</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> would offer money toward
college tuition in return for a commitment to teach after graduation. A similar
program successfully improved teacher quality for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 years</TIMEX>, until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> killed it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>.

            

               
                  New
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 3</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> could be the tripwire for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War III</ENAMEX> and
profiles the delusional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> who could ignite it: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fanatics</ENAMEX> who
want to retake the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apocalypse-awaiters</ENAMEX> who
want to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> rebuilt, and seething <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheiks</ENAMEX> who will wage war before
ceding authority over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX>. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> could save your
life, according to an article. Swine engineered with human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and birthed by
surrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sows</ENAMEX> could serve as spare-parts <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with failing
organs. Pig <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> await regulatory approval of cross-species transplant trials.
... A piece profiles a group of white-hat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX> called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lopht</ENAMEX>," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Naders</ENAMEX> of the online world. They crack computer systems of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to reveal their security holes. Crackees, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>,
appreciate the warning.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story excerpts the controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>
biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> initially found his subject a "shatteringly
banal" cultural "yahoo." He was "miserably blocked" until he thought of
inserting his fictionalized self into the narrative. Revelations: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> lost
half his blood after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hinckley</ENAMEX>'s assassination attempt, and he approved the
arms-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> deal while woozily recovering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> surgery. Other
highlights: In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 1</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> gushes with schoolboy crush describing his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> fictional encounter with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>: "His purposeful body
moved on, exuding liniment. I dropped the candy wrapper I had been holding--and
as I reached for it, his wet sleeve brushed my hand." One excerpt , in the form of a screenplay fragment, floats <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s view that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Wyman</ENAMEX> roped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gipper</ENAMEX> into marriage by feigning a
suicide attempt.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX>
            

            The
c over story rehashes the conventional wisdom about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. He calls for bold liberal reforms. Though he abstains from
showbizzy campaigning, he markets his virtue and "exploits his legend." His
proud reserve--a product of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> in the spotlight--is refreshing but does
not bode well for his capacity to shepherd big ideas through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
... An article marvels at the revival of religion in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, now used
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> to control a restive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taoists</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhists</ENAMEX> may practice as long as they support the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> still
feebly pushes secularism: It just inaugurated an annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hero</ENAMEX> of Atheism
award.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story explores modern treasure-hunting. Entrepreneurs
now use cheap new technology, such as remote-operated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, to salvage
artifacts from ancient wrecks. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvors</ENAMEX>" sell their finds online, stage
exhibitions for profit, and auction film rights. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archaeologists</ENAMEX> argue that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">treasure</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> wreck artifacts. ... An article notes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s female juvenile
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> were raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who were arrested or incarcerated. Many of
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> were casualties of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> crack epidemic.

            
               
                  
The
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have too much control over their treatment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> used to dictate treatment, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> the pendulum has
swung too far toward patient autonomy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians</ENAMEX> should inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> of
their options but step in when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> make bad choices or are too distressed
to choose rationally. ... An essay in the fall books section praises
"collaborative filtering" as a substitute for the independent bookseller. You
enter your preferences and a software programs spits out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>
who share your interests. This "doppelganger search engine" will help sleeper
books thrive in the era of superstores.

            

               
                  Business
                
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week , Oct. 4</TIMEX>
            

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70 th</NUMEX> anniversary issue looks forward to the Internet age, predicting
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economic boom is just the start of a period of massive,
technology-driven global growth. ... A piece touts the Web as a tool of
revolution. Grassroots movements fund raise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruit</ENAMEX>, and plan mass protests
online. When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> bullied service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> into blocking pro-democracy sites,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberactivists</ENAMEX> tapped into off-shore servers.

            

               
                  The
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> cannot be counted on to end racial profiling.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> have upheld traffic stops that are mere pretexts for searches and
erected evidentiary boundaries to ending profiling. Only political action will
eventually end racial profiling.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story earnestly deconstructs pro wrestling, mourning it as evidence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s moral decline. The disappearance of the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
villain symbolizes the weakening of the nation-state and the spread of moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relativism</ENAMEX>. The popularity of narcissist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulk Hogan</ENAMEX> presaged the
election of unprincipled rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. ... An article excoriates
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s "power grab." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> argues that any use of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> in international affairs is illegitimate unless authorized by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX>. This specious doctrine could hamstring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
