
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rotten Eggs</ENAMEX>

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> won their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">th World Series</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pitcher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Clemens</ENAMEX> shut out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> inning, leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanks</ENAMEX> to
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> win. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> agreed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanks</ENAMEX> performed even better than they
did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> did even worse than in recent post-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> what baseball and politics have in common.)

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> met for their second
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, who did not attend, still managed to draw more
attention than any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who showed up. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Click for Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s
account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>' deranged performance.)

            

               Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> held their first
debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundits</ENAMEX> awarded victory to: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, who started early, stayed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late</TIMEX>, and showered questioners with declarations of heartfelt warmth; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, whose low-key manner made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> look desperate; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, because
nearly everyone watched the game instead. (See "" for a full assessment.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armenia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> and several other government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were
killed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of others were hurt when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> opened fire on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> during a speech by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vazgen Sarkisian</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assailants</ENAMEX>
finally surrendered after a day, claiming that they had only meant to scare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> and that shooting by government security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> had
forced them to fire back. The motives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assailants</ENAMEX>, who yelled that they
were staging a coup and demanded to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, are unknown. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> downplayed the incident, claiming that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are quiet and the only events are taking place around the parliament
building." Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> suggested it further underscored the instability of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Caucasus</ENAMEX> region.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> ordered a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> cut in federal spending. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> also provides <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85 billion</NUMEX> for labor, health, and education. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drafters</ENAMEX> claimed that it doesn't use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> monies to fund federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> disagreed, finding that the bill depends on
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$43 billion</NUMEX> in "creative accounting" and that the budget would have to be cut
by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.8 percent</NUMEX> to be balanced without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> funds. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> gloated
over the findings, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> threatened to veto the measure.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted to ban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>-assisted suicide. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
approval is expected, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has not yet said whether he'll veto the
measure. If ratified, the bill will overturn an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> law that allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
to prescribe lethal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> to terminally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Pro-euthanasia
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> warned that this would make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> wary of prescribing painkillers
to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, for fear of being accused of assisting a suicide.

            

               The online auction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> may be a fraud. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> have already dropped out, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who tried to place bids
received no response. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietors</ENAMEX>' explanation: We're inundated with
responses and will be up and running shortly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' explanation: The
site is a sham, intended only to drive traffic to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s porn sites.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> dissects the ethics of the sale in ".")

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Golfer Payne Stewart</ENAMEX> died in a plane crash. The Learjet
carrying him and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> others lost contact with air-traffic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> shortly
after takeoff from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX> It traveled on autopilot for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,400</NUMEX> miles
before crashing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> suspect that a sudden loss of cabin pressure caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to lose
consciousness or die early in the journey, but they say they are unlikely to
ever find the definitive cause. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>, a two-time <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder Cup</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, was recognized for his unconventional golfing
uniform--knickers and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">tam-o'-shanter</ENAMEX> hat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sentinel</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>'s charisma, charm, and emotional play were his
true legacy.

            

               The Dow Jones industrial average is changing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
stocks. In: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC Communications</ENAMEX>. Out:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodyear Tire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears Roebuck</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Carbide</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX>' spin: The
new index reflects that the economy's future is in
high-tech . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX>' spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duh</ENAMEX> --what took you so long?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>. After
criticizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> openly for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> announced that he would seek the
Reform presidential nomination, which would bring him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX> in federal
funds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>, who said he would decide by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> whether to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
would likely spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million to $200 million</NUMEX> of his own money on a campaign.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have become 
too similar and bland. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>'s spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have
become too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">polarized</ENAMEX> and extreme. Pundits debated whether the candidacies would: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
take votes from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) take votes from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>) create a
self-destructive battle for the soul of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX>
Party. ("" outlines how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> selects its presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$268 billion</NUMEX> military spending
measure. He has threatened to veto the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> remaining appropriations
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> budget because of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' proposed cuts in social
programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> criticized the military bill for including budget gimmicks
and pork-barrel projects but said that he could not "allow our national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> needs to be held hostage by this budget battle." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> simply realized that contesting defense spending would be unpopular.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' spin: We're winning the budget fight by convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to
compromise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin: Now it's your turn to compromise.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> continues to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> have
died and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 160,000</NUMEX> have fled the breakaway republic since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> began
military operations there in the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> terrorist bombings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> are gathering near the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX>, though they have not
announced plans to invade the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> called for peace talks, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> rejected the offer, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militants</ENAMEX> would use a cease-fire
to rebuild their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is trying to take us over
again. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> spin: No, we're simply preventing terrorist attacks on our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The American spin: Either way, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> risks restarting a bloody
and futile war.

         
      
   
