
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=350300619-12101999><SPAN class=350300619-12101999><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambulance Chasteners</ENAMEX></SPAN></SPAN>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Bringing Out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Schrader</ENAMEX>--who collaborated on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driver</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bull</ENAMEX> , and others--team up again, this time for a
film about a burned-out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> respond with a sprinkling of hearty positive reviews, but the majority
are gingerly worded negative takes. Almost everyone draws parallels to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driver</ENAMEX> (another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manhattanite</ENAMEX> on the edge driving an automobile), though
nobody says it compares favorably. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX> does call it "superbly shot ...
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of bravura moments and high-wire performances" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> raves that "it contains some of [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s] most brilliant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). Overall, though, the reviews complain
that the film feels too familiar and short on plot. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> the film
in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Man</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> film
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm D. Lee</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>) gets lukewarm reviews, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moviegoers</ENAMEX> still made it No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> at the box office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. The story focuses
on a group of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> reunited for a wedding, which makes it "a kind of
Big <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chill</ENAMEX> for black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonnae O'Neal Parker</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). (A similar comment in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> provoked an
indignant letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taye Diggs</ENAMEX>.) Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say it
"does not deliver on what could have been a promising premise" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Zwecker</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ), but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX> finds it "funny,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sentimental</ENAMEX>, cheerfully bawdy." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about the film.)

            

               
                  Crazy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banderas</ENAMEX>' directorial debut--which stars his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie Griffith</ENAMEX>--leaves
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> cringing. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banderas</ENAMEX> directs "capably enough" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ), the plot is a dud. Twin stories follow a batty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s
flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> after killing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, and a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s first
encounters with racism; the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> story lines link up at the end. "Of all the
patronizing white-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> movies made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> about the civil rights
movement, this has to be the loopiest" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Daly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Banderas.</ENAMEX>)

            

               Books
            

            

               
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.W. Norton & Co.</ENAMEX>). Positive responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liar</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Poker</ENAMEX> ) inquiry into what makes Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>--and all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>--tick. On the upside, the book is a ripsnorting read, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> "has a
natural talent for spinning hilarious scenes and uncovering wicked details"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Levy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> writes in the New York
Times , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> uses a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX> approach, enlivening his account of
complicated financial deals and even more complicated engineering feats with
snappy cameo portraits, exclamatory descriptions and lots of subjective
judgments." Or as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Quittner</ENAMEX> writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , "sometimes I got the
feeling that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX> so reveres his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> that he became his apologist."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club" on The New New</ENAMEX>
Thing .)

            

               
                  Personal Injuries
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Turow</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Farrar</ENAMEX> Straus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Giroux</ENAMEX>). Excellent reviews for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> novel, about a
morally ambiguous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s collaboration with law enforcement to nail a group
of corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>. It's "street savvy and emotionally rich" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Z. Sheppard</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ); though "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">l</ENAMEX>]egal fiction has turned depressingly formulaic and
melodramatic lately ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turow</ENAMEX>'s just gets richer and smarter" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeHaven</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> delivers one of the few downbeat
reviews, claiming that the novel "imparts little of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX>'s knowledge"
that graced his other books and that "it lacks a fundamental sense of suspense"
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).  (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read an
excerpt from the book.)

         
      
   
