
   
   
      
         
            Right Aid

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> passed broad HMO reform. The bill gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> new
rights, including the ability to sue health plans for denying care. It passed
by an unexpectedly wide margin after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> rejected more limited
protections proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX>' spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finally</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> will have to pay for their actions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX>' spin: And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> will have to pay the cost through higher
premiums. The 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
                called the vote a "stunning" sign
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have lost the ability to set the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> agenda.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> criticized congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. First he said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> shouldn't "balance their
budget on the backs of the poor." Then he said his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> often neglects the
disadvantaged by focusing on economic wealth. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>'s clothing . <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> of running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on the backs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said his
comments made a "positive case" for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> compassion.
(
                  Slate
               's "" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyzes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "triangulation"
strategy.)

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were indicted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> money-laundering
case. A former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> were
charged with illegally transferring <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $7 billion</NUMEX> to foreign accounts
without proper licenses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobsters</ENAMEX> and corrupt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> of laundering many times this amount through foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
spin: This is just the tip of the iceberg. The cynical spin: The way these
investigations go, the tip is all we'll ever see.
(
                  Slate
               's "" describes how money laundering works.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115 billion</NUMEX>. The merger of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>- and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest long-distance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> is the biggest
corporate acquisition in history. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>'s data communications strength and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wireless network</ENAMEX>, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will offer the full range of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> services. Wall Street's spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mammoth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are the wave of
the future, so this marriage is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mammoth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> reduce competition, so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consumers</ENAMEX>
are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>. Wall Street's counterspin: Actually, the merger increases
competition with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, which benefits
everyone.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is debating a nuclear test ban treaty. In response
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> pressure, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> scheduled an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 12</TIMEX> vote after
delaying the treaty for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>. Despite public support, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
majority is almost certain to defeat it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Proponents</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ratification would
set an example for the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> signatory <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> counter that it
would compromise <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> security. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' spin: We're outsmarting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> by calling their bluff and will win the vote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' spin:
You're outsmarting yourselves by giving us an issue.

            

               A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> power plant leaked radiation. The incident,
which exposed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to radioactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> after the worst
nuclear accident in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s history. The risk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> is
reportedly "negligible ," but the condition of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> who were exposed remains unclear. The industry's spin: The incidents
were flukes, and everyone else is safe from future accidents. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>'
spin: Everyone else is as safe from accidents as we were.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is campaigning as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>." He
shook up his campaign by moving his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
and challenging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> to a series of debates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said he'll assemble a
"leaner, tougher" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, who has recently raised
more money than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. The optimistic spin: Running as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">energize Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign. The pessimistic spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretending</ENAMEX> to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>
when he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> looks ridiculous.
(
                  Slate
               's ""  rounds up the assessments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s moves;
and "" analyzes the importance of being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>.)

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum of Art</ENAMEX> opened its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" exhibit.
Record <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> attended the controversial show, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> had
tried to block by halting checks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> and filing suit for lease
violations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> countersued on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> grounds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s spin:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX> are guaranteed freedom, not taxpayer support. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s old spin:
Withdrawing support violates this freedom. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s new spin: Thanks for
the free publicity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>. Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' spin: The controversy is more
interesting than the art. (
                  Slate
               's "" and "" debated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s move. And in "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Cohen and Deborah Solomon</ENAMEX> debate whether the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" art is worth all the fuss.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> entered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> incursion and the preceding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> of air raids were necessary
to punish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">militants</ENAMEX> for recent bombings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and to prevent the
militants from invading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dagestan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> control <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> are preparing to battle elsewhere. Chechens were divided
over where to direct their anger: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> for clumsy attacks that
mostly hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) at the militants for provoking these assaults. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> worried that the strategy would revive the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> Chechen
war.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> began its new term. It is expected to be the
most controversial term in recent memory, with cases on free speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and
state, and the federal-state balance of power. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> hope their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-4
majority will make this the defining term of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> said the decisions are "destined to transform, for better or
worse, the legal landscape."

         
      
   
