
   
   
      
         
            Triumph of the Swill

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warning</ENAMEX>: This review
contains profanity and unwholesome ideas. Parental discretion is strongly
advised.)

            If you haven't seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">South Park: Bigger</ENAMEX>, Longer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Uncut</ENAMEX> , then what are you waiting for, you shit-sucking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle-fucker</ENAMEX>?
Do you want to miss this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Duck Soup</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>)? True, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Duck</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soup</ENAMEX> didn't resort to bunches of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-letter words--OK, cannonades of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-letter words--for shock value. But the value of shock was cheaper back
then. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> has to haul out the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. At an early juncture,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creators Trey Parker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Stone</ENAMEX> must have decided there'd be no point in
doing a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> film if they couldn't make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX> choke and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Waters soil himself. You can taste their glee in hitting their marks--hitting
them and annihilating them. This isn't just the most riotously inventive movie
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, it's the raunch anthem of the age.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> (and
screenplay collaborator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Brady</ENAMEX>) have concocted nothing less than an
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">80-minute</TIMEX> Swiftian epic--a ribald, hyperbolic satire of the notion that movies
"warp our fragile little minds." Inspired, no doubt, by the reception to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> on television and to its ancestor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Judge</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beavis</ENAMEX> and
Butt-head , the film depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> going to war, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> being gorily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slaughtered</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> journeying to heaven and hell. But the basic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premise</ENAMEX> remains deliriously simple. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four third</NUMEX>-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protagonists</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cartman</ENAMEX>, and mush-mouthed sacrificial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb Kenny</ENAMEX>--sing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>-style ode to their "peaceful, redneck, podunk" wintry
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mountain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> (where denizens step over the homeless on their way to church
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>), and then bluff their way into an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-rated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> cartoon called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asses of Fire</ENAMEX> . That picture stars a crudely drawn, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beavis</ENAMEX> and
Butt-head-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duo</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Terrance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip</ENAMEX>, who entertain each other by
spewing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-letter words and passing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> in each other's faces. "I wanna be
just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip</ENAMEX>," announces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cartman</ENAMEX>, who shows off his new
vocabulary at the pond on which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> idyllically <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice skate</ENAMEX>. Impressed, the
rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> rushes off to see what the fuss is about--or, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>-speak, aboot .

            The upshot is pandemonium. By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asses of Fire</ENAMEX>
has been trimmed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> to a permissible <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> are cursing authority figures and a militant countermovement--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAC</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mothers</ENAMEX> Against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethel Merman</ENAMEX>-ish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>--has marked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrance</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip</ENAMEX> for execution and driven the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to war against its
neighbor to the north. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> could be speaking for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX>--which
forced last-minute cuts in this "uncut" feature for the sake of an R
rating--when she intones, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horrific</ENAMEX>, deplorable violence is OK as long as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't say any naughty words."

            For all the film's
obscenities, its primary influence is musical comedy. It could have been
dreamed up at a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer</TIMEX> drama <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> with a liberal gay element. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX>
abounds in screamingly campy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parodies</ENAMEX>, from the opening ensemble to Terrance
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip</ENAMEX>'s peppy rap duet "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shut Your Fucking Face, Uncle-Fucker</ENAMEX>" to the
principal's exhortation to substitute "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bum</ENAMEX>," "poo," and the phlegmatic "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M'kay</ENAMEX>"
for, respectively, "ass," "shit," and "fuck" while leading a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Busby Berkeley</ENAMEX>-ish
dance line. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> sing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is a big,
fat, stupid bitch. When the film shifts to hell, the muscle-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX> does a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soulful</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meat Loaf</ENAMEX>-style schlock-rock ballad on his longing for a better
world--in this case embodied by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> of half-naked sailor types lolling about
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX>. Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bolton-ish Satan</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> with complex
emotions; he is disconsolate over his empty affair with the recently arrived
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, who only wants to fuck him in the ass and take over the world
and who is blithely uninterested in the big red <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">devil</ENAMEX>'s feelings. Maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
of the movie's gags are expressly gay or else trade on such expressions as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ass-ramming uncle-fucker</ENAMEX>," but the overall effect is the opposite of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homophobic</ENAMEX>. In the climax, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> watches a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> show in which a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Big Gay Al</ENAMEX> dresses up as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> and sings that he's feeling
"thuper." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is rapt.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bigger</ENAMEX>, Longer & 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uncut</ENAMEX> is
hardly PC, but it's still a piece of joyous left-wing propaganda. The allied
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of "morality," it says, are far more dangerous than the most "immoral"
language. The filmmakers even subvert the far right on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biblical</ENAMEX> grounds: It's
the repressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mothers Against Canada</ENAMEX> who usher in the apocalypse. (Actually,
it's a fat, overbearing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who ushers in the apocalypse--a scenario
that gave me pause but which on reflection seems more plausible than others
I've heard.) The movie reminds us, once again, how topsy-turvy this puritanical
culture really is. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Brooks</ENAMEX> who pointed out--when his great
Lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>) received a restricted rating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> for
its use of "fuck" in a "sexual context"--that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> says "I want to
fuck you over this desk," the picture will get an R rating, but if he says, "I
want to fuck you over with this desk," it will get a PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>. What the fuck, we
must ask, are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> being protected from?

            You say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> is crude? <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crass,</ENAMEX>
maybe, but rarely <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>. It's not even, as some have complained, visually
crude. Yes, the animation in, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> is more intricate, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
employs vast armies of animators, each going at his or her minute task like an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX>. How primitive. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> , the
round-headed cutouts in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parkas</ENAMEX> who hop along in front of flat backdrops
have more impact: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> have boiled their movement down to the
essential gesture. The look is never monotonous: The frames are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dadaist</ENAMEX> quilts
into which real photos are sewn--and the fact that that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s head
and not a drawing makes his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pipsqueak</ENAMEX> voice and cries of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let's fuck</ENAMEX>!" even
more hilariously fatwah -worthy. And it's the kindergarten
straightforwardness of the images that makes the obscenities so delectable: The
"shits" and "fucks" rush out of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' mouths at hyperspeed, always
a beat faster than you expect. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">puke</ENAMEX> rushes out faster, too.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bigger</ENAMEX>,
Longer & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uncut</ENAMEX> is my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> --the film that returns
me to a righteous (in this case, righteously filthy) adolescence. I've seen it
twice (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time was even better) and plan on another visit. I won't
bring my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, though. It's important that she sneak in on her own.

            I doubt that I'll see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Pie</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time
because the gags aren't as intricate as the ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> , and the
whole thing is rather obvious. But the movie, directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Weitz</ENAMEX> from a
first-time script by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Herz</ENAMEX>, made me and a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-heart
shriek with embarrassment. This one's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>--and funny. The
long-heralded teen-sex comedy has already been dubbed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porky</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> , but
it's worth remembering that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porky's</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>) was a piece of sexist junk,
and that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Pie</ENAMEX> and the vastly superior There's Something
About <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>) dramatize adolescent sexual panic in ways that seem more
likely to relieve than to perpetuate it.

            The gimmick is that the male leads (the amiable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Klein</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Biggs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Ian Nicholas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye Thomas</ENAMEX>) make a pact that they will lose their virginity before graduation,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> hence. ("No longer will our penises remain flaccid and unused: We
will get laid.") Subsequent jokes are grounded, predictably, in their
sundry sexual humiliations; easy stuff, but concentrated and layered so that
they add up to a vision of adolescence as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>-wracked purgatory. The
masochistic element takes the edge off the picture's implicit misogyny.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Pie</ENAMEX> strives to out-gross-out its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> and does so
handily. I don't envy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s teen-sex filmmaker the challenge of topping
the pie scene or the cloudy glass of beer bit. I wish a sequence that involves
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> stripping and masturbating in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biggs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> while he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX>
ogle her on the Internet weren't so poorly staged and acted. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is so
much like a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>-rate porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> assumes she was hired to
help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--but the punch line never comes.) The movie recovers
and then some when that sexy "dork" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyson Hannigan</ENAMEX> (from Buffy the Vampire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slayer</ENAMEX> ) shows up to chatter about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> camp experiences. You'll never
look at a flute the same way again.

            The only truly inspired segments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Pie feature the amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Levy</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biggs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, who's always walking in
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in the middle of some creative bout of wanking. Flustered but
suffused with good-natured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> heartiness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levy</ENAMEX> initiates a series of
"father-son" talks that are among the most excruciating ever filmed. Yes, our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had many of the same sexual traumas we did but, no, we don't want to
hear about them in detail. That's the ultimate gross-out.

         
      
   
