
   
   
      
         
            <EM>Tarzan</EM>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartoons</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Tarzan
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> from all
corners rave over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s first major release of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never</ENAMEX> has an
animated feature seemed more animated by sheer kinetic joy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). What makes it so great? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The animation,
bolstered by a new technique called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Deep Canvas"</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Collins</ENAMEX>' energizing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">percussion</ENAMEX>-heavy soundtrack; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the timeless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> story (although
some note un-PC bits have been left out of this version). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) calls it "one of the more exotic blooms in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hothouse</ENAMEX>." A few gripes from the fringes: According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gehr</ENAMEX>, although beautiful to look at, the film is "numbingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">formulaic</ENAMEX>" and rife with the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> clichés: "absent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>,
unthreatening yet princely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, perky but ditzy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>, swarthy villain, cute
sidekicks, hugs, lessons, and a CD's worth of forgettable pop tunes." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to see a listing of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tarzan</ENAMEX> films, all
the way back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX>'s silent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tarzan of the Apes</ENAMEX> .)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General's Daughter</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). Critics
dump on the gratuitous violence--especially a rape and murder scene involving a
naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> staked to the ground--in this thriller starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Woods</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Stowe</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ), it's a "well-made thriller with a lot of good acting" but is
"so unnecessarily graphic and gruesome that by the end I felt sort of unclean."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon West</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Con Air</ENAMEX> ) "shows a knack for underutilizing good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> while pumping up the story's gratuitously ugly side" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ). And in his scathing review in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenstern</ENAMEX> probably doesn't realize that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> describing the film as
"soft-core porn in an expensive star package" is likely to attract rather than
repel the target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run Lola Run</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). This
high-energy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX> has taken its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by storm, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are equally impressed: It's a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hyperkinetic</ENAMEX> pop culture firecracker of
a film" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lola</ENAMEX>) has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to run across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and recover money lost by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>. If she's
too late, he'll be killed. And so "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lola</ENAMEX> takes off, trucking along with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">muscular R. Crumb</ENAMEX> look and distinctive flaming-cranberry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>," and from that
point on, the film is full if "smashing bravado" and "sheer cleverness"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The film crackles with little tricks--at
times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lola</ENAMEX> morphs into an animated figure, and her trip starts over three
times, each version ending differently. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> pipe up with
complaints--the film is weightless and a bit air-headed--but most find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lola</ENAMEX>'s
whirlwind race against time exhilarating. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in

                  Slate
               .)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Shadow: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Legacy of Watergate</ENAMEX>
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are wary of the unimpressive
analysis and shaky sourcing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>'s latest, which delves into the
effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> on the presidency. Shadow "is filled with
authoritative accounts of conversations ... that are at best re-creations based
on biased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>' memories, at worst near-fabrications" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gannon</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). And as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Tapper</ENAMEX> notes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> "regurgitate the most titillating tidbits,
usually missing the point of the tome's larger thesis." Highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was
afraid his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> wouldn't forgive him (what a shocker) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> was
deeply pained by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s affair (another surprise). Speculation has
arisen about who gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> material, and according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> , the "No.1 suspect" is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Barnett</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read an excerpt and to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s take on
the book in 
                  Slate
               .)

             

            

               
                  Tough, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tough Toys for Tough, Tough Boys</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Self</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>
Press). Reviewers fall into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>'s latest collection of stories.
One deems it more of the same old riffing on the underside of society, "calling
up as many vile impressions of humanity as possible" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liesl Schillinger</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ), while the other detects a new maturity in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX> and
labels this "his most disciplined storytelling yet," marked by "a new control
and polish (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Everyone concedes
that his writing is masterful; it's just a question of whether he has
progressed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Lethem</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ) finds both
ends of the spectrum in the book: "When he's at his best, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>'s struggle with
these opposed gifts conjures up fiction that alternately boggles, amuses and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">horrifies</ENAMEX>. At his worst, he merely offers punch lines that are laboriously
stretched on a rack of realist detail." (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> here.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Da Real World</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missy</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Misdemeanor</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wea/Elektra Entertainment</ENAMEX>). Hip-hop's most innovative female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> turns in
her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> album, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> deem it a worthy follow-up to her blockbuster
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">platinum</ENAMEX> debut, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supa Dupa Fly</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>). But after praising the album's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">freshness</ENAMEX> and listing the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest artists</ENAMEX> (from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eminem to Aaliyah to Lil</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>), most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> start nit-picking. Main gripes: The rhymes are only so-so,
and the tired sexual politics that provide most of the lyrical subject matter
send a mixed message. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Music
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">¡Viva el</ENAMEX>
Amor!
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pretenders</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). Borderline
reviews--"competent but utterly unexciting" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Nichols</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> )--for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s first album in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. Front woman
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrissie Hynde</ENAMEX> still shines with her trademark snarl and gravelly voice, but
some of the songs are serious clunkers, and even the best sound like a rehash
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s older material.

         
      
   
