
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">276</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Circuit Breaker&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               
                  Fill in
the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Summers</ENAMEX> disdains an opinion handed down by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Court of Appeals for the 11 th Circuit</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are saying
'We'll just have a local option on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, and you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down there
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> can go ahead and _____________ all you want.'
"
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 275</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Symbolic Logic":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 
                                    
                                       
                                          
A federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>, to make a change in its official
city seal. What
change?
                                       
                                    
                                 
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "They
have to remove the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> swoosh and replace it with the Ten
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commandments</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Fredericksen</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Remove the hidden hologram of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bess Truman</ENAMEX> lifting her dress over her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City</ENAMEX>
motto, 'Drive out the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>,' must be translated from brazen <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> into the
more subtle <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ordered trigger locks to be painted onto the crossed musket
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emblems</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX>
            

            "It
now says, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Federal Judges RULE</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Courts SUCK</ENAMEX>!' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Unlike a modern
corporate logo designed by professional graphics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, where minimalism and
self-justifying folderol are key, a government seal ought to embody clutter and
boneheaded symbolism. The seal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>'s home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> is perfect.
It's got bears! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of them, standing up (rampant). The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1960 World Book</ENAMEX>
says that means <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> supports itself and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, although it
looks more like a poster for animal boxing, which might be the state sport of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>. (Formerly the state sport was catching and returning runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bears</ENAMEX> are holding up what might be a dinner plate that says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United We</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stand Divided We Ball</ENAMEX>," indicating a surprisingly open marriage or that the ink
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smeared</ENAMEX>. In the middle of the dinner plate (or is it a base drum?) there is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crescent moon</ENAMEX> (or a set of cattle horns, symbolic of a self-deluding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> who
thinks she could beat a bear in a fair fight, but I don't like her chances).
Below the moon (or cow) is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> (or dog) who also seems ready to rumble, and
to the right of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> (or dog) is an eagle with a cloud above its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, or
maybe a cartoon balloon showing what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eagle</ENAMEX> is thinking (it's tough to make
out), probably something very funny, indicating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eagle</ENAMEX> hopes to get its
own comic strip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some day</TIMEX>. Also shown are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 or 25</NUMEX>, one of them
could be a dust speck--symbolizing something to do with the sky or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> time
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spaceships</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spaceships</ENAMEX> like in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Wars . There are a helmet and some ferns or laurel, some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX>, and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> motto, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salus Populi Suprema Lex Esto</ENAMEX>," which, if I remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>,
means "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best People in This State Don't Have To Obey the Traffic Laws</ENAMEX>."
That's a lot more than you get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> swoosh. Or swish.

            
               Show <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            They've got to remove their ichthus .

             

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Clark</ENAMEX> gave the town <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> to
eliminate the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>" that adorns the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> city seal, as well as
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, flags, street signs, and stationery. He noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> "is
exhibited extensively throughout southwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> to denote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>-owned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>."

            The case was brought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webb</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiccan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> was represented pro bono by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, a "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> public interest law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>."

            See the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
unreconstructed seal at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">republicmo</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. (Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX>.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s Prissy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Overpriced Attic Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Match the evocative
description from the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX> catalog with the item it
describes:

            
               Catalog Copy
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "Graces your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with artful opulence worthy of
the gods."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "Brightens your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with a whimsical
touch."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "This ladybug holds a timely surprise."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "Brings to your home the splendor of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> love these working replicas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guns</ENAMEX>
That Killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "Designed and personally signed by
world-renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nutcracker artist</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>'s chair swivels freely, just like
its life-size <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>!"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. "Sends wave after wave of erotic pleasure
surging through her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. "Place this intriguing gadget near the kitchen
door to welcome wayfaring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nestled</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knothole</ENAMEX>."

            
               Item
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Heirloom Bombè Chest</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,295</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. "Grape Arbor" Murano Glass Chandelier</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,495</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Fanciful Frogs Bowl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27.50</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D. Ladybug Pendant Watch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$35</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Steinbach</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scarecrow</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nutcracker</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F. Miniature Office Furniture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$35</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Wooden Candy Dispenser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$32</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H. Eastern</ENAMEX> Bluebirds
Wall <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plaque</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$99.50</NUMEX>

            
               Answers
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-B, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2-C</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-D</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-A</NUMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-(I may have misread that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-F</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-(That's from a different
catalog--sorry), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-H</NUMEX>.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McDermott</ENAMEX>'s Online
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headline Haiku</ENAMEX>
            

            Award to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> push <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
Plan mass resignation
Descend on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cnn</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 1999</TIMEX>

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Aquatic mammal puns.

         
      
   
