
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Booze You Can Use</ENAMEX>

            I love <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, but lately I've been wondering: Am I
getting full value for my beer dollar? As I've stocked up on microbrews and
fancy imports, I've told myself that their taste is deeper, richer, more
complicated, more compelling--and therefore worth the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent to 200 percent</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">premium</ENAMEX> they command over cheap mass products or even mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX>. And yet,
I've started to wonder, is this just costly snobbery? If I didn't know what I
was drinking, could I even tell whether it was something from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, vs.
something from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pabst</ENAMEX>?

            I'm afraid we'll never know the answer to that
exact question, since I'm not brave enough to expose my own taste to a real
test. But I'm brave enough to expose my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>'. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX>, while working at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, I put out a call for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> for a "science of beer" experiment.
Testing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> had to meet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> criteria: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) they had to like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
they had to think they knew the difference between mass products and high-end
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microbrews</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> tasters were
selected, mainly on the basis of essays detailing their background with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. A
few were selected because they had been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> department
where I worked. All were software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> ; all were male, but I
repeat myself. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly half</NUMEX> had grown up outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or lived
abroad for enough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to speak haughtily about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> macrobrews. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tasters</ENAMEX> came in talking big about the refinement of their palates. When they
entered the laboratory (which mere <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> before had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>), they discovered an experiment set up on the following
lines:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Philosophy</ENAMEX>
               : The
experiment was designed to take place in two separate sessions. The first
session, whose results are revealed here, involved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> exclusively from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Lagers are the light-colored, relatively lightly
flavored brews that make up most of the vattage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> consumption in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. Imported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lagers</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corona</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heineken</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Budweiser</ENAMEX> is a lager; so are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>, most light <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>, and most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bargain-basement</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Beer snobs</ENAMEX> sneer at lagers, because they look so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">watery</ENAMEX> and because so many bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. But the lager test came
first, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lagers</ENAMEX> pose the only honest test of the ability to
tell expensive from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt-cheap beers</ENAMEX>. There are very few inexpensive nut brown
ales, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> pale <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ales</ENAMEX>, extra special bitters, or other fancy-pantsy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">microbrew</ENAMEX>-style, nonlager <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>. So if you want to see whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can
taste a money difference among beers of the same type, you've got to go lager.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>, the ideal of public service requires lager coverage. This is what most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> drink, so new findings about lager quality could do the greatest good
for the greatest number.

            In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> stage of
the experiment, held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks later</TIMEX>, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX> reassembled to try
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fancier beers</ENAMEX>. The results of that tasting will be reported separately,
once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s mighty Windows 2000-powered central computers have .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 Materials</ENAMEX>
               : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> lagers
were selected for testing, representing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct price-and-quality
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Through the magic of the market, it turns out that lager prices nearly
all fall into one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> ranges:

            a) High end at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.50 to $1.60</NUMEX> per pint. ("Per pint"
was the unit-pricing measure at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bellevue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, that was the
standard supply source for the experiment. There are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4.5 pints</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>, so
the high-end price point is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $7</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>.)

            b) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 80 cents</NUMEX> per pint, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">under $4</NUMEX>
per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>.

            c) Low at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 cents to 55 cents</NUMEX> per pint, or under
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>.

            The neat <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:3:2</TIMEX>
mathematical relationship among the price <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> should be noted. The high-end
beers cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly three</NUMEX> times as much as the cheapest ones, and twice as much
as the middle range. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> used in the experiment were as follows:

            
               High End
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grolsch</ENAMEX>. Import lager (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holland</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.67</NUMEX> per
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pint</ENAMEX>. (See an important .) Chosen for the test because of its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>-snob chic;
also, one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heineken</ENAMEX>. Import lager (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holland</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.53</NUMEX> per
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pint</ENAMEX>. (Sale price. List price was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.71</NUMEX> per pint.) Chosen because it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s long-standing most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">import</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wicked Lager</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>-scale
"microbrew." <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.11</NUMEX> per pint. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deep-discount</ENAMEX> sale. List price <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.46</NUMEX> per pint.)
Like the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, this put us into the gray zone for a lager test. Few
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> "microbreweries" produce lagers of any sort. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>'s is called a lager
but was visibly darker than, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Adams</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lager</ENAMEX>. National macro-microbrew. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.56</NUMEX> per pint. (That was list price. The
following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> it was on sale for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.25</NUMEX> per pint, which would have made it do
far better in the value rankings.) Calls itself <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Best Beer</ENAMEX>. Has dark
orangey-amber color that was obviously different from all other lagers
tested.

            
               Mid-Range
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Budweiser</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.84</NUMEX> per pint. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sale</ENAMEX>. List price
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.89</NUMEX> per pint.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Self-styled King</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Genuine Draft</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.84</NUMEX> per pint. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sale</ENAMEX>.
List price <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.89</NUMEX> per pint.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coors Light</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.84</NUMEX>
per pint. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sale</ENAMEX>. List price <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.89</NUMEX> per pint. Isn't price competition a wonderful
thing?) The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silver Bullet That Won't Slow You Down</ENAMEX>.

            
               Cheap
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.55</NUMEX> per pint. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sale</ENAMEX>. List
price <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.62</NUMEX> per pint.) A k a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beast</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmidt's</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.54</NUMEX> per pint. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sale</ENAMEX>. List <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.62</NUMEX>
per pint.) Box decorated with a nice painting of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.50</NUMEX> per pint. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sale</ENAMEX>. List <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.69</NUMEX> per
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pint</ENAMEX>.) Painting of mountains.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway</ENAMEX> that
supplied the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> didn't carry any true bargain-basement products, such as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Red</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX>," "Old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>," or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with generic printing that
just says "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beer</ENAMEX>." The experiment was incomplete in that regard, but no tester
complained about a shortage of bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. Also, with heavy heart, the test
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> decided to leave malt liquors, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey</ENAMEX>'s (with its
trademark wide-mouth bottles), off the list. They have the air of cheapness but
actually cost more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX>, probably because they offer more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> per
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pint</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3 Experimental</ENAMEX> 
               procedure: Each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">taster</ENAMEX> sat down before an array of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> plastic cups labeled A through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. The</ENAMEX>
A-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX> coding scheme was the same for all tasters. Each <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cup held 3 ounces</NUMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the sample <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>. (Total intake, for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taster</ENAMEX> who drank all of every
sample: <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 ounces</NUMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half normal</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>. Not lethal; also, they were
just going back to software coding when they were done.) Saltines were
available to cleanse the palate. The cups were red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">opaque plastic</ENAMEX>, so tasters
could judge the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>'s color only from above. There was no time limit for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tasting</ENAMEX>, apart from the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> limit in which we had reserved the conference
room. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> experimenter (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> of most of the others there) rushed through
his rankings in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> and gave the lowest overall scores. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taster</ENAMEX> who
took the longest, nearly the full <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>, had the ratings that came closest
to the relative price of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>. (This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.) The
experimenters were asked not to compare impressions until the test was
over.

            After tasting the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>, each taster rated beers A
through <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX> on the following standards:

            
               Overall quality points: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zero</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undrinkable</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> as dream <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. Purely subjective measure of how well each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">taster</ENAMEX> liked each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>.

            
               Price category: The tasters knew that each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">beer</ENAMEX> came from the expensive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, or cheap category--and they had to guess
where A through <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX> belonged. A rating of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> was most expensive, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for average, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
for cheap.

            
               Description: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amusing presumption</ENAMEX>," "fresh on
the palate," "crap," etc.

            
               Best and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worst: Tasters chose one Best and</ENAMEX>
one Worst from the "flight" (as they would call it if this were a wine
test).

            When the session was over, results for each beer
were collected in a grid like this:

             

            To see all the grids for
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>, click .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> Data 
               Analysis: The ratings led to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> ways to assess the quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Best and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worst</ENAMEX>.
Least scientific, yet clearest cut in its results. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tasters</ENAMEX> named a
favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> of them chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> . The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX> , the cheapest of all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> in the sample. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taster</ENAMEX> who made
this choice advises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> on what new features should go into the next
version of Word.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX> was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> to receive both a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best and a Worst</ENAMEX>
vote.

            Bottom rankings were also clear. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> naming a
Worst <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grolsch</ENAMEX> , the most expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> in the survey.
Results by best/worst preference:

             

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Overall 
               preference
points
               . This was a subtler and more illuminating look at
similar trends. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> were ranked on "corrected average preference
points"--an average of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero-to-100</NUMEX> points assigned by each taster,
corrected, just like ice skating scores, by throwing out the highest and lowest
score each beer received. The tasters used widely varying scales--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> confining
all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> to the range between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>, another giving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX> as his lowest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mark</ENAMEX>. But the power of our corrected ranking system surmounted such
difficulties to provide these results:

             

            Here again one costly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> --shows up well, while another, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grolsch</ENAMEX> ,
continues to struggle, but not as badly as the medium-price <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genuine Draft</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s success could reflect its quasi-mislabeling,
presenting a strong-flavored <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> as a "lager." It could also reflect that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> simply thought it was good. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> guessed it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX>.)
As for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grolsch</ENAMEX> ... it is very strongly hopped, which can seem exotic if you
know you're drinking a pricey import but simply bad if you don't. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGD</ENAMEX> overtook
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grolsch</ENAMEX> in the race for the bottom because, while many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grolsch</ENAMEX>,
some actually liked it; no one liked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGD</ENAMEX>. There are some other important
findings buried in the chart, but they're clearest if we move to ...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value for Money</ENAMEX>: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Taste-o-meter® .</ENAMEX> Since this experiment's real purpose was to
find the connection between cost and taste, the next step was to adjust
subjective preference points by objective cost. The Taste<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-o-meter</NUMEX> rating for
each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> was calculated by dividing its corrected average preference
rating by its price per pint . If <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Beer X</ENAMEX> had ratings twice as high as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beer Y</ENAMEX>, but it cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as much, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beer Y</ENAMEX> would have the higher
Taste<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-o-meter</NUMEX> rating. When the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> beers are reranked this way, the results
are:

             

            In a familiar pattern, we have
Grolsch bringing up the rear, with less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-quarter</NUMEX> the
Taste<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-o-meter</NUMEX> power of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX> , the No. 1 value <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. The real
news in this ranking is: the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX> ; the
embarrassment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heineken</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Genuine</ENAMEX>
Draft , an expensive and a medium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, respectively, which share the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cellar</ENAMEX> with the hapless <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grolsch</ENAMEX> ; and the nearly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX>-like
value of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best and Schmidt's</ENAMEX> . It
is safe to say that none of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX> would have confessed respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmidt</ENAMEX>'s before the contest began. But when they didn't
know what they were drinking, they found these beers much closer in quality to
"best" <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> than the prices would indicate.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Value for Money</ENAMEX>: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Snob-o-meter® .</ENAMEX> In addition to saying which beers they
preferred, the tasters were asked to estimate whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> were expensive
or not--in effect, to judge whether other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would like and be impressed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>. One taster perfectly understood the intention of this measure when
he said, in comments about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beer</ENAMEX> B (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heineken</ENAMEX>), "I don't like it, but I bet it's
what the snobs buy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snob</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-o-meter</NUMEX> rating for each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> is similar to the
Taste<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-o-meter</NUMEX>. You start with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>" ranking--whether the tasters thought
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> belonged in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> 1 (cheap), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>--and then divide by the price per
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pint</ENAMEX>. The result tells you the social-mobility power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>--how
impressive it will seem, relative to how much it costs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snob</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-o-meter</NUMEX>
rankings are:

             

            We won't even speak of
poor Grolsch or MGD any more. The story here is the amazing
snob-power-per-dollar of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX> , closely followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmidt's</ENAMEX> . A
dollar spent on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX> gets you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the impressiveness of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a dollar</NUMEX> spent
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grolsch</ENAMEX>, useful information when planning a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. Not everyone liked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX>--one called it "crap"; another, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LITE</ENAMEX>." But the magic of
statistics lets us see the larger trends.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Conclusions</ENAMEX>
               . Further
study is needed. But on the basis of evidence to date, we can say:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> beer truly survived the blind taste test. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> , which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> tasters independently ranked "best" without knowing they
were drinking a fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. (They knew it was darker than the others but
couldn't have known whether this was some trick off-brand sneaked into the
test.)

               Don't serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grolsch</ENAMEX> unless you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will consider it exotic,
or unless you've invited me.

               Apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grolsch</ENAMEX>, the tasters really had trouble telling
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> from another . This conclusion is implicit in many of the
findings, but it was really obvious during the experiment itself, when the
confident look of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>-who-know-their-beer quickly turned to dismay and panic as
they realized that all the lagers tasted pretty much the same.

            

            The evidence suggests other implications about
specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>. For instance, the comments about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coors Light</ENAMEX> are much
less enthusiastic than the average-or-better numerical rankings. Most tasters
paused to complain about it--"fizzy and soapy"--before giving it reasonable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX>. But the main implication, and the most useful consumer news from this
study, is a radically simplified buying philosophy for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lager beers</ENAMEX>.
Based on this study, rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> should:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> when they want an individual
glass of lager to be as good as it can be.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX> at all other times, since it
gives them the maximum taste and social influence per dollar invested.

            The detailed rankings and comments for all tasters
on all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> may be found .

            Next installment: fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
