
   
   
      
         
            The Politics of <EM>Talk</EM>

            What
does it take to win <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election</TIMEX>? First you must establish name identification,
viability, and a "vision." Then you must lower the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s expectations, rebut
charges of pandering and profligacy, and fend off attacks on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.
What does it take to launch a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> successfully? As Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
Brown demonstrated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the answer is: pretty much the same thing.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
Name identification. Having served in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> high-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 15 years</TIMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> was well
positioned for a run at Talk . She scored an early publicity coup by
getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> to appear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> at its debut. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> also
benefited from a gaffe by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>, who
responded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s appearance by banishing Talk 's launch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> from
a city-owned site. His attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> made the front pages of the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloids</ENAMEX>, giving Talk a free media hit.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pandering</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, broaden their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> by
appealing to the public's lowest instincts--and, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, are accused
of pandering. The rap on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> is that she's "vapid" and "shallow," and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> is "fluff" and "froth." A parody Web site calls <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk "Chatter</ENAMEX>!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banter</ENAMEX>! Emotion! Solipsism! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pretense</ENAMEX>!" As often happens in campaigns, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>
suffered an embarrassing defection <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX> quit and
told the press he had been saddled with "celebrity profile assignments."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s surrogates have replied that a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, like a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>,
must toss a bit of red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> now and then to sustain her popularity
and her movement. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>, has lent credence to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caricature</ENAMEX>. She has told the press that her editorial knack lies in being
"easily bored" and that the problem with celebrity hype is that it's "dull."
Faced with the charge that she's "lowbrow," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> has espoused a "high-low"
formula under which Talk will endeavor, according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>, "to
balance the higher-brow stuff and the trashier stuff." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have
also circulated her quote that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> should "be places where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can
picnic intellectually." These comments create an impression of flippancy and
flip-flopping, which bolsters the argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> lacks conviction.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vision</ENAMEX>. The best way to deflect charges of pandering and flip-flopping is
to articulate an essential message or "vision." Brown constantly boasts that
Talk has a "point of view." But when called upon to define it, she
speaks of a "look," a "tone," and an "atmosphere." Talk , she told the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , is "about expressing--without encumbrance of any
kind--a vision, in a sense, of the times that we are in." She comes off
sounding like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, whose ruminations on "the vision thing" convinced
everyone that he recognized the importance of having a vision but didn't quite
know what the word meant. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> speaks often of her "passion" and
"desire" for good writing. Message: I care.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Character</ENAMEX>. Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> have gone negative, calling her
"ruthless" and tyrannical. She seems unsure whether to stay on message--"The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs bark</ENAMEX> and the caravan moves on," she told <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> --or to make negative campaigning an issue. While her surrogates
decry the "long knives" arrayed against her, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> accuses her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> of "blood
sport." At times, she plays to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, projecting kindness and tolerance:
"I don't understand this fear thing. I'm not vindictive." At other times, she
plays to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>, wearing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>' scorn as a badge of honor: "I've fired
a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and killed a lot [of copy]. I don't make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that way."
Like any smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> spins the attacks on her as evidence of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">formidability</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Smith</ENAMEX> puts it, "What is it
about her that scares the rest of the press?"

            Brown
also has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> streak that threatens to escalate pandering into a
character issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> pitches himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who feels your pain.
Brown pitches Talk as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of "intimacy," starting with its
cover story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Intimate Hillary</ENAMEX>," in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> divulges her
"feelings" about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s infidelities. The consensus among political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> is that whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> used Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, vice versa, or both, the whole
thing was "calculated" rather than intimate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s assertions that the piece
plumbs the "depth" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' "shared passions" and "spiritual intensity"
add to the impression that she's more interested in advertising intimacy than
in achieving it.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
Fiscal responsibility. The old rap on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> was that she spent wastefully
and ran up big deficits at The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s spin is that
she cut the deficit: "When I arrived, it was losing money, and when I left, it
was losing less money." But the old rap has been overtaken by a new rap--that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> is fielding a "B <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> because she's no longer paying top
rates. Meanwhile, the hard-times ethic of fiscal austerity has given way to a
good-times ethic of "invest and grow," which frowns on frugality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>, is criticized for being
"weak on the buzz factor," "sheepish" about courting fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>, and
addicted to "earnest seriousness." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague likens</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remnick</ENAMEX>'s avoidance of
limousine service to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s despised modesty.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.
Expectations. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, must limit expectations so that
she can impress everyone by exceeding them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> has done so. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week ago</TIMEX>, the
hype about Talk had spent itself. "Expectation is so high that her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> are already predicting the biggest let-down since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide</ENAMEX>
Shut ," crowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York's Daily News</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> were predicting a "gigantic fizzle." But by the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> came
out, the backlash, too, had spent itself. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , "the
correct attitude" prior to Talk 's debut "was to be sick of it already
without having seen it. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> has created something that shouts READ
ME."

            And being read,
ultimately, is the name of the game. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> market is less like a general
election, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> with the higher negative rating always loses,
than like a crowded primary, in which the fight for attention is crucial, and
it's worth alienating some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in order to attract others. The more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> is
attacked, the better she does. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> vetoed Talk 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> site
and told the press it was "unimportant" and "irrelevant," all he did was make
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> important and relevant. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> put the point
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">succinctly</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>: "Is any publicity good publicity?" She answered: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">People</ENAMEX>
are rarely indifferent to the magazines I've put out. Sometimes they hate it,
but they are engaged." In other words, yes.

         
      
   
