
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">298</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fair Play&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "I'm so excited!"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hairstylist Richard Ferris</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syracuse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Fair</ENAMEX>. "This
is the most exciting thing that has ever happened to me." What happened to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX>?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question(No <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">297</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ick":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Christakos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blu Dot</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design and Manufacturing</ENAMEX>, discusses the latest trends in his industry. "We
worried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would say, 'Oh, ick, see the _____________.' That hasn't
happened."
               
            

            "Gills
on that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> falling off the thrill rides."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Weishaar</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Crushed appendages of our Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lofquist</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Way</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s face bleeds off the side of the urinal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>. In fact, aim has
improved by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> since we introduced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these</TIMEX>."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Kate Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>--or ugly modular furniture constructed to shoddy specs."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX>
Shearer Gabel
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Were it an ordinary quiz
and were you ordinary quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, I'd dilate on your detestation of
cutesy unconventional spelling. (What does it mean when the boyz make
illiteracy a fashion? And is a resistance to that fashion, a clinging to
conventional spellings, just a class marker and a reactionary <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at that?) But
it is not an ordinary quiz, it is one where I thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
for taking time away from whatever it is they do (I've written it down
someplace, but you know how it is when you're just back from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>;
everything is at sixes and sevens.) to be such excellent quiz wranglers. And
you are not ordinary quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, according to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest hosts</ENAMEX>, each of
whom expressed his amazement at seeing so many first-rate responses. Apparently
my plan of throwing out the really good ones has now been exposed. In the
future, I'll try to be, if not more discerning, at least more cunning about
concealing my limitations--you know, like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Cash</ENAMEX> in that movie where he
cudn't reed gud.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carvell</ENAMEX>'s Answer
            

            Just wanted to let you
know--the secret word for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> is: particleboard. The quote comes
from the Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, center-column story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX>'s Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> about particleboard's growing acceptance in the design <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christakos</ENAMEX> is describing an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$89</NUMEX> coffee table with particleboard edges. "It
actually looks kind of cool," he says. "We worried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would say, 'Oh, ick,
see the particleboard .' That hasn't happened." The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> then gives its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> some tough love: "For those still inclined
to say 'ick' at the sight of particleboard, the message is simple: Get used to
it." To which most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, no doubt, will respond aloud, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, you get
used to it, you puss. You want a piece of this?"

            
               Perfect

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pairs Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crest</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--the more lackluster and indistinguishable the
products, the more each category tends to generate a dominant duo vying to
appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> in what is an essentially trivial decision. And so it is in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> world of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. Below, a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-parter:

            
               The

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Putative Pairs</ENAMEX>
            

            Which of the following duos are genuine?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beanie Month</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Beth</ENAMEX>'s 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bean Bag World</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Bear</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Bear</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club International</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stamping Arts</ENAMEX> & Crafts
            

            
               Rubber 
               Stamper
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muscle Media</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Pump
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Draw Bowhunting</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Bowhunting
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Golfer
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Forbes</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Archaeology
            

            
               Extra

               Credit
            

            Match each cover story with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in which
it appears.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Osito</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Inside Story on Growlers and Squeakers</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Get Huge and Ripped</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adding Shimmer to Your Work</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rut Tactics That Bag the Giants</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hit It Long and Strong</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley of the Gilded</ENAMEX>
Mummies"

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All</NUMEX> pairs are genuine, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> and
Archaeology may be an imperfect match; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> might more
accurately be paired with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloated Plutocrat</ENAMEX> , were there such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.
Oh and by the way, have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Barkin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelman</ENAMEX>--I've been away--begun
divorce proceedings yet?

            The cover stories run in
the same order as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>; each is from the latter title in each
pair.

            
               Best

               in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Breed</ENAMEX>
            

            Most delightful sentence
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "If I forget thee, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">O Jerusalem</ENAMEX> ... now
you're just a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>-click away."

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            Contempt for innovative
spelling.

            
               Common

               Denominator in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Ads of the Saratoga Paper</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASCAR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
