
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandi's Bra</ENAMEX>

            
               What's the
Goal?
            

            Normally, I find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> to be one of the
more intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> on the mainstream beat. However, his analysis (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>")
of the "controversy" surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandi Chastain</ENAMEX>'s removal of her jersey after
clinching the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> trophy is indulgent, quixotic, and utterly
aggravating.

            He dismisses the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> do it" explanation as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superficial</ENAMEX>, when it's the only one that makes any real sense. Does anyone, on
either side of this absurd debate, really believe that an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX>, upon scoring
the winning goal in an international championship game, was actually trying to
stage some kind of cultural coup? With adrenaline pumping, in the moment of
realizing the dream of being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, with memories of the soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greats</ENAMEX> running
through her head, she did what soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> do when they can't contain
themselves. Are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> of the world so conceited that they really believe
that she was acting to supply them with more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fodder</ENAMEX>?

            I think it was the game against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> when,
in celebration of a goal, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> did a running flip-flop-flip, a
common soccer<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-player</ENAMEX>'s celebration. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX> called it gymnastics.
Apparently, to him, the only sports against which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would be measured were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gymnastics</ENAMEX> and figure skating. Regardless of which side of the sports bra
debate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saletan</ENAMEX> supports, or anyone else who considers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chastain</ENAMEX>'s behavior in
light of its social commentary rather than its expression of athletic
competition and pride, it's the same kind of sexism.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Soccer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, for
the moment, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s sport. That means that the culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>, with all
its grace and skill, brutality and bravado, will be exhibited by female
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>. It makes me wonder what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be saying if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
baseball became popular, and the commentariat was forced to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> chewing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tobacco</ENAMEX> and grabbing their crotches.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad Levinson</ENAMEX>
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>

            
               Don't Devaluate
Now
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> has been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time a very</TIMEX>
critical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>'s currency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>; he has suggested a devaluation
many times in the past. Almost at the end of his article (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>"), he says that
given that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> devaluation didn't bring hyperinflation, it could be
expected that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentinian</ENAMEX> devaluation wouldn't bring hyperinflation. He
concludes that from the fact that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have dismal economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">histories</ENAMEX>, but dismal doesn't mean the same. On the surface both countries
might look quite alike, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s reaction to inflation and economic
measures has proved to be very different, so we shouldn't expect to see both
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> reacting the same way.

            I deeply admire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX>, but if he wants to write
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> or any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, he should dedicate some time to
trying to understand what each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is like. They all might look the same,
but they are different; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very different and react in different ways.
Historically, what has been good for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>) has been a
disaster for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>, and this works the other way around. If he had
dedicated time to studying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>, he would have found out that Eduardo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duhalde</ENAMEX> is desperately trying to gain votes, relying on old clichés that he
expects will still be appealing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Argentinians</ENAMEX>, and trying to show how
different he is from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Menem</ENAMEX>--in part because he is different and in part
to avoid the opposition attack. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> would also have found out that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buenos Aires Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> is not representative of the way things are: Bonds
are important, and what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> are doing is important.

            I agree that we have a
regular recession and that the currency board prevents us from applying the
usual recipe, but it's not clear that it would work, and at this point breaking
the peso commitment would be extremely onerous. Right now we have a recession
and an increasing fiscal deficit (a comment on the virtues of keeping balanced
accounts would be very appropriate); if we devaluate, chances are we would also
have an inflation outburst, a rush against the banking system, and a capital
flight. When analyzing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argentina</ENAMEX>, it's important to keep in mind that since
we've been cheated many times, we have learned how to beat the system.

            -- María <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>
Segura
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Buenos</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aires</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argentina</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> replies:
                
               I was, of course, aware of the politics
that led to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duhalde</ENAMEX>'s remark. And in case this wasn't clear, the article did
NOT claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>'s currency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> is necessarily a foolish idea--only
that its downside could not be ignored. But I will say this: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> should always
be suspicious of arguments that claim that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is utterly different
from others. Yes, every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is unique--but not all that unique. Anyway,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few months ago</TIMEX> many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>--were
claiming that the contrast between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX> success and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> crisis meant
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> must emulate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>'s currency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>; you can't take that
position and then claim that the role reversal that has taken place since
doesn't teach a contrary lesson.
            

            
               Pilot Error
            

            I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX>' warning (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>") to
inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> who may know how to fly under good weather conditions, but
who haven't much under the belt on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a hazy night</TIMEX>. We all mourn the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX>, but at the same time, I will go beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX>' opinion and say
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s decision to fly on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a hazy night</TIMEX> in a new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-engine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> over
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is not risky--it's down right reckless . I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, and
if I knew that my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> were going up in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-engine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> who lacked sufficient experience, on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a hazy night</TIMEX> over the sea, I'd do
everything in my power to prevent it from happening. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> wants to take
that chance alone, fine, but once he allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, he has to be
responsible enough to make the right decision for not only himself but for
those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> as well.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>' safety is
the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> wasted his own life and the
lives of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young and beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> without thinking, This isn't worth
the risk , when he knew it could be dangerous under such conditions.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX> Shapiro
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodside</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Governer Bush</ENAMEX>, in
Deed
            

            Regarding "": I have been in the title insurance
business for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27 years</TIMEX>, and prior to that did my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s thesis on the field at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wharton</ENAMEX>.

            It is not true that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> must include a prior
set of restrictions in a deed when he sells his property. He may simply refuse
to include them. It is up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>'s title <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--to
discover them in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of title" and to determine if they have any legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> or effect.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did not have to do anything except direct that
the restrictions be omitted or stricken from the deed he granted to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>.
(The only circumstance in which he would need to seek the consent of other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landowners</ENAMEX> in the development would be if he wanted to petition to change the
restrictions or permit an exception to them.)

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> should have been fully aware of
the language in this instrument, which both he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> had to sign, and of
his legal prerogatives. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, he should have had the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decency</ENAMEX>, fortitude, and sensitivity to recognize the importance of refusing to
include these restrictions in his deed.

            Incidentally, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, the presence of a racial restriction in a set of deed
restrictions makes all the rest of that set of restrictions (e.g., as to the
maximum height of fences, the prohibition of nonsingle-family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX>, etc.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">null</ENAMEX> and void. (This was a result of a case involving the will of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Girard</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girard College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> that went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> in the
1960s and resulted in a landmark decision.)

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lancaster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
