
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peddling Pedophilia</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, APA: Take
Your Licks
            

            I can grant the dysfunction of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> over
is being uncharacteristically soft on what is, after all, a marked instance of
using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> doublespeak to avoid taking responsibility (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>"). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> is not
fessing up, and it should.

            You claim that the target article is indeed a
deserving target, but you don't take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX>'s culpability in publishing it.
In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, it was a peer-reviewed article, so at least three
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, in addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, felt that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> included both legitimate empirical research and a reasonable
theoretical construct. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> place, if, as you seem to suggest in your
"it was a dead letter" argument, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> publishes articles that are not read,
mean nothing, and clearly won't be taken seriously, isn't that a striking
indictment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX>'s publishing pretensions? If it wants the articles it
publishes to be taken seriously, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> should take criticisms of
those articles seriously, and so should you.

            You are not reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX>'s statement on this
with your normal discernment. You write:"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> distanced itself from the
study, noting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>'s long record of fighting pedophilia and
insisting that the article does not mitigate the illegality and immorality of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pedophilia</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX>'s historical position on sexual abuse is perfectly
irrelevant in assessing the meaning and claims of the target article. Critics
of the article want to talk about what the article actually says, not about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX>'s historical position.

            Presumably, the APA
wants the articles it publishes to be taken seriously. Presumably, if the APA
thinks that reconceptualizing adult-child sexual contact so that some instances
of it are no longer thought of as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">constituting</ENAMEX> abuse is simply a mistake, then
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> can come right out and say so. That the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> has conspicuously failed to
do so is a major factor in motivating ongoing concern about the article.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Graves</ENAMEX>
            

            Spring
Green, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>

            
               Free
Suicide!
            

            I take exception to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus Sanai</ENAMEX>'s assertion (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>") that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oregonians</ENAMEX>, as seen by the actions of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX>, are unintentionally "bribing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go early" in order to save
our precious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Medicaid</ENAMEX> dollars. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanai</ENAMEX> fails to mention the methodology
that is employed in determining which medical treatments will be covered.
Specifically, it is not mentioned in the piece how preventable ailments receive
a lower ranking, regardless of cost. In fact, it seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanai</ENAMEX> wishes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> to believe that this list was arbitrarily constructed. Nothing could be
further from the truth.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
Chinburg
            

            
Keizer, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>

            
               Cracks in the
Façade
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>'s image of
the standard old public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>") seems to be derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mayan</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roman Coliseum</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cathedral</ENAMEX>. A little checking might persuade you that these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> were by no
means the norm in the long lost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Age</ENAMEX> of public construction. By
definition, you know of them because they survived. A much larger number of
structures put up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more years ago</TIMEX> did not survive. The ruins or
the disappeared outnumber the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several thousand</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> were abandoned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, would the survival rate of our public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
be better or worse? I am not as certain as you are.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
Burtless
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               Turn Down Those
Stereotypes
            

            When you asked "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX>
Star <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wars Racist?</ENAMEX>" (see ""), it caught my attention. I don't see much of
a need to accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lucas</ENAMEX> of being racist. While I am fully aware of the
stereotypes you pointed out and agree with you to a point, I didn't pay
attention to them until you brought it up. I have always felt that racism would
eventually disappear if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you would just drop it instead of making an
issue out of it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Curts</ENAMEX>
            

            
Monrovia, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
