
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> Don't Kill Baptists

            

               A 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gunman</ENAMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>, a "loner" with no criminal record, yelled
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> rhetoric as he opened fire at a youth worship service. He then
killed himself. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 
               criticized congressional inaction on gun control in
the wake of recent shootings. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> countered that the
killings were "a wave of evil" that legislation could not stop.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX> drenched the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>. It came ashore in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, causing floods and power outages throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX>, then
avoided major damage. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> spin: We're going to get hammered.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> spin: OK, we didn't get hammered, but we got really wet.
(
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> the weather reporting
industry.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> refused to disclose details of his
administration's deliberations over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican clemency</ENAMEX>. Citing executive
privilege, he denied congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' request for records relating to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s release of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> imprisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> played politics with clemency and is trying to cover it up. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is playing politics with investigations and is
harassing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Auto Workers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DaimlerChrysler</ENAMEX> tentatively agreed to a new
contract. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> deal is believed to include a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> wage
increase and a guarantee that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will not block unionization of
additional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. It must still be approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DaimlerChrysler</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75,000</NUMEX> union
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> had argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> deserved to share in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automakers</ENAMEX>'
record-breaking profits. Industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> suggested that even with the
wage increases, labor costs per car will decline due to efficiency
gains.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> passed campaign finance reform. The bill, which was
opposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, would ban unregulated "soft money"
donations and curb "issue ads" by advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> may eliminate
the issue ad provision to overcome a promised filibuster. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> say the change will call the bluff of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who had objected to the bill on free speech grounds. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> say that without additional limits on labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>' political
expenditures, the revised bill remains unfair.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> is sending peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to East
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> will provide most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has promised limited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> involvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesia</ENAMEX> said its
military would withdraw as international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> arrive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
hopes to restore peace and bring back <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. Others foresee a bloody conflict with
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and militia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who are part of a nationalist
backlash against intervention. (
                  Slate
               's  "" explores
the prospects for intervention.)

            

               Another bombing rocked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> explosion in two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, bringing the death toll to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 300</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, who suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Caucasus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> in the bombings, are sweeping the country
and interrogating darker-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> says his
government has "the strength and resources to wipe out terrorism." But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> are questioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s ability to govern in the wake of the
crisis, speculating that he may: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) resign within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) fire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>) delay parliamentary elections.

            

               Major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> unveiled service improvement plans. The
voluntary changes were offered as an alternative to proposed "passenger rights"
legislation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX> claim their initiatives will greatly improve
baggage handling, ticket refunds, and information on flight delays.
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say the plans are legal "gobbledygook" offering no new protections to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> may run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>.
Despite pleas from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to remain loyal, he's becoming increasingly
vocal about his frustrations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>. Pundits variously
characterized the likely move as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) politically astute, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> would
gain a platform for his views; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a sign of desperation, given his poor
performance in the polls; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) misguided, since a three-way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> would hurt
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> that
the move would be good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> documents show that the use of incendiary tear gas at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> was
disclosed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Records</ENAMEX> indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> received files detailing the devices used in the raid much earlier
than previously thought. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Danforth</ENAMEX> agreed to head an
independent investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> in response to suspicions of a cover-up.
Pundits debated who was more damaged by the new information: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who cried "cover-up" while the information was under their noses;
or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>, who was unaware of her own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s reports.

         
      
   
