
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart of Glass</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Northwest</ENAMEX>'s distinguishing feature isn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> or money or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>. It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX> . Not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Chihuly</ENAMEX>." Not "glass
art by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Chihuly</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX> is all you need to say, whether you're
talking about a particular glass piece ("a Chihuly") or evoking the movement,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, the aesthetic, and the regional identity epitomized by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>'s (and the glass world's) most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. Not since Bernini
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">decked Rome</ENAMEX> with fountains, or at least not since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyeths</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>'s
official art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, has an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> so exemplified the spirit of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or
region--and it took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyeths</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX>'s work doesn't say
anything outright about us, but he's the best mirror we've got for divining
what we've come to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            A little background, with apologies to anyone who
lives here and already knows it all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Chihuly</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> who
gets most of the credit for elevating glass blowing from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> to a
bona fide--and wildly popular and lucrative--art form. He grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacoma</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s soporific little-sister <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, and headed first back <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>, and then to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, to study in the emerging studio glass movement. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, on a tree farm
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north of Seattle</ENAMEX>, he founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilchuck Glass School</ENAMEX>, which made that
movement an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> even as he turned it into an industry.

            Try as we may, we can't
escape the glass <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chihuly</ENAMEX> makes (or rather, has others make): the lurid
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Venetians</ENAMEX>," writhing "sea forms," and extravagant, candleless "chandeliers"
resembling giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wasps</ENAMEX>' nests or clusters of water-filled condoms. The loftiest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">galleries</ENAMEX> and living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> out here have their Chihuly bowls; the crasser
tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries stock copycats</ENAMEX>. To gain "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> credibility," the apartment
set in the sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frasier</ENAMEX> sprouted one. No new cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> or
festival shopping experience is complete without a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX> (click if you think
I'm exaggerating). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s new symphony hall boasts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> Chihuly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chandeliers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chihuly</ENAMEX> himself is just as much a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fixture</ENAMEX> as his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihulys</ENAMEX>,
especially in of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Times</ENAMEX> ' gossip column. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sample</ENAMEX>: "While a
tour of the [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chihuly</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> is standard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX> did it one
better. He tried his hand ... at glass blowing.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Opera</ENAMEX>
commissioned a set (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mylar</ENAMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chihuly</ENAMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da Vinci</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tut</ENAMEX>
have topped the attendance record set by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Art Museum</ENAMEX>. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> project <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Allen</ENAMEX> picked for his new film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was a study of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>' inspirations, including ... you guessed it. But the ultimate
confirmation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX>'s stature is the lottery hometown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> stage to mock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>-struck provincialism and celebrity fawning: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> gets to
"smash a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX>."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> still lags
behind its erstwhile rival <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacoma</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chihuly</ENAMEX>-mania. For <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> is a last
chance at world stature. Its grandest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landmark</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Neo-Baroque Union Station</ENAMEX>,
has been renovated and reopened as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX> showcase, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of all
chandeliers in its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">atrium</ENAMEX> and more big pieces scattered around. This is just
the warm-up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Glass Museum</ENAMEX> (originally the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly Glass</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>") being built on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacoma</ENAMEX>'s waterfront, reached by a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">474-foot</NUMEX> "Chihuly
Bridge of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacoma</ENAMEX>'s captains of industry and finance all ponied up for
it. As one of them told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , "Every downtown needs a niche."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX> is the natural choice for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacoma</ENAMEX> and not just
because he's a native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. His is the perfect art for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wannabes</ENAMEX>, new
money, and self-conscious arrivistes . In other words, perfect for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">precociously</ENAMEX> wealthy, culturally callow <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Northwest</ENAMEX>. Glass has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>
seal of approval, but it's supremely and (as practiced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX>) almost
purely decorative--blissfully unburdened with threatening, ambiguous, or other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meanings</ENAMEX>. "You don't have to be smart or art-historically sophisticated to
understand these," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX>'s assistant explains in one of several
documentaries on him by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s public TV station. "They're merely
beautiful." Forget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy</ENAMEX> and her gloomy paintings; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>, shimmering and
vacant, is the ideal TV art, a match for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverdance</ENAMEX> and the tenors.

            Glass also suits a money-drunk,
technology-intoxicated place like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>. It's showy and luxurious, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glittery</ENAMEX> as jewelry and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> times bigger. It's hard, slick and,
literally, edgy. At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX> taps an earlier, earthier ecotopic
sensibility. His forms evoke not only phalli and vaginas but sea squirts and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anemones</ENAMEX>--the marine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biosphere</ENAMEX> that sustained the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwesterners</ENAMEX>, which
we still delude ourselves into thinking we're sustaining. His "baskets" mimic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> basketry outright. The implicit, if wishful, message: We can
have our machines and money and preserve the wild, unspoiled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>.

            But beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chihulys</ENAMEX>
are just part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chihuly</ENAMEX> phenomenon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chihuly</ENAMEX> himself is the main show. With
his rampant curls, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bluff growl</ENAMEX>, black eye patch, and bright-colored pirate
shirts and scarves, he's the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX> to geek chic, a year-round version of
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seafair Pirates</ENAMEX>" who frolic at our big <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">parade</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> for the
new buccaneer capitalism, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jester</ENAMEX> who amuses (but never challenges) the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX>. He reprises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> as courtier, standing like a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> onstage when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> visits, partying on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Allen</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yacht</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candice Bergen</ENAMEX> and, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> hosted his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CEO Summit</ENAMEX>, the world's most
celebrated gathering of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX>, who provided the entertainment? The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philharmonic</ENAMEX> and, with "an exhibition of glass-blowing art," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Chihuly</ENAMEX>.

            Not that he blows glass himself, though he still says
things like this, from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chihuly Baskets :</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> blowing is
a very spontaneous medium, and its suits me. ... I've been at it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and am as infatuated as when I blew my first bubble." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX> hasn't
actually blown since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, when an auto accident cost him an eye and his depth
perception--and made his career. He acquired the trademark dashing eye patch,
without which he'd be just another chubby little guy with frizzy hair. And he
hired other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>, to blow more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> than he
could alone--enough to make him the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christo</ENAMEX> of glass, decking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> streams
and (you've gotta admire the chutzpah) Venetian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canals</ENAMEX> with bright globes and
tubes.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eye-Patched One</ENAMEX> has
gone far, and so has this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. How far? Consider the other time, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago</TIMEX>,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> had a distinctive, defining artistic tradition--and not one but
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity artists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris Graves</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Tobey</ENAMEX>, and others in the generation
later dubbed "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX>" drank deep of both the drizzly, mossy
natural scene and of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> art and philosophy. Tobey sketched spinach hawkers
and bums at the downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pike</ENAMEX> Place <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Market</ENAMEX> and was sometimes mistaken
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Graves hid out in the deep woods. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobey</ENAMEX> painted calligraphic "white
paintings" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> bodhisattva <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, in delicate gouache and pastel--media
notably unsuited to large atriums. Today these seem as quaint as hand-bound
books or handwritten letters.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chihuly</ENAMEX> succeeds because he's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of art in
the usual sense; he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, ringmaster, and impresario--and, above all, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>. No one expects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> to do the production work. No one
argues anymore over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is really a techie or worries about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bezos</ENAMEX>' literary taste. And no one cares whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX> blows glass.

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s software, bookselling, and coffee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tycoons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chihuly</ENAMEX> has triumphed by marketing and branding the hell out of his
product, elevating it to something at once precious and ubiquitous. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> trick is not so much to create something out of nothing as making
something very large out of something small, and then repeating the process. A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred million</NUMEX> PCs, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> "personalized" book and CD sales, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a zillion</NUMEX> cups
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> ... or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of chandeliers made of brittle blades of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>. Which
is, after all, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just melted</NUMEX> silicon.

         
      
   
