
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Disordered</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note: Some of the letters below originally
appeared in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> feedback forum.
            

            
               Who's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deliriously</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mean-Spirited</ENAMEX>?
            

            Your review of my book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diana in Search of</ENAMEX>
Herself was so confusing that I scarcely know how to respond (see the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> "" posting). Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> asserts in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence that it was
"deliriously mean-spirited"--a surprising statement, given that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> among others have
remarked on the even-handedness of my book. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX> is
herself "deliriously mean-spirited," and I resent the fact that she relies on
material from my book in an effort to make her arguments.

            Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> assesses the book in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> other
place, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> suffered "from what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> dubiously diagnoses as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">borderline</ENAMEX> personality disorder." The review promptly lists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> psychological
problems that plagued <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, all of which are common in those afflicted with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">borderline</ENAMEX> personality disorder. For the record, I used the term as a framework
for understanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>--in particular how its symptoms interacted to produce
the chaotic behavior that so many close to her witnessed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. I
emphasized that while I couldn't say with certainty that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> had the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disorder</ENAMEX>, the evidence (as presented throughout the previous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">363</NUMEX> pages) was
compelling. As it happens, a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> have approached me since
the book's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was a classic borderline.

            I suppose that I should
be flattered that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> meatiest paragraphs (of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>) in the review were
drawn entirely from my biography. But as someone who read a vast amount of what
had been written about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, conducted 150 interviews (many with her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intimates</ENAMEX>), and included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> pages of detailed footnotes, I find it dismaying
that 
                  Slate
                would run such a disingenuous review.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Bedell Smith</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Sucking Up to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Boss</ENAMEX>
            

            "" always makes for interesting reading; whether or
not it really gets anyone to give (besides maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>) is open to
question, but I'm sure it can't hurt. At least it's better than trying to rank
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>.

            I have a question about that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$225 million</NUMEX> gift that
heads the list, though. As far as I can see, the gift was made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Gates Foundation</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateses</ENAMEX> themselves. Obviously, most (all?) of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>'s assets have come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateses</ENAMEX>, and I don't want to
diminish the generosity of surrendering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 billion</NUMEX> for the public good. But
strictly speaking, there doesn't seem to be any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> on The

                  Slate
                60 list, nor are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Carnegie</ENAMEX>, or the very
living <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Annenberg</ENAMEX> listed. (In truth, I don't know how much the Annenberg
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> gave away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last quarter</TIMEX>, but let's pro-rate its annual giving and
guess that it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $25 million</NUMEX>, based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>'s figures. Here is the
summary if you want to look it up.)

            In fact, if I understand the rules, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 billion</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> will have to give away <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly $170 million</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">quarter</NUMEX> and, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s market and economy, ought to have considerably more than that to spend,
even after hedging against inflation. Aside from the occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombshell</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateses</ENAMEX> seem to have just about guaranteed themselves the top
slot on The 
                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> for the rest of their lives, even if they
never give another nickel away.

            As I said, I don't want to suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>
isn't a generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> nor even that his giving doesn't represent considerable
sacrifice on his part (though it must be nice to be able to give that kind of
money away). But as this edition is constituted, it looks an awful lot like
sucking up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>.

            (Of course, if it helps
keep you in business, by all means carry on.)

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Hammett</ENAMEX>
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann Castle</ENAMEX>
replies:
                
               You're right that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-of-the-list gifts come from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Gates Foundation</ENAMEX>. The funds in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> were given by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> themselves, so they meet our criteria as gifts from living
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateses</ENAMEX> use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> as their giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>,
as do some others on the list.
            

            
               You mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Carnegie</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Annenberg</ENAMEX> as examples of foundation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> who are not on the list.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX> are easy to explain--they are no longer living, and we
decided to list family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> gifts only when one of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> is
still alive.
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annenbergs</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leonore</ENAMEX>--have
appeared on the list previously. But, according to a cursory search done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annenberg Foundation</ENAMEX> announced gifts totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.78 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX>, a
total that under our terms would not have met the minimum for the second
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter of 1999</TIMEX>. This total was composed of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> gifts ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150,000</NUMEX>.
            

            
               Our method looks for single large gifts. There's
nothing sacred about that technique; others have ranked cumulative giving over
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX>, etc. We count pledges as well as paid gifts. I look for gifts
announced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> or the recipient as gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>--that's why
you saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> name appear for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Slate</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this quarter</TIMEX>. I also search for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and have set
an arbitrary minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>.
            

            
               We don't list gifts that we can't verify. A gift
was announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James E. Beasley</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple University Law</ENAMEX>
School as "the largest endowment in the history of [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>]" to the law
school, which has been named the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James E. Beasley School of Law</ENAMEX> in his honor.
We couldn't verify any amount, so this gift was not included in The
Slate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>, although it almost certainly would have qualified.
            

            
               Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make all their gifts through their
foundations; others do a portion of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropy</ENAMEX> that way. Some give at a
particular time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>; others spread it out. Many of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> making
announced large gifts also give anonymously, and I don't try to ferret those
out. Our goal is to celebrate both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, so we list gifts as
they are made out of a foundation to a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonprofit</ENAMEX>. That's why the
Gateses were not credited with the even larger amount that was announced in all
the papers: If we recognize them for the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> they put into their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX>, then we can't recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that receive that money
down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> or we'd be double-counting.
            

            
               The fact is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateses</ENAMEX> now have created the largest personal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
and will probably continue to make the top or near the top of the list.
However, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX> noted in , there are plenty of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there
who could meet and exceed their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> running total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$255 million</NUMEX> and not even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wince</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lager Heads</ENAMEX>
            

            Don't get me wrong. I vastly enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX>'
deep, probing piece on blind beer tasting (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>"). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallows</ENAMEX> does perpetuate a
few common mistakes that should be cleared up.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lagers</ENAMEX> are the light-colored, relatively
lightly flavored brews that make up most of the vattage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> consumption in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s success could reflect its
quasi-mislabeling, presenting a strong-flavored <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'lager</NUMEX>.' "

            Both of these statements are incorrect in their
definition of "lager." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lager</ENAMEX> is one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, the other
being <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ale</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> come in all varieties of flavors, strengths, and colors,
from the pale, crisp <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pilsener</ENAMEX> (what most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> are modeled on, albeit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weakly</ENAMEX>) to thick, deep brown, rich, strong (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.5 percent</NUMEX>) "doppelbocks." What
defines a beer as lager is its method of fermentation: at cool temperatures,
using a specific type of "lager" <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX>, with an extended cold maturation
period. Ales, on the other hand, tend to experience warm, rapid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fermentations</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> is a lager
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> that happens to be brewed in a slightly fuller-flavored style, something
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">akin</ENAMEX> (perhaps) to mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s and '50s</TIMEX>. But it is as
much a lager as any of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX>' tasting.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Myers</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX>, Best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Beers</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Boy</ENAMEX>
Scout
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Wheatcroft</ENAMEX>'s article "" portrays all adult
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout leaders</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pedophiles</ENAMEX> who are involved with scouts for nothing more than
a steady diet of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. How tragic that this is the legacy that our
prurient minds attach to one of the finest civic-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>.

            I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> throughout my childhood <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. I
attained the rank of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>, and never once did I feel as though I was in danger
of being molested, attacked, leered at, or otherwise harassed by an adult
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who were adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> while I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout</ENAMEX> were in many ways
more influential on my life than my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were. To lump these pillars of
respectability in my life and in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> with the few bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> that slip
through the cracks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is a grave disservice to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who willingly give their evenings, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>, and dollars to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> whose core goal is to mold impressionable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> into upstanding,
moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            In the future, please
research a story more before sniggering and laughing at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a scout
uniform ... he's trying to make his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> into better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>,
something that articles like yours will never do.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Maly</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cedar Rapids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
