
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> on the Web

            By their Web sites ye
shall know them. The presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have staked their places on the
Web to raise money, to distribute speeches and position papers, and to show off
their cybersavvy. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are better than others. Here's a quick guide.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>  
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> pitches himself as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer disdainful</ENAMEX> of big money. The site even offers a copy of his personal
financial disclosure statement. However, you'll soon discover that clicking
around the site causes an unsolicited "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Make a Contribution</ENAMEX>" box to pop up
repeatedly on your screen.

            

               Bottom line: Large, confident, and dull
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
            

            Lest anyone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sex life, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> you can click to from any
page are "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gore Family</ENAMEX> " and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tipper</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> ." And while other sites gloss over the legal rules for giving
money, this
contribution form requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to check boxes stating, "I am not a
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national</ENAMEX> who lacks permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> status in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>" and
"The funds I am contributing are my own personal funds and not those of
another."

            

               Bottom line: Cybersprawl
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s site lets you
pledge to write a check but, unlike other sites, doesn't let you use your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> card online. There's also an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Online Internship</ENAMEX>
Application ," which offers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> experience in "correspondence,
grassroots <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, volunteer coordination, fundraising, events planning
and coordination, and media events." Hurry--the deadline for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> term is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 6</TIMEX>.

            

               Bottom line: Low-tech, high dudgeon
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
            

            This site takes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">personalization</ENAMEX> to the next level, asking for information in
return for an individualized pitch. An "Issues " page focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s favorite topics, such as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX>-Based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initiatives</ENAMEX> ." The "En
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Español</ENAMEX>" section offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> pages in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>, including this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> , which touts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s corazón y
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visión</ENAMEX> . An audio message of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> communicates directly to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. The "Youth Zone " explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s view of politics--it's
just like baseball! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are leagues, the primaries are playoffs, and
the general election is the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>.

            

               Bottom line: Prosperity with a surface.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Forbes</ENAMEX>
            

            Calls itself "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> full-scale Internet campaign" and is by far the most technically
sophisticated site, with an array of slide shows, videos, and a "personal control panel " that repackages his position
papers, speeches, and press releases as links from an icon symbolic of
high-tech, individual empowerment.

            

               Bottom line: The gold standard
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
Hatch
            

            Uncharacteristically hip
in appearance, the home page features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> silhouetted against a black
background. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> are encouraged to stuff virtual ballot boxes by a
vote
online page, which links to Internet polls. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">links</ENAMEX> invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> to write <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and create the illusion of a
groundswell for their favorite dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatch Toons</ENAMEX> attack the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>: A cartoon of a wayward youth smoking something quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>'
impression that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is "presidential material. ... If we can just hang on
'til he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>."

            

               Bottom <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Line : Spare and strange</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
Keyes
            

            The site is utterly
disorganized but lovingly maintained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>' acolytes. Its audio and
transcript archive of his speeches and radio shows is amazing.

            

               Bottom line: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grassroots</ENAMEX> 
               fire and brimstone
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">McCain</ENAMEX>
            

            A special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exposes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s server as the largest single source of visitors
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s site and offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubya</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> should browse (Reason
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: to contribute). A link to a campaign-finance
petition underscores <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s reformist position. His "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign Store</ENAMEX>" offers
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Official Campaign Material</ENAMEX>" that "may be ordered for a small contribution." A
biographical video costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clicking</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> on the Issues"
takes you not to his position papers (which requires a further click) but to
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> Poll," which invites you to weigh in on a rigged question. Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is presumably too principled to change his mind based on this "poll," it
seems to be a participation device for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible</ENAMEX>.

            

               Bottom line: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curious George</ENAMEX> gets caught
            

            

               Reform
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Buchanan</ENAMEX>
            

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> switched
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, he also switched his Web site and logo. For a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, he's
surprisingly upfront about his pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plank</ENAMEX>, though "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cleaning Corruption Out of Government</ENAMEX> " is (more suitably) his
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> issue. His new book, which prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> to call him soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, is proudly displayed on his home page, so you can judge it for
yourself (but first you'll have to buy it). The low-tech site lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peasant army</ENAMEX> contribute , join an
e-mail list, and browse speeches, press releases, and policy statements.

            

               Bottom line: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peasants</ENAMEX> with PCs
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Trump</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> page calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trump</ENAMEX>
"the experienced, decisive can-do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America</ENAMEX> needs as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>." The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Can I Help Donald?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX> claims "you can convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX> to
run" by giving him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> or more. Every page ends with a prominent link to a
donation solicitation. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">People Are</ENAMEX>
Talking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> " button takes you to the comments of great thinkers
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Adams</ENAMEX>. And check out his bio :
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald J. Trump</ENAMEX> is the very definition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> success story,
continually setting the standards of excellence. … He is the archetypal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>--a deal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> without peer."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bottom Line</ENAMEX>: Too autoerotic for underage viewing
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Libertarians</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Browne</ENAMEX>
            

            When you enter the site, a
pot leaf signifying medical marijuana pops up on your screen. If you click the
link to join <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browne</ENAMEX>'s exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> , you get a form that
begins, "Due to the complexity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> regulations, we are unable to accept
on-line donations at this time." If you click "Join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian Party</ENAMEX>,"
you're required to check a box affirming that you "do not believe in or
advocate the initiation of force as a means of achieving political or social
goals"--just to make sure you're not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim McVeigh</ENAMEX>.

            

               Bottom line: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild, Wild</ENAMEX> Web
            

            

               Unannounced
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Beatty</ENAMEX>
            

            A pretty logo with
literally nothing behind it.

            

               Bottom line: Inauspicious metaphor
            

            
               Criticism and
Parody
            

            
               All <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
            

            Clever parody site that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">captures Gore</ENAMEX>'s ticks and shticks. Headline on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goretopia</ENAMEX>" page:
"Envisioning a post-present future for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> that will follow the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s generation." The "Socialized
Medicine" page exults, "New treatments are slowing the development of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">acne</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> also vows to "give each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> a talking Chihuahua" and "reduce class sizes to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>."

            

               Bottom line: If only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> had such a light touch
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bore 2000</ENAMEX>
            

            The graphics bear an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uncanny</ENAMEX> (and possibly actionable) resemblance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s official site, but the
content is weak. All jokes, all secondhand. Includes a "Bulletin
Bored."

            

               Bottom line: Stiffer than its subject
            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
Watch
               
            

            A serious site, light on
graphics but heavy on content, with links to dozens of articles scrutinizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and several plugs for itself from major news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. Calls itself
"a non-advocacy site" and claims to be the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">First George W. Bush Site</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>."

            

               Bottom line: Opposition research headquarters
            

            
               GWBush
            

            Excellent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libertarian</ENAMEX>-oriented, anti-drug-war site. Its theme is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hypocrisy with</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bravado</ENAMEX>." A stamp on the home page boasts, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRUG-FREE</ENAMEX> SINCE <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>." A mock
press
release has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> promising "to raise the age at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> can be
tried as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> ... to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 40</TIMEX>." Best joke: Every picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> includes a
digitally-added white streak under his nose.

            
               Bottom line: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best</ENAMEX>
parody site of the campaign
            

         
      
   
