
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cocaine Question</ENAMEX>

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Clymer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>,
responding in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> to a question about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long-ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> abuse, had issued
"another awkward answer" of the sort that had "made the issue linger." A
Times "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Watch</ENAMEX>" story noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s previous answers had
obviously failed to "end the questioning." What both articles neglected to
mention was who had asked the question in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Clymer</ENAMEX>.

            This
practice of self-concealment, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> pass off as "objectivity," is one
of the great frauds of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism. While many "opinion" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> argue
openly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> question is legitimate--pointing out, for example, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has jailed drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have investigated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sex life--most "news" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> pretend that the question is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immaculately</ENAMEX> conceived and needs no justification. Reluctant to become "part of
the story," news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> press the question while obscuring their complicity
in keeping it alive. Instead, they tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that the question is "dogging"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. Nonsense. Questions don't dog <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters dog politicians</ENAMEX>. And
while they're dogging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, they ought to account for dodging a few questions
of their own.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Who's asking 
               the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> question? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX>
pretend that the question drives itself. It "hounds," "haunts," and "stalks"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. It "percolates," "persists," and "swirls around" him. It is "turbulence,"
a "storm," a "blizzard." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stacks</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who has led the drug
frenzy, said the question has "a kind of organic life." "These things take on a
life of their own," agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Balz</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . "It followed
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>] from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the question that will not go away," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Williams</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. "The questions would not go away,"
agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bloom</ENAMEX>. And who, exactly, had followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and
asked him the question <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bloom</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Who's judging 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s answers? Not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. They
don't evaluate the merits of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s remarks. They just assess whether
the remarks will succeed or fail politically. Rather than treat the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>
inquiry as a dialogue in which the questions as well as the answers are subject
to rational scrutiny, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> depict it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of nature. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
replies have failed to "douse the questions," "dampen the controversy," or
"turn down the heat." On the contrary, they have "stoked a brush fire," "fed
the story," and given it "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX>," with "the automatic and absolutely
inevitable effect of keeping it going." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> are just part of this
"automatic" cycle. They're not hurting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. He's hurting himself.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Why is the 
               press pursuing him? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> who
acknowledge their role in the assault seldom offer a reason. They say they're
just doing what comes naturally, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is to blame for provoking them. His
answers "opened the door," "courted scrutiny," and "encouraged" more questions.
"His not answering it is just like waving red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">carnivores</ENAMEX>,"
argued <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Feeney</ENAMEX> of the frenzy-leading <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> . "It's
inevitable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> will push until there's an answer." On Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning America</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Gibson</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, "You know
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s answers] won't push the questions away, and he'll get them
again and again." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. What's wrong 
               with his answers? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> who admit
to judging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s answers generally accuse him of "shifting," "backpedaling,"
"altering," and "reversing." And what exactly did he reverse? He "reversed his
stance of not going beyond acknowledging youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'mistakes</ENAMEX>,' " complained the
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> . "First it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>, then it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, then it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>." The complaint is not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> reversed his
story--there is no contradiction in being drug-free for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--but that he reversed his spin, obliging his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> to "defend the
change of strategy." Why concede a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s substantive consistency, when
you can attack his tactical vacillation?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Did he 
               use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>? Careful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> never infer
such impropriety. Instead, they posit the appearance of impropriety,
warning that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s answers "create an appearance at least that he has
something to hide" and "leave the implication" that he used hard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. His
assertion of "marital fidelity," according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , "only adds to
the impression that he is hiding something about other aspects of his life." By
confining their inferences to such "impressions," the media sidestep the
unpleasant duty of ascertaining the truth.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Is he 
               lying? Again, scrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> eschew this
question, focusing instead on public perception. Dowd, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> of the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Black</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "looks
like" and "sounds like" he's dissembling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> may have "created the impression with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that he is being cute or coy rather than forthcoming." Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>,
too scrupulous to characterize the public's perceptions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, quoted their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' perceptions of the public's perceptions. ("Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said ...
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> came off as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonesque</ENAMEX>," ventured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX>.)
Since the media decline to characterize the truth, perception is all that
matters. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inconsistencies</ENAMEX> and ambiguities, real or imagined, are to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>
as catnip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>," shrugged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> , justifying the
drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX>'s persistence.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Is the 
               controversy important? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> tend to ignore
this question, focusing instead on how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is "handling the crisis." "What
disturbed me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week</TIMEX> more was not even the fundamental issue, but it was
the handling of it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> agreed: "What should especially
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disturb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> is Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s political judgment. If there's bad news to
get out, Politics <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> says release it as early as possible." 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                called the controversy "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big public test of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s instincts and of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and the results were pretty wobbly." Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX>, too timid to endorse even this superficial assessment, reported
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>" and "top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>" were questioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "erratic handling
of the drug question" and warning that his "candidacy had been bruised by his
handling of the issue."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. What exactly 
               is the question? The media imply that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> keeps refusing to say whether he has used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>. But that's not how the
question has generally been posed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this two-week</TIMEX> frenzy. The first
version, crafted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowland</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>, was: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sir</ENAMEX>, is it not in your interest to tell us flatly if these
rumors are or are not true? ... Everybody says--every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>--[that] it's
to your disadvantage not to answer it." The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> version, posed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, was whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> thought rumors of his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> use were "being
planted." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> version, posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , was: "How can you make
questions about whether you used illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> go away? Won't
they dog your campaign until you answer?" As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s inquisitors focus less on
the truth and more on politics, the inquisition becomes self-justifying.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> are happy to exploit and hide behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s
pseudo-objectivity. While defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "privacy," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>
stipulated that "it is the media and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who decide what
questions should be asked." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> agreed: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX> feels the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> don't determine what is the statute of limitations on questions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and committing a felony. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the press do." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> called the drug story a "side show" but added that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s wounds were
"self-inflicted. ... The general principle is that these questions,
unfortunately, are going to be asked." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> concluded, "I don't
think it's going to go away. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is going to beat it to death until
he finally has to just say one way or the other."

            It's
hard to feel sorry for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, given his preposterous spins on the question. He
says he's stonewalling it because divulging past drug abuse "sends bad signals
to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surrogates</ENAMEX> claim that he's leading a "heroic" effort
"to purge the system of this 'gotcha' politics." He's making himself a
"positive role model" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and displaying the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>" for which "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are hungering." "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the line of
fire who's had the guts to stand up and say, 'I'm not going to play by the old
rules anymore,' " former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX> boasted on television this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, chastised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> for
failing to "show the same courage that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> has shown" by "taking a stand"
against "personal destruction." Comments like these make you wonder not whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> ever used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, but whether they ever stopped.

            The
point is not that the question is unfair. The point is that the power to choose
and craft questions is more profound than the power to choose and craft
answers--and with that power goes responsibility. When the question is as
controversial as the answer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who report the exact answer and who
said it ought to report the exact question and who asked it. And if it's their
question, they ought to justify it. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor Jr.</ENAMEX> spends an entire
column proposing and defending a better question than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
so far: "Would you seek long prison terms for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-olds</TIMEX> for doing
what you say you may or may not have done as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--and when you now
suggest that whatever you did was a mere youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indiscretion</ENAMEX>, and thus
irrelevant to your candidacy<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" You can decide for yourself whether you like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s question--and that's the point. He has thought it through, spelled it
out, and told you who's asking it and why.

            The
same can't be said for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . In its editorial on the
cocaine controversy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "to be honest, and to let
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> take his measure. In his campaign, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> has emphasized the
importance of assuming responsibility for one's own actions. He should be
thinking now about how to set a good example." So should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
