
   
   
      
         
             When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Things Happen to Bad Ideas</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX>, I was looking for something to
watch on television while I made dinner, and there was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Dobbs</ENAMEX>
introducing financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James K. Glassman</ENAMEX>, identifying him as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of Dow <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">36,000</NUMEX> (presumably a forthcoming book ). I immediately
switched to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">History Channel</ENAMEX>. But over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few days</TIMEX> I found myself
thinking, one might almost say brooding, about the sighting.

            You see, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX>--who has used such forums as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial
page to propound his view that the prospect of future earnings growth justifies
much higher stock prices than anything yet seen--participated in a

                  Slate
                "" about the subject. His sparring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clive Crook</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , a publication that has repeatedly asserted that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
stock prices are not only excessively high but dangerously so and that the
history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s notorious "bubble economy" is being repeated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, the
dialogue came to a sudden screeching halt when it became clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX>'s
views were based not on some at least debatable vision about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s economic
prospects but rather on a simple misunderstanding of corporate accounting (in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glassman</ENAMEX> was claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> can eat their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed corn</ENAMEX> and
plant it too). It is unclear from that exchange whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glassman</ENAMEX> understands
even now that his famous calculation involved naive double-counting--he
certainly did not concede any mistake--but an embarrassed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crook</ENAMEX> saw no point in
continuing the discussion.

            It isn't all that unusual a story. Indeed, it is quite
commonplace for influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to propound economic doctrines that are "not
even wrong," that is, that involve a basic conceptual or accounting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impossibility</ENAMEX>. But there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kicker</ENAMEX> in this case. Imagine a

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> who for some reason just could not grasp <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crook</ENAMEX>'s
point, who despite everything found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glassman</ENAMEX>'s position convincing. That reader
would presumably have invested heavily in the stock market--and profited
handsomely as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> rose from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 9,000</NUMEX> at the time of the dialogue to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 11,000</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, someone who did understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crook</ENAMEX>'s logic,
and who therefore understood why even the most optimistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have been
finding it increasingly hard to justify current stock valuations, might well
have shifted heavily into cash, perhaps even shorted the market, and would soon
have been gnashing his teeth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who had no idea what he was talking about
gave what turned out to be good advice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who made sense got the
prediction all wrong.

            How could such a thing
happen? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason is that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> the economic news, both at home and
abroad, has been better than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expected. But, anyway, stock prices
are at best very loosely related to fundamentals--if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe they are
going higher, they do, at least for a while. And so it is very easy for someone
who is completely wrong about the fundamentals to make a correct prediction
about the direction of stock prices, and conversely.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Glassman-Crook</ENAMEX> episode set me thinking, for it is
not the only recent case in which good things have happened to bad ideas. And
as you might guess, another major example involves yours truly--and the debate
over the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Paradigm</ENAMEX>.

            The basic idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
Paradigmatics was and is that the old speed limits on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economic growth have
been repealed. In the past, sustained growth at more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 2.5 percent</NUMEX>
eventually led to an overheated economy, one in which the pressure on scarce
capacity led to accelerating inflation. But according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> in a "new
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>," those constraints were a thing of the past: Because of rapid
productivity growth--much faster than the official statistics indicated--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">globalization</ENAMEX>, rapid growth would no longer lead to inflation.

            Now to anyone who was prepared to do a few thought
experiments, it was immediately apparent that this argument was logical
nonsense. As many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> (including me in a 
                  Slate
                ) tried to
explain, measured productivity and measured growth are constructed from the
same data. Even if there was an unmeasured acceleration in productivity, it
would not allow the GDP numbers published by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> to grow
any faster than before. And global economy or no global economy, a national
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> has a speed limit determined by the sum of labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and productivity
growth. And so, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>, when the measured rate of productivity
growth showed little sign of increasing, it was natural for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like me to
dismiss the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Paradigm</ENAMEX> argument as silly.

            The trouble is that since
then the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy has in fact grown rapidly, without any signs of inflation
until very recently. This performance has been made possible partly by an
acceleration of measured productivity growth, partly by the surprising
quiescence of wages, despite a very tight labor market; but the effect is that
those who believed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Paradigm</ENAMEX> feel vindicated, and those of us who
made fun of it have some explaining to do.

            To be fair, you can make a better case on behalf of the New
Paradigm than on behalf of the hapless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> may have
engaged in some garbled logic, they were nonetheless onto something--namely,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> were telling them tales of a "productivity revolution," and even if
the data didn't show any evidence of that revolution, they felt sure that
somehow growth was going to accelerate. They couldn't articulate their feelings
very well, and what they actually said didn't make any sense, but they were
nonetheless right in their sense that something new and good was happening to
the economy.

            Still, both cases show
that in the buzzing, blooming confusion that is the economy it is all too easy
for those who would make economic predictions to be right for the wrong
reasons, and conversely. Confused thinking does not necessarily lead to
disaster; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>-trap logic is no guarantee of success. Or to quote a :

            
                I returned, and saw under the sun, that
the race is not to the swift, nor the battle to the strong, neither yet bread
to the wise, nor yet riches to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of understanding, nor yet favour to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of
skill; but time and chance happeneth to them all.
            

            But there is also, I think, another moral. If being
smart is no guarantee of being right, having been right is not necessarily an
indicator that someone is smart. Suppose that you hear someone making what
sounds like a dumb argument, but you know that he has an impressive track
record at market or economic prediction. Guess what: The argument may be as
dumb as it sounds.

         
      
   
