
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999>The Decline of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX></SPAN></SPAN>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
            

            The
cover story
                predicts excitement from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
presidential race, if not from the selection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> then from their
stances on the economy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
opine that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> plan "does
nothing to address the underlying problems of rising health costs" and "is
simply endorsing a massive rise in government spending on health care."
... An article debunks the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> have always been
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fixture</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1850</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no more than a 10th</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
owned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. ... Another piece attributes the decline of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s media
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">empire</ENAMEX> to his belated entry into new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> and his alienation of the local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> on which his broadcasting deals depend. (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> and new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>, see ".")

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19 and 26</TIMEX>
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX> brags to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> will need his
blessing to win a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat. "How enthusiastic[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>] I would support
her would be based on how she respects and regards the new dynamics of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
politics," he hints cagily. ... A piece reviews growing scientific evidence that the
practice of religion promotes good health. Possible explanations: Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">religions advocate temperate lifestyles</ENAMEX>, and prayer encourages mental
well-being. The findings amount to "a health boon" and "a new argument for
taking faith seriously." ... The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB "</ENAMEX> column protests the "gross generational inequity" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> plan. Prescription drug coverage for the elderly
isn't nearly as pressing a need as education and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> nutrition.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story is an oral history of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX> told by film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> and family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. He comes across as a paranoid perfectionist. He required <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX> or more
takes on a single scene and once called an employee and demanded help while she
was in labor. ... An article explores the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patel Motel</ENAMEX> phenomenon: More
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> are owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> have the last name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patel</ENAMEX>, indicating that they belong to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>
merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcaste</ENAMEX>. Why? Motels are fairly easy to run and come with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>,
and many were for sale at the time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> began immigrating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> in large numbers. ... A grim piece profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevron</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Niger River</ENAMEX>. His job consists of
paying off tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> to prevent them from disrupting pumping operations. He
relies heavily on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> military muscle to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevron</ENAMEX>'s interests.

            

               
                  Vogue
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> heralds the return of curvy models. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> of fashion androgyny
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin chic</ENAMEX>, waifs and weird-looking "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>" are yielding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runway space</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">full-bodied Breckish</ENAMEX> beauties. Reasons for the zaftig vogue include the
mainstreaming of the hip-hop ideal of beauty and the popularity of curvaceous
actresses such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> testifies,
"They're no longer asking for stick legs. No one wants their butt removed."

            
               
                  Business
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story says that megabillionaire and
stock-picking legend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX> has quietly shifted his focus from buying
individual stocks to purchasing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Stocks have shrunk from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkshire Hathaway Inc.</ENAMEX>'s assets in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX> currently.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story purports to critically examine the hype
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surrounding Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> but really just adds to it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-stars <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX> are featured naked on the cover--"like
you've never seen them. " (Like you've never seen him , perhaps:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> put a naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kidman</ENAMEX> on the cover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.) Contrary to
previous reports, there is no necrophilia in the film, but there is an orgy.
... An article examines "cascading," the post-affirmative action
phenomenon in which minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> denied access to top-tier universities
attend lesser ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irvine</ENAMEX> claim they are
succeeding in a supportive atmosphere. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> worry that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
underestimate the importance of blue-chip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> credentials. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> wrote a nearly identical piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX>.)
... A "surprising" survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> ages <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6-14</ENAMEX> finds
that the overwhelming majority believes in God, pray, feel safe in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>,
admire their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, are in no hurry to grow up, and disapprove of premarital
sex.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story , while profiling several instant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> and
noting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> now get stock options, says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 60</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> feel they are missing their chance to prosper during the
high-tech boom and bull market. (For 
                  Slate
               's earlier
take on Internet envy click .) ... An article examines the latest hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dietary supplement</ENAMEX>: SAMe.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> trials and anecdotal evidence suggest the naturally occurring
substance can relieve depression, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, and liver disease without the
toxic side effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>. ... A photo essay vividly depicts the brutal rite of genital
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutilation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>. A circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> looks on as an "initiate"
lying on the ground has her clitoris removed with a razor blade.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story hails the "class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>" who graduated from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Point</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">456</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'39</NUMEX> played a vital role in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major
wars, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> ought to keep his distance
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>, according to an analysis . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> might be tarred by the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
fumbling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and budget battles. ... A piece mocks a law pushed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster</ENAMEX> requiring school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to say "sir" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ma'am</ENAMEX>" when addressing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>
            

            A
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>" item sourced to "some old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Family</ENAMEX>"
suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is considering running for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-president</ENAMEX> to serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX>, also
the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to be impeached. ... A piece warns
that Wall Street's blue-chip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> may be just as unstable as the infamous
hedge fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term Capital Management</ENAMEX>. Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are just as heavily
leveraged as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX> was, exposing them to staggeringly enormous potential
losses.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover
story blasts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>'s antitrust case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was snookered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> into assailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> for its
predatory conduct. But the evolution of the browser market belies the charge.
Contrary to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s predictions, the Internet has thrived, and bullying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> is part of the "creative destruction" that leads to marketplace
innovation. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> is alternately disagreeable and boring,
according to an article. The quixotic presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> refuses to answer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>' questions and even disagrees with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> when she introduces him
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> as "demure." ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> publishes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s Map
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. West of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retrograd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovaria</ENAMEX> borders
Fredonia, topped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souvlaki</ENAMEX>, which is adjacent to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insomnia</ENAMEX>, a neighbor of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Check Republic</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
