
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize Losers</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Recriminations</ENAMEX> flew <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> after the collapse, amid farce and bitterness, of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> peace agreement. They were directed primarily against
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hume</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-ruled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the left-wing tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mirror</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trimble</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>-designate
of a new devolved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> government (which was supposed to have been
formed, but wasn't, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s chaotic inaugural meeting of the provincial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>), should give his prize back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedes</ENAMEX>. By boycotting
the meeting, and thus provoking the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seamus Mallon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble</ENAMEX> "achieved the near-impossible" of making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, "look like a statesman," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> said
in an editorial.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Hume, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Social Democratic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX>, to which Mallon
belongs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who first brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> into the peace negotiations, also came
in for criticism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> reproached him for failing to
guarantee that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDLP</ENAMEX> would continue to govern the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionist Party</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> were expelled from the yet-to-be-created
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>. Under legislation rushed through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, this would happen if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>, with
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> is affiliated, were to persist in refusing to decommission its
secret hoard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> also reproached
Trimble for his failure "to take a risk for peace." "More was needed from this
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>," it said--and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX>, "More was needed from this
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> as well."

            
Writing on the editorial page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudley Edwards</ENAMEX>, a noted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ulster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX>, was
strong in her condemnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX>. "What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX> begged of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hume</ENAMEX>,
and what every moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionist</ENAMEX> wanted of him too, was that in the name
of democracy he would stand by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionist Party</ENAMEX> and refuse to sit in
government with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramilitaries</ENAMEX>," she wrote. "Had he
promised to exclude <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> without the beginning of decommissioning, he
could have saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Agreement</ENAMEX>. Instead, he played the tribal card. It will be
up to his future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX> to judge this great failure of statesmanship."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX> said it was "preposterous" to blame the debacle on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble</ENAMEX>, who,
defending himself in an op-ed article for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>,
wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionists</ENAMEX> have an undeserved reputation for saying "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">no.</ENAMEX>"
"We have said 'yes' to many things which would be countenanced in no other
democracy," he said--to "power-sharing with former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>" and to "a system
of allocating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> in the proposed Executive which would lead to an
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble</ENAMEX> pledged to continue the search
for a peace process because "the prize for success is large enough for us all
to put <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s setbacks behind us and to move forward." He has an
enthusiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> in the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
which said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that he deserved "the thanks of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> throughout the world" for his stand on the decommissioning issue.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, described in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers as sad and
fatigued, was also criticized over the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Friday agreement</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> suffers loss of credibility on Ulster" was an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-column headline in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> had carried off
a dramatic coup in negotiating the agreement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>--"he had the surest of
touches back then"--but that "now, as the truly historic deal lurches towards
the precipice, his own approach is increasingly confused and his credibility
damaged." The main charges against him are that he keeps inventing artificial
negotiating deadlines that aren't kept and that he "wavered wildly" in his
approach to the all-important decommissioning issue. Adding to his woes on the
worst day of his premiership, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Nazione</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florence</ENAMEX> published a letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the old-guard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> would not be welcome
on his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual holiday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>. "His 'warrior's stance' on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> crisis makes him distant from the feelings of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto</ENAMEX>
Pucci, who said there would be demonstrations against him.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press coverage of the crisis was generally pessimistic, with the
Times ' editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> finds itself once
again "at a melancholy crossroads under a lowering sky" and that its future is
now "a space colonised by fear." They qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>'s pledge to battle on for
peace with reports that he is privately deeply frustrated. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, by contrast, looked more hopefully ahead. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
Independent and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> led their front pages with the news that former
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX>, who chaired the peace negotiations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, has
been invited to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Downing Street</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> to discuss with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertie Ahern</ENAMEX> what role he might play in resumed peace efforts in the
fall.

            By a
strange coincidence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckingham Palace</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to receive an
honorary knighthood from the queen for his role in brokering the agreement.
"It's a day of irony," he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Independent</ENAMEX> afterward. "No-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
could have foreseen this would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> the process encountered this
difficulty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>." Meanwhile, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> on the front page of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> began his article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> experienced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX> of not making
history <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>."

         
      
   
