
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">304</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Hee, Hee, Hee&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               You give the lead,
I give the headline from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Mirror</ENAMEX> : "He's Huge, He's
Powerful, He's Fast and He's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mean</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Decline and Fall":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               "That was a miserable year, when I watched a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I love
more than life--you know, one of the really fundamentally solid, decent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--go from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">92 to 38</TIMEX> in a very quick period of time." Who watched whom go
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92 to 38</NUMEX> what?
            

            "Donny
Osmond, on a good Mormon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> divorces."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eunuch Li Ming</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pu-Yi</ENAMEX>'s approval rating in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>. Damn
that infernal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Yat</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">"</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lofquist</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Peck</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>'s moving up the list of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">All-Time Assholes</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
don't know, but in the metric system he would have gone from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 to 10</TIMEX>: Now,
really, isn't that a lot easier?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            
"During his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s primary campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> go
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1992 to 1938</TIMEX>, the heyday of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coughlin</ENAMEX>, dragging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>
with him. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is trying to prevent him from jumping <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>. Just
because you're repositioning yourself as compassionate, doesn't mean you want
to lose the wacko vote altogether."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> does
succeed in its takeover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX>, an unlikely event given that no such talks
are in progress or even contemplated, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz Action Figures</ENAMEX> will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hitting Toys</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>" Us just in time for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some annual</TIMEX> event traditionally cheapened
by ritualized gift-giving stripped of any genuine feeling. You know, for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, the senile old fool

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>, the self-deceiving, middle-aged dunce

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the horny hillbilly, and what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>!

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, the foxy grampaw--how comical are the erections of his withered old
penis!

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>, the indiscriminate erotic glutton; how often she has sex!

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who still owns slaves

               Flockhart, the brittle underweight neurotic, yet still somehow appealing,
in a tense yet vulnerable way

            

            Enjoy their adventures
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-SPANimation</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Poll-Tested</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> endured a
dark <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of the soul when he watched his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s approval rating fall from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92 to 38</NUMEX>.

            
               Beating a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Fish</ENAMEX>
Follow-Up
            

            "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout fishermen practice 'catch</ENAMEX> and release,'
although it is true that some still catch and eat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbaric</ENAMEX> isn't it? Almost as
bad as running <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> down a chute and hammering their brains out."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>
            

            (Actually, for my
weekend recreation, I practice "run them down a chute and hammer their brains
out and release." Right into my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s yard. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suckers</ENAMEX>!-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> .)

            
               Publishing Notes
Extra
            

            The cover of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paladin Press</ENAMEX> catalog (Vol.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>) features this notice: "WARNING: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paladin Press</ENAMEX> does not
intend that any of the information contained in its books or videos be used for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> purposes. In specific cases involving such misuse, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paladin</ENAMEX> will
cooperate with law enforcement investigations."

            I believe a similar notice appears on the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX> catalog.

            Just inside, on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, is this announcement:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EXPLOSIVE BOOKS NO LONGER AVAILABLE</ENAMEX>. In light of the current political and
legal climate in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, we have concluded that it is no longer feasible
to publish or sell certain titles on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX>, demolitions, improvised
weaponry, and self-defense, or anything by that quirky but lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX>."

            "We didn't really
include the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Tyler</ENAMEX> crack," they would have added, if they had a sense of
humor and, you know, added things.

            
               Clarification
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hard Rock Cafe</ENAMEX> does
not serve its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> poorly prepared <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> made with inferior ingredients;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hard Rock Cafe</ENAMEX> has no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, same as every other quiz.

         
      
   
