
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">325</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Wrapped Attention&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               In a TV commercial
running in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> cover a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX> look-alike in bubble wrap then
roll her down a hill and through a sprinkler. We don't find out what's being
advertised until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, when the tag line comes up. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> points and the
game: What is the tag line?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 324</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad About Beef":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Gregg</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, comments on some declassified documents with this personal anecdote: "My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residence</ENAMEX> had just been broken into by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> angry about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> quotas.
They tried to burn my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down. And I thought, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'God Almighty</ENAMEX>, if they get
this mad about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>, what will they do when they learn we have _________ here?'
"
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beefcake</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Finkle</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dee</ENAMEX>
Lacey
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K. Coombs</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Copies of the final."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Gaffen</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Pollack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacey</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "If
this were 'Match <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Game '74</ENAMEX>,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Nelson Reilly</ENAMEX> would answer 'bazooms.'
"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenton</ENAMEX> Cernea
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>'s balsamic glazed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">onions</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Majors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippert</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Todd York</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            We risk hubris, given
our lackluster national cuisine--not that I'm knocking high-fat, high-calorie,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">high-profit</ENAMEX>, bland stuff served up on a bun and eaten in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>--if we mock the
food of another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. So, unlike many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Quiz participants</ENAMEX>, I won't. Instead,
I'll point out that one of the pleasures of urban life is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">juxtaposition</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of different eras, clothing of various subcultures,
books, movies and, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. When we make dinner plans, we don't name
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>; we list <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>: Should we go for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>? And I'll say this: If all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of the world got
along as well as do the bagel and mango on my breakfast table every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>,
that would be an impressive amount of along-getting. Right, anxiety-free doggy?
Rrrrrrrrright!

            
               Critical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass Appeal</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            If they get this mad about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>, what will they do
when they learn we have nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> here?

            During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> stored
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, including some with a no-nukes
policy, not always informing local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of this deployment. Currently
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction are kept in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least seven</NUMEX> foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.

            It took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX> to declassify the document,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">History of the Custody and Deployment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nuclear Weapons</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1945</TIMEX> through
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1977</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Arkin</ENAMEX> first requested it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom of</ENAMEX>
Information Act for use in a book he was writing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuclear Battlefield</ENAMEX> .
An article describing the document is in the current Bulletin of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atomic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg</ENAMEX>'s
colorful anecdotes now delight his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia Society</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Chen</ENAMEX>'s at the
Movies Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Norton</ENAMEX> explains what the fighting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fight Club</ENAMEX> is really about: "It's very much a metaphor for
self-transforming radicalism, for the idea of directing violence inward at your
own presumptions. ... The fighting is a metaphor for stripping yourself of
received notions and value systems that have been applied to you that aren't
your own. And freeing yourself to discover who you actually are."

            "And pummeling your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> into a bloody pulp,"
he did not add.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> more preposterous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor jabbering</ENAMEX> here.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Buyers</ENAMEX> Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
responses are for sale to reputable or disreputable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. Drug dealers
welcome. Contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>'s parole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> for details.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sure</ENAMEX> and Certain Proof
That <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are Over Again Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Actual evidence gathered from actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>,
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Man</ENAMEX> can't bust our news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Sizer</ENAMEX> was running a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> bookstore here when he decided to
launch a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> business: selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 19</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>)-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carvell</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Jones</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Semiotics of Panty</ENAMEX>-throwing--by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Vitzthum</ENAMEX>."
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon 's Table of Contents</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 19, 1999</TIMEX>)-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy Nolan</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jimi Hendrix's 'Let Me Stand Next to Your Fire</ENAMEX>' now used to tout <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunfire</ENAMEX> in TV spots."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>.
               

               "By using her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> in exchange for stock in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>
adds her name to a list of cyberrepresentatives that already includes the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shatner</ENAMEX>. I'm speechless."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>
Macleay
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peace</ENAMEX>, love, and understanding--hrrrpphh, that's funny! What a joke. I
swear to God. You know what I'd do? I'd line 'em up and shoot 'em. Yeah, yeah.
Shoot 'em all. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hrrrpphh</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilarious</ENAMEX>." (My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, now
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX>.)-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim O'Grady</ENAMEX>
               

               "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink Panther/Owens Corning Fiberglas</ENAMEX> commercial co-opting Fractured
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fairytales</ENAMEX> . I hope moose-and-squirrel got mucho bucks out of them,
considering the legalistic stink the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P.P.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>) made several years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> when a gay nonprofit anti-violence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had the temerity to call itself
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Pink Panthers</ENAMEX>' (although in this drunk-on-synergy era <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> probably owns
all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Ward</ENAMEX>'s output as well)."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Gormley</ENAMEX>
               

               "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, I co-authored a 'comprehensive and dramatically told' ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> ) biography of radical anti-war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Berrigan</ENAMEX>, and it sold many less copies than, oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewel</ENAMEX>'s diary or a
novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Hawke</ENAMEX>. Yet conveniently, my book made it into paperback and can
be purchased by clicking here."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim O'Grady</ENAMEX>
               

               "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> was used to fight imperialism in solidarity with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>, not to promote one's own books."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Funny foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pokémon.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
