
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">326</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Scents and Sensibility&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "This is a dream
for me--to find the soft parts and touch them and even smell them. It's very
exciting." Who said this about what? 
               
                  (Question courtesy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Aaron</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 325</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrapped Attention":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               In a TV commercial running in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> cover a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX>
look-alike in bubble wrap then roll her down a hill and through a sprinkler. We
don't find out what's being advertised until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, when the tag line comes
up. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> points and the game: What is the tag line?
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>: The courage to laugh at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on death row. The creativity to
carry out the execution in bold new ways."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Tapper</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"Arrive moist and fresh. Fly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Express</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrill Markoe</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everybody in Packing Materials</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX>. (You forgot to mention she was
lip-syncing "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helter Skelter</ENAMEX>.")-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannella</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Estrada-Berg</ENAMEX> )

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year later this</TIMEX> footage was found. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch Project II</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Krug</ENAMEX>
            

            "We're
adding new diagnostic procedures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>. We're your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Day</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> suggest that the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> is an ad for which we do not
know the product. Sure, this is cowardly, intellectually dishonest, and an
insult to the democratic process, but it's also thrifty, and that's important,
too. (Not important to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.W.</ENAMEX>, who enjoys <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scrooge McDuckian</ENAMEX> campaign funds, but
important in ways that will be revealed at the end. Of something.) As long as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.W.</ENAMEX>'s policies remain ambiguous, every TV ad is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> ad. Any
commercial that features some kind of cool car driving through some kind of
perfect landscape implicitly says: Let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.W.</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>) take the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> (the
car) into the future (it's just over the next fashion model). Or the ad when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wagnerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soprano</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.W.</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spears</ENAMEX> (anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">system</ENAMEX>) the cell phone (bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>?) of a discourteous opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> (affirmative action? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>?): I
think that means he wants to cut taxes for his rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. You can't be
overly literal. This thing works subconsciously, like workfare.

            
               Answer
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shop</ENAMEX> together, play together, eat together."

            The ad is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mills Corp.</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> and
newest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, each organized around the theme "total experience," by which is
meant a combination of shopping and entertainment, by which is meant a chance
to buy stuff at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foot Locker</ENAMEX> and then play a video game. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> combine
discount shopping, high-tech amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arcades</ENAMEX>, theme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24-30</NUMEX>
screen multiplexes showing the same teen-sex comedies, but on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24-30</NUMEX>
screens.

            The reason we don't know
why they're being so mean to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX> until the end of the ad? "That was
very deliberate. The idea is to give a sense of intrigue that this is a new
type of experience," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Parlota</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of the ad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> that produced the spot. "Of course, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find out it's just
another crappy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, they get pretty damn mad, but by then, I'm <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> away," he
did not add.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Weddings</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            
               Results:
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connecticut College</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montclair State</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Holyoke</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fordham</ENAMEX>


               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Colorado</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Carolina State</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Francis</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Francis</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davidson weds Davidson</ENAMEX>

            

            
               Highlights:
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> owns and manages olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">groves</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>."

            "In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> he is a
fly-fishing guide."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beat the Odds:</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>, graduated
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law</ENAMEX>. The groom, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>, graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire College</ENAMEX>; he is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antiques</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Content-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> campaign.

         
      
   
