
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">319</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Formerly Known As&quot</ENAMEX>; 

            
               There's been more
and more of it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, but now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> committee
proposes to eliminate it or at least rename it. What's the old name; what's the
new? 
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">318</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Non, Je Ne Regrette Rien":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               "You won't hear any apologies from me," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Ostroff</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX>. "Anyone who continues to maintain that there was
some mistake here doesn't understand the way science proceeds." What isn't
Ostroff apologizing for?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the whole point of the study was to see how well endangered condors
could withstand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebola</ENAMEX> virus."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Trying to pass off a few flasks of blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion</NUMEX>
dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> research project."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX>, not biology. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheesh</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyrie O'Connor</ENAMEX>
            

            "Why
can't you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> understand that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cybill Sheperd</ENAMEX> would make an outstanding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roche</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Random Hearts</ENAMEX> . 'As anybody with any understanding of the scientific
process could tell you, the problem here lies with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sydney Pollack</ENAMEX>,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ostroff</ENAMEX>
noted. 'Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> surely shares some of the blame.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            To apologize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convincingly</ENAMEX> takes exquisite timing. Do it too soon and you seem glib and
insincere: "You're sorry? Well, 'sorry' won't make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s leg grow back!" Do
it too late and you seem, actually it's glib and insincere again. "Oh, you're
sorry about slavery? About what you did to that nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Galileo</ENAMEX>?" Too long
deferred, your apology will be dismissed as self-aggrandizing. It wasn't you
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> you lead that committed the misdeed. The apology shows
what a sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you are, while you needn't alter your behavior at all,
unless your slaves are doing something unkind to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Galileo</ENAMEX> or that gimpy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> of
his. To have meaning, the apology must convey recently acquired insight into
personal wrongdoing, something neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Ostroff</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox TV</ENAMEX>
network seems inclined to do. Sorry about that.

            
               Unregrettable
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ostroff</ENAMEX> is not sorry that it took so long to
realize that what seemed like an encephalitis outbreak in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> was
really an infestation of the West <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX> virus in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. OK, they got the city
right almost at once, but not a lot more. And don't expect him to say, "I
apologize for all the confusion, like not bothering to get in touch with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who first identified the disease."

            It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracey McNamara</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bronx Zoo</ENAMEX> who
noticed there were a lot of dead crows in the neighborhood, but her emus were
doing fine, and they're highly susceptible to encephalitis, so there had to be
some other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> at work. Creepy detail: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> were bleeding from the
brain and had badly damaged hearts. "We had dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and I
thought we needed to pursue this." But she couldn't get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention</ENAMEX> to seriously consider her suspicion
that the bird <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> disease were the same.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNamara</ENAMEX> is understanding about the chaos at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Zelicoff</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Center of National Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arms</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandia National Laboratories</ENAMEX>, takes a harder line: "It is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sobering</ENAMEX>, not so reassuring demonstration of the inadequacies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
detection network for emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>."

            "If you're waiting
around for me to say, 'Oooh, sorry your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>'s brain is bleeding,' " Ostroff
did not add, "you've got a long wait coming."

            
               It's a Small, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small</ENAMEX>
World <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stinking of Death Where You Really</ENAMEX> Work up an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appetite Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            War, earthquake, radiation leaks--in an age of
swift transportation, one encounters death in many forms befalling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faiths</ENAMEX>. Can you navigate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s post-fatality formalities without
committing an embarrassing faux pas?

            Below, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX> denominations. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX>, will
food be served or do you need to bring a sandwich?

            (All facts from the
delightful new, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How To Be a Perfect Stranger: A Guide to Etiquette in Other</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Religious Ceremonies , Vol.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX>.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Q: Will Food Be Served</ENAMEX>?
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Islam

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Baptist</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disciples of Christ</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hindu</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quaker</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Church of Canada</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Episcopalian

            
               A:
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Possibly. Often, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> prepare <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for mourners and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. (
               While the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> sit around mourning manfully, but in some larger and incomprehensible
sense, equally. Forget it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake</ENAMEX>, it's religious tradition.)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Yes, but no alcoholic beverages. It would be
considered impolite for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> not to eat. No grace or benediction will be
recited before or after eating or drinking. (
               Use the time to
contemplate how your fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptists</ENAMEX> have been on the wrong side of every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> policy from the civil-rights movement to gay rights with a stop-off to
support the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>.)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Yes. Wait for grace to be said before eating. It
would not be considered impolite not to eat. (
               It would, however, be
considered impolite to take a bite out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX>.)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Possibly. But no alcoholic beverages. (Note:
even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYOB</ENAMEX> considered thoughtless, vulgar.)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Varies according to tradition. (But beware of
con <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>: No <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> tradition includes formal tie-in with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Hut</ENAMEX>.)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Possibly. (Although snacking during actual
service is discouraged.)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Possibly. Given the broad ethnic mixture of
Catholicism, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> may have a "wake" at which <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> (and often drink)
is served. (Others may be pandered to by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> offended by snippy art
shows. No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is served during the pandering.)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Often refreshments or a light <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> will be
served at a reception immediately following the memorial, funeral, or interment
service. (And should you get a bad clam, an excellent system of universal
health care is provided: Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>!)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Probably. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guests</ENAMEX> should not wait for a grace or
benediction before eating. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guests</ENAMEX> will eat as they arrive, after expressing
their condolences to the bereaved. (
               Etiquette note: Don't crowd the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nova</ENAMEX>.)
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Yes, but it won't be
very good and the portions will be small. (I paraphrase.)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ongoing Bail-Out</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            "And now a reply from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hast</ENAMEX>
..." Boom. That's where I dive for my remote control like a terrier down a rat
hole--you know, if the terrier was digging really fast.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to submit other actual
examples from any news source of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> used to call
"letters we never finished reading." (Or something like that.)

            Best examples to run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Terrifying flesh-eating virus; stupefying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prime-time TV</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
