
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babbling Brooks</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  The
               
               
                  Muse
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">October Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Brooks</ENAMEX>'
new film--which he directed, co-wrote, and stars in--is "good but not great
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). The plot: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>) has lost his edge, and he enlists the aid of a muse (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX>) to
inspire him. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> being <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, this muse requires a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons</ENAMEX> and gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany's</ENAMEX> to keep her going. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) positively glows for the film, calling it a "mordantly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hilarious cri de coeur</ENAMEX> ." But most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> aren't so enchanted: Although
"there are lots of punchy lines," the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-joke movie doesn't have all that
much to say" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s
review in 
                  Slate
               , and here to
find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudley</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  Do<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">-Right</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indifferent</ENAMEX> reviews for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> live-action version of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Ward</ENAMEX> cartoon to
star <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Fraser</ENAMEX> (the first being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jungle</ENAMEX> ). It's a
"genial" film with "lots of broad slapstick humor that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
wince at" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are outright
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irritated</ENAMEX>--it "disappoints in every way possible," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> )--but most are just mildly annoyed. Maslin, however,
gives the film a surprisingly upbeat review, admiring its "appealing
try-anything spirit" and noting that it "works well as family entertainment"
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
visit the film's official site.)

            

               
                  The
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astronaut</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wife</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>).
The final entry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> of blah movies is one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Universal</ENAMEX> wouldn't preview for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, presumably to postpone the bad reviews for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>. Now that it's
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, the pans are pouring in for this "ridiculously derivative" movie
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) about an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX>) who
returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> after a strange, and possibly alien, encounter in space. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlize Theron</ENAMEX>) is now pregnant--and sporting the same hairdo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia Farrow</ENAMEX>
wore in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> --and must determine what has happened to hubby
and what to do about it. "Instead of a movie about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Astronaut</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wife</ENAMEX> seems like a movie made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Selier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Theron.</ENAMEX>)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Headlong
               
               
                  : A Novel
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Frayn</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Books</ENAMEX>). Strong notices for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>'s
latest, a story that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">engagingly</ENAMEX> combines a comedy of manners with elements of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">farce</ENAMEX> and art-historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> story" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Seaton</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). The main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, a philosophy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, stumbles on what he
believes to be a lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruegel</ENAMEX> painting and becomes obsessed with both obtaining
it and determining whether it is genuine. Along the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> gets a
"fascinating tour through the intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thickets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruegel</ENAMEX> scholarship"
that manages to be "as entertaining as it is intelligent, as stimulating as it
is funny" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> finds all the art history tiresome, as it has the side effect of
"entirely halting [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frayn</ENAMEX>'s] promising frolicsome narrative." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

            

               
                  Faster
               
               
                  : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Acceleration of Just About</ENAMEX>
Everything
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Gleick</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantheon</ENAMEX>). Gleick, whose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> previous
books were nominated for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Book Awards</ENAMEX>, gets positive but passionless
reviews for his rumination on the speed of contemporary life. Although
Faster is full of interesting details of how the brain perceives time
and how technology both steals and adds <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to our lives, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gleick</ENAMEX> never makes a definitive conclusion about the data he has
collected. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hy</ENAMEX> is it that whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> are given the choice, we opt for
faster? Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gleick</ENAMEX> fights shy of this big question. That is disappointing, if
only because we have such high expectations from this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Holt</ENAMEX>, the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). It's "as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gleick</ENAMEX> couldn't quite make the short
leap from being merely a superb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> to an astute social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
Kisor, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
