
   
   
      
         
            Scouting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys</ENAMEX>

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn Waugh</ENAMEX>'s novel
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brideshead Revisited</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sebastian Flyte</ENAMEX> turns the pages of the
News of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> and sighs, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another naughty Scoutmaster</ENAMEX>." This was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few years</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> had been created, but they had
already become a source of indelicate mirth.

            Now another scoutmaster (I do not say naughty) has
led to an important ruling by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dale</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and has been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX> since he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. He was happy in his work
as a scoutmaster, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scout officials</ENAMEX> saw a newspaper photograph of him leading
a gay rights group at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers University</ENAMEX>, and they threw him out. He sued and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">won</ENAMEX>, the court ruling that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX> may not discriminate on grounds of race,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creed</ENAMEX>, sexual preference, or whatnot.

            "Most good schoolmasters," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waugh</ENAMEX> wrote, "are
homosexual by inclination--how else could they endure their work?" He had
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in mind but might well have been thinking of any number
of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> instruct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> have long
elicited private sniggers about the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> they attract--going back, in
fact, to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>, that curious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Stephenson Smyth</ENAMEX>
Baden-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>.

            He created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX>, shortly after
returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> from a tour of duty as a cavalry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>.
During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Boer War</ENAMEX> he successfully commanded a vastly outnumbered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> during the siege of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafeking</ENAMEX>, and he went home a national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.
Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a few years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX> had spread throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Empire</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and almost from the beginning there were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scoutmasters</ENAMEX> who loved their little charges not wisely but too well. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">naughty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> after another trailed sadly through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtrooms</ENAMEX>, to the
delight of the dirty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baden-Powell</ENAMEX>
himself never landed in court, he was certainly a strange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. He was obsessed
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and "boyology." The index of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Jeal</ENAMEX>'s excellent biography
Baden-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> speaks of his "aesthetic and sexual interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>,"
"pre-marital celibacy," "dreams of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>," and "anxieties over sexuality."
He got married, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX>, to (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeal</ENAMEX> put it) "a sporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> whose interest in
outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">comradeship</ENAMEX> seemed at least as great as her desire for sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fulfillment</ENAMEX>," and he even managed to beget <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. But thereafter he
always slept out on his balcony (and this in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> climate) rather than
in the marriage bed.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-P</ENAMEX>," as he was known throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scout</ENAMEX>
movement, studiously recorded his dreams, which were often about young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. In
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, he recalled, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> snatched a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX> away from him and asked whether he
had ever been "disciplined." And in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX> manual <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scouting for Boys</ENAMEX> ,
which has a fair claim as one of the most influential books of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>, he focuses keenly on lust (though he does not mention
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX> outright). Baden-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> considered sexual desire a transitory
phase in adolescence, and he was obsessed with self-abuse. He recommends that a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> beset by impure thoughts should drive them way by plunging his
"racial organ" into icy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.

            It seems unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dale</ENAMEX> thus counseled
his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scout troop</ENAMEX>, though certainly any naughty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scoutmaster</ENAMEX> who nowadays
passed on that advice from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of scouting would more likely find
himself in hot water, rather than cold.

         
      
   
