
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bare Bones</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX>
Project demonstrates that there's nothing scarier than nothing. The movie
has no ghosts or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witches</ENAMEX> on display, and its lone bit of gore is a piece of
cloth containing a mottle of indeterminate organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. It has no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surprises</ENAMEX>, either, since you know going in that the ending won't be happy. The
movie opens with a placard declaring that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> went into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woods</ENAMEX> near "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burkittsville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>" to make a documentary and were never heard
from again, and that their footage was discovered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after their
disappearance. The placard doesn't mention who edited the footage--the
ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hitchcock</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassavetes</ENAMEX>?--but that's a minor point. I could tell you the
story--give away every detail--and The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project would still
freeze your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. Working on a budget that's chump change and a script that's
little more than a framework for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>' improvisations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myrick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eduardo Sanchez</ENAMEX> have harnessed the most irrational fears of every
human alive. They have reanimated the genre not by adding to it but subtracting
from it--by cooking it down to its bare bones and then rattling those bones
like fiends.

            The first thing they've
done is remove the omniscient point of view. With the important exception of
that opening title card, there is no larger perspective. The film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Donahue</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Leonard</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> bear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>' names)--tote their own video and movie cameras, so
that we see what they see and no more. Actually, we see even less, since we
lack their peripheral vision and are cruelly limited to whatever passes through
their lenses. Thanks to first-rate sound equipment, though, we hear everything
they hear--especially a snapping of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> in the dark outside their tent
that escalates into an omnidirectional clatter. When they yell into the
darkness (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Hello?</ENAMEX>"), the darkness remains dark. A light illuminates the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foreground</ENAMEX>, but the blackness beyond that pool seems, if anything, blacker.
There might be no more irrationally terrifying shot in the annals of film than
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in which the camera hurtles behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather</ENAMEX>--a hazy white streak in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> of the screen--amid crackling sounds as she throws a look into the trees
and shrieks: "What is that? What the fuck is that? " We never see what
the fuck that is. If we did, some part of us would probably relax, because it
would look like a special effect. But no part of us is allowed to relax.
Ever.

            Is The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project a work of "art"? Not by
my definition. Art rarely tortures you so single-mindedly. After the first
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX>, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> interview <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Burkittsville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> about the
history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elly Kedward</ENAMEX>, found guilty of sorcery in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1785</TIMEX>
and lashed to a tree during a harsh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>), the remainder of the movie is
their increasingly desperate odyssey through the woods. They trudge one way,
double back, pore over maps and compasses, whine, trudge some more, come upon
mysterious piles of rocks or bundled twigs, and whine even louder. The action
unfolds in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX> halfway between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, and the washed-out tones
suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> took the forest's colors with her when she died.
The grueling monotony is broken only at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> go into their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tents</ENAMEX> and the sounds come again and the very celluloid seems to shiver with
cold and fear. The camera twitches incessantly: The lone stationary shot is
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather</ENAMEX> sobs an apology to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> for having dreamed up the project,
and the way she's framed and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-lighted she looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lon Chaney's Phantom</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> with nostril hair. I don't apply the adjective "visceral"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">casually</ENAMEX>: The shaky camera summons up our fight-or-flight responses. Leaving
the screening, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was convinced she had food poisoning from an earlier
meal; when we stopped and analyzed her symptoms, we realized that she had
motion sickness. The movie had literally made her sick.

            The power of that can't
be slighted, however. I love horror pictures and am a tough scare, but I
started having nightmares about The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project before I even
saw it--solely on the basis of its preview. I slept even less after I did see
it. When I caught an interview with the superbly nervy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Donahue</ENAMEX> on
television, the first thing I thought was, "Thank God, she's alive." Then she
said, "This movie must be working because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come up to me all the time and
say, 'Thank God, you're alive.' " The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> an envelope arrived at my door
with a bunch of sticks lashed together in the familiar form of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">talisman</ENAMEX>. I rushed to the phone and called the movie's publicists to make sure
this was a promotional gimmick. When they said yes, I started breathing again;
otherwise, I might have called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>--or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exorcist</ENAMEX>.

            What is it about The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project that taps
into such primal emotions? Consider its antithesis. The remake of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haunting</ENAMEX> has the bad fortune to open in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same month</TIMEX>, and what might have
been dismissed as just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>, overstuffed big-studio scare picture will now be
held up as a counterexample. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wise</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> original, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Haunting of Hill House</ENAMEX> , is overrated, but it manages to
evoke the eeriest aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s fiction: the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' neuroses
acquire an inexorable life of their own and threaten to eat them alive. Nothing
much happens in the empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>, but when something does--for instance, a
thunderous pounding on a pair of big doors, as if all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>'
accumulated nervous energies had been focused on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> spot--the movie's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reticence</ENAMEX> pays off like gangbusters (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ghostbusters</ENAMEX>). In the new version,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan De Bont</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speed</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twister</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pounding</ENAMEX> comes early and serves as an overture for a bunch of
computer-generated special effects: ghosties that swirl around like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinkerbell</ENAMEX>,
statues that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> to life and grab <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Everything is exasperatingly,
often laughably, overexplicit, and once a dread becomes material, a ghost story
becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> movie--a different, far less terrifying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>.

            Here are sound effects so hammy that they might
have been borrowed from one of those old haunted-house party albums. Doors
don't creak, they CRRRREEEAAAKKK and then close with a reverberant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KER-CHUNGGGGGG</ENAMEX>. From the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeta-Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lili Taylor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Wilson</ENAMEX>--set foot in the farcically garish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill House</ENAMEX>, it's clear that Something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> is watching them: You can tell
because Something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> respires so loudly that he's either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Vader</ENAMEX> or an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asthmatic</ENAMEX>. By the time poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> stands up to the big, bad ghost on behalf of
a lot of little, good ghosts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> are holding onto their
stomachs to keep from retching with laughter. Writing, directing, acting--this
is one of the most maladroit ghost movies ever made.

            But even if the script weren't so tin-eared and the
direction so clunky, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Haunting</ENAMEX> still wouldn't come within screaming
distance of The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project . The reason is philosophical. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De</ENAMEX>
Bont, a lavish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">materialist</ENAMEX> who thinks that movies can do anything if you throw
enough money around, wants to scare you by showing you stuff. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myrick</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sanchez</ENAMEX> want to scare you by not showing you stuff--and by reminding you how
much you can't see and will never know. With all those cameras onscreen,
they've liberated horror from the realm of movies--from the realm of the
light--and nestled it back into the dark where it was born.

         
      
   
