
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brides To Blush At</ENAMEX> 

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Just a quick comment
on the poor advice you gave to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> inquiring about a . I married someone
who was briefly married before. However, I was a first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>. It is my
contention that if you accept an invitation to attend an expensive black-tie
affair that you should bring a gift of at least the value of your meal. I was
outraged and shocked that anyone would give a gift of less than that. If they
did not attend, a similar, albeit somewhat less expensive gift would have been
acceptable. I think it is incredibly poor taste, rude, and offensive for anyone
to bring a "token" gift--especially if one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has never been married. Shame
on you for promoting bad manners.
            

            

               --RS
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear R$</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is guessing you
subscribe to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldier</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, because you are certainly a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mercenary</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> also suspects that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s prior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> may have
snagged some fabulous presents, thereby irritating you because you
feel--correctly--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terrific presents within a
short period of time. What is actually in incredibly poor taste is to mentally
make a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">quid</NUMEX> pro quo--the quid being the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>, the quo being the gift. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Presents,</ENAMEX>
my dear, have to do with one's finances and one's feelings--not the cost of a
meal. And how, exactly, by your lights, are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> supposed to know the
cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>? Do you, by any chance, suggest having it engraved under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">répondez</ENAMEX>, s'il vous plaît ?

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, alarmedly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My co-worker
recently announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her wedding</TIMEX> and mentioned that everyone should be receiving
their invitations soon. I decided to give her an elaborate wedding shower and
to include all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>) who work with us. I coordinated
this event from A to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Z.</ENAMEX> Everyone chipped in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> for a travel
certificate to be used for their honeymoon. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> attended and the
event went off without a hitch. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> was extremely grateful. My question
is: Am I still responsible for buying a wedding gift? I wasn't sure if it would
be in poor taste for me to consider my efforts and contribution to the shower
enough.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               Unsure
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Un</ENAMEX>,

            Ah yes, we are still in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> for brides. Your query involves some interesting concepts. We
must assume that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> for whom you organized the shower was a close friend
... otherwise, why else go to all that trouble? Given that your efforts
involved a lot of time (and perhaps paying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>) and afforded the
couple a wonderful celebratory <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, along with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900</NUMEX> to apply to their
honeymoon expenses, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels you have given them a grand wedding gift. Why
don't you write a note telling the bridal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> that you had such fun
arranging their party and that you and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> at the shower will have
fond thoughts of them while they are away honeymooning. That way they will know
that was the gift you wanted to give them.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, sentimentally

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               In reference to the
letter from "" who was worried about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> catching the bouquet: I was
married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> and gave all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 12</TIMEX> a chance to catch a
small stuffed animal before I threw the bouquet to the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>. This worked
out really well, and I highly recommend it to anyone! That way, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> of
honor could catch the bouquet without my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> tripping
her.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear C,

            Sweet. Smart. And what
fun if a youngster misunderstands the custom just a little and imagines she
will grow up to marry <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Winnie the Pooh</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, delightedly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am alienated from all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and sisters
(except <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>) for good reason. We do not communicate. No problem there. But now
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--my nieces and nephews--are beginning to make overtures to me
... e-mails, letters, invitations to graduations, requests to visit, to write
recommendation letters, etc. This even though I have tried to keep my addresses
and phone numbers secret. 
               Am I being unreasonable to extend my desire
to remain incommunicado to the next generation? Don't advise me to make up with
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX>. I am quite happy to be "divorced" from them.
            

            
               Thanks.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Pat</ENAMEX>,

            Are you very rich, or
famous? Mention of your "addresses and phone numbers," along with all these
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lurching in your direction would suggest there is an attraction
beyond the obvious. You sound a bit misanthropic, to be honest, but assuming
you have supportable reasons for ringing off from many in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, Prudie
sees no reason to cut off the next generation. It is a possibility that the
discarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> have put their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> up to warming up the situation, but
that seems slight. If you have no interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, or these particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, decline the entreaties ... but as gently as you can.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, delicately

         
      
   
