
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=660525219-21091999><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Malibu Dream Knee</ENAMEX></SPAN>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie Gives</ENAMEX> the
Finger
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahor</ENAMEX>--an anaplastologist at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University Medical Center</ENAMEX>--has discovered a new use for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> doll. By placing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>'s legs inside a hollow prosthetic finger, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bahor</ENAMEX> discovered that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>'s transplanted knee joint gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> greater mechanical flexibility
and control over their artificial digits. "Although you could previously only
move joints that were in the hand [as opposed to the fingers], the plastic in
the legs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> dolls allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to position fingers in different
flexion," she told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University Chronicle</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Hostetter</ENAMEX>, the
medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> prosthetics clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>, noted that the technique is an
inexpensive way to provide articulation in a finger and that it will help
prosthetic fingers become functional as well as cosmetic appendages.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ascent of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Darwin</ENAMEX>
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Kansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> has mounted a small exhibit illustrating the ideas
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Darwin</ENAMEX> in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas Board of Education</ENAMEX>'s decision to
eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Darwinism</ENAMEX> from statewide science tests. The exhibit, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man an Ape</ENAMEX> or an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Angel?</ENAMEX>" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth Spencer Research Library</ENAMEX>, features both a first
edition of On the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Origin of Species</ENAMEX> and a letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX> to geologist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James E. Todd</ENAMEX>, who joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KU</ENAMEX>'s
staff in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX>. University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Haines</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Librarians</ENAMEX>, we don't censor. ... When there's a controversy, we like to bring
out the books that caused the controversy." While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> staff isn't
taking an official position on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s decision, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haines</ENAMEX> did admit, "We have
our personal opinions, and you can probably guess what they are."

            
               No Ph.D., No
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High-Tech Laser Lab</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Campbell</ENAMEX> has resigned his post at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lawrence Livermore Laboratory</ENAMEX> after
anonymous faxes revealed that he had never earned a doctoral degree. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>,
formerly associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for laser programs at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Livermore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> program to conduct weapons research, announced his decision to
leave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 27</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> had allowed the laboratory to believe that he had a
doctorate from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton University</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> said, when in fact he had only
finished his Ph.D. course work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> also told the New York
Times that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> requires "all senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to hold a Ph.D. or its
equivalent in experience." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> said only that he was leaving for personal
reasons.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> of the
Class
            

            An
unusual fossil skull, which may contain new clues about human evolution, was
discovered in an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">curio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports
that the skull arrived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> as part of a collection of rocks, minerals,
and curios. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop owner</ENAMEX> recognized its significance after he cleaned it and
turned it over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> at the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Museum of Natural History</ENAMEX>. Paleoanthropologists
examining the skull have traced its origins to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> and presume it to be
that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homo erectus</ENAMEX>. However, they also note that the skull, which probably
belonged to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 20s</TIMEX>, has a high, humanlike forehead, not the sloping
kind typical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homo erectus</ENAMEX> and other early hominids. "It's not like any other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homo erectus</ENAMEX> we know from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> or anywhere else," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Delson</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City College of New York</ENAMEX> paleoanthropologist directing the investigation.
"Of course, it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, but it could represent a distinctive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>."

            
               Bullshit!
Bullshit! Bullshit!
            

            A team
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tourette's syndrome</ENAMEX>--the condition that leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to suffer muscular spasms and to
blurt out obscenities--may be a psychological rather than a physical disorder.
Sufferers may actually be able to control their sputterings, according to
experiments led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Flanagan</ENAMEX> at Queen's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC Online</ENAMEX>
reports. In one experiment, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourette</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> was directed to hold a
weighted box loaded with sensors. Anticipating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s regular tics, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> monitored how his grip on the sensor box changed as his arm
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twitched</ENAMEX>. They observed the subject adjusting his grip on the box just before
experiencing a tic, indicating that at some level he was in control of his
actions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flanagan</ENAMEX> concluded, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourette</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sufferers</ENAMEX>] have motor control over
these tics, and these movements look normal and have all the same sort of
response we would expect to see in voluntary movement." He also suggested that
his findings may point the way toward behavioral therapy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for a summary of the experiment.)

            
               No More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teachers</ENAMEX>,
No <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More Books ... No More Notes, Either</ENAMEX>!
            

            
College <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, drop your pencils! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">StudentU</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, an Internet startup conceived by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oran</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>, may make note-taking in class obsolete. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> is developing a professional
online note-taking service to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> augment their own notes or to catch
up after a sick day, he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . Student stenographers
are paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> per semester plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> additional note-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX> they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recruit</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. In return, they must post their jottings within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">StudentU</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> Web site, which is open to all and financed by
advertising revenue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Gitlin</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX>, railed
against the concept in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> op-ed: "The very act of taking notes ...
is a way of engaging the material, wrestling with it, struggling to comprehend
or to take issue, but in any case entering into the work. ... A download is a
poor substitute."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caltech</ENAMEX>: No. 1
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Institute of Technology</ENAMEX> stormed from <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> place to top this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s rankings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX>
... but how? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> explains that a "technical change" in its methodology
accounts for the move. Writing in 
                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Gottlieb</ENAMEX> that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> fiddled with the rules." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Duffy</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Cary</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               , defending their ranking methodology as
an improvement over their previous techniques.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bury My Heart</ENAMEX> at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toxic Waste Dump</ENAMEX>
            

            The
most controversial academic book of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> is The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecological Indian</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Myth and History</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> anthropology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard Krech III</ENAMEX>.
Working from firsthand reports as well as archeological and scientific data,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Krech</ENAMEX> asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> are not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proto-environmentalists</ENAMEX> so
fondly imagined by "spiritually undernourished <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>" (in the words of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>). Rather, they hunted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extinction</ENAMEX>, exhausted large stretches of land, and mismanaged natural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Veech</ENAMEX>, writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , points out
that: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Krech paints</ENAMEX>] us a more complex portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that rejects mythologies, even those that both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> might wish to embrace."

            
               Tell It on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Beal Frazier</ENAMEX>, a tenured accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> who is married to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Frazier</ENAMEX>, has returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Carolina State University</ENAMEX>,
where she was fired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> for "neglect of duty." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCSU</ENAMEX> accused
Frazier of neglecting to complete paperwork and of raising her personal and
professional problems in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frazier</ENAMEX> denied the claims, saying that she missed deadlines
because she was suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, which was a result of sex
discrimination she faced within her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College of Management</ENAMEX>
beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frazier</ENAMEX> sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for sex discrimination and
retaliation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, just before the decision to dismiss her was finalized. Now
she is settling with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and will be reinstated to her full
professorship, receive back pay of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>, benefits, and a cash payment. She
will be on leave, retroactively, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 1998-99</TIMEX> academic year
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002-03</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frazier</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> she would not have been able
to pursue her lawsuit had it not been for the commercial success of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
Mountain .

            
               What Said Has
Said
            

            
Literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, and
public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX> has responded to the accusation that he has
systematically distorted his life story. In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commentary</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justus Reid Weiner</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Center</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Affairs</ENAMEX>, accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> of lying about his childhood in order to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">portray</ENAMEX> himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX>, when in fact he grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. Said has responded in an article published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Ahram</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Hayat</ENAMEX> , and online at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterpunch</ENAMEX> .
Said disputes the charges and challenges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weiner</ENAMEX>'s research methods. Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Cockburn</ENAMEX> have stepped up to bat for him in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Press</ENAMEX> , respectively.
Still, others have taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weiner</ENAMEX> at his word: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> has
labeled Said the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tawana Brawley</ENAMEX>," and others have called for his
replacement as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Language Association</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX>
Surf
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University</ENAMEX> has fallen to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> place in a
survey that ranks <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> by the jobs their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> win at top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. When the survey was last taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> ranked <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> it trailed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leeds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">College London</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nottingham</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
