
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">278</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Interest Rate&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 278</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest Rate</ENAMEX>":
Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carleton S. Fiorina</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>, the newly announced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard company</ENAMEX>, meets the press: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My ________</ENAMEX> is
interesting but really not the subject of the story here."
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 277</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summerize":</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX> did it when they were young, and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will attend <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> to learn how to do it
better. Do what?
            

            "Let's
just say that somewhere <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joycelyn Elders</ENAMEX> is smiling."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Krause</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thomas</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Oder</ENAMEX> had similar
answers.)

            "Liven
up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klan</ENAMEX> rally in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s case, with the smooth, lilting
sound of a banjo."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>
            

            "Flirt
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> was young<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            "If I
remember camp correctly, surrendering completely to an arbitrary and irrational
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> under the threat of violence."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Largely ignoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>--good advice for all--many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> assumed that shorthand
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> is senility, and shorthand for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX> is the old arrow
through the head bit, which he performed back when he was still--oh, cruel,
cruel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>!--funny. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> has indeed been in many bad movies recently,
and he certainly benefited from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s editorial policy of publishing
anything at all if it was written--or dictated over the phone--by a celebrity.
But there is another reason, more tragic and ironic, why this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted</ENAMEX> and
imaginative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> seems less funny lately. Comedy relies on surprise. A joke sets
up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of logic, and then subverts it in a surprising and delightful way;
that's the punch line. A comic persona embodies an unexpected way of seeing the
world. But the more successfully a comic does this, the more familiar his point
of view becomes. And finally, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of exposure to even the liveliest
comic mind--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> certainly has one--we can all make up our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> gag or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> denial or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> unworkable budget policy. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of seeing things is too familiar to surprise us, too predictable to be
funny. And so a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX>'s success creates his failure. That, and appearing
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy Chase</ENAMEX>.

            
               Give Me an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Give Me</ENAMEX>
an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Give Me ... Oh, Just Give the Damn Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX>.

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 3.3 million</NUMEX> active cheerleaders
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--if they weren't active, they wouldn't deserve to be called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cheerleaders</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97 percent</NUMEX> of them are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, competitions, and
uniform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> that make up the "spirit industry" is described as "a
virtual circle of cross-marketing," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Webb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Varsity Spirit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> big in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> areas.

            Maintaining a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cheerleader</ENAMEX> can run <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in equipment, travel, and entry fees--tough
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>, but far cheaper than the high-priced world of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASCAR</ENAMEX> racing, where
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> can't even talk, let alone spell out mood-boosting words letter by
letter while leaping into the air. On the other hand, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX> are
disappointed that cheerleading contests include so few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fiery collisions</ENAMEX>.

            
               It's an Orderly and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Predictable Universe Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
think I also have an obligation to deal with the hurt and the harm done to
these police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> who were put in a position where they had to kill your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>, on the radio, hectoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margarita Rosario</ENAMEX>, the mother
of an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX>, who was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> lying face down when the cops shot
them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> times
            

            "Quite
sensitive and quite honest."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>, evaluating his comments to the
dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s mother
            

            
"There's no point in moralizing whether this is a good or bad thing."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeWitt</ENAMEX>, advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>, on a whole other subject
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ongoing Domain Name</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            The domain name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">WebInvest</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is already registered
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth L. Riffle</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OneBornEveryMinute</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is still available.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to submit a similar
pair--a domain name that is already taken along with an amusing and available
alternative.

            You can check the availability of domain names at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eHost</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com/domain_reg/</ENAMEX>index.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>.

            Replies due by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 22</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            The old arrow through the head bit, the old
autoeroticism thing.

         
      
   
