
   
   
      
         
            Voting Online

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts
            

            Next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi Kantor</ENAMEX> will report on the emergence of Internet voting and some of
the obstacles to it, the most daunting of which is ballot security. But let's
assume for the moment that the practical problems can be overcome. Will
Internet voting be good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy?

            The
chief argument for e-voting is that it will cause more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to vote. As
everyone knows, turnout has been declining. In presidential elections, it has
fallen from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63 percent</NUMEX> of the voting-age population in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 50</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. There are many reasons for this, but one of them is surely the
inconvenience of casting ballots in person. Before you can vote, you need to
have registered, often <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election</TIMEX>. Then you must go
somewhere and stand in a line--on a day that seems scientifically chosen to
maximize the odds of lousy weather. If you're going to be away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> on
Election <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX>, you have to think ahead about getting an absentee ballot.
E-voting would eliminate these hassles. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> believe that it would
have its greatest impact on participation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 18-24</TIMEX>, who turn out in
lower numbers than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            On the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> are a variety of objections. In addition to concerns about fraud,
some argue that Internet voting would accentuate the socio-economic skew of our
elections. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wealthier</ENAMEX>, whiter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more likely to vote than poor people
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. Since they're also more likely to own personal computers,
online voting might exaggerate the disparity. There is also an argument that
the familiar process of voting in person serves a civic purpose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Valelly</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swarthmore College</ENAMEX>, argued  in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Republic</ENAMEX> recently that real
voting is a "vital public ritual that increases social solidarity and binds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together." You might call this the communitarian objection. Valelly
thinks that e-voting would create "political anomie."

            I
think it's fairly easy to answer the race-and-class argument. No one thinks
that e-voting would replace r-voting any time soon. So long as it is an
optional alternative, e-voting makes it easier for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
vote--especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living abroad, and frequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flyers</ENAMEX>--without inconveniencing anyone else. This is what's called a win-win
situation. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>, access to the Internet is forecast to become
dirt cheap and quasi-ubiquitous. But for those who still can't afford or don't
want private access at home, there will be public Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">libraries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>--and probably grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and bus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> as well.
E-voting might actually be a boon to the poor, who often can't miss work to
vote as easily as higher-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> can.

            The
communitarian objection is a bit more troubling. Around the world, people
struggle and die for the right to vote, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> once
did. If you've ever seen the once-disenfranchised standing in line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> to
cast the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ballot of a lifetime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guatemala</ENAMEX>, it's hard not
to be appalled at how cavalierly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> treat voting in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It's
tempting to say that anyone unwilling to sacrifice an hour to exercise the
right to vote doesn't much deserve it. Having to take a bit of trouble to vote
reminds you that voting is the cornerstone of all our rights. By eliminating
the ritual, e-voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> to diminish the meaning attached to it.

            I'd
say that this complaint is valid but not persuasive. The chief value of the
ritual of voting is to convey the significance of voting to democratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Once the ritual becomes a deterrent to the act itself, as it pretty
clearly has, it ceases to serve its purpose. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the communitarian
objection to e-voting seems more aesthetic than substantive. On the Internet,
more of us will exercise our right and fulfill our civic responsibilities. We
just won't meet in a church <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> to do it. The trade-off of higher
participation for poorer visuals would seem one well worth making.

            In fact, e-voting is less
of a leap than it might seem. When you think about it, voting has long been a
fusion of public and private, of tradition and technology. The secret ballot
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Era</ENAMEX> reform. Voting machines--which utilize primitive, punch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> computer processing--came into widespread use in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. These two
innovations mean that we already vote privately by computer--we just visit a
public place to do so. It's not that nothing will be lost when we all vote from
remote terminals instead of at the local polling place. But what we stand to
lose is ephemeral. What we stand to gain from virtual voting is very real.

         
      
   
