
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">320</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Futurific&quot</ENAMEX>; 

            
most significant developments in the history of the space age," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John E.</ENAMEX>
Pike of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation of American Scientists</ENAMEX>, reacting to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s big event.
What happened?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">319</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Formerly Known As":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  There's been more and more of it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>,
but now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty committee</ENAMEX> proposes to eliminate it or at least rename it.
What's the old name; what's the new? 
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheating</ENAMEX>; collaborative learning."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Scott</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie Haskins</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            
"Herpes; happy pants."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Oates</ENAMEX>' oeuvre ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whatsername</ENAMEX>'s stuff."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Finkle</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Untenured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>; groundskeepers."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disabled</ENAMEX>; genetically inferior and slated for elimination."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> oddly
contradictory views of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> life. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> view, loutish slack-jawed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, admitted to college only so the bursar can suck money out of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> alumni <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, cheat their way through class and, if that doesn't get
them good enough grades, bully their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> into upping their marks. Those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craven souls</ENAMEX> knuckle under because, weak and untenured in their pathetic
tweeds, they must capitulate or end up doing yard work at some ethnically
cleansed eating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>.

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> in a parallel universe,
perpetually drunken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> sleep it off in class, their clothing disarrayed
in such as way as to catch the eye of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sadean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> by whom they are
sexually exploited in exchange for better grades. The only ones exempt from
this cruel pawing are the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, who aren't there anyway, and the
physically disabled, who are being quietly slaughtered, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX>'s special-duty teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>.

            Which of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princetons</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> attended?

            

               Inflatable 
               Answer
            

            A+<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">; A With Distinction</ENAMEX>.

            Worried about grade inflation, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> faculty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> proposes replacing the A+, worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX> grade points, with the new
designation that would be worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 4.0</NUMEX>, the same as an A, but would denote
particular academic excellence.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times attributes the increasing number of A plusses and the decrease in C's
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>'s to "lenient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who badger them for higher
grades."

            
               Some

               Other Actual Name Changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> Web addresses used to end ".<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wg</ENAMEX>" indicating the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX>; they will now end ".<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ps</ENAMEX>" indicating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is pretty
much an afterthought.

               The e-mail newsletter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Today</ENAMEX> will now be known as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>@hcny,
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> protects its trademark from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Club</ENAMEX>, which
might also have to change the name of its all-male nude review, you know, if it
had an all-male nude review. Which I for one would certainly pay to see. More
for cultural than erotic reasons. Not that I begrudge anyone his pleasures.
I'll stop now.

               The advertising tag-line "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Always Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>" will now be "Enjoy all that's
inside," in an effort to reinvigorate sagging <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cola</ENAMEX> sales. "They want to try
root <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, then fruit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>; they jump all over the place," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
Llewellyn, grouchy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Coca-Cola Bottling Co.</ENAMEX> "They'd drink
their own urine if we let them. The fickle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bastards</ENAMEX> should be <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-whipped,"
he did not add.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Barkin</ENAMEX> will, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> soon (if there's a God in heaven, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX>'s
stock continues to plummet as a feckless addlepated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> drives a once-thriving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> into the ground with his big bald <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>) be changing her name to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, if I can just get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to lift that restraining order.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Correction Corner</ENAMEX>
            

            (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Without Missed Dinner Extra</ENAMEX>,
I foolishly wrote "Use the time to contemplate how your fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptists</ENAMEX> have
been on the wrong side of every social policy from the civil-rights movement to
gay rights with a stop-off to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>." Below, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Murdoch</ENAMEX>
sets me straight-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>.)
            

            You're doubtless thinking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Baptist</ENAMEX>
Convention. Let me assure you that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Baptist Convention</ENAMEX> was entirely
in support of civil rights; it is a largely black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>. The American
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baptist Churches</ENAMEX> (note the plural: Baptists object to the idea of
denominations, choosing to "freely associate" instead) absolutely took the
liberal position on practically any social issue from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> on (which is
why they're losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Baptist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Baptist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conventions</ENAMEX>).

            Who's the largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Baptist Churches</ENAMEX>.

            
               Ongoing

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bail-Out Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Some leads so deftly encapsulate the article to
follow that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> instantly knows he'd sooner be struck blind than read
on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to submit actual examples from any news source of
what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> used to call "letters we never finished reading" (or
something like that), like this one from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>:

            "What a contradictory country this is ..."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 12, 1999</TIMEX>

            Best examples to run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            Faculty-student sex.

         
      
   
