
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Sight&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "I've never seen
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, as he used something for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. Apparently he enjoyed the experience: "Now that I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowner</ENAMEX>, I
better get one of these." What was it, and what did he do with it?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 299</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Would Jesus Sue?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, a group of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
lifted. Ban on what?
                     
                  
               
            

            "The
use of 'Baby I'm-a Want You' in the regular rotation of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hymns</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Scheft</ENAMEX>
            

            "Those
new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'People</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crucifixes</ENAMEX>' with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> hanging on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer Gabel</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>-based religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nikonovich-Kahn</ENAMEX>
( Melody 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yiu</ENAMEX> had a similarly beefy answer.)

            
"Teaching creationism as science, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Narnia</ENAMEX> books as history."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunting</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and hounds, the smallest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> form."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>
Day
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Murderous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>, deadly bombings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasus</ENAMEX>, scary tumors in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cardinal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, fugitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Frankel</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Holsenglacis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>,
runaway parade floats plowing into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> and yet not crushing a single
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>--so much news and so little time, the effect of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> schedule on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>--which, incidentally, you can play all week
without paying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> sales tax or showering or even getting out of your
pajamas: Such is our end-of-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> malaise. Or perhaps it's just a perverse
disappointment that the anxiously anticipated NQ3C problem was no problem at
all. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> question No. 300 resulted in no fiery
eruption on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s ... well, never mind. I'm sure
we all did the best we could, although many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, absorbed with the
idea of burning heretics, seem to have confused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C of E</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RC</ENAMEX>, so
let's all reread <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Barchester Towers</ENAMEX> and study up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gordon</ENAMEX> riots,
with our trousers down around our ankles.

            
               Thank You, Sir, Could I
Have Another Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolmasters</ENAMEX> want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to lift the
ban on their fundamental human right to hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with a stick.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX>, school beatings were banned from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, bringing them in line with state-run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> where
caning was outlawed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years ago</TIMEX>.

            "I believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should not intervene in
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> bring up their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. This is dictatorial and an example of the
nanny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,'' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Williamson</ENAMEX>, headmaster of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> Fellowship
School in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liverpool</ENAMEX>, which is leading the protest. "It's a slippery slope.
First you can't thrash them, next you can't give them a good boot in the ribs,
then no summary executions of the really impertinent ones," he did not add, nor
did he emphasize his point by menacingly slapping his palm with the "Fellowship
Stick," as he does not call it since it does not exist.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX> was unimpressed with the spanking-obsessed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">schoolmasters</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> is itself against corporal punishment so it
is unlikely to uphold any arguments that the new provision against caning is an
infringement of human rights,'' she said

            
               See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX>. See
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett Koop</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Everett</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Which were actual topics
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today in Health Chat</ENAMEX>," a regular feature on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Everett Koop</ENAMEX>'s
Web site, and which are
cheap attempts to mock a beloved national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>'s efforts to cash in on this
whole Internet thing?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Itches</ENAMEX>!"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stay-at-Home Moms</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Stay at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Least 500 Yards Away</ENAMEX> Due to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
Order Dads"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love the Swelling, Hate the Redness</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "Memory Loss or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "What Was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Last One Again?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "Does <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Smell Funny?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> With MS"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Women With Motorcycles--Nude</ENAMEX>! Nude! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NUDE</ENAMEX>!!"

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. "Adios, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Señor Spleen</ENAMEX>"

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ostomates</ENAMEX>"

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. "Tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance</ENAMEX>"

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. "Tough <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guys Do Dance With Ultra-Hot</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ostomates</ENAMEX>"

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conquering Self-Abuse</ENAMEX>"

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shirtless Pictures</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop</ENAMEX> for Those Who
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Surrender to Self-Abuse</ENAMEX>"

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. "Don't Pick at
It!"

            
               Actual Topics
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 5, 8, 11, 12</TIMEX>, and
14.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Burning heretics.

         
      
   
