
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999>How Much Would <I>You</I> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sell</ENAMEX> For?</SPAN></SPAN>

             

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 28</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover editorial accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of covering
up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economic misbehavior. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> money-laundering probe destroys
the illusion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy is becoming civilized. The West should
admit that loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> are a naked effort to avert <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">implosion</ENAMEX>.
... A piece reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are auctioning their
services on Internet sites such as <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX>bid4geeks.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  New
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story calls for an end to racial profiling.
Eliminating racial profiling will make policing more difficult, but the cost is
worth bearing because profiling burdens targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, engenders rage against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, and undercuts the ideal of a colorblind society. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> exhorts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> to answer the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>
question. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't want another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> burdened by explosive
secrets.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 29</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story condemns the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Milosevic Generation</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">twentysomethings</ENAMEX> are both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">despairing</ENAMEX> and corrupt. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sponsor girls</ENAMEX>" trade sex for pilfered designer
clothing. Most young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> are plotting to emigrate because there are no
opportunities at home. All deny atrocities occurred in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
... A profile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Anthony</ENAMEX> as the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>.
The crooner followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky Martin</ENAMEX>'s footsteps from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menudo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> pop stardom,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Anthony</ENAMEX>'s angelic voice and passionate presentation will trump
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>'s bubblegum appeal. His English-language debut should finally bring him
crossover success.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> joins the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">above</NUMEX>) in
focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>. A sympathetic article about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> draft
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dodgers</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of them crossed into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> to avoid serving in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 2 percent</NUMEX> have been granted political asylum, and few are
authorized to work. Visas to Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are rarely granted.
... A piece denounces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Haig</ENAMEX> for parlaying his brief
stint as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX> into a career as an international
influence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peddler</ENAMEX>. The former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> helps defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> sell weapons
to dicey <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 30</TIMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Institute of Technology</ENAMEX> vaults from <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> university rankings . Its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-to-one</TIMEX>
student-faculty ratio is much praised, as is its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> spending of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$192,000</NUMEX> on
each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> revised its methodology to reward high spending on
instruction.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cal Tech</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> undergrads are so hard-working that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> computer
science <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> is scheduled from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight to 2 a.m.</TIMEX> ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> fill out the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swarthmore</ENAMEX> is the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> . ... An article claims that research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> are refocusing on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undergraduates</ENAMEX> in response to charges that they take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> for granted.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX>, for example, forced its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize winners to teach</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undergraduates</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 30</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomer</ENAMEX>'s first-person account of taking
care of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly parents</ENAMEX>. ... A poll finds that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>
use should disqualify <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> from office. A related article says the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> flap may have exposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>'s campaign
as ill prepared. ... A piece reports on anti-drug <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mormon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> who are
terrorizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Straight Edgers</ENAMEX>" get their high from fighting.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> are on trial for murder, and a vegan <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Straight Edger</ENAMEX> just finished
probation for firebombing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story presents a kinder, gentler portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> call the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Software</ENAMEX>" may throw temper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tantrums</ENAMEX> and compete fiercely, but he's basically a fun-loving family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">prefers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedans</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">limousines</ENAMEX> and breaks into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> for kicks. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> reveals that he recently transferred a huge chunk of stock to his
charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>, boosting its endowment to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 billion</NUMEX>. ... An
excerpt from a book based on a survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> reveals
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> don't want more time with their working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, they want mom
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> to make more money.

            

               
                  The
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6 and 13</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story counters the conventional wisdom that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
straw poll boosted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> and hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' second-place
finish proves that his support has a low ceiling, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s victory
demonstrates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is jerking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> back into the mainstream and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">successfully</ENAMEX> co-opting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> themes. ... An editorial applauds the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> for abandoning its singular focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> policy. More resources for economic development and alternative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> are the only way to quell guerrilla violence, ensure political stability,
and cut <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> production.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 30 and Sept.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
            

            The
cover
story crowns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s leading
conservative. He is especially lauded for his loyalty to "originalism," the
theory that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> should be interpreted in accord with original
intentions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> (as channeled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>). ... An editorial
laments the presidential campaign's substance deficit. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is
presenting policies for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' consideration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> are wooing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> with charm, biography, anodyne rhetoric,
and "calculated haze."

         
      
   
