
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> Hots Up

            The
Age of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melbourne</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with an "exclusive" report that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are systematically covering up their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> atrocities
by liquidating pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militiamen</ENAMEX> involved in the crimes. Quoting
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> defense and diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> has
received "detailed signals intelligence" about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military's plans
to cover its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> before a proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> human rights investigation. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> is believed to detail conversations between senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNI</ENAMEX>) figures in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Timor</ENAMEX> and possibly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> about silencing senior
and middle-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militiamen</ENAMEX> who may be persuaded to assist the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> with
inquiries," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">intelligence</ENAMEX> shows that "they will go to great
lengths--any length--to cover their tracks ahead of such inquiries," a source
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> . "The information is on the lines that if any militia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
show signs of splitting from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> ... or show signs of talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia members</ENAMEX> will be taken out, liquidated. There
are suggestions that deaths have already occurred there [in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Timor</ENAMEX>]."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a report of "a huge build-up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>" along
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Timor</ENAMEX> border, establishing a front line against militia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incursions</ENAMEX>. It
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> included most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. "A
pattern has emerged of militia launching small raids into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> to
confront the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Interfet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
Straits
Times reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Timor</ENAMEX> that pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> are
being trained by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> defectors to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Capt.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domingos Pereira</ENAMEX>, a company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of the notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aitarak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX>, told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that they hoped to step up cross-border attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> in a
month or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. "We don't have a chance in a conventional war," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pereira</ENAMEX> said at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> border training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> visited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. "But we can
make it very painful for them in a guerilla war. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> must die for
what they have done to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Post</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are
conducting a campaign of hatred and misinformation against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
peacekeeping force in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militiamen</ENAMEX> killed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in the territory <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> were described in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kompas</ENAMEX> , as "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Timorese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>." The
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terbit</ENAMEX> ran a photograph of charred bodies in a
burnt-out <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dili</ENAMEX> with a caption saying they had been set alight by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, whereas the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> all reported that they were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of militia terror.

            In an
editorial in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> edition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX>
called on the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golkar Party</ENAMEX> to dump <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J. Habibie</ENAMEX> as its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in the imminent presidential election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> not only bears the
"stigma" of the discredited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>, but he has also
performed very badly during his time in office, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "During that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May last year</TIMEX> up to the present, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> has seen its fortunes and
its international reputation sink lower and lower into the depths of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ignominy</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straits Times</ENAMEX> ran an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> condemning the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>
for opposing ratification of the global nuclear test ban treaty. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> "know they risk nuclear proliferation if they scuttle it" but will
do so because they "want to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> his top foreign policy
goal," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "If he fails, he cannot be faulted for trying. History
will note that it was a recalcitrant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> that killed the treaty
because of political infighting."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> reported that there were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">32,863 suicides</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>--the
highest number on record. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> could turn out almost as bad, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,056</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suicides</ENAMEX> reported during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX>. The problem is especially
severe among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">50s</NUMEX>, of whom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,103</NUMEX> killed themselves in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, an
increase of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45.7 per cent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. "The slumping economy, which forced many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to cut jobs, was singled out as a prime reason for the shocking
phenomenon," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX>
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has ordered complete safety inspections of all its
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> following <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s recent uranium plant accident. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Nuclear Corp.</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> disaster was due entirely to "poor
management and human error" and had nothing to do with nuclear technology. Of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> involved in the accident, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rookies</ENAMEX> and the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> had very little operational experience, it said. "Such practices are
totally forbidden in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. All nuclear power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> are required
to have licenses and be well-trained."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX>'s latest
electoral humiliation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> noted
that this was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> election defeat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Social Democrat</ENAMEX>
Party. "The state losses have come at such frequent intervals <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this autumn</TIMEX> that
each is known as a 'Black <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>,' " the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ran an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> about the surge of the extreme right in
the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> general election. It warned that the rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jörg Haider</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Party</ENAMEX>, is no less alarming because he may not be a
neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>. "As a clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">xenophobe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haider</ENAMEX> has taken care to make just enough
extreme statements to justify his 'credentials' with outright racists and
neo-Nazis, while mainly sticking to more acceptable forms of extremism," the
paper said. Noting that he blames whole classes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ills</ENAMEX>, it commented: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Singling</ENAMEX> out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> because of nationality is no less
racist than doing so because of skin color or religion. Though it is often
treated as a milder form of racism, there is no firewall of principle
separating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> form of racism from another. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haider</ENAMEX> is now the most
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">xenophobe politician</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. If his hate politics are not
universally ostracized, his power could well grow, with ramifications that go
far beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> itself."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> has decided to shelve
plans for the beatification of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Pius</ENAMEX> XII <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> because of the new
allegations that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pius XII</ENAMEX> didn't do enough to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> during
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the pope "did not want to bring to its conclusion"
a beatification "which divided instead of unifying" different religions and
cultures.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, Le Monde
led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s decision to allow the extradition of Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> to stand trial. Welcoming the decision in an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said it "creates a precedent: No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> or tyrant may
cite national sovereignty to claim impunity from justice."

            The
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> fronted the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heinz Co.</ENAMEX> is considering
halting production of its "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad cream</ENAMEX>," which it created for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX> and promoted with the slogan, "There's a tang to living when
there's a tang to what you eat." Sales have fallen dramatically as consumers
have turned instead to vinaigrettes, salsas, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mayonnaise</ENAMEX>. Labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament Dennis Turner</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Commons</ENAMEX> catering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>, said the loss would be a disaster. "It's one of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foods</ENAMEX> like roast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> and pork crackling," he explained.

         
      
   
