
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">258</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss Dis&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Fill in the blank
as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Levrat</ENAMEX> assesses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s referendum on asylum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX>: "There is a
side to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> that is very generous, giving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, and a
stricter side that wants to make sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming in are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">____________</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 257</ENAMEX>)--"Big 'n' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sturdy":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veerabhadran Ramanathan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> from the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Foundation</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripps Institution</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oceanography</ENAMEX> was surprised by
the extent, thickness, and persistence. Of what?
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deepak Chopra</ENAMEX>'s toupee."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gina Duclayan</ENAMEX>
            

            "Jenna
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elfman</ENAMEX>'s hips."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Rejection letters regarding grant requests."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Terns</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
belly lox at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barney Greengrass</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Scheft</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
cloud of doom over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>'s campaign."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlin</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            The worst part about the sea, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramanathan</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripps Institution</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oceanography</ENAMEX> must both lament when it comes time for
their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> talent show, is that nothing amusing ever takes place beneath it.
Which you certainly couldn't say about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Errol Flynn</ENAMEX>. Which is why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noël Coward</ENAMEX>
set so few of his plays underwater. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, is always
poking about in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villain</ENAMEX>'s undersea lair, and his attempts at repartee are
just parody bait. When the diving suits go on, the witty banter stops.
Something to do with all those air hoses, like trying to be witty at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>. It is impossible to name a single amusing movie that takes place
beneath the waves. Just look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX>, the very model of marine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sophistication</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> whose intelligence we're always called upon to
admire like some horrible precocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. They're frequently found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX>
World, performing in shows whose dialogue will not be quoted later at dinner.
In some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, they'd be the dinner. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">dolphin</ENAMEX>, not the precocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
Although it's a thought.

            There are, of course,
many elegant and flirtatious scenes set on yachts. Clearly, wit operates best
on the surface.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vast Polluted</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramanathan</ENAMEX> announced the discovery of a vast haze,
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3.8 million square miles</NUMEX>, about the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, hanging over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Ocean</ENAMEX>. "It appeared as if the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subcontinent</ENAMEX> was surrounded
by a mountain of pollution," he said.

            The problem with this haze, blown over the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> by
winter winds from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX>, is that it blocks out sunlight, lowering the
temperature.

            The prevailing winds
reverse in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late spring</TIMEX>, blowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">haze</ENAMEX> north over the land, where its
particles combine with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monsoon rains</ENAMEX> and fall to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, dissipating the
cloud. But that's bad too, because the haze-sodden precipitation is just the
sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> that plays havoc with both terrestrial and marine life.

            
               Entangling
Alliances Extra
            

            Below, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> putative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wedding</ENAMEX>" page. Which is
true, which is false?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dentist marries lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer marries</ENAMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> marries law firm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> law school marries <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX> marries <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> marries other Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Mis</ENAMEX> marries other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Mis</ENAMEX> .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan Stanley</ENAMEX> marries <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ING Barings</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consultatio Asset Management</ENAMEX> marries <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hicks Muse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tate & Furst</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Unit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">VH1</TIMEX> marries line <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Performances</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. Psychotherapist marries ob-gyn.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Aerobics instructor</ENAMEX>
marries funeral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>.

            

               Answers
            

            All are true.

            
               Best
Career
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bride</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>, is the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Commissioner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Police Department</ENAMEX>. She is also a cabaret
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">singer</ENAMEX>."

            
               Worst
Career
            

            "She
is the assistant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Franken</ENAMEX>."

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Comical foreign names, nautical penises.

         
      
   
