
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real American Love Story</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> broadcast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An American Love</ENAMEX>
Story --a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10-hour</TIMEX> film about an interracial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--spawned a great deal of
chatter to the effect that mixed-race couplings were the wave of the future. In
fact, they are the wave of the past. Interracial marriages accounted for only
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.2 percent</NUMEX> of all marriages in the Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Population Survey</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, a gain
of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only two-tenths of</NUMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, and the number of mixed couplings
actually decreased slightly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. The census pattern suggests that slightly
more interracial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> will fall into each other's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming years</TIMEX>
but that there will be nothing resembling a dramatic acceleration of marriage
across the color line.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> already has almost 400 years of race
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mixing behind it</ENAMEX>, beginning with that first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> that sailed into
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamestown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> who were already pregnant by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have grudgingly accepted the fact that sex between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> and
slaves such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX> was frequent, leading to a
many-hued race of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do not look <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> at all, even though they call
themselves "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>." Outside of recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, there are virtually no black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of purely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">descent</ENAMEX>, which is to say no black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who lack white ancestry, left in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four centuries</TIMEX> of race
mixing have had a similar impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who define themselves as white.
Convincing estimates show that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> had
some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> ancestry. This inheritance most often arrived at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> door
in the form of a fair-skinned black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who had slipped over the color line
to live as white. Put another way, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veins</ENAMEX> think of themselves as white and conduct themselves as such--and check
"white" when they fill out census forms.

            How did so much "black" blood get into so many "white"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>? Consider the story behind the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loving</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> ,
in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> overturned laws in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that forbade black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to marry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Loving</ENAMEX> was white and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mildred Jeter</ENAMEX>
was black. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> after the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were married, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caroline County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sheriff</ENAMEX> dragged them from their marriage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bed and</ENAMEX> jailed them for the crime of
being married. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lovings</ENAMEX> were then exiled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> under pain of
imprisonment. In banishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Dominion</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caroline</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> said from the bench: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Almighty God</ENAMEX> created the races, white,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX>, yellow, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>, and red and placed them on separate continents, and but
for the interference with his arrangement there would be no cause for such
marriages. The fact that he separated the races shows that he did not intend
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> to mix."

            This statement would have
been ludicrous anyplace but was especially laughable in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caroline County</ENAMEX>--and in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lovings</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Point</ENAMEX>, which had been an epicenter of race
mixing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 200 years</TIMEX>. There were many such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>, for example, white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
and their fair-skinned black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> lived so close together that they bumped
into each other on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. Mixed-race <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were initially treated as a
"new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" who existed in the space between white and black and deserved a
status not quite as high as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> but higher than that of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
general. This special status began to dry up just before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX> and
evaporated when slavery ended and free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> competed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> for jobs and
political power. White <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> became obsessed with drawing an impossible
line that would preserve white "racial purity"--another way of referring to
white political dominance. The "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-drop rule" defined as black anyone who had
any black ancestry at all, even if that ancestry was invisible to the naked eye
or in the genealogical record. Those who fell on the black side of the law
often lost the rights to vote, to hold high-status jobs, and to defend their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> and property in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>.

            The revocation of special mulatto rights accelerated the
practice of passing for white. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Point</ENAMEX> was locally known as the "passing
capital of the world." Passing for white was so common there that a section of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Point</ENAMEX> had actually been named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Passing</ENAMEX>.'' Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Pointers</ENAMEX> lived
as negroes at home but crossed the line to seize white privileges just an hour
or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two</NUMEX> away in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX> Local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were often taken for white during
excursions to nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, where they shopped in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> that did not serve
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and were admitted to the "white only" sections of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>.

            Having learned the
rewards of whiteness early, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> grew up, moved away, and continued
the charade. Those who entered the armed forces, which were segregated until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, were often classified as white and attached to all-white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. This made
for dicey moments when brown-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Point</ENAMEX> turned up in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">all-black</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. Some of these former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> kept the secret, but a few
exposed the passers as frauds. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> had laws that forbade
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">interracial</ENAMEX> marriage, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> had no clue what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanks</ENAMEX>
were going on about when they argued over who was really white or really black.
To the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, race was defined by what you looked like: If you
looked white, well then, you were.

            Back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caroline County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who were passing were
sure to travel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> alone to prevent their white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> from knowing who and
what they were. The passers from Passing married white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>, moved into
white jobs, took up residence in white neighborhoods. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> returned
to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Point</ENAMEX> to visit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> went along with the masquerade. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ditched</ENAMEX> brown-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> stayed out of school
to avoid being seen on the colored bus headed to the colored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Principals</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> stuck to the script. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebony</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Point</ENAMEX> had "infiltrated the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> more than any
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroes</ENAMEX>. When a student plays hooky from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and
says an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">in-law</ENAMEX> is visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, we understand. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just can't
afford to catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro school</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> without giving away the racial
identity."

            This infiltration was
common not just in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> but all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The most
interesting document listed in the amicus briefs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loving</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
is a statistical study called "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African Ancestry</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White American</ENAMEX>
Population" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Stuckert</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> and anthropologist from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuckert</ENAMEX>'s statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are tough going, but
eye-opening for what they show. Simply put, he examined census and fertility
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> to arrive at estimates of how many white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> lines
and how many fair-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> had crossed over the line to live as white.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuckert</ENAMEX>'s tables show that during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX> alone, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly 15,550</NUMEX> fair-skinned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> per year slipped across the color line--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 155,500</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuckert</ENAMEX> estimates that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>--or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 28</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> classified as "white" in the census--had
black ancestry within the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>. He predicted that the
proportion would only grow in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming decades</TIMEX>. The belief that one's
ancestors are "racially uniform" is a basic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> fiction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuckert</ENAMEX> wrote,
but a fiction nonetheless.

         
      
   
