
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward W. Said</ENAMEX>

            The game of biographical "gotcha" is a perennially
popular form of ideological blood sport. The goal is to find an incriminating
datum that will leave a permanent stain on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>'s reputation, make his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craven apologists</ENAMEX>, and give the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> a ready-made
judgment that can be wielded without too much reading or thought. If the
anti-communism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Orwell</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Koestler</ENAMEX> bugs you, you can point to
recent allegations that the former was a snitch and the latter a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX>. If you
resent the fact that your college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> forced you to read I, Rigoberta
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menchú</ENAMEX> , you can rejoice in the discovery that she embellished some
important details of her life story. Didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX> beat his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>? And what
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX>'s thing for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> and his taste for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>?

            To this list now add
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> literature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward W. Said</ENAMEX>, the subject of a fiercely debated
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commentary</ENAMEX> . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Israeli</TIMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justus Reid Weiner</ENAMEX>, contends
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>, who was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>, has
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> deliberately obscured some facts about his early life, and
amplified others, in order to create the impression that he was, of all things,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>.

            Not so fast, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weiner</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s childhood was not "the
parable of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> identity" marked by dispossession from a beloved
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">homeland</ENAMEX> and the subsequent pain of exile. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> "grew up not in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>, where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, had moved as an
economic expatriate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately nine years</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>'s birth and had
become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of a thriving business; and there, until his own departure for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as a teenager in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>, the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX> resided in
luxurious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>, attended private <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and played tennis at
the exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gezira Sporting Club</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of its few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>."

            A similar account of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> can be found in a new book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Out of Place</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of which is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX>. The book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> , is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wrenching</ENAMEX>, intimate account of growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>'s wealthy Levantine
expatriate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, of summering in the dreary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort town</ENAMEX> of Dhour
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">el Shweir</ENAMEX>, and of visiting the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, sometimes for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">as long</TIMEX>
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weiner</ENAMEX> claims that the memoir is an elaborate sleight of
hand and speculates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> decided to "spin" the story of his past--by
telling the truth about it--when he heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weiner</ENAMEX>'s inquiries. In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> since his essay appeared, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weiner</ENAMEX>'s motives, methods, and assertions have
been roundly attacked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weiner</ENAMEX> has made some attempt
at clarification. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a recap of the controversy and links to relevant
articles, or click here for my review of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Out of Place</ENAMEX> .)

            Just who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s real estate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holdings</ENAMEX> and his grammar school records rate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX> words in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Commentary</ENAMEX> ,
not to mention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of research by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Center for Public Affairs</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Followers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> politics, as well
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> often appears,
know him as an eloquent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> cause. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> of The
Nation know him as a formidable reviewer of opera and classical music.
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate students</ENAMEX> in a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciplines</ENAMEX> know him as
the author of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientalism</ENAMEX> . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> who make up the
membership of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Language Association</ENAMEX>--minus one who resigned in
protest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s election--know him as Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Hayat</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>-language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Ahram</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>, know him as a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> on politics
and culture. Each of these identities--political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>, literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>,
university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>--are, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s case, inordinately
complex in and of themselves. The tensions between them--between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aesthetic</ENAMEX>, and political impulses that are felt with enormous passion and
expressed with great vehemence--make Said an uncommonly interesting, and
endlessly controversial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual figure</ENAMEX>.

            Most controversial--and
most misunderstood--has been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> affairs. He has
published <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> books on the plight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, including
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Question of Palestine</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After the Last Sky</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), and
Peace and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Its Discontents</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), a scathing critique of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> peace
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accords</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> calls "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles</ENAMEX>." These writings, his
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>, and his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> of service in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestine National Council</ENAMEX> (the now-defunct <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exile</ENAMEX>, from which he resigned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> after being diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>) have
invited smears and misrepresentations: A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade ago</TIMEX> Commentary branded
him "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of Terror." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> once called him
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>." And he showed up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>, unnamed, in
The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's special "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" issue as a well-dressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">don</ENAMEX> rumored to be "on the payroll of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX>."

            Until very recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> has been an insistent voice for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> statehood: He helped to draft the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Algiers Declaration</ENAMEX>" of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, which linked this aspiration to the recognition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s right to
exist. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, he has often said that his own place in such a state
would be as its toughest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>. Even as he has been unsparing in his
indictments of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> policy, he has not let <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>--or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>--off the hook. He has assailed the corrupt,
authoritarian regimes that rule most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world, punctured the
ideological phantasms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabist</ENAMEX> nationalism and reactionary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islam</ENAMEX> alike,
and bemoaned the impoverished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> cultural and intellectual life. He
has also, within the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, been a consistent advocate of
reconciliation with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of terrorism. The Question of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestine</ENAMEX> called for a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-state solution" at a time when the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambition</ENAMEX> was total control over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Mandatory Palestine</ENAMEX>. The book,
published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, had, as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'90s</TIMEX>, never been translated
into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> or published in any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, in the wake of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Camp David</ENAMEX> accords, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> delivered a message from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Cyrus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vance</ENAMEX> to one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> indicating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would
recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> as a legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> to peace talks in exchange for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> ignored the message. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX> shook hands on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">lawn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>, who had been invited to the event by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>,
stayed home. Since then, as bien-pensant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> opinion has embraced
the "peace process," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> has bemoaned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s "capitulation" and grown
increasingly disgusted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s dictatorial rule over a few scraps
of occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">territory</ENAMEX> and with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s continued expropriation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
lands. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>, he wrote that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> toward which the peace process seemed, however pokily, to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tending</ENAMEX> could not provide democracy and justice for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. Instead,
he called for a single, "bi-national" state based on a constitution (something
neither <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> nor the areas controlled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> currently
has), with "the idea and practice of citizenship, not of ethnic or racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, as the main vehicle for coexistence."

            But to treat Said solely, or even primarily, as a political
figure is necessarily to produce a distorted view of his life. He is, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and
foremost, a literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, who wrote his Ph.D. at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>--on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Conrad</ENAMEX>,
a lifelong obsession--under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Levin</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> of a comparative
approach to literary study. Said's subsequent work has retained much of the
expansive spirit and rigorous methodology of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>'s teachings. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Beginnings:</ENAMEX>
Intention and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Method</ENAMEX> , the book which made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s academic reputation, is a
bulky study of how novels begin, carried out through painstakingly close formal
analysis and displaying crushing erudition.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s fame outside
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> rests on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientalism</ENAMEX> , his sweeping account of how
Western art, literature, and scholarship have produced a deformed, biased
picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> culture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of colonial domination. The
impact of Orientalism far exceeded its subject, vast though that was. In
addition to laying the groundwork for "post-colonial" studies as an area of
inquiry, the book inspired a flurry of scholarship devoted to "the other"--to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who, by virtue of race, gender, sexuality, or geographical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">location</ENAMEX>, are unable to represent themselves and so (to echo the line from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> that serves as the book's epigraph) "must be represented" by those more
powerful. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orientalism</ENAMEX> , with its harsh critiques of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">philology</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> social science, contributed to an epistemological shift
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional</ENAMEX> disciplines were no longer to be taken for
granted as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> of objective knowledge but themselves became the
objects of ideological analysis.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s methods and his substantive claims have come
under attack. Because his theoretical debt to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel Foucault</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unabashedly</ENAMEX> political intentions marked him as an avatar of the emerging
academic left, a lot of the criticism came from traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> , for example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>, one of the chief modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientalism</ENAMEX> , decried <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s
inflammatory tone and questioned his knowledge of history, philology, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>. (To read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' piece, click here. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s angry response, click here.) But the most sustained assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientalism</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premises</ENAMEX>, and on its prestige, came from the left. In a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In</ENAMEX>
Theory --a wholesale slaughter of the sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> of the postmodern Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian Marxist</ENAMEX> literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aijaz Ahmad</ENAMEX> raised further
questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s mastery of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> and accused him of
self-aggrandizement and insufficient political discipline. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX>
attacks Said for trashing the norms and values of traditional scholarship,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmad</ENAMEX> rebukes him for hewing too closely to them. And while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> believes Said
to be motivated by a crude anti-Western leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">animus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmad</ENAMEX> finds him
altogether too enamored of the canons of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> literature and avers that
Said possesses "a very conservative mind, essentially <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> in its
structure."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmad</ENAMEX> are both
right. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientalism</ENAMEX> and its even more ambitious sequel Culture and
Imperialism are works of passionate, almost agonized ambivalence. To read
them is to encounter a mind at war with itself and the world (and ready to go
to war with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, as any number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> over the past
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quarter-century</ENAMEX> will show). Said's evident love of the literature and music of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> continually collides with his righteous anger at what the West has
done to the rest. His desire to use literary criticism as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> on the side
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oppressed</ENAMEX> sits athwart the pleasure he takes in letting his mind play
over the meaning in a novel or a poem. The results are books at once exhausting
in their detail and maddening in their omissions, uneven in tone, overreaching
and underargued. "He is easily distracted" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leonard</ENAMEX> remarked in
an appreciative review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture and Imperialism</ENAMEX> , "answering too many
fire alarms, sometimes to pour on more petrol."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> rientalism and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture and Imperialism</ENAMEX> are
unquestionably incendiary, but they are also permanent and exemplary works of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-20 th -century</TIMEX> criticism, in no small part because they invite so
much argument, because for all the intellectual authority they project they
remain open, vulnerable, provisional. And they also fulfill the basic mandate
of literary analysis, which is to illuminate the works they discuss: To return
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verdi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aida , Conrad's Heart of Darkness</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kipling</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> after reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> on them is to find them richer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>, and
more complicated than you had ever imagined.

            More than anyone else in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX>
Said has sought to embody an unfashionable, perhaps obsolescent idea of the
intellectual--immersed in culture and committed to politics, placing "criticism
over solidarity," speaking truth to power, and steering clear of gods that
fail. There was a time when this idea flourished more widely--even in the pages
of Commentary .

         
      
   
