
   
   
      
         
            Free Shows

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               " " ' s disgusting letter concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> and
gift parity, along with her psychotically misguided ideas of the whys and
wherefores of giving gifts are a great deal more than "alarming." I found
myself deeply troubled by her fantastical notions and saddened by the
possibility that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> might be taught these same ideas. Needless to
say, I thought your response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RS</ENAMEX> was absolutely correct.
            

            
               Nevertheless, I must
take issue with your slander of mercenaries. A mercenary makes it clear he/she
is fighting for money, not attempting to hide the expectation of booty behind a
wedding invitation.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cordially</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ML III</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear M</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thanks you for
your support and regrets that she may have insulted official mercenaries. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RS</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> with the tally sheet, is by any chance reading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s
Prudie, she may be interested to know that there was much mail essentially
calling her a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with a cash register where her heart ought to be.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, assuredly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               As a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> approaching <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>, I am confused
about how I am supposed to react to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s fashions. At a recent conference of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, we were seated around a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-shaped table--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>--with no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tablecloth</ENAMEX>. Several of these professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> across from me were wearing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> skirts. They spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the entire</TIMEX> meeting pulling their skirts down so
their lingerie preferences were not so obvious. Am I supposed to look at the
ceiling the entire meeting, steal the occasional glance, or just assume it's a
'90s thing?
            

            
               Along these same
lines, I was recently in a retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> had on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> dress. As
she leaned over the counter to hand me my purchase, it became clear that her
lingerie preference was none at all. I didn't know whether to stare at the
ceiling, pretend I saw nothing, or thank her for the free show. In both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instances</ENAMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had to know that everyone was getting an eyeful. I
missed the era of free love while in grade school and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">am</TIMEX> wondering if we are
now in the era of free looks.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Somewhat Dazed</ENAMEX> and Confused
            

            Dear Some,

            You have nicely named our new era. Fashion is deep
into spandex and see-through, with the off-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-shoulder style occasionally
revealing a stray <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boob</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s</NUMEX> motto, "Let it all hang out," has moved
from emotions to body parts.

             Clothing is meant to
cover or reveal. The look-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-me outfits say just that. As for your particular
question about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> skirts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> minus underwear, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do not purchase their clothes in the dark, so whatever is able to
be seen is fair game for whatever response feels natural. You may even stare if
you like. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> gives you permission.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, permissively

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Maybe you can help with this problem. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
and I have a subscription to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s symphony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX>. Sometimes things
come up that prevent us from using our tickets. When this happens we give them
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who are also classical music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. We have made it clear to this
couple we expect nothing in return, as we have already paid for the tickets
that would go to waste if they didn't use them. However, being polite people
and good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> has, as a gesture of thanks, invited us to
be their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> at a minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I are not
enthusiastic about this, especially since getting there requires a drive of
close to an hour. But we don't want to appear ungrateful to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or hurt
their feelings. (We can't use the "We're busy" excuse, because they've given us
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different dates to choose from.)
            

            
               Is there a graceful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of declining, or have you some suggestions for handling this
dilemma?
            

            
               
--In Need of Help in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear In</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie sympathizes with your feelings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ix</NUMEX>-nay on
the ballgame ... she, herself, having been briefly shown on national TV reading
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> game and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Bowl</ENAMEX>.

            It is best to be upfront, both to handle the matter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">truthfully</ENAMEX>, as well as to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">scotch</ENAMEX> baseball invitations on into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> therefore suggests you tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) you are most appreciative
that they wish to reciprocate; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) neither you nor your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is a sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
long car rides hurt your behinds; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) a leisurely dinner, just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of
you, would be much more to your liking.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> believes there
are certain occasions when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> plays along in order to spare someone's
feelings. This is not one of them.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, decidedly

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>,
Prudie,
               
            

            
               The tone of "" about
that "geezer" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Hefner</ENAMEX> rather surprises me. Really Confused seems to want to
criticize Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hefner</ENAMEX> because he is no longer a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 30</TIMEX>, yet he still
manages to attract the attentions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> young attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Would Really
Confused be less confused if Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hefner</ENAMEX> were a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gen-Xer</ENAMEX>? Would you be less
critical of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> if Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hefner</ENAMEX> were under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">30</ENAMEX>? In other words, it
appears that numbers are driving the argument here, and I can't tell if it's
the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, any number over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, or an interaction effect.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantitatively Questioning the Quality of Life</ENAMEX>, a k a SB-B
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Quant</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie can't speak for
Really Confused, so she will speak for herself. If Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hefner</ENAMEX> were under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>,
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX> would no doubt be an implied tribute to his
attractiveness. At the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>-something, however, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> has about it the
barest whiff of self-serving motives. Without the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>, the money, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous friends</ENAMEX>, and the publicity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks the object of their affections
would be just another eccentric old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who stays in his pajamas. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has
wondered in the past, in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, why do geezers with young
girlfriends not know that they might as well glue an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express Gold Card</ENAMEX>
to their foreheads? Oh, well. As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> component, let's not go there,
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> say.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
appropriately

         
      
   
