
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round</ENAMEX>-Up

            What happened--old as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hills</ENAMEX>, ancient as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ax</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in a clay cup, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> under the fingernails.
The river forgets the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and the winter sun slides
beyond the far hills. All of them had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, and all
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> sang while swimming and as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> sang
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> left the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> which ringed the water
for the clouds where the distance whispered a different dream
than the dream dreaming this

            dark <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. The men
were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> not that long ago--
delicate, confident paddling alongside their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
through the hot <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> dark green with splash and shout--
summer just a whistle and gone.
Of course, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> will still hold stars,
the moon's journey, the planet's orbit. There will
always be nests, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX>, the swaying and the saying.
They have names and are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> exactly like you
lined up in jackets, boots and caps--
cold with the waiting.

            It is unbelievable, even
some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
begin to sob. Trucked out to no-where
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, plumbers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>.
It is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, snow rides the collapse of clouds.
There are just shades of brown and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grey</ENAMEX>,
a line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>--a dark scribble
like markings done by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.

            As each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is shot,
whether he drops backward
or to the side
he forgets us, his own name, this place,
civilization
like the kiss

            in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> at the lit
threshold
whose intent was to swear return.

         
      
   
