
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s Most Wanted

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> update: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is offering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> for
information leading to the arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>. The offer also applies
to other alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. The hopeful spin: It will put teeth in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>'s indictment. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reservists</ENAMEX> blocked roads
and pledged not to move until they are paid. They have not collected their
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5-</NUMEX>a-day wages since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Violence continues. Ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> torched
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> fired on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The post-conflict
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-mortem</ENAMEX> continues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> 's defense of his negotiations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> ("My job was not to make moral judgments"). (Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s
""
in 
                  Slate
                on why the war's outcome should leave pundits
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blushing</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians</ENAMEX> will unionize against managed care. The American
Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> voted to form a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> to negotiate for better wages and
working conditions but promised never to strike. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spins: 1</ENAMEX>) Collective
bargaining will win <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> more control over the type and quantity of
medication they prescribe, resulting in better care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Collective
bargaining will win <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> higher pay, resulting in higher costs for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> barred lawsuits against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> for violating federal
laws. Individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> will no longer be able to sue states that
violate federal laws; only the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> may do so. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX> called
this a coup for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> protested that the ruling emasculates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' power to bind states
to federal law. Law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erwin Chemerinsky</ENAMEX> opines in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> that the decision is
"the height of conservative judicial activism" because it "invented new rights
for state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> at the expense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>."

             

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> restricted its definition of physical
disability. The court ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose impairments can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">corrected</ENAMEX> (with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, eyeglasses, or the like) aren't eligible for
protection from job discrimination under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Americans With Disabilities Act</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Employers</ENAMEX> were relieved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> for the disabled fumed at "the absurd result
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> being disabled enough to be fired from a job, but not disabled
enough to challenge the firing." The 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
                predicts that the decision will
spark a legal fight over the definition of correctability and urges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to
revise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADA</ENAMEX>'s ambiguities.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial ended after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> of testimony. A
ruling is expected in late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX>. Early verdicts from the press: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The ruling
will tame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and hearten its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The trial itself has
already tamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and heartened its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahlia Lithwick</ENAMEX>'s
"" in 
                  Slate
                for the play-by-play.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> as a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> is charged with covering up his and Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legal work on a crooked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> land deal. The trial, scheduled to
begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>, is expected to coincide with her announcement of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
candidacy.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> says he will run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> emphasized his middle-of-the-road politics, working-class roots, and
low expectations of success. He told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that he's running because "if
something happens to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, I don't know if we would have an
alternative who could beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> voucher plan is being challenged in
court. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-in-the-nation plan--which subsidizes
private or parochial school tuition for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in "failing" public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> who
choose to transfer--contend that it violates church-state boundaries. A win
could jeopardize nascent voucher programs in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, as well as the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of dollars <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> already spends on private, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>-linked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> lied to customs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columba Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, declared <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $500</NUMEX> worth of goods upon her return from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> vacation, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> found <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19,000</NUMEX> in receipts in her passport and fined
her <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,100</NUMEX> on the spot. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> claimed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> low-balled only because
she was embarrassed to confess to him how much she'd blown on clothes and
jewelry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Politicos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> told the 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
                that the gaffe won't hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb</ENAMEX> or his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> defeated a plan to restrict <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> steel imports. The
steel industry had lobbied ardently for the bill, claiming that imports are
sapping business and eating jobs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, and a slew of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> opposed the bill, agreeing that it would
invite protectionist retaliation from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Chapman</ENAMEX> concurs that steel jobs are being lost
because of increased productivity: "a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> simply aren't needed
anymore, and no amount of xenophobia will alter that."

            

               A federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> is deciding if and how to tax Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commerce</ENAMEX>. The newly convened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is supposed to deliver its findings
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2001</TIMEX>, when the current ban on e-commerce taxes expires. The
free-market spin: An online sales tax will drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> to overseas
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> and hinder e-commerce's explosive growth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> spin:
Explosive e-commerce growth fueled by no-tax shopping will decimate state
revenues. The traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>' spin: Explosive e-commerce growth fueled
by no-tax shopping will decimate us .

            

               Brain surgery was successfully performed on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, surgeons operated in vivo on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 6-month-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> suffering from
excessive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in his brain. They jubilantly announced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, born in
May, shows no sign of the congenital condition. The disclaimer: They won't know
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> is brain damaged.

            

               A serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> is on the loose
               . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">declared Rafael Resendez-Ramirez</ENAMEX>, suspected of murdering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Enemy No. 1</ENAMEX>." All of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">offed</ENAMEX> near railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX>, leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> is
traveling on freight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> is making Europeans ill. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> products were removed
from store shelves in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> after
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drinkers</ENAMEX> complained of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nausea</ENAMEX> and intestinal trouble. (See "" for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> reaction.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> traced the problem to a preservative used on
shipping pallets and a bad batch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX>, neither of which presents a
serious health threat. Financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say the serious threat is to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>'s
overseas sales, which make up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> of its profits.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Edward</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophie Rhys-Jones</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commoner</ENAMEX> and a public relations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> staged a more casual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wedding than Edward</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> did, dispensing with superformal dress, showy
titles, and a postnuptial smooch. The post-game analysis: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) They're very shy.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) They're very media savvy; by avoiding the pomp of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weddings</ENAMEX>, they signaled to the press that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> will be scandal-free. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
Informal, my bum. They are moving to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> equipped with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">water</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> strainers. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Check Monday's "</ENAMEX>" for saucy
commentary from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Explorers</ENAMEX> found the oldest deep-sea shipwreck yet. They
located <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>-holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> that sank near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s coast about
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,700 years ago</TIMEX>. They immediately posted their findings on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic Society</ENAMEX> 's Web site.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX> auctioned off love letters written to her by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>. The letters were purchased for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$156,000</NUMEX> by a software
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magnate</ENAMEX>, who promptly announced that he might return the notes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex Beam</ENAMEX>'s take on how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maynard</ENAMEX> has already auctioned
herself .) Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> will follow a previous tell-all
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX> with one of her own. The 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX>
                shudders at both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s eagerness to capitalize on their
relationships with the reclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> was badly hurt in a car accident. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> was
hit by a minivan while walking on the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> and
suffered a shattered leg and a collapsed lung.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Stars</ENAMEX> beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo Sabres</ENAMEX> to win their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> NHL
championship. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sabres</ENAMEX> protested the overtime victory, arguing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett Hull</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skate</ENAMEX> entered the crease as he was scoring the winning goal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Referees</ENAMEX> ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hull</ENAMEX> had possession of the puck both inside and outside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crease</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hockey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> called it the latest example of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>'s
championship hex.

         
      
   
