
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon Is Still Dead</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> resigned
the presidency, the conventional wisdom seems to hold that his once-abysmal
reputation has been largely rehabilitated. It's a familiar story: On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX> public approval rating, facing
a possible prison sentence; by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9, 1999</TIMEX>, he has been transformed into a
foreign-policy visionary, a domestic-policy liberal, and no worse a scoundrel
than lots of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>. "What had seemed impossible in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> had happened," his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Ambrose</ENAMEX> wrote (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX>
already). "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> was respectable, even honored, certainly admired."

            The historical irony is
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious</ENAMEX>--and spurious. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> talk as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> has already
been rehabilitated, and that's flat wrong. To be sure, there are favorable and
critical views of him, simple and complex ones. But the most vivid and enduring
remains the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> as our national political villain. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tricky Dick</ENAMEX> lives
on.

            Even in his early career, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had a reputation as a
comeback <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> he salvaged his spot as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Eisenhower</ENAMEX>'s running
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> with the famous "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Checkers</ENAMEX>" speech. He did it again when he won the
presidency in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> aired The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Obituary of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> . And we've been hearing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s latest rehabilitation
practically since the resignation itself. Yet too often, it has turned out to
be all hype and little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>.

            Take his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">prime-time</TIMEX> TV
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frost</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frost</ENAMEX>'s softball
questions would allow him to tell the public his side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> story
for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. While the broadcast drew <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 45 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>--the same
as an episode of the top-rated <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Days</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> won few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX>; after
the show, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lowered their opinions of him than raised them. He
remained, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> wrote in a typical review, "careless of the record,
heedless of the proper limits of power, unable to plead guilty to anything much
worse than 'screwing up' and coming no closer in history to that final
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">absolution</ENAMEX> in history he seeks."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nine years later</TIMEX>, though, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's turn to
pronounce a return to respectability, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">splashing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s photo on the cover with
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-page article, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-page interview, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> photographs inside. The
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, the article noted, had advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, written
several books, and made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> 's list of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's Hot</ENAMEX>." But, again,
what the large print gave, the fine print took away. Those who took the time to
read the article learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s support came mostly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
circles and that die-hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> scoffed at his alleged foreign policy
expertise. An accompanying poll found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> wished him to
remain in exile from public life. With the cover line--"He's Back"--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> unwittingly helped create the very phenomenon they were
supposedly just observing.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> following, various episodes served as
occasions for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> pundit or another to declare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s reputation restored.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> would visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>, or criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> policy in a
strategically leaked memo, or meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>; each time he was
pronounced rehabilitated, even as polls showed that he remained unpopular. His
death on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18, 1994</TIMEX>, brought a new zenith of revisionism: an outpouring of
praise from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and other public figures. Television and radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> aired a relentless parade of fond reminiscences about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, news
anchors drummed home the now-familiar lines about his comeback (again creating
the fact they were ostensibly just reporting), and the eulogies at the funeral
itself never once mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>.

            Yet even this final
rebound proved illusory. No sooner had the tributes subsided than an equally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vociferous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX> spoke up to denounce the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>-gloves treatment. Many
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most esteemed political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Baker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Halberstam, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX>--chastised their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> for soft-soaping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
life in death. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Haldeman Diaries</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month later</TIMEX>,
with its reminders of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s scheming, sinister side, confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>
would hardly be forgotten soon.

            Those proclaiming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s return miss the subtext of their
own proclamations. Implicit--and sometimes explicit--in every story about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s comeback has been the underlying story of his calculated efforts to
come back: He authored foreign-policy books, wined and dined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, and
waged court battles for control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tapes. These stories don't
dwell on any glorious new achievements on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s part. Rather, they underscore
his campaign for rehabilitation and the public's alleged willingness to grant
it. In his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Image</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Boorstin</ENAMEX> coined the term
"pseudo-event" to describe events that have no intrinsic news value but get
treated as if they do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s comeback is a classic pseudo-event, erected
almost entirely on self-fulfilling punditry--a series of interviews, a magazine
cover, a cascade of adoring eulogies.

            This doesn't mean that no
one is rethinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s achievements. He continues to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> busy.
(I'm writing a book about him myself.) And most of the recent major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon</ENAMEX>
books--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Parmet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Aitken</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Hoff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wicker</ENAMEX>, and (this
month) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin Gellman</ENAMEX>--have been quite sympathetic. Yet they haven't made much
of a dent in his overall reputation among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>. In the latest ranking of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> by professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX>
(admittedly no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RN</ENAMEX> finished in the bottom tier, alongside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulysses Grant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Harding</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Hoover</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Twenty</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> surveyed judged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s presidency a "failure"; none called it
"great."

            Besides, even more telling than the views of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> are
the images of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> in popular culture, where he remains resentful, paranoid,
and ruthlessly power-hungry. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> , for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> has
appeared in caricature <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 20</NUMEX> times (according to the "Simpsons
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archive</ENAMEX>" Web site). He's almost always portrayed as the dark, suspicious
figure circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. On various episodes he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bluebeard</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grim Reaper, of "the Jury of the Damned"</ENAMEX>; he takes part in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snake-bludgeoning</ENAMEX> (in a scandal exposed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> book); his enemies
list is used for dastardly purposes; even his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Checkers</ENAMEX> is said to be bound
for hell.

            Nor do <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movies show any sign of revising
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s image. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> gave us the familiar,
shadowy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, emphasizing his most savage and conspiratorial qualities.
"He's the darkness reaching out for the darkness," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Hunt</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dean</ENAMEX>
in the film. "Look at the landscape of his life and you'll see a boneyard." The
recently released <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> portrays the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX> wrote
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , "with his hunched shoulders, darting paranoid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gaze</ENAMEX> and crocodile grimace ... the quivering, skulking embodiment of a single
word: guilty." For now, that remains the most vivid and pervasive image of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> mind. And it's not likely to fade any time
soon.

         
      
   
