
   
   
      
         
             That '70s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gossip</ENAMEX>

            After making her way through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>,
Keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabs</ENAMEX> feels as though she's been stuck in a bit of a time warp. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabs</ENAMEX>, suffering from an overload of nostalgia, read like magazines one might
have thumbed through while waiting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Douglas</ENAMEX> or Merv
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffin</ENAMEX> shows. How else to explain headlines such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Lavin</ENAMEX> finds
happiness in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">heartland</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhoda</ENAMEX> shattered as charity folds"? (The latter
would, of course, be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valerie Harper</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in the failed
venture turned out to be none other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Weaver</ENAMEX>, television's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCloud</ENAMEX>.)
Why, there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dukes of Hazzard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Bach</ENAMEX> at a premiere! An
exclusive interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Nelson Reilly</ENAMEX>! A new album from the real-life
band that inspired the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Partridge Family</ENAMEX>! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , meanwhile, has
landed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">showbiz insider</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlene Tilton</ENAMEX>--she played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Ewing</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> , you'll no doubt recall--as its newest gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>. I mean,
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlene Tilton</ENAMEX>'s not where it's at, who is?

            After a brief check to verify that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Gong</ENAMEX>
Show is, in fact, no longer on the air, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> perused the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's story about rhinestone cowboy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen Campbell</ENAMEX>, who is shown
"relaxing in the comfy floral-pattern bedroom" of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bionic Man</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Majors</ENAMEX> is set to return to
television in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> sitcom. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> has a page of
photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> (including both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Whelchel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Facts of</ENAMEX>
Life and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Mandrell</ENAMEX>!) sporting the hairdo made famous by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majors</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ex-wife Farrah Fawcett</ENAMEX> circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>. But apparently life is a mixed bag for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Fawcett</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> has a story titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Fabulous Farrah</ENAMEX>
shows she's still got it--at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>," it also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fawcett</ENAMEX> is in such dire
financial straits that she's had to cut back her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX>'s visits from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times a week. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> couldn't refrain from running a truly
unfortunate time-lapse sequence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> picking her nose in public.

            Even when they do manage
to focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebs</ENAMEX> who have actually worked regularly in the last, say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the tabs seem uncommonly fixated on looking backward. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's special double issue contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>--count 'em!--pages
chronicling celebrity style makeovers over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, while <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s
Star devotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> full pages to "before they were stars" pictures. Vanna
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> was a very cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> indeed. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> is pretty sure she had the
exact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Gilbert</ENAMEX> once wore in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>.

            With so much photographic evidence on hand, it's only
natural that there's much discussion about who's had plastic surgery. The tabs'
short answer: pretty much everybody. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> has the requisite doctor
on hand to assess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebs</ENAMEX>' before and after photos. He gives high marks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX>'s "light-handed surgical touch" but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Rourke</ENAMEX>, whose
"skin is pulled back so tightly he looks like a lizard."

            Those reported to be
contemplating plastic surgery include pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Britney Spears</ENAMEX> (liposuction, per
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Sheindlin</ENAMEX> (face lift, breast lift, dermabrasion,
also from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camilla Parker Bowles</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> worth of
miscellaneous fixes, to help her win the race against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophie Rhys-Jones</ENAMEX> to
"become the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> ). The most talked-about
face lift prospect is, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, "wearing dark sunglasses and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">navy</ENAMEX> blue pantsuit," was seen visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Avenue</ENAMEX> plastic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surgeon</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> insists that no consultations were done in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. Instead, the circumspect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> is said to have sent various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> "high resolution photos taken of her face from different angles" in
order to get their opinions.

            We learned of the putative planned lift only after
discovering that the "before and after photos" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> promised on the cover
of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Star</ENAMEX> were nothing more than a computer simulation--much
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's simulated "mugshots" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>,
around whom tabloid suspicion is once again furiously swirling. Perhaps the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloids</ENAMEX>' loaf was sliced just a little too thin, but there seems to be an
unusually high ratio of tantalizing headlines to banal copy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. To
wit:

            

               The new book that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> claims "blows [the] lid" on pop star
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandy</ENAMEX>'s love life reveals such gasp-inducing nuggets as, "I liked [former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boyfriend Kobe Bryant</ENAMEX>]. He had that confidence and innocence about him that
attracted me."

               The "remote island paradise" where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Gifford</ENAMEX> bumped into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramour</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzen Johnson</ENAMEX> turns out to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nantucket</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, which last we checked sits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a mere</NUMEX> stone's throw from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Cod</ENAMEX>.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> teases us with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">secret life of Sopranos hunk</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Gandolfini</ENAMEX>, which turns out to be that he is married and has a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.

               And those "intimate secrets" about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> offered up to the
Star by her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butler</ENAMEX>? "She'd put an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> on and come downstairs
and look at me and say, 'You don't like this, do you?' If I said, 'No I don't,'
she'd go back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> and try something else on."

            

            The tabs seem so mired in the mundane that they've beefed
up their coverage of celebrity errand-running. The low point might have to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> story titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Kudrow</ENAMEX>'s friendly trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairdresser</ENAMEX>,"
complete with a photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kudrow</ENAMEX>--whose expression suggests she may have just
realized she's not alone--with her head piled high with silver foils. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> also catches <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every minute</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brolin</ENAMEX>'s
action-packed trip to a plant nursery, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> spots rock star
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGrath</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">band Sugar Ray</ENAMEX> "washing his undies with the ordinary folk
at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">laundromat</ENAMEX>." (Hel-lo! Tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> on holiday! Who is he
sleeping with, for God's sake?) After slogging through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> pages
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's "supermarket secrets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstars</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> was
particularly interested to learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Lawrence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eydie Gormé</ENAMEX>, who
seemed to just vanish into thin air at about the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Burnett</ENAMEX>
Show went off the air, are alive and well and often seen picking up "the
latest stain removers and cleaning supplies" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trancas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX>. A "store
insider" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Erewhon</ENAMEX> supermarket on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beverly Boulevard</ENAMEX> breaks the startling
news that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Boat captain and Mary Tyler Moore stalwart</ENAMEX> Gavin
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLeod</ENAMEX> "is crazy about our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">almond butter</ENAMEX>."

            Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports that NYPD
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Franz</ENAMEX> was spotted spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> in a supermarket
inspecting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 50</NUMEX> ears of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX>. "He sniffed each ear, poked it and even
counted all the kernels," confides an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX>.

            Keeping Tabs is highly skeptical of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franz</ENAMEX> corn
purchase, however, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
recently shed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">35 pounds</NUMEX> on the kind of high-protein, low-carbohydrate diet in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> is verboten . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franz</ENAMEX>, the story says, owes it all to the diet
books sent him by--wouldn't you know it?-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three's Company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Somers</ENAMEX>. We bet he'll be fitting back into those old leisure suits in no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
