
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> has always been viewed
as the least <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> believes
words are deeds and images are action. The self-styled "awkward old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> to the blandishments of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX>, is supposedly the beefy substance
of this superficial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Yet no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> figure depends
more on image than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>, and none has relied so much on words
and symbols as a substitute for action. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s defining moment, after all, was
taking responsibility for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>. Taking responsibility apparently meant doing
nothing (except supervising a post-mortem investigation that doesn't appear to
have investigated anything).

            Even so, the symbolic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> represents a new and
mostly encouraging model of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>, a perfect fit for an age of what
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Rosen</ENAMEX> calls "criminalized politics." Traditionally--at
least during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past half-century</TIMEX>--there have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of attorneys
general. One is the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidant</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Meese</ENAMEX>, who treats the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
private law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. The other is the faceless, trustworthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> foot
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>. Remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Barr</ENAMEX>? I didn't think so.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is neither. She arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wife</ENAMEX>, and so she has remained. She was ignorant and
independent of insider <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, and has stayed that way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> never much
liked her and never confided in her, and she reciprocated. She was, she said,
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>," not his. It is this outsiderness that has made her such
a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> and such a bad one.

            This is a time when the
mere act of taking a high-level political job subjects any official to
suspicion of criminal wrongdoing. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, a
primary--arguably the primary--job of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> has been to
supervise the investigations of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has appointed
independent counsels to investigate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of her fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and has overseen innumerable internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> investigations of
administration corruption. You can argue about whether this constant
surveillance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> is a good thing, but there is no doubt that these are the
most highly publicized cases the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DOJ</ENAMEX> handles.

            No one is better suited to them than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>. She is smart,
but mostly she is trustworthy. She pays the list price for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> to avoid
the appearance of favoritism. She avoids the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> because she doesn't want
to be tainted by him. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> speak with awe about her integrity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s
independence has given her the courage to appoint counsels to probe her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, and the courage not to appoint counsels even
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wolves</ENAMEX> were baying for them. She refused to authorize an independent
investigation into campaign fund raising, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> outrage, because
she believed the law did not require it.

            Since she rejected a
fund-raising independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have painted her as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tool, charging that she was helping him so she could keep her job.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> even likened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>.) But the charges haven't stuck.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s entire success at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> rests on her image as an ethical paragon. The
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> may be tainted, but thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squeaky Janet</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AG</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> are unsullied.

            To appreciate the hugeness of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s accomplishment,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hearken</ENAMEX> back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meese</ENAMEX> was under investigation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> inquiries into other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were suspect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> was
mistrusted, a national disgrace. Under any <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> crony (imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>!), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> would have been similarly compromised. After <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>,
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> proposed making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> independent of
presidential control. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> is the next best thing: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is independent not
just by temperament but also because she is unfireable. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX> since she
took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, she has been supervising <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> embarrassing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitewater</ENAMEX>, fund raising, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> espionage, etc. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
can't afford the political beating he would take if he cashiered her.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> pays a price for her life tenure and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outsiderness</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has all-but-excluded her from policy-making. Under
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crony</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys General</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> exercised vast influence
over legal policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, for example, shook up federal law
enforcement. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has husbanded crime policy to itself,
unwilling to entrust it to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>.

            This has made her an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> without measurable accomplishment in law enforcement or
prosecution. Crime has plummeted, but she gets no credit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> brought an
ambitious, liberal agenda to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>. She favored alternative punishments,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">longed</ENAMEX> to help troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, worried about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Draconian anti-</ENAMEX>immigration policy,
and disliked the death penalty, mandatory minimum sentences, and the
crack/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder cocaine</ENAMEX> sentencing disparity. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> ignored her. Instead, her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> has had to enforce an
expanded federal death penalty, throw more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in federal prison for longer
sentences, punish juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> more harshly, support mandatory minimums
and the crack/powder disparity, and double the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Patrol</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>
opposed some of these policies internally but had too little influence to stop
them.

            Which brings us to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waco</ENAMEX>, where the symbolism and substance
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> collide most alarmingly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s deserved reputation for integrity is
merely negative. She has not achieved anything magnificent. Her integrity has
simply prevented her from corrupting the process. She has not conducted any
powerful investigations, but she has had the wisdom not to block others from
conducting them.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> mess, however, has exposed the limits of
mere honor. Most reports suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> lied to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> over and over
about what they had done, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> believed them. In this case, she, not an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, supervised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> and the probes, and she settled
for cursory answers. It's easy to call this gullibility and incompetence, and
that's exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are doing: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX> on the right, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Klayman</ENAMEX>, is demanding her resignation. (It's worth noting,
however, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> similarly deceived <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGs</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Ridge</ENAMEX>
fiasco. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys general</ENAMEX> have an impossible relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>: They
nominally supervise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> and hence are held responsible for its
misbehavior, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> behaves like an autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.)

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> who exerted more control over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>, who was a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-knocker, and who
had the full support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> might have dragged the truth out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> did not and could not. But no such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>
could have survived the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals, much less survived them with her own
reputation--and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s--intact.

         
      
   
