
   
   
      
         
            FBLie

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> 
               admitted lying about its actions in the Waco
disaster. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of denials, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> confessed it had aimed
"pyrotechnic" tear gas at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Davidian</ENAMEX> compound. "We continue to believe
that law enforcement did not start the fire," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>
commissioned an investigation and vowed to "get to the bottom" of the
misrepresentations. She admitted, "I don't think it's very good for my
credibility."

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> may have laundered money for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> are examining whether mobsters diverted
funds--including foreign aid--out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> through an offshore network
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticizing Al Gore</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naively</ENAMEX> accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> pledges of economic
reform.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sprinter</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Johnson</ENAMEX> broke the world record for the
400-meter dash. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> tallied his long list of medals and
called him "the
most dominating track and field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>." "I can do better,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> commented.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> 
               war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> caught a suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Momir Talic</ENAMEX>, the highest-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to be
arrested so far, was seized in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               Post
predicts that the arrest will remind other suspected war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> not to travel abroad .

            

The hike was widely expected, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> surprised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> by hinting
that they may raise rates again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. The stock market, which had rallied
in anticipation of the move, remained stable, and bond prices inched up. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> not to sabotage the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s actions by
passing tax cuts.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were caught smuggling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. They stashed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and marijuana in food trays and used their
security clearances to transport the contraband.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will prosecute the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX>
               . A
government order excused most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> saying they had been brainwashed into
joining a subversive political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Sheinbein</ENAMEX> will serve a murder sentence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. The American
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> had fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> after allegedly committing murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> refused to let him be extradited back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.
Under a plea bargain, he will serve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> from both
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> decried the way he manipulated the discrepancies between the two
legal systems.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> voucher program was ruled unconstitutional.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled that the program's publicly financed scholarships to
parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> violate the separation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. City officials
wondered what to do with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who were scheduled to begin private
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of vouchers wondered whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> will finally address the issue.

            

               An earthquake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 18,000</NUMEX> and possibly as many as
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurriyet</ENAMEX> in effect charged
construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> with , and international papers roundly condemned
their shoddy building standards. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Independent</ENAMEX> noted that while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> "could assault the [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKK</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> after the earthquake." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> explains why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> to bury their dead. "" reports that the grassroots relief effort could
strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> democracy.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">whistleblower</ENAMEX> resigned. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colleagues</ENAMEX> had called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notra Trulock</ENAMEX>'s allegations against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> racist and had said there was
not a "shred of evidence" against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> . Trulock
countered that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> initial suspects in the case were of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> background and called a recent report exonerating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration "a whitewash."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Bret</ENAMEX> 
               hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meteorologists</ENAMEX> had predicted
the storm would equal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Andrew</ENAMEX> in power and destruction, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bret</ENAMEX> hit the least-populated stretch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf Coast</ENAMEX> and was quickly
downgraded to a tropical storm.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> said he 
               hasn't used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>.
After vowing never to discuss his drug history, he admitted that he had "made
some mistakes" but said he would have passed a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year</TIMEX> background check in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. The media debated whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s drug history should be probed.
Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are
entitled to know about felonies committed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacks</ENAMEX> argued that past dabblings with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> could make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s drug
enforcement policy hypocritical. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> chastised <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s past
after years of investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> chastised
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> for investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s past after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s.

                  Slate
               's "" blasts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for hounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> while
pretending that the story is driving itself.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> will merge to create the world's
largest financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>. Bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> will
resuscitate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> banking industry and thus the entire economy. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> hails the move as "a long-overdue effort to deal with the
realities of an overcrowded market, massive bad loans and woefully low profit
margins."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> 
               found evidence of a previously unknown ancient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primate</ENAMEX>. They say that a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 million</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year-old</TIMEX> fossil of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> ape
provides new evidence of a common ancestor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX>, chimps, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>.

            

               A study alleges 
               that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> of Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are
addicted to being online. "Marriages are being disrupted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are getting
into trouble, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are committing illegal acts," warns its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. "If you go
back far enough, I guarantee that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of cultural normalcy were
terrified by the invention of the toaster ," retorts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>
Achenbach on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> Web site.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> 
               blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayed</ENAMEX> commanded an intoxicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chauffeur</ENAMEX> to drive them and that
both could have survived had they been wearing seatbelts.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Thompson</ENAMEX> swam 
               the world's fastest <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 - meter</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">butterfly race</ENAMEX>. The record, set by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Meagher</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, was the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-oldest in swimming.

         
      
   
