
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dead Kennedys</ENAMEX>

            Drawn
by the scent of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have swarmed the crash site of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> While pedestrian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> investigate the disaster,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pundits</ENAMEX> debate the more entertaining question: Why does this keep happening to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>? Some say the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is "reckless." Others argue that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> are admirably bold and that it's unseemly to criticize them. Each camp
oversimplifies the truth. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> traditions: courage, gravity,
and martyrdom on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side; recklessness, frivolity, and mayhem on the
other.

            The
"recklessness" spin, fueled by talk radio and the Internet, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>
seek "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX>," "live close to the edge," are "wild" and "addicted to risk,"
and have a "dangerous streak." This spin laughably equates all dangerous
behavior. "Taking physical risks is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> family tradition," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . "During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Jr.</ENAMEX>, ... died on a
virtual suicide mission. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kennedy</ENAMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, rickety crafts whose
crews boasted that 'they were expendable.' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> always
seemed to be falling out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>."

            To
prove that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> was reckless, these spinners paste together weak
bits of evidence. As a boy, he used to evade his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. He once
took a survival course. Another time, he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and was charged by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rhinoceros</ENAMEX>. "He learned through all these experiences to make light of danger,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asserts Newsweek</ENAMEX> . Later, he enjoyed rock climbing, paragliding, scuba
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diving</ENAMEX>, kayaking, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rollerblading</ENAMEX>. He asked permission to rappel down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushmore</ENAMEX>. He launched a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>--demonstrating, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>, that
"like other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> had a taste for danger and
took risks." He invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> to a black-tie dinner. He even lived "in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">edgy</ENAMEX> warehouse district."

            The
"courage" spin puts an equally simplistic gloss of nobility on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">escapades</ENAMEX>. As questions about recklessness bounced around the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> talk
shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy pal Douglas Brinkley</ENAMEX> argued that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jr.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
family [are] 'in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>,' and they're living a vigorous life." "They're
bold," agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lieberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX> "They have always had courage.
They've always wanted to live to the fullest." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> admonished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, "It is an active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, an achieving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
and so its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have taken some chances." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> boasted
that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> have always been risk-takers, in play, politics and war. At
its best, there is a certain nobility to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>' refusal to let life
intimidate them."

            But
not all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s risk-taking has been "bold" or "wild." Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> have
been far more reckless than others. Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s death reckless? Let's
consider the criteria.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
Who caused the tragedy? Most of the coverage depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> as the victim of
a family "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> are "stalked by tragedy," suffering "bad luck"
or a "near-biblical blight" that has been inflicted, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX>,
by "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gods</ENAMEX>." Not only were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX> assassinated, but "the younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> has been haunted by bad news as well," says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> --"as if fate were picking them off," laments <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> .

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passive</ENAMEX> language obscures an important distinction. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX> were
murdered, the "younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>," far from being "haunted" or "picked off,"
caused its own grief. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> overturned a jeep, leaving his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>
paralyzed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Jr.</ENAMEX> introduced mescaline to his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, who
eventually died of a drug overdose. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> slept with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' teen-age baby
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sitter</ENAMEX> and later skied into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, went
out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Teddy</ENAMEX>, brought home a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and ended up being
tried unsuccessfully for rape.

            Which
of these traditions does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> belong to? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> argued that
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> was "cut down far too early." Again, passive language
distorts the facts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> was at the controls when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> crashed--just
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cousin Joe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Teddy</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
Who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>? On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> played the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year-old</TIMEX> video clip in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX> tried to explain to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> why,
having driven his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> off a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> after a party on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chappaquiddick Island</ENAMEX>--and
having swum to safety while his young campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Jo Kopechne</ENAMEX>, drowned
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>--he had failed to report the accident to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. In the clip,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> raised the question "whether some awful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> did actually hang over
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>, whether there was some justifiable reason for me to doubt
what had happened and to delay my report."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX> offered the clip as an omen of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>" that would strike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years later</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Barnicle</ENAMEX>, heaped praise
and sympathy on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX> for having "borne so many" family tragedies. Nobody
pointed out that at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chappaquiddick</ENAMEX>, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, the person
most responsible for the tragedy was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> was not--and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s invocation of the family "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>" was a clever way of
papering over these differences. Thanks to this blurring of the
victim-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perpetrator</ENAMEX> distinction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> was able to get elected to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> despite his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> accident, which likewise devastated his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chappaquiddick</ENAMEX>.

            Which
tradition does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> belong to? Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, recalling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>'s and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>'s assassinations, have cast his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> as the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of his
crash. "Stop blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>. It is enough that tragedy once again punished the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>. But attention is gradually shifting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bessette</ENAMEX>
family, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. The Chappaquiddick
analogies can't be far behind.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
For what purpose was the risk taken? To illustrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>' penchant
for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX>," "recklessness," and "disaster," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> compares
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s crash to the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX>, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> bombing mission
and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s fatal "crash" into a tree while playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> on
skis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Alter</ENAMEX> likens <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s flying to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
piloting of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">PT boat</ENAMEX> in the war: "They both grabbed life by the lapels." These
comparisons obscure the difference between risking one's life in war, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> did, and risking it playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>. Which tradition does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> belong
to? He was flying to a wedding--a more commendable pursuit than the one that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">killed Michael</ENAMEX>, but nothing like the war that killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Joe</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
What precautions were taken? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> was an
inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>, took off after sunset, wasn't licensed to fly in the poor
visibility he encountered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, flew the more dangerous route over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and
never contacted air traffic controllers for assistance. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> point out
that he was trained at a top-flight <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> and usually brought along a flight
instructor but that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s weather reports offered no warning of poor
visibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnicle</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, argued that to accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> of "poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX> is way out of bounds," because "he could just as well have been killed
in a subway accident."

            By
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enumerating Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s usual precautions, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> show that he was more
careful than many of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>. But against that background--and comments
from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> who say they decided the weather was too dangerous for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flying</ENAMEX>--his decisions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> appear all the more unwise. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>
would be alive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> if he had taken his usual precautions--and certainly if he
had taken a train instead.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
Was the protagonist morally reckless? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Recklessness theorists associate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s "lack of judgment" with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>' debauchery. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s "fearless adventurism has sometimes played out in
scandal: for example, the drug problems of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patrick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> ... or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s notorious involvement with his teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">babysitter</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, "If he was less reckless than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>, it was not saying much;
there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who turned down the invitation to take to the skies with
him." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> who said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> story is
really about karma, about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who broke the rules and were ultimately broken
by them."

            This
critique confuses different dimensions of "judgment" and "breaking the rules."
To err in assessing the weather is human; to pork the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX> is depraved.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> knew the difference: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, he observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> that
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> had "surrendered his judgment." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Recklessness theorists</ENAMEX> such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> --which casually associated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s "succession of stunning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">girlfriends</ENAMEX>" as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s "sexual snacking" as a married
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--show far worse judgment than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> ever did.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnicle</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>, however, gloss over the same moral
differences when they demand that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> stand with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Teddy</ENAMEX> and mourn
the loss of "another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>" instead of "assessing judgment." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judgment</ENAMEX> is
precisely what should be assessed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> should never have taken off
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>. The risk was unnecessary, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who entrusted him with
their lives are dead because he screwed up. But let's not confuse one
catastrophic misjudgment with a pattern of decadence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s death was
far less noble than the tragedies suffered by the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--and
far less blameworthy than the tragedies wrought by the worst.

         
      
   
