
   
   
      
         
            I'm OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro K</ENAMEX>

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I'm a grad student
at a large research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>. A cutie from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>--also a
grad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, in another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>--caught my eye <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>, and I am
positively smitten. Although I've made my affections for her very clear, she
has turned me down for dates because she prefers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of her
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Euroclique</ENAMEX>," a group of grad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> also from "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Continent</ENAMEX>." Frankly, I
find most of them annoying and downright dorky. Thus, it seems clear that my
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwestern</ENAMEX> roots turn her off. What can I do to win this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">affections</ENAMEX>?
            

            

               --R.S.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear R.</ENAMEX>,

            Tell her your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandfather</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser Wilhelm</ENAMEX>? Only kidding. As a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwesterner</ENAMEX>, Prudie
feels special kinship with you. The thing you must do in a situation like this
is accept that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s attractions are hardwired. (Have you noticed how often
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> resembles the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>?) There is a slim chance that this young
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX> is just not interested in you (with no consideration of nationality
involved) and is trying to let you down gently. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s rule is an old
retailing maxim: Your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> markdown is your cheapest. Do not wait around for
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to change her mind. Just accept things as they are and cast your eye
elsewhere. Prudie bets you a euro you will find another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> about whom you
will be smitten.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, romantically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I was raised in a
family where we were never big gift-givers. On special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> we each give a
meaningful gift and mainly focus on having a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> or an outing together.
My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, sees <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and birthdays as
occasions for major asset transfers. In other words, they are more into dollar
value than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. (My dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was horrified last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> with my
family when all he got was a shirt and tie.) I worry that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s family
does not see our carefully chosen gifts as the sincere expression of love and
affection that they are. Sometimes I feel trapped in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polynesian</ENAMEX> cycle of
humiliation by gift giving. Any tips?
            

            
               --Yours
humbly,
            

            

               Daughter-in-Law
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Daughter</ENAMEX>,

            You obviously march to a
different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> than your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> ... one who is not high-stepping through
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neiman Marcus</ENAMEX>. The first thing is for you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> to agree on an
underlying philosophy of gift giving. The ideal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks, is choosing a
gift with some real thought behind it that does not break the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. Since your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is used to lavish gifts, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of you should probably make a budget
for presents. It really is the thought that counts, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes your
in-laws will come to appreciate your thoughtful choices.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, selectively

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years old</TIMEX> and have a wonderful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> who is thoughtful, kind, understanding, etc. I have nothing bad to
say about him (here it comes), but I don't feel a real connection to him. If I
look at him from a logical standpoint, he would be a perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with whom
to spend the rest of my life. I am physically attracted to him, and I care for
him deeply, but I just feel there is something missing. I think all this has
been exacerbated by the fact that I recently had a conversation with a stranger
to whom I felt more drawn than I do to my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. (Nothing happened ... just
great conversation and what I felt was a real connection.) We've only been
going out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX>, so maybe I should give it more time. I don't want to
throw away something very good just because of some need that may be foolish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whim</ENAMEX>. Help!
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hopelessly Confused</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Hope</ENAMEX>,

            Love is not logical, so
forget that. You may, however, have <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Immature Woman Syndrome intensified by The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Handsome Stranger Phenomenon</ENAMEX>. Sometimes an inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--a young
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--will be turned off when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is too nice. And sometimes it's just
not the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. As you point out correctly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> is not enough time
to give you the answer. Your need for connection is not a foolish whim. Just
because you can't put your finger on what's missing doesn't mean it's not
missing. On the other hand, for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> real caring along with physical
attraction makes for a pretty pleasing situation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests, without
chucking your current relationship, you try to arrange another encounter with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Handsome Stranger</ENAMEX> to see what happens a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time. (Assuming, of course,
you didn't meet him on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> and have no inkling of how to find him
again.) Life is choices, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes you make a good one.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, thoughtfully

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> is getting married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> and has asked me and some other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> to be bridesmaids. Financially we are all OK, but by no
means rich. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiance</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are footing the bill for a
very elaborate wedding and a honeymoon to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Her dress costs around
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX>, to give you an idea. The bridesmaid dresses she has picked out are
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX>, which we are supposed to buy ourselves, plus shoes, plus special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undergarments</ENAMEX>. So it's basically <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $500</NUMEX> that she is asking each of us to
spend. Is it rude of her to expect us to do this? It seems so to us. But ... we
feel like we can't really say "no" to being her bridesmaids, either. How should
we handle the situation? Can we ask her to have her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> pay for a portion of
the dresses so it's not a financial hardship for us?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               Dis-dressed
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dis</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is a long way
from her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">bridesmaid days</TIMEX>, but interestingly enough, your dilemma was faced by
someone on whose birth certificate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s name just happens to be. The
numbers involved in that situation were roughly double the ones you mention.
What happened there was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>'
dresses. Afterward, however, one of the bridesmaids was so annoyed by the
costly selections that it ruined her friendship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> believes
that if a family of means picks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>' dresses that are out of the normal
price range, they should foot the bill. (For some unknown reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bridesmaids</ENAMEX>'
dresses are often worn only once ... maybe because they are usually ugly. This
is just one of life's little oddities.) As for your question about whether or
not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> is rude in asking you all to shell out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of dollars</NUMEX>, she
is not rude, simply thoughtless. Because your letter indicates that all you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> have the same views about the expense, one of you should speak to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> on behalf of all the bridesmaids and say that her selection is a little
steep for everyone and perhaps her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> might pay for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. Prudie guesses she
will say yes.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, hopefully

         
      
   
