
   
   
      
         
            Asynchronic

            I'd been doing that, going
out just after sunset--
the sky a bowl of blue-green light,
a basin filled with cold, still <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seawater</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Shops</ENAMEX> in the advancing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX> looked like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> tanks
flooded with neutral overhead lighting that fell
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> about to close up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.
When I tugged back a sleeve, the wrist was naked--
forgot my watch again--and both hands chapped and rough.
Why do our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> fingers, no more, and no less?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zoologists</ENAMEX> would know. Meanwhile
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the routine, strictly business
clocks glimpsed through windows
during the rounds of my unofficial beat
could substitute for a watch. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:25</TIMEX>;
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">storefronts</ENAMEX> down, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:22</TIMEX>;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:29</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> didn't agree with itself.
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX>, it didn't agree with me, either;
but then it never entirely had (and never will?).

A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">white-haired man</ENAMEX> with olive skin and tattered clothes
limped into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met Food</ENAMEX> and panhandled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>,
one I recognized, her face mild and familiar as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>.
For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half a second</TIMEX>--strange--it felt permanent,
indestructible as the tiny gleam
that pearled in the dark <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupil</ENAMEX> of her eye.
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:33</TIMEX> ... And now a go-getter poised at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:45</TIMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> in a sky by then blue-black ink,
and I roughly <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minutes</TIMEX> older,
arms dangling at my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>.
But no wiser, only a bit farther
into the walk, with a sudden hunger pang,
the gut's alarm bell, sounding dinner hour.
All I'd seen, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, the clock-faces,
menagerie of the populous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, were saying
(so to speak), "Feast your eyes on this."
If the banquet had agreed with me,
and if I'd had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> to return to ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> had moved in back there, a silent
dimension unconcerned that it would turn us
out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> (first you, and after
you'd gone, then me), according to some
ironclad schedule followed or policed
at glacial speed by supervising hands ...
Or, worse, when my door swung open,

            by spidery digitals that
glared
across the darkened <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:58</TIMEX>--

            
numbers reflected counter, greener, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX>-like
(detail, the lost-and-found of deity)
in the crystal of the watch I left there on the table.

         
      
   
