
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swann Song</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, a federal judge ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>,
to stop busing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to integrate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> noted the perfect
symmetry--busing had begun with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swann</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mecklenburg Board of Education</ENAMEX> decision--and the
neoconservative-dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commentariat</ENAMEX> cheered the demise of what it deemed a
failed experiment. But while busing did great damage in many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX> it was widely considered an against-the-odds success. That fact makes
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s news all the sadder.

            The landmark <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swann</ENAMEX> suit had its origins in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown II</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX> II
gummed up the initial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown ruling</ENAMEX>--which had decreed segregated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> unconstitutional--by saying, in a now-infamous oxymoron, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">desegregation</ENAMEX> should proceed "with all deliberate speed." By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
had seen more deliberation than speed. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 2 percent</NUMEX> of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX>
attended integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. To maintain this racial separation, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of
all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were actually bused to schools far from their homes, a form of
busing that raised no outcry from the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.

            With the injustice self-evident, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> and
other civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> trolled for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to challenge the system, finding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vera</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darius Swann</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanns</ENAMEX> wanted their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>, to attend
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seversville Elementary School</ENAMEX>, one of the few integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seversville Elementary</ENAMEX> happened to be closest to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, but the school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> refused to admit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swanns</ENAMEX> filed suit
but lost. They continued to appeal until their case reached the desk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James McMillan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> confederate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMillan</ENAMEX> was on record deriding "the folly ... of requiring that
pupils be transported far away from their natural habitat so that some
artificial ... racial balance be maintained." But when he examined the Swann
case he realized that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>'s school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> was plainly in violation of the
law and that it wasn't going to desegregate unless forced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. The
precedent had been set with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX>
School <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of New Kent County</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, in which the court ruled school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boards</ENAMEX> had an "affirmative duty" to ensure "racial discrimination would be
eliminated root and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMillan</ENAMEX> ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlotte</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to draw up a
plan to take steps--not necessarily busing--to do so.

            At first, school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> refused to implement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">desegregation</ENAMEX> plans and then submitted plans that failed to address the
problem. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMillan</ENAMEX> could do was reject them. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of school board
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stalling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMillan</ENAMEX> appointed an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX> to devise a desegregation
strategy, which entailed the busing of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to previously white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>,
and vice versa.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> began rolling
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 9, 1970</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enraged</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> protested, sometimes violently. McMillan
received death threats and was hanged in effigy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swanns</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> was fire bombed. Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were beat up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Some white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> withdrew and sent their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, while others
formed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to agitate against busing.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high court</ENAMEX> unanimously upheld <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McMillan</ENAMEX>'s
decision. But the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, split between busing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>,
continued to produce half-hearted integration plans that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMillan</ENAMEX> had to
dismiss as not "in good faith," and busing continued according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s
prescription.

            Meanwhile, a previously
apolitical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie Ray</ENAMEX> began convening local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, black and white, pro- and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-busing</ENAMEX>, to work out an alternative
solution--and also endeared herself to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> at a backyard barbecue. Her
informal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens Advisory Group</ENAMEX>, finagled an end-run
around the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and persuaded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMillan</ENAMEX> to put it in charge of the
busing plan. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, the board compromised with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> on an
arrangement that won <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMillan</ENAMEX>'s approval, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX> he withdrew the
court from supervision of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>'s desegregation plans, trusting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to do it fairly.

            After the initial round of white flight, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
maintained for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two decades</TIMEX> a mix of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 60 percent</NUMEX> white and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
percent black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, especially affluent ones, in
once all-black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> lifted those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>' quality, since white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>'
complaints about outdated textbooks, sub par <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, and dilapidated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> were heeded by school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX>' test scores rose too, after
a special effort led by a pro-busing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> found new pride in their integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, generating more
goodwill. Political reform followed too, creating a city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that better
represented both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. Finally, a solid educational system
provided a foundation for the economic growth the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> has recently
enjoyed.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>'s busing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> hinged on several things. Unlike the earlier schemes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s plan didn't
exempt the wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> in southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>. As a result, some lower-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> no longer felt singled out to carry the burden of integration.
Acknowledging the situation's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">class dimensions</ENAMEX> blunted the racial
animosity--and created a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and less affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. Also,
the white flight that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed busing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and elsewhere was not really an
option. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> could flee to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> (and some did), but
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> had consolidated its school system in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> the outlying
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> as well as the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> were embraced in the busing blueprint. (A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling exempted suburban school districts from busing,
meaning few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">metropolises</ENAMEX> experienced wholesale integration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>-style.)

            Equally important--and I admit this sounds kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cornball</ENAMEX>--success required the civic spiritedness of pro- and anti-busing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> alike, who saw their way clear to hammering out compromises. This meant
shelving the belief that a single, foolproof plan could be implemented once and
for all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizens</ENAMEX> got involved with adjusting the busing plan (and refighting
painful battles) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year after year</TIMEX>--a demanding but inescapable
burden. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1990s</NUMEX> even saw a major overhaul, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> introduced magnet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> devoted to excellence in a single area, such as math, and open to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from all neighborhoods--to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> extra incentive to travel long
distances to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.

            Unfortunately, the
magnet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> began the undoing of desegregation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>. To remain a
tool for continued desegregation and not just for excellence, the magnet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> had to maintain set-asides for black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newcomer</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Capacchione</ENAMEX>, who had not witnessed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s efforts in the
'70s to surmount mutual distrust--sued to enroll his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> into a magnet
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> didn't want to "tip" all white. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the case came before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Potter</ENAMEX>--a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX>, and
a sworn enemy of busing since he fought against it on the front lines in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>.
Calling bused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> "cogs in an experimental machine," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX> declared that
all vestiges of harm wrought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crow-</ENAMEX>era dual school system have
evaporated. This despite a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlotte Observer</ENAMEX> study that found
that without busing, segregation would return for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">district</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> have come far, and we can hope
that integration may someday endure without a conscious effort to preserve it.
But it's dishonest or naive to claim that that moment has arrived. Thirty years
may seem like a long time to someone nursing a grievance since the pitched
battles of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '60s</TIMEX>, but in the sweep of history--on the heels of 90 years
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crow</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> of race slavery--it's nothing. Ironically, busing will
become unnecessary only when no one seems to have a problem with it
anymore.

            Now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>'s civic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX>
of continued desegregation efforts, have to reckon with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX>'s ruling. While
not carrying the weight of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision, it does point the way for
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, if they want to follow. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> decides in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next weeks</TIMEX>
whether to appeal, it also has to scramble to make sure its denser (largely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX>) areas will have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to house the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who can't be bused
across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> anymore to less crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>.

            The most distressing part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX>'s decision was
his swipe at social experimentation. As all great social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> have known,
fixed formulas, one-size-fits-all policies, and judicial fiats rarely solve
intractable problems. The only thing that does is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> called "bold,
persistent experimentation," as the example of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Charlotte</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nobly</ENAMEX> attests.

         
      
   
