
   
   
      
         
            Press and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising Information</ENAMEX>

            
               WHO WE ARE:
            

            A complete list of

                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> can be found in .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADVERTISING</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INFORMATION</ENAMEX>:
            

            
               Learn about advertising opportunities on 
                  Slate
               
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, or contact 
                  Slate
                Associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus Krohn</ENAMEX> directly.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRESS CONTACT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INFORMATION</ENAMEX>:
            

            E-mail press@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> for general questions, or feel
free to contact our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> directly:

            
               TV, radio, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, area media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX>:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Baum</ENAMEX>, db
communications

            Phone: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">703</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">548-5553</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dan</ENAMEX>@danbaumcommunications.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            
               Print, Internet, and
general media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX>:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rutherford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trylon Communications</ENAMEX>
Phone: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">212</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">725-2295</ENAMEX>
jeffru@tryloncommunications.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            
               To reprint articles
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
               , contact:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Weydert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syndicate</ENAMEX>
Phone: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">732</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">390-4480</ENAMEX>

            
weyded@nytimes.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            
               RECEIVE A COMPLIMENTARY
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUBSCRIPTION TO SLATE</ENAMEX>
                  :
               
            

            Sign up for a complimentary subscription to choose
from our selection of premium e-mail delivery services. Receive

                  Slate
                News <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each morning</TIMEX>, including "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," or get our
political briefing, plus more. Click here to request a free subscription.

            In your e-mail, please
include your name, media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, address, and phone number.

            
               REQUEST A MEDIA
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KIT</ENAMEX>:
            

            Get general information about 
                  Slate
               ,
our features, articles, and staff biographies in the 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
Kit. Click here !

            In your e-mail, please
include your name, media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, address, and phone number.

            
               SIGN UP FOR <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OUR DAILY</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NEW TODAY" E-MAIL SERVICE:</ENAMEX>
            

            Keep up with what's new on 
                  Slate
               
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekday</TIMEX> with our free e-mail delivery. You'll get 
                  Slate
               's
Table of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Contents</ENAMEX> page e-mailed directly to your inbox with links to all

                  Slate
               's exclusive commentary and features. Click here to sign up.

         
      
   
