
   
   
      
         
            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kind of Wonderful</ENAMEX>

            In repose, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>
is plainly gorgeous, but she's even more so when she fastens those huge eyes on
some lucky co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. She's the anti-Garbo: She doesn't vant to be alone.
For an "object of beauty," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> has an astounding amount of chemistry with
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>. She managed to penetrate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Everett</ENAMEX>'s languid self-regard in
My <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Friend's Wedding</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>) and made the brilliant but remote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denzel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> almost puppyish in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Pelican Brief</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>). In the past,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Grant</ENAMEX> has mainly had chemistry with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Grant</ENAMEX>, yet in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Notting Hill</ENAMEX> , he focused on something other than his own adorableness.
Above all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> warms up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> known for a narcissistic
blend of preening and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>-like self-containment, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gere</ENAMEX> proved in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pretty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woman</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>) to be a marvel at reflecting her light, like a piece of space
debris that in the rays of the sun reveals jewellike facets.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>'s reunion,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Runaway Bride</ENAMEX> , is a laborious screwball romance, which, in its first
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX>, had me checking off the details it got wrong about journalism,
small-town life, and human relations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie Carpenter</ENAMEX>, a
hardware store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> ( check ) and junk sculptor ( check ) with a
tendency to panic and leave her grooms open-mouthed at the altar. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gere</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, who hears about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX> in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and, without even a call to confirm his facts ( check ), devotes his
next piece to an un-PC screed on the inconstancy of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> ( check )
with this "runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>" as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exhibit A. The</ENAMEX> column makes him instantly
( check ) unpopular with all those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan USA Today</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
( check ) who recognize him on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> ( check ), not to mention
the hordes of small-town <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who wait for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> as if it were the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Humor man</ENAMEX> ( check ). After the
subject of the column responds with a letter composed on a manual typewriter
( check ) disputing its facts, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> ( check ) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>) promptly ( check ) fires him ( check ).

            My notebook has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 50</NUMEX> more checks, but once the premise
had been established and the leads began to interact, I stopped totting up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inanities</ENAMEX> and had a good time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Marshall</ENAMEX> (he did Pretty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Woman</ENAMEX> , too), isn't especially talented at tying up loose ends or gliding
over awkward inconsistencies. His strength is that he loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> (he's an
amusing one himself). He'll drop everything for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goofy</ENAMEX> face, a riff, a flaky
bit of business. It doesn't matter that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Cusack</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairdresser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pal</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie Metcalf</ENAMEX> as a busybody <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hector Elizondo</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ex-wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and also his best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> ( check ) don't have much in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of rounded parts. They're in there improvising and having a blast. Compare
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">larky</ENAMEX> turns to the robotic caricatures in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> You've
Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> --it's the difference between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> who thinks she has it all
figured out and one who says, "Surprise me, make me laugh."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX> is a great role
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>, who can be alternately warm and skittish, promiscuous and clammy.
Each of her weddings (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX> gets a videotape) is a terrific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slapstick</ENAMEX> turn. Watch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> swivel away from an expectant groom as if anti-magnetized,
bearing her out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> on its own power. Gere, meanwhile, has become
exceedingly likable. Perhaps it's all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> meditation, which has mellowed
his showy Method edges. His enviably thick hair has gone from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>-and-pepper
to just <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>, and those tiny, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slavic</ENAMEX> eyes have acquired a worldly glint.
Alternately mocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX> and enjoying her hugely, he's like a happy,
laid-back stalker.

            In the event I ever teach a filmmaking class, I'm going to
have a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Work of Hugh Hudson: What Not To Do</ENAMEX>." The riotously
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">inept Revolution</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>) will be the ur-text, but I might find a place
for the genteel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Life So Far</ENAMEX> . It's not that it's bad, it's that on a
dramatic level it barely exists. I've never read the source text, a memoir by
Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denis Forman</ENAMEX> about his affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> childhood, but another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forman</ENAMEX>
book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Night at the Opera</ENAMEX> , is one of my bibles--a cheeky guide to the
genre by a former deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Opera House</ENAMEX>. This movie is
supposed to be about the way the arrival of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>'s dishy young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
(Irène <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>) throws the estate into a libidinous chaos, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson's</ENAMEX> camera is
always in the right place to catch the rolling hills and splendid staircases
and in the wrong place to catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>' expressions. The loss is especially
vexing since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Firth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Elizabeth Mastrantonio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm McDowell</ENAMEX>) might be giving fine performances, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robbie Norman</ENAMEX>
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> might be extraordinary. The script might even be good. We'll just
never know.

         
      
   
