
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">286</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Supplies Party&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Vinyl rope,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magnets</ENAMEX>, large nails. What's the connection?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 285</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Counterintuitive</ENAMEX>, Sir!":
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Louis Caldera</ENAMEX> has
announced a plan that will put more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. What is this
program called?
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puberty</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take</ENAMEX>
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Day</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Oder</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Project Louie Caldera's Kid Gets an A in Math or Else</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Van</ENAMEX>
Dussen
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> Present <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Shoot a Pepsi Drinker and Win a Guest</ENAMEX>
Spot on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson's Creek</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contest</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Glassenberg</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Whatever, just so long as they're not singing 'Mony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mony</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen</ENAMEX>
Werthmann
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            The admonition, "You
become what you behold," has yielded to "You become what you belittle." We
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> mocked the militarism of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> youth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX>, and now we're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embracing Louis Caldera</ENAMEX>'s ballistic schemes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>, we taunted the clunky
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX> for their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon squareness</ENAMEX>; now we drive cool <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX>.
The joys of deriding portly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> burghers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> haven't prevented us
from becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> fatties. Nor has the fun we all had sneering
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s squandering its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Sea</ENAMEX> oil windfall in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s and '80s</TIMEX> kept
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> from proposing to give away the budget surplus to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>. The frightening conclusion, if mockery precedes mimicry, is
that any minute now we'll all be working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lock</ENAMEX> and Load
Answer
            

            The program is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Junior Reserve Officer Training</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps</ENAMEX>.

            To meet what it calls a growing demand from high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> will double its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JROTC</ENAMEX> by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2001</TIMEX> academic year, adding
it to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> more high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, for a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,420</NUMEX>. After that, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> will be added annually for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">230,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the program <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> will supply various pieces of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' marksmanship training.

            Taught by retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JROTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> cover history, current events, technology, communications,
physical fitness, and the ever popular shooting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Militaristic</ENAMEX>? You bet! But the
good kind of militaristic. "By expanding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JROTC</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> is broadening its
investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> through a program that emphasizes the
values that have made our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> great," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caldera</ENAMEX>. "Insert your own dark
joke about those values," he did not add.

            
               Nominal
Extra
            

            Once left to
talented--or not--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amateurs</ENAMEX>, naming new products is now frequently the task of
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>. But has professionalizing this chore resulted in richly
evocative names? Can you tell what sort of products the following are (each
advertised in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> )?

            
               Names
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Tiempo</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Aero

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Altima

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">DaVinci 2</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Tango 3</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rav 4</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turbo Power</ENAMEX> 1500

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Rebel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Supreme</ENAMEX>

            10.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge Cherry</ENAMEX>

            

               Products
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Nike soccer</ENAMEX> shoe

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> PalmPiloty
thing

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> carish sort of
thing

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Another PalmPilotish
thing

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Adidas soccer</ENAMEX> ball

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> SUV

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Hoover vacuum
cleaner

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Canon 35mm</ENAMEX> camera

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Minolta camera

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fake Queen Anne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bedroom</ENAMEX> set from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drexel Heritage</ENAMEX> furniture

         
      
   
