
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">267</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;You Be the Playwright&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               I set the stage
for a script based on an actual current event.
            

            
               Setting: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courtyard</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Prop: A briefcase
containing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX>.
            

            
               Female Lead:
Kaethe, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> wearing hot pants and a bikini top.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Male Lead: Father</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> wearing something priestly.
            

            
               Question: What is
the opening line of dialogue?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 266</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Booed and Hooted": Fill in</ENAMEX>
the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Riordan</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gay Pride parade</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>, explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> was heckled the length of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">march</TIMEX>. "Nobody is barred from being in the parade. It's completely open to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. He's just not ______________."

            
"Completely open to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>, dammit."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Terns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shany Mor</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Cass</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"Supposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX> step."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Nolan</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Anyone's type."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            The problem with parades is the wrong thing
moves--the entertainment, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. That's why the piano is used so
seldom in parade music, and it's why we're a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of fatties--all that
standing around waiting for some baton twirler to arrive. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>
finally brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pietà</ENAMEX> over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, they didn't put
it on a float and trundle it down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street</ENAMEX>; they displayed it in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">reverential hush of the World's Fair</ENAMEX>. The statue sat; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> moved,
gliding past it on conveyor belts the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> intended.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Macy's Thanksgiving Parade</ENAMEX>--and isn't a holiday
so much more festive when it has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>?--does both. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving Eve</TIMEX>,
crowds stroll past the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloons</ENAMEX> while they're being inflated. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The next morning</TIMEX>,
there's a traditional parade, with Huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pneumatic Licensed Characters</ENAMEX> dragged
past cold, immobile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX>, lined up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-deep at the curb, unable to see
much beyond the frost-covered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in front of them, and the
occasional chunk of plummeting debris.

            So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, let's
switch from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gay Pride Parade</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gay Pride Street Fair</ENAMEX>--good exercise, a
cultural celebration, and a chance to buy inexpensive socks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viva</ENAMEX>!

            
               They're Not
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Laughing At You, They're Laughing Near You Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            "He's just not popular ."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> himself sees the jeers not as political
protest but as psychological distress. "You should be able to march as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> anyplace you want, and if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't deal with their
own anger over that, that's really something emerging from inside them," he
said. "And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Tea Party</ENAMEX>? Some kind of oedipal thing," he did not
add.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s surprise at being booed was not
entirely disingenuous. His policies toward the gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> have been
sufficiently benign to cost him some right-wing support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race.
Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> sentiment was particularly vigorous among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. "Couldn't they be forced into some separate Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pride Parade?</ENAMEX>" he did not ask.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX> and straight New
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yorkers</ENAMEX> can now come together to boo the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
announcement of yet another giveaway to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>--this time a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$28 million</NUMEX>
subsidy to the publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has dispensed
more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> in tax breaks and electrical subsidies to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, squandering public money and shifting the tax burden to smaller
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basement Workshop</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hobby Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s favorite hobby
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>) just mailed out its terrific new catalog of
radio-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, and accessories. A few highlights:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEGATECH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B2 STEALTH</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$319</NUMEX> "the most recognizable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> in the
world."--Thanks to that new "recognizable stealth" technology. And I believe
this one comes with a tiny, unreliable map of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>.

               M1A1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm R</ENAMEX>/C Mega <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tank</ENAMEX> "offers the thrills and excitement of
commanding your own battle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Simple enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> to operate
(yet sophisticated enough for an 'expert' to enjoy)."--Which, coincidentally,
is also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX>'s motto.

               GRAF ZEPPELIN DIRIGIBLE KIT <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29.95</NUMEX> "Plans for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> were originally
penned over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years ago</TIMEX>."--Pretty much like real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> procurement
schedules.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEROMAX</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2000 HAND-THROWN PARACHUTE W/MAN</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.99</NUMEX> "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of fun for young
& old alike."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> goes up; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> comes down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> goes up; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> comes down.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> goes up; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> comes down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> goes ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX FREE FLIGHT HELICOPTER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ATTACK</ENAMEX> COBRA <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29.99</NUMEX>--Believed to be
particularly effective when parked near the combat zone.

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Single-Entendre Bonus</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: The list includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prowler</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wizard, Mongoose, Venus Probe, Fire Streak, Zinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corkscrew, Astrocam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">110</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bertha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Dawg</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exo-Skel</ENAMEX>.

            List of what?

            
               A: All
are the names of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beta Rocket Kits</ENAMEX>, selling for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.49 to $31.99</NUMEX> in the AHC
catalog.

            
               Rocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Silow-Carroll</ENAMEX>
invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to devise a sequentially trumping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX>, like this one:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> crush <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
drives out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> fits.) Replies due by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.

            
               Headline
Haiku
            

            "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Classic Rock Fan</ENAMEX>'s
Lament"

            I Was
Seldom Taken
To Listen
To <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27 1999</TIMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leisure</ENAMEX>" only)

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
Heaney
            

            Chance for the gold
elusive as the cure
for trials of heart.
Quick action eases sting.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Science</ENAMEX>
Times" only)

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lois C.</ENAMEX>
Ambash
            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Clothes make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--or any permutation of these
words.

         
      
   
