
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Eclipse</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>

            In the
absence of a unifying international story, most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> led on
domestic stories, with one notable exception: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> devoted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gallons</ENAMEX> of ink to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11</TIMEX> total eclipse of the sun, which should be visible
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern Europe</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay of Bengal</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> observed
that "[e]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clipses</ENAMEX> used to be about soothsaying and portents of disaster. Now
they are about tourism and commerce." Indeed much of the coverage revolved
around anticipated traffic jams, tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rip-offs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>' complaints that there are
fewer eclipse-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> than they planned for, weather worries, and gloomy predictions of ill-prepared
spectators permanently damaging
their vision. (For comprehensive eclipse packages, see these Web sites from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s Le
Monde , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundo</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> will provide a live Web broadcast of the
eclipse from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 a.m. to 3:30 a.m. PT</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> here.)

            In a
story of economic eclipse, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> fronted a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s forced
mergers in the financial sector. The moves will consolidate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
current roster of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> finance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> merchant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of next month</TIMEX>, with the government
forming the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliances</ENAMEX> rather than allowing market forces to bring them
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. ''If you're suddenly told, 'Here's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you're going to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marry</ENAMEX>'--and all this irrespective of cultural differences and without knowledge
of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>'s business practices--it's a bit of a shock,'' a top official
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> told the paper. Although the new structure has not yet been revealed,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IHT</ENAMEX> reported that "the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> has already said that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> would be controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX>, who make up slightly more than half of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. Ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> make up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a third</NUMEX> of the
population but control a disproportionately higher percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
wealth." There is no word yet on how current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> will be compensated
for their equity.

            The
saga of former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>, who has been under
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> arrest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1998</TIMEX> when a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> requested his
extradition to face charges there, took still more turns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> called on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to release <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> because the
procedure has taken so long that it is no longer legal. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spaniards</ENAMEX>,
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who originally demanded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s extradition, protested
the move. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have also asked that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>
be extradited to their jurisdictions, so it is possible that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
request is withdrawn, the proceedings will continue with one of those countries
as the petitioner. Also, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph of London</ENAMEX>
reported, it is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> could face trial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>
withdraws its request. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> has tried to persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to
find an "extrajudicial" solution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> problem, perhaps referring the
matter to adjudication. A surprising editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> came out against such a
solution. "It isn't a question of political ideology or of bilateral relations
with a friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It's a question of what is or isn't right. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> and this matter ... is having a negative effect on bilateral
relations. But if our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>, it is an even better friend
of justice," said the paper.

            The
alarming lead story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX>
claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> (mad cow <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>) epidemic "may have been caused by
a scientific experiment that went wrong. The blunder has cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> £4bn
[<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.4 billion</NUMEX>], claimed the lives of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and triggered fears that the
death toll could eventually reach <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several million</NUMEX>." According to the story,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>, taken from the brains of slaughterhouse
carcasses, were injected into <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> in a bid to create a new breed of
super-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX>. But the experiment ... backfired. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>, extracted from
pituitary glands, were transmitted in an agent that spread <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mad cow disease</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> received little attention in the other serious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> and the
Age of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> gave prominent coverage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to aboriginal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>' plans to use
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sydney Olympic Games</ENAMEX> to bring global attention to the plight of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">indigenous Australians</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> 's story, "an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Aboriginal 'embassy'</ENAMEX> will be set up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> for the
duration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> to lobby visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIPs</ENAMEX> and media." This comes after
suggestions of an indigenous boycott of the games were rejected, in part
because several aboriginal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>, such as track <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy Freeman</ENAMEX>, are
medal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX>, and after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> organizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> "did a back flip"
and decided to fly the indigenous flag at official venues. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> predicted that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> will
be angered by the "strategy of shaming ... <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> in the eyes of the world for their mistreatment and neglect of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aborigines</ENAMEX>" because "[t]hey will see it as calculated to tarnish the national
image at a time when all other efforts are directed towards polishing it and
showing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> at its best." But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claimed, "[s]uch anger is not
only futile but misdirected." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> placed hope in the
acknowledgment by some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native leaders</ENAMEX> "that the presentation of Aboriginal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, though useful to win some political arguments, is ultimately
disempowering for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aborigines</ENAMEX> themselves. If international scrutiny shames white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> into necessary reappraisal of flawed policies, well and good. If it
also sharpens <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>' understanding of the need for greater efforts
on their part, even better."

         
      
   
