
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Library Cad</ENAMEX>

            You'd think that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> would be thrilled to name
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> after the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who ever walked (or, in this
case, took a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> "jog") down it, but that's not how it works in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX> Late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, sign-wavers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> mobbed city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> while
the city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> considered whether to rename the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson Clinton Presidential Library</ENAMEX> will be located "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenue</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hecklers</ENAMEX> offered derisive amendments: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impeachment Avenue</ENAMEX>" was
proposed. But the city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> eventually compromised, renaming just the few
blocks of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Markham Street</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--a plan the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> said he came to embrace after asking himself, "What would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> do?"

            After a bit of fussing
from radio talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> and newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-name dust-up
blew over, but it's one of the few controversies connected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Library</ENAMEX> that has. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> beat out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Springs</ENAMEX>
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1997</TIMEX>, city policies from sales taxes to zoo funding
have been tangled up in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that will be his legacy. As
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> noted, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>, even if they say it's not about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, it's about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Rockers</ENAMEX> dispute that a world-class library
building will be a boon to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where the finest example of modern
architecture is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCBY Tower</ENAMEX>, and the principal tourist attractions are quilt
shows and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that had a cameo in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gone With the Wind</ENAMEX> (not to
mention the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> propositioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>). But just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>
Rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are embarrassed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central High</ENAMEX>, the discomfiting monument to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">desegregation</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s other claim to history, some are queasy about
celebrating their not-so-favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.

            After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>
had hardly won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal broke and a vast new field
of inquiry revealed itself to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> wiseacres: What's going to be in this
lie-brary anyhow? A cigar and a dress? Oral histories?

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> has provoked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> not just because
it's a litmus test about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Even some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> have a bad taste in
their mouths about the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> arranged to pay
for the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">28-acre</NUMEX> site. Private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> will fund the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 million to $125 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>, but city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> agreed to deliver construction-ready land. And
after recovering from the initial euphoria over winning the big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX>, Mayor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Dailey and Co.</ENAMEX> realized they had to find <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> to buy and clear the
property.

            For a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> budget, that's a
jawbreaker, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> had made a commitment. They hit upon the idea of
issuing "parks revenue bonds," which didn't require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> approval, and
pledging revenues from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> to pay them
down. The problem: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> revenue bonds can only fund <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>. Is a library a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX>? That depends on your definition of the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> called the
library a "presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>," and that took care of it.

            (The plan to take money
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> is another saga. For reasons too <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> to explain,
it's the only unaccredited big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, and it could use a cash
infusion. City <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are incredibly sensitive to the charge that they are
buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> land with money that should go to feeding the giraffes. When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s newly hired zoo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for a meet-and-greet recently,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> were warned in no uncertain terms that he was not to be asked about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> welcomed this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>-bond trick,
but other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> were not so gratified, among them 66-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Harris</ENAMEX>, a self-described "retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>,
claiming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> land deal is an illegal tax because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> will have to
raid the general fund to make up for lost parks revenue. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pulaski County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancery Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s favor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> plans to
appeal her case to the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. She has vowed to pursue the case to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, or at least until she runs out of money.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> isn't the only one
taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Pfeifer III</ENAMEX>, a vocal opponent
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, owns a piece of property in the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and promises
to fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s attempt to take his property by eminent domain.

            And then there's everyone else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
proposed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one-cent</NUMEX> sales tax to shore up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>'s frayed budget, the city
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolted</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pfeifer</ENAMEX> argued loudly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was
forecasting a deficit because it is saddled with debt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> didn't approve, to
fund a library they didn't request, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who didn't inhale. City
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> squealed at that contention--the sales tax plan didn't mention the
"presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>," and a deficit had been projected before the library
land grab--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dailey</ENAMEX> was questioned about it everywhere he went, and his
answers didn't impress. The tax was walloped by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> referendum. Since then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has frozen hiring and chopped
programs to stave off a budget emergency.

            All this time, the land for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> has sat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undisturbed</ENAMEX>, covered with tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> and empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, its intended purpose
marked only by a banner that has grown progressively more tattered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
originally hoped groundbreaking would take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months ago</TIMEX>, but it hasn't
happened yet. Still, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> is beginning to seem less of an albatross.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> finally picked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Stewart</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polshek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard M. Olcott</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polshek Partnership</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, along
with exhibit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Appelbaum</ENAMEX>.

            One unanswered question is how much time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
will spend in his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> once his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> is completed. Perhaps he'll live
in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs apartment</ENAMEX> and huff around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in jogging shorts as he did when
he was governor. The rumor of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> run seems dead, but a local satirical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revue</ENAMEX> proposes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> capitalize on his legendary press-the-flesh skill
by working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> greeter. Speaking of pressing the flesh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will
undoubtedly put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> to good use. No one expects that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will spend
a lot of time in carrels poring over his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, but even so, he has a good
track record of making the most of the stacks. It was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law Library</ENAMEX>,
after all, that he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> put the moves on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
