
   
   
      
         
            
<P>Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Sensation&quot; Art Worth the Fuss</ENAMEX>?</P>

            "What modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> wants," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> symbolist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poet Paul Val√©ry</ENAMEX>, "is the grin without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> without
the boredom of its conveyance." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Bacon</ENAMEX> was fond of this quote, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damien Hirst</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Quinn</ENAMEX> are fond of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Bacon</ENAMEX>. Knowing this, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dealer Jeffrey Deitch</ENAMEX> suggested the title for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> exhibition. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bacon</ENAMEX>
cited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Val√</ENAMEX>©ry to mean precisely that modern art, including realist art like his
own, could do without narrative, without literary values. Indeed, art had to
strive to achieve an instantaneity that bypasses laborious storytelling. Things
have pretty much come full circle if you now think that what makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Generation-Sensation</ENAMEX> so groovy is that they "graft" literary themes onto modern
art. I can't quite think that you are being serious when you assert that love
and death and nature are themes germane to literature to the exclusion
of the visual arts: There's plenty of each big theme, I'd have thought, in
Titian, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rembrandt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>.

            You coyly ask permission to voice the heresy that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">formalism</ENAMEX> is overrated, as if we are writing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> and you have something
brave to say. Come on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formalism</ENAMEX> has been the theory non grata
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter of a century</TIMEX>. It has been replaced by a conceptual orthodoxy every
bit as reductive and exclusionary as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Fry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clement Greenberg</ENAMEX> never
actually were. The analysis of art profits nothing by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Manichaean</ENAMEX> opposition
of form and content. It is a symbiosis of form and content that makes
for satisfying aesthetic experience. Anyway, as soon as a generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>
or connoisseurs declares for one, the gauntlet is dropped, and the next will
plumb for the other.

            Incidentally, you do subscribe to one
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">formalist</ENAMEX> dogma. The insistence that one must see an exhibition before
having anything critical to say about ideas and images within it attributes a
great importance to the visceral experience of objects, an attendance to form.
If the art is so much about "real life" as you praise it for being,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communicating</ENAMEX> beyond the precious confines of the art world, dealing with
themes and issues that are bigger than paltry aesthetic experiences, then all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX>, surely, to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Citizen Rudy</ENAMEX> for plunging right in with his criticism?

            To me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Hatoum</ENAMEX>, whose work you admire, is very
typical of a kind of institutionalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-gardist</ENAMEX> whose work sends me to
sleep on my feet. Installation--her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>--is a non-starter anyway, at best a
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> of window dressing or stage design, simply the wrong instrument for
conveying subtle ideas visually (if her ideas are subtle). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatoum</ENAMEX>'s
grating nihilism always needs to revert to theories or story lines extraneous
to the actual object to have any validity, with lots of special pleading on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feminist</ENAMEX> and Third World fronts. It's odd that you started our correspondence
by congratulating the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brits</ENAMEX> for their raucous theory-free and politically
incorrect humor and you should end up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatoum</ENAMEX>, who could have been invented
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> magazine (and virtually was invented by the arid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal Third Text</ENAMEX> ).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Whiteread</ENAMEX> is vastly more interesting, to me,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Hatoum</ENAMEX>. Even with her, though, the problem remains that too much of the
aesthetic decision has been taken before the work begins; that form is imposed
rather than achieved. But still, I'd say to anyone earwigging this
correspondence that it is worth going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, crossing the pontifical
picket line, and breezing past the offal and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofilis</ENAMEX> just for the clear, calm,
meditative experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whiteread's Ghost</ENAMEX> . I've long been convinced
that it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whiteread</ENAMEX>'s masterpiece (better than her short-lived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
and the West <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> watertower), but I'm coming round to realizing that it is
a masterpiece on any terms. So, I must say I'm grateful to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saatchi</ENAMEX> for
letting me see it at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Academy</ENAMEX> at theirs, and now the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>, too. It's a rare case of improvement on repeated viewings.

            But let's be honest:
Most of the stuff in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" evaporates even during the first viewing. As
soon as you "get" the joke, say, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gavin Turk</ENAMEX> depicting himself in a waxwork
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Rotten</ENAMEX>, in the pose of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX>'s portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>, there is not much
left for aesthetic uplift. As an ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saatchi</ENAMEX> will be aware of the
infamous dictum of a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of propaganda (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goebbels</ENAMEX>) that the lie
repeated often enough becomes truth. I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>'s job is to resist the
inevitable process by which junk exhibited often enough (and written about
enough) becomes important.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            P.S.: I hate to think of
you lonely at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX>. How about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> sometime?

         
      
   
