
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Sickness</ENAMEX>

            Ready for vengeance, everyone?

            It is I, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, reporting to
you from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Hall of Consumer Justice</ENAMEX>, a k a the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>'s
poorly air-conditioned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic office</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> has had a terribly busy month
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquaman</ENAMEX> never had it so busy), and he is pleased to report that demand for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> has grown exponentially. He is also disconcerted, because the sheer
number of e-mails in response to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s installment means that too many
evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are treating too many loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> without regard for the
basic norms of customer care, such as answering the phone and not calling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> bad names.

            Before we turn to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s shameful examples of
corporate malfeasance, a couple of housekeeping notes:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> wrote to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
Avenger know they were pissed off by his use of the term "pissed off" in last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>'s column. The term "is offensive to anyone with any sense of courtesy,
pride in themselves, décor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, and sense of decency," the vengeful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reader R.</ENAMEX> wrote.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> notes that he possesses a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal of "décor of personality." He also notes that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, driven
to near madness by customer-service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>, use strong language to
describe their plights, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> is merely reflecting their
anger. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> offers this piece of advice: When writing to
"consumer care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>," or whatever they're being called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, do not use
the honorific "asshole" by way of greeting. And remember: The assholes are the
ones making seven-figure salaries. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the other end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">800</ENAMEX> line
are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">lackeys</ENAMEX> and shills and running <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, but they aren't assholes.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">lackeys</ENAMEX>,
it has now been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 47 days</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johna Burke</ENAMEX>
promised to share her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s reservation policy with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>.
For those of you who missed the , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> attempted to help an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aggrieved U-Haul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> who made a reservation for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, only to be told
close to the time of pick-up that no such reservation existed.

            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>--apparently unimpressed by the supernatural
power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>--has not deigned to provide answers, no fewer
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avengers</ENAMEX> e-mailed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past month</TIMEX>, complaining about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>'s reservation policy. "I reserved a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U-Haul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
to be picked up at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.</ENAMEX>, reports. "I hired some help for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> to help me move. When I arrived <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that morning</TIMEX> to pick it up, I was told
it was not there yet. After much complaining, a few phone calls were made, and
I was told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 miles</NUMEX> away."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.</ENAMEX>'s complaint is entirely typical. Another member
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenging Brigade</ENAMEX>, B., wrote in to say this: "A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX> last <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 th</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July weekend</TIMEX> told me the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>
reservations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> available <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> late, and I only got it by threatening legal action."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> will
revisit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> issue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each month</TIMEX> until satisfactory explanations are
provided. That is the least the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> can do for you, the pissed-off
consumer.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> also put out a call for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airline</ENAMEX> and pest-control horror stories. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wag</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>, wrote in to ask, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX>
there a difference between pests and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>?" (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contest alert: Best</ENAMEX> punch line
e-mailed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
will be rewarded by public mention in this space, plus a lifetime supply of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turtle Wax</ENAMEX>, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> can figure out what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle Wax</ENAMEX> is.)

            The complaints poured in. As noted previously, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> is but one superhero, and he issues abject apologies to all
those who did not receive personal responses.

            Pest control will be dealt with in a future
episode. But about those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>: The interesting thing about the airline
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">complainants</ENAMEX> is that they don't even want the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> to seek
retribution or restitution. All they want to do is vent. Maybe no one believes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> even care anymore or are capable of responding to complaints.

            The complaints covered
the waterfront: baggage problems, surly flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>, mysteriously
canceled flights, billing atrocities. But the most compelling complaints
concerned bereavement fares. There's nothing like an airline screwing with
someone who's going to bury his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to make the blood boil.

            "Recently, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> passed away and I needed to travel
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Wayne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> in order to attend her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">funeral</ENAMEX>," our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D.</ENAMEX> writes. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June of last year</TIMEX>, I had traveled
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Airlines</ENAMEX> (that should send up a few red
flags), and was given a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> travel voucher because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> literally did not
show up. Being that airline tickets, even a bereavement fare, purchased at the
last minute can be quite expensive, I opted to cash in my voucher."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D.</ENAMEX> says he made the reservation by telephone,
holding the seat with his credit card. He was told to present his credit card
with the voucher upon his arrival at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, where he would be charged,
obviously, only for the part of the ticket not covered by the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> voucher.

            Then, trouble. "On arriving at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> I
proceeded to do this and was told by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> that the tickets were already
purchased and I could not use my voucher," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D.</ENAMEX> writes. "I contested this, but
she was unwilling to budge and unwilling to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>, telling me that,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'That</ENAMEX>'s just the way it is.' "

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D.</ENAMEX> says he let it drop, vowing to "settle this
upon my return from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX>."

            After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX>, he contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>, he says,
and after much frustrating dialing, reached an answering machine. "I had to
leave my particulars on a voice mail because no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were available to take
my call. This worked out poorly, since when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> called me back, she got
my voice mail and left a message with the same number. So when I called back,
of course all I got was the same opportunity to leave my particulars on their
voice mail system."

            This is when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arrrghh</ENAMEX>."

            After much go-around,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D.</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX>, told them his plight, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amex</ENAMEX> canceled the
entire charge.

            I e-mailed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laughlin</ENAMEX>, who
responded first by questioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D.</ENAMEX>'s motivation: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s remarks about
the 'plane never showing up' and 'raising red flags' cause me to question his
story. It just sounds like there's something more personal here."

            One could argue that a passenger might have
"personal" feelings about an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> after said airline messed with his head
while he was traveling to his mother's funeral.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laughlin</ENAMEX> followed up, though, by saying that "the
death of anyone close is a very emotional and trying experience, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> frequently behave differently as a result of their pain." She's
still blaming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> but, she continues, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> at the
airport should have taken extra steps to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in his time of need. I
wish that was the case, and I apologize on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Airlines</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grudging</ENAMEX>, double-edged,
but an apology all the same.

            We will return to the issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> in a future
episode, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> would like to relate another tale that caught
his attention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past month</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in question is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX>, and the
story most definitively does not end with an apology.

            In short strokes, the story goes like this: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Summerhill</ENAMEX>, an associate professor of history at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>,
ordered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> phones from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX>. He was billed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>--weirdly, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
different prices (still another charge, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one cent</NUMEX>, was also billed to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> card by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX>). He fought the bill; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX> fought back, by
phone and fax, wasting a good amount of time.

            Finally, his credit card
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> agreed that he was the victim of false billing and canceled out the
charges for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> phones. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summerhill</ENAMEX> continued to be
billed, but one thing he did not receive in the mail was a rebate on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> remaining phones, part of a special promotion he signed up for. Though he
paid for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> phones, he withheld paying his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> fee until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> PCS
straightened out his case and gave him his rebate. In response, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> PCS
canceled his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> and referred his case to a collection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, which is
threatening his credit rating.

            When I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX> (which is a tale in
itself--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">800-line</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>, citing policy, refused to disclose the telephone
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, apparently fearing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> might try
to talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> whose salaries they pay), a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Murphy</ENAMEX>,
told me the case was terribly complex. Actually, it isn't: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> PCS billed a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six</TIMEX> phones, refused to stop billing him, and threatened him when
he wouldn't pay for service pending a resolution of the problem.

            Summerhill, who is now a happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, says he will pay the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> fees when he receives an apology and the
rebate money. The rebate money is owed to him, and so is the apology. He
estimates that he has spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 to 50 hours</TIMEX> trying to straighten out the billing
problem, which is clearly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX>'s problem.

            But no apology is
forthcoming. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> received an e-mail from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Hill</ENAMEX>, an
"executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX>, who writes that she works "directly for Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sukawaty</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> concedes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX> was at fault for erroneously charging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summerhill</ENAMEX> for phones he did
not want--she claims he was charged for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> phones he didn't want, even though
his records show he was billed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>--but she says the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> is also at
fault" for not paying his bill for telephone calls made on the phones he did
use.

            I spoke with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> directly and told her it seemed
reasonable to me that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summerhill</ENAMEX> would withhold payment until his billing
dispute was settled and the rebate issue resolved. She said he was wrong. I
mentioned to her the quaint notion that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> is always right," and she
said, "in my opinion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> is wrong."

            Obviously, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">juju</ENAMEX> has not yet
worked on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summerhill</ENAMEX> reports that it has worked on the
collection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. "I told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that I was reporting this matter to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> consumer protection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
at 
                  Slate
               . She didn't say anything about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> or the consumer
protection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but she did ask me to please not give the name of the
collection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to 
                  Slate
               ."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summerhill</ENAMEX> has
promised to tell everyone at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> and in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Reserve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> to boycott
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX>. "I'm pro-business, I love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, I love capitalism, but these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are crazy," he said. "They could make this go away, but they won't."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint PCS</ENAMEX> could take a cue from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Airlines</ENAMEX>, one of
a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> with sterling reputations for customer
service. A little while back, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> received a plaintive e-mail
from B., who reported that he was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> on his flight not to
receive free drink coupons. Apparently, the flight was late, and as a friendly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gesture Southwest</ENAMEX> let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> get drunk on its dime. But not B. Somehow,
he was skipped over.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Stewart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX>, know of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX>'s sad story, and within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
received this reply: "As I'm sure you've heard, we here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Airlines</ENAMEX>
pride ourselves on our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customer Service</ENAMEX> and would NEVER want it to be said that
we deprived anyone--particularly a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Customer</ENAMEX>!--the opportunity to have a drink
on us."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> will be mailed an apology,
plus <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX>, plus a coupon book for free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>--including mixed
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>!

            "I hope that this will satisfy your sense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>," he wrote.

            It does indeed.

            
               
                  Got a consumer
score you want settled? Send e-mail to shoppingavenger@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
               
            

         
      
   
