
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=630250921-01071999><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Alone</ENAMEX></SPAN>

             

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 23</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover editorial argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is an
uncertain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colossus</ENAMEX>, despite its military and economic dominance. The rejection
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX> and cuts to international peacekeeping
funds demonstrate the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> unilateralism. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
can't guarantee global stability by might alone: It must work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>.
... A survey piece argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> has replaced
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> as the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>. ... An article explores <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's Hamburger University</ENAMEX>--one
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,600</NUMEX> corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> operating in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HU</ENAMEX> teaches the
fundamentals of hamburgerology in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> languages to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> a year. Its
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> hopes to acquire the accreditation to award <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> official
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diplomas</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX>
            

            The
magazine celebrates its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">85 th</NUMEX> anniversary with a cover essay claiming
that liberalism has triumphed in the realm of ideas during the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> values liberalism in a different way. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, democratic freedoms are most fundamental. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>,
negative rights--guarantees against government interference--supercede
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> values. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, positive freedoms--primarily welfare
guarantees--trump democratic and negative freedoms. ... An article says recent natural disasters are not evidence
of global climate change. The real evidence for global warming is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> long-term
trends: The incidence of heavy downpours is increasing and the "frost-free"
season is lengthening.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sugar</ENAMEX>'s stranglehold on public policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Taxpayers</ENAMEX> support
an irrigation system that facilitates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> growing but ruins the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everglades</ENAMEX>. Sugar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX> have funneled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX> to federal officeholders in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past eight years</TIMEX> to block any cuts in sugar subsidies, which add <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> bills. ... A reflection on Woodstock '99
concludes that the concert was a slow-motion riot clogged with overflowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sewage</ENAMEX>, overpriced concessions, and acoustic atrocities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>'s attempt to
raze the festival grounds symbolizes the collapse of communal bonds and
boundaries.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 24</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>'s greatest asset is its pop-culture
appeal. The piece echoes the familiar line that party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nut stew</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">haters</ENAMEX>, pot-legalizers, and campaign-finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>. Juicy
detail: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> views <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> as a shill sent by the traditional
parties to sabotage the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> effort. ... An article marvels at a
"linguistic big bang" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>, where deaf <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have invented their own
language in a generation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teachers</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for the deaf were so inept that
the assembled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> improvised a complex sign system, demonstrating that
language is innate, but requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to grow. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
linguists have observed a language's birth. One creative sign: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Ortega</ENAMEX> is
identified by a tap on the wrist, a mockery of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-president</ENAMEX>'s gauche
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolex</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov. 1</ENAMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> explores <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> niche offerings. Since the
hamburger market is plateauing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">franchisees</ENAMEX> to offer new food
stuffs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McBrat</ENAMEX>, the bratwurst on a bun in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLobster Rolls</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reviving New England</ENAMEX> sales; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indophilic Brits</ENAMEX> are eating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">McChicken Tikka</ENAMEX>; and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> can enjoy the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maharajah Mac</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
25
            

            The
cover story spends a week in a suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> high
school. Highlights: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> take psychopharmaceuticals, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adderall</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zoloft</ENAMEX>. In lieu of metal detectors, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Safe Teams</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> target troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are assisted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who snitch
on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deseg</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> bused from the inner-city find class
differences harder to bridge than racial ones. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 hours</TIMEX> a week
to make up the allowance gap. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
               's prescription for what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ails American</ENAMEX> .) ... An article questions television's awkward
embrace of gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> are featured in prime time,
but few shows are sophisticated enough to script love lives for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homocharacters</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
25
            

            The
cover package celebrates <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>
sports with the recollections of key figures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX> reveals that he plans to fight an exhibition
match, despite his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX>. He says the violent trash talking of his youth
was an attempt to scare white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> because "they scared us." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Owens</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> recalls her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s pride at defeating
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> race" during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1936</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA Commissioner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Stern</ENAMEX> details how a "generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">virtuosos</ENAMEX>" turned basketball into
a marketing machine. ... An article slaps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Entertainment Television</ENAMEX> for refusing to
pay its talent decent wages. Comedians get a fraction of union scale, and even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BET</ENAMEX>'s marquee talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> bristles at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s blaxploitation.
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story argues that archeology casts authoritative doubt
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">creationism</TIMEX> but corroborates key parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>. For instance, a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX> inscription memorializing a victory over the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David"</ENAMEX> provides material evidence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>'s existence, while the
remains of a crucifixion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> indicate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> would have killed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gospels</ENAMEX> allege.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25</TIMEX>
            

            An
editorial congratulates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> for killing the "arms
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> fantasies" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX>. It was an
unenforceable joke. Our next (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should rebuild <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX>. ... An article laments the decline of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dukakis Democrats</ENAMEX>. There are
no paleoliberals left for the right to lampoon. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
really has forged a pro-free-trade, fiscally conservative <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> way.

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
            

            The
chief cover story , countering basic conservative theology,
argues that peace activism helped win the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. The nuclear freeze movement
undermined support for an aggressive military buildup by emphasizing the cost
and riskiness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s own proposal to
eliminate nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> was sparked by the peacenik slogan "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> option."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25</TIMEX>
            

            A
piece argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s economic slide will transform the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> way of
doing business. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> agreements and the tightening of capital markets have
opened <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to foreign investment. The Internet is energizing homegrown
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> and increasing the national appetite for business risk.

         
      
   
