
   
   
      
         
            You Don't Tug on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape</ENAMEX>

            Greetings, oh frustrated and bone-weary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>! It is I,
the great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, who has pledged himself to the betterment of all
humankind, or at least to that portion of humankind that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX>
and rents <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> has much to discuss <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: You
will hear the tale of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hasidic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> who suffered greatly at the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>,
but who, due to his mystical and gentle nature, sought not the help of lawyers
but instead the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, who is a part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kabalist</ENAMEX> and runs
special discounts for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Tuesday</TIMEX>, and you will also learn the winning
answer to the recent contest question "How much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle Wax</ENAMEX> constitutes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s
supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Turtle Wax?</ENAMEX>"

            But first, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> would like to tell
his own tale of consumer woe. Many of you might find this a shocking statement,
but even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> sometimes gets smacked upside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> by the
evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of rampant capitalism. Granted, this seldom happens when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> is wearing his cape and codpiece and special decals, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> seldom ventures outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Hall of Consumer Justice</ENAMEX> in
his cape and codpiece and special decals, on account of the fact that he
doesn't want to get arrested.

            What you should know is
that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> is a mild-mannered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for a major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metropolitan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, and it is in this guise that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
sometimes finds himself holding the short end of the consumer stick. Whatever
that means.

            Take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following</TIMEX> incident, which occurred at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heathrow</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX>, which, I am told, is somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, who
was scheduled to transit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heathrow</ENAMEX>, was
feeling ill and generally fed up at the end of his trip and so decided to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">upgrade</ENAMEX> himself, using his own money, to business class. The total cost of the
ticket: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,732</NUMEX>. Remember that exorbitant sum.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> flight, out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, left late and arrived even later at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heathrow</ENAMEX>, though not too
late to make the connection. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> and several other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were met at the gate by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, who said that there
was no time to make the connection, which was leaving from a different
terminal. Technically, he admitted, there was enough time, but since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airways</ENAMEX> was committed to "on-time departures," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s doors would be
closing early. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> argued in his mild-mannered manner that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX> did not, in fact, have a commitment to "on-time departures"
because the originating flight did not depart on time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
received no answer to this statement. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> was booked
onto a later flight and so asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> if he could use a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX>
telephone to call Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, who would be waiting for him at the
other end. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> directed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX>
business-class <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX>, where a telephone would be made available to him.

            You, of course, know what happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
Avenger was told by a very nasty airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> that only first-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> would be allowed to use the telephone. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
argued, in an increasingly less mild-mannered manner, that the call was
necessitated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX> screw up and, therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX>
should pay for the call, he was told that pay phones could be found outside the
lounge. This was when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> stated very loudly that for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,732</NUMEX>, he
should be allowed to make a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-minute</TIMEX> phone call. And it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>!
Weekend calling rates, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>'s sake!

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX> is an insufferably greedy
little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> was given no recourse but to invoke
the power of his high office. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> asked this nasty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> if she
had ever heard of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>. To the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>'s dismay, this
was her answer: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>"

            What about 
                  Slate
                magazine<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "No."

            Well, whatever. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, while not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">identifying</ENAMEX> himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>--this would have meant changing
into his codpiece and cape in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">business-class lounge</ENAMEX>--informed this poorly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">informed British Airways</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
foremost consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> (this is a lie, but she's <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, so what does she
know?) and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> would hear about this treatment and seek
vengeance.

            Well, did her tune ever change. Not exactly her
tune--she remained as mean as a ferret, but she did let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> use
her telephone.

            The moral of this story
for the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny-pinching</ENAMEX> might make you rich, but it also gets
you blasted in 
                  Slate
                magazine. The other moral: Superheroes
should never travel without their codpiece under their pants.

            There is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> airline the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> believes
understands the fundamentals of customer service, and that is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX>. But more on that in the next episode. First, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>
outrage. The following letter contains perhaps the funniest story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenger</ENAMEX> has heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>, and by now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> has received
upward of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.7 million</NUMEX> complaints about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>. The story comes from one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hwang</ENAMEX>:

            "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year ago</TIMEX>, I, too, reserved a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> and
get this--they said someone with my SAME NAME--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Hwang</ENAMEX> is really
common--and going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAME SUBURB of Chicago</ENAMEX>, picked up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>. Amazing!!
They had to rent a bigger truck to me, which, of course cost more and at that
point, they have you by the balls."

            At least the anatomically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confused Susan Hwang</ENAMEX> got her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>'s
correspondents wind up having to rent from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder and Budget</ENAMEX>, who seem to keep
extra <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> on hand in order to benefit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>'s nefarious practice of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overbooking</ENAMEX>.

            On a semi-positive note, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> did finally
hear from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johna Burke</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>, who apologized for the
inconvenience caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX>, the . (For other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Haul</ENAMEX> horror stories, click .) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX>,
you'll recall, was left standing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-Haul parking lot when a credit-card
reservation he'd made was dishonored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two day</TIMEX> rental
reservation should have been honored so long as he provided us with his credit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card number</ENAMEX>, which we will assume was the case. This is what we at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-Haul call
a 'confirmed reservation.' "

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke</ENAMEX>'s letter, though, is filled with what we at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> call "bullshit."

            "Once we have a confirmed reservation we should
have moved heaven and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> to see that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two day</TIMEX> reservation was
filled," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke</ENAMEX> wrote.

            Yes, of course they
should have--but they never do. This is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke</ENAMEX>'s fault. She is simply paid
to explain the inexplicable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> has received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">164</NUMEX>--no
exaggeration for effect in this instance--letters so far from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who say
they had confirmed reservations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>, only to show up and find no truck
waiting for them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> would like to hear from more--to show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke</ENAMEX> and the bossmen at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-Haul the hollowness of their concept of "confirmed
reservations."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more thing before we get to our tale of rabbinical woe:
the winning answer to the recent contest question "How much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle</ENAMEX> Wax
comprises <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Turtle Wax?</ENAMEX>"

            Fifty-eight of you wrote in, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> with the correct
answer, which is, of course: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Depends</ENAMEX> upon how many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Turtles you wanna wax</ENAMEX>," in
the words of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samir Raiyani</ENAMEX>. Or, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as another</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Bitterman</ENAMEX>, wrote, it "depends on the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX>--and whether or
not you park it in a covered space."

            Unfortunately, because so
many of you wrote in with the more or less correct answer, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
is unable to award the contest prize, which was to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s supply of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>-a-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roni</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> treat.

            Now to our hapless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX>, who wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenger</ENAMEX> seeking worldly justice in his case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>. The story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX>
is entirely typical of the airline industry--a minor problem made enormous by
the cruelty and ignorance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who are, in theory, hired by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedheads</ENAMEX> who run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> to take care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX> in time for his flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, parked curbside, unloaded their
luggage, and proceeded to the check-in counter. There the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> asked a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>
representative if he could leave his luggage by the counter for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to
check in while he parked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, to which he received a positive response and
left to go <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. No one told him, though, that he must first show his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX>'s license to the ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.
            

            The ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> refused to check the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>'s bags
once he left, telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> that "security reasons" forbade him from
checking the luggage of ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> who were not present. But then she told
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>: "If you want, you can pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an extra $100</NUMEX> for the extra
bags"--i.e., charge his luggage to her ticket.

            "How could it be a
security issue," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX> wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, "if they're ready to take
money for the bags<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX> was running late (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> is not a
parking-friendly place), and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> refused to check her bags without his
bags. She was then told that she would miss the flight, and then her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
began crying, and then she began crying.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX> finally made it back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terminal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25 minutes</TIMEX>
before the flight was scheduled to depart. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> handed him one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and
took the other to the gate. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at the counter treated me like a piece
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>," he wrote. "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> she said she's not sure whether the flight is still
open. Then she took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than five minutes</TIMEX> to look around and find someone who
said, 'Yeah, I think we just closed it a minute ago.' ... In the meantime, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> went to the gate and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the gate told her there's plenty of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for me--and let her wait outside the gate for me for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another 15 minutes</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> didn't realize that [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>] could not come because of the luggage
issue and the haughtiness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> downstairs."

            At the ticket counter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX> was told that he
wouldn't make this flight and that he should book himself on another. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, got on the flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> book him on another flight, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> flight, and he schlepped--that's the
only word for it--to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> terminal, only to be told that his was a
"voluntary" transfer--he was late for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> flight--and so therefore he would
have to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $300</NUMEX>. "My fault!?!? I'm thinking to myself, 'If your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have been competent enough to tell me that I should show my
license and courteous enough to put the luggage on for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, then I would be
on a flight now with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, not roaming an airport with a
starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> being sent on a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX> chase."

            Here the story becomes as confusing as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of</ENAMEX>
Leviticus, but suffice it to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> continued to torture <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi S. for</ENAMEX>
another day--finally forcing him to buy a new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> ticket.

            "I have never in my life
been treated so horribly," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX> wrote.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Brown</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>,
to discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX>'s case. To his surprise--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> has not had
very good experiences on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> investigated the complaint and wrote: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>
has issued a credit for the value of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rabbi S.</ENAMEX>'s ticket for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$244</NUMEX>. In addition, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customer Relations</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> has been communicating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> on this
incident and is sending him the difference between that ticket and the cost of
a new ticket, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$219</NUMEX>, plus a letter of apology for the behavior of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Airport</ENAMEX>. She is also enclosing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> travel coupons
valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX> each."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, however, had no
explanation for the behavior at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX> ticket counter--entirely typical
behavior that often makes the already unpleasant air travel experience
completely unbearable.

            In the next episode, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> will tell the
story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Airlines</ENAMEX>, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> that seems to actually care about
customer service. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> needs your help! Keep those airline
stories coming--and all those other stories, too--except computer stories. Let
me say again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> does not fix computers.

            One final request: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> would like
to hear from anyone who has actually eaten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX>-a-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roni</ENAMEX> and from anyone who
could explain why it is known as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> treat."

            Onward, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>!

         
      
   
