
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Diced Islands</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> reports that pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militiamen</ENAMEX> fleeing from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multinational</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> are setting up guerrilla bases
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Timor</ENAMEX>. "They have supplies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, sympathy
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> which they have moved into exile with them,"
says the paper. "The already tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will be, in effect, partitioned, with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> unable to secure the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> warned the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> not to pursue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">militiamen</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Timor</ENAMEX>. He told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX> , "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> will not stand
still if our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s borderlines are breached." (For a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> primer, click
).

            On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eve</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s withdrawal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, the
Straits
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> reported that in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX> on the island,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> were seen selling what appeared to be either looted goods
or redirected foreign aid at "exorbitant prices" to "needy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX>." The
paper said, "Whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, it was clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was being sold to the
highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>--and those with the right credentials. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX> who sided
with pro-independence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> were either ignored or sold goods at sky-high
prices."

            Less
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> after the murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dili</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Bell</ENAMEX> called on the press to
voluntarily reduce their numbers in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. In a column in the
Independent on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , he said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> have better things to
do with their limited resources" than to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. He also claimed
that the number of news-gatherers in areas of conflict has become
"unmanageable. News events get distorted under the weight of them. They bring
an unacceptable increase in the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> from land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>, sniper fire
and brigandage."

            Many
papers around the world contrasted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s ambiguous response to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
earthquake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>'s no-strings-attached aid to rival <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
after that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> temblor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> of slowing
international rescue efforts by refusing permission to fly through mainland
airspace. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> mission, for example, was forced to avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and to take
an air route via <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX>, causing a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12-hour</TIMEX> delay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also said that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has been asserting its sovereignty claim by "thanking foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>
for offering help to 'our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> area.' " Another attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
humanitarian response came in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> , which claimed that when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
that it needed cash donations rather than rescue assistance, the mainland's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a mere $100,000</NUMEX> in cash and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> in relief goods: "small
indeed, when compared with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> has given to help
flood-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> air force bombed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> in what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> described as an attempt to "destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> militants
based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>." The militants have twice invaded the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>
region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagestan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month</TIMEX> and are thought to be responsible for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apartment</ENAMEX> bombings that have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kommersant</ENAMEX> said that the air raids show that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> will no longer capitulate to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> but will only speak in the
language of force" and concluded the raids have rendered the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> leadership
"less bellicose."

            An
op-ed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> Times by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> proposed a bold
solution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-Chechen conflict: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> the territory independence.
Calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechnya</ENAMEX> uprising an "act of banditism" and a "civil war," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kagarlitsky</ENAMEX> said that independence for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> would clarify the situation and
make it much easier to resolve. "If we do declare <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechnya</ENAMEX> independent, we can
create a real border between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, ... that we can give
international status. Such a border would be easy to fortify and control. It
would also be easy to close. ... Likewise, our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would have to
guarantee full equality and respect for the civil rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX> who choose
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> as their place of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> don't have any
clear status. Against such a background, there is an anti-Caucasian hysteria,
which holds any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> from that region responsible for the actions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
in the hills of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagestan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Racist paranoia</ENAMEX> doesn't distinguish between rebel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salespeople</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marketplaces</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Experience Music Project</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> could be in trouble if its
British equivalent is anything to go by. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Centre for Popular Music</ENAMEX>
opened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sheffield</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> but is already threatened with closure after
attracting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> it expected. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX>
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> was seen as "vital in helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to shake off its Full
Monty image of dying industry and unemployment." However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is
said to be too expensive and has been attacked for playing down the "sex and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>" aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>. "It is all a bit innocent," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Frankel</ENAMEX> told the
Times . "You can get round it in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX>, and you expect a bit more
than that for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">£7.95</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12.50</NUMEX>]."

         
      
   
