
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daddys' Boys</ENAMEX>

            Except for political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can tell
you precisely one thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>: His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
No wonder he's in major-league denial when asked about matching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poppy</ENAMEX>'s
achievements. "These are the kind of psychological analyses that I'm not really
thrilled about talking about," he told the New York 
               Times ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">revealing</ENAMEX>, in a classic Freudian protestation, more than he realized.

            But it would be
impossible for anyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s shoes not to bear an especially heavy Oedipal
burden. The life of the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quincy Adams</ENAMEX>--illustrates why. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> has followed in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s footsteps by
attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillips Academy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, getting into the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, running for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and now, seeking the presidency. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX>" (as he was called to
distinguish him from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>) had the more daunting task of succeeding his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and an eminent
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>--as one of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX> of the early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>. If W.
were to learn even a little about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX>'s unhappy plight, he might well realize
the virtues of psychological self-analysis.

            The senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Revolution and wrote the influential tracts Thoughts on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> and
Defence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitutions of Government of the United States</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> . He saw no reason his eldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1767</TIMEX>, shouldn't attain
equal greatness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> set a rigorous course of study for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, assigning
him, for example, to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thucydides</ENAMEX>' History of 
               the Peloponnesian
War in the original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 10</TIMEX>. Morally stern, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> also admonished
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to make "a good account" of himself, and continued to hector him well
into his adulthood. "You come into life with advantages which will disgrace you
if your success is mediocre," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> wrote to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">JQA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1794</TIMEX>. "If
you do not rise to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> not only of your profession but of your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, it
will be owing to your own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laziness, Slovenliness</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obstinacy</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> didn't need his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s entreaties to work hard. He had internalized them fully, and his
copious diary entries reveal neurotically high ambitions and an obsessional
level of self-reproach for not meeting them. "Indolence, indolence, I fear,
will be my ruin," he wrote at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 20</TIMEX>, voicing a refrain he repeated throughout
his hard-working life. At that same young age, he awoke <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> with a
hangover after a night spent caroling with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, during which, he recorded,
"the bottle went round with an unusual rapidity." Yet for all his
self-flagellation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> learned self-control early. It took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and many more hangovers before he learned the same. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX>'s
paternally instilled perfectionism sparked a lifelong case of clinical
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>'s growing-up experiences sparked a born-again Christianity that
has led him to believe all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are bound for hell.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> benefited as well as suffered from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
position. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Herbert Walker Bush</ENAMEX> furnished his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> with contacts in
politics and in the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX> extended to his son equally rare
opportunities. As a boy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> accompanied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> on a diplomatic mission to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
and, through that experience, won the assignment, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 14</TIMEX>, to be secretary
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interpreter</ENAMEX> on another assignment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>. These jobs primed JQA
for his later diplomatic career. And, just as the intellectually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undistinguished George W. doubtless</ENAMEX> got into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> as a "legacy," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX>, though he
had mastered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thucydides</ENAMEX>, surely wasn't penalized for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s name when he
was admitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>.

            For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX>'s earliest
intellectual triumphs, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> senior was at least inadvertently
responsible. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 24</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> wrote his first major work of political philosophy,
in the manner of many works then, under a classical pseudonym, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Publicola</ENAMEX>." A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rejoinder</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Paine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rights of Man</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Letters From Publicola</ENAMEX>"
emphasized the role of passion, not reason, in governing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s political
behavior. Its conservative tone and polished style--compared admiringly to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Burke</ENAMEX>--led many to assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX> had authored it. The case of
mistaken identity fed its popularity and launched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX>'s career as a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essayist</ENAMEX>. The episode stands as yet another eerie precursor to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s
life: As a much-overlooked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> story noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>
became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> largely because many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> they
favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> were "actually thinking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>"; the confusion triggered a
virtuous cycle of high poll numbers, improved fund-raising, and endorsements
that has lifted W. above the pack.

            Naturally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> came both to revere and to recoil from the
magnitude of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s accomplishments. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1793</TIMEX> address, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> vowed that
while "the copious treasures" of fame and achievement "have already been
gathered by the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>," he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> would still stay true
to "the precious memory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sages</ENAMEX>." Though he was ostensibly paying tribute
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, it was not hard to hear the deep filiopietism beneath the
surface.

            On the other hand, JQA
struggled to stake out his own terrain as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> or, his ultimate fantasy, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>. Naturally awed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s achievements, he swore he didn't want a
career in politics (again, not unlike the way W. pursued business after failing
to get elected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 31</TIMEX>). Yet no sooner had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> undertaken his
pursuits as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, recently elected as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, informed him that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX> had named the young man
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>. The news dashed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX>'s hopes for independence from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>. "I wish I could have been consulted before it was irrevocably made," he
said of the appointment. "I rather wish it had not been made at all." The
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, took the occasion to chide his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to start paying
attention to how he dressed.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1797</TIMEX>, he appointed his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to the even more prestigious post of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prussia</ENAMEX>. In both
diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> received laudatory reviews, and he was marked as an
important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in his own right. It could only have served as a painful
reminder of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s still-greater fame, then, when, after losing the
election of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1800</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> recalled his son so as not to give
his rival the satisfaction of deciding whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> should continue in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post</ENAMEX>.

            Following his career as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Quincy</ENAMEX> went on to ascend ever higher in politics. He served as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, and then, during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monroe</ENAMEX>'s presidency, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>, where he was largely responsible
for formulating the principles behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monroe</ENAMEX> Doctrine. Ensconced in what
was then clearly the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> position in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> was the presumptive
front-runner in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1824</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, though it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX> who
won a plurality (yet not the necessary majority) of electoral votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> won
the presidency only because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Clay</ENAMEX> backed him in the run-off in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Representatives</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> never lived down (false) rumors that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay</ENAMEX>
had cut a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corrupt</ENAMEX> Bargain." He unwisely fed the rumors and harmed his own
reputation by naming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>.

            Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>' relatively unremarkable presidency, however,
he rebounded as no other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-president</ENAMEX> ever has. He ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> and, revitalized, served for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX>--notably helping to
overturn the shameful "gag rule" that forbade the reading of anti-slavery
petitions on the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. It takes little imagination to speculate
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX> felt liberated to enjoy this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> career only because on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1826</TIMEX>, midway through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX>'s presidency, his venerated old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> passed away.

            The tragedy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JQA</ENAMEX>'s life is that, for all his
spectacular achievements, he was doomed to feel inadequate next to his
larger-than-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> should only have such problems.

         
      
   
