
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">305</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe Sects</ENAMEX>"

            
               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xinhua</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> described a step <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has taken to ensure "social stability
and safety" during their big <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">50 Years of Revolutionary Rule</ENAMEX> celebration set for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>? What did <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> do?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 304</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hee, Hee</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           You give the lead, I give the headline
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Mirror</ENAMEX> : "HE'S HUGE, HE'S POWERFUL, HE'S FAST
AND HE'S MEAN"
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, and he was in a bad mood. 'The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meek</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX> won't inherit nothin'--they're a bunch of chumps,' He was quoted as
saying."--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>
            

            "In a
world <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> (formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret) Thatcher</ENAMEX> completed his historic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sex-change</ENAMEX> operation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nikonovich-Kahn</ENAMEX>
            

            "Shamu
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">killer whale</ENAMEX>, relaxing in his tank at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea World</ENAMEX> after being given the power
of speech, showed a thoughtful side to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
'I like to bite the heads off seals,' said the giant marine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mammal</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look, I Didn't Ask Them To Give the Hurricane My Name, and I Wish No One Ill</ENAMEX>,
and I Realize It's a Bit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sick</ENAMEX>, but, You Know, I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kind of Glad It's Really</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kicking Ass</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And</ENAMEX>
yet we'd all like to keep working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> ..."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Rogers</ENAMEX>
( similarly , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Thomason</ENAMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Or</ENAMEX>
that's what small, weak, slow-moving, and sweet-tempered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy</ENAMEX> the Friendly
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snail Bent on Taking Over the World</ENAMEX> would have you think."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
Heaney
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            While the headline seems to describe something
pretty scary, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> qualities--huge, powerful, fast--actually sound
pretty appealing until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> comes along. We'd welcome a huge, powerful,
fast <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or coal mining apparatus, or mythical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroad</ENAMEX>-constructing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Henry</ENAMEX>. But meanness trumps the other qualities. Once it arrives in the
sentence, even reversing the previous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> gets you nowhere. There's nothing
attractive about something small, weak, slow, and mean. Horrible. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his twilight years</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> tiny typo, one
dropped letter would transform the headline into a dark and pompous assertion
about the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>: "HE'S HUGE, HE'S POWERFUL, HE'S <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FAST</ENAMEX> AND HE'S <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MAN</ENAMEX>." Two
dropped letters, and we've reached the ludicrously boastful, like the lyrics to
some dreary rap: "HE'S HUGE, HE'S POWERFUL, HE'S <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FAST</ENAMEX> AND HE'S ME." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
dropped letters, and it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> making a catty remark about a co-worker.
That <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">007</NUMEX>, he is just so mean!

            
               Anglocentric
Answer:
            

            "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of terrified <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holidaymakers</ENAMEX> fled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> as monster <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX> headed towards them."

            That storm has
apparently targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vacationers</ENAMEX> with its stormlike fury. Some other
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>-relevant details from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> 's coverage:

            

               "The storm, twice the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> ..."

               " 'It's terrifying,' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debby Campbell</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bath</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somerset</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Shepherd</ENAMEX>."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Gater</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, planned to marry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Robinson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>, there on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
but they are sheltering on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>-floor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballroom</ENAMEX> of their hotel near the
capital <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>. 'The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wedding</ENAMEX> was to be in a gazebo on the beach but I don't
suppose that will still be standing,' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Staffs</ENAMEX>."

               "Were she still alive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">People's Princess</ENAMEX>, would also fear the
colossal storm, but would admirably conceal her terror with a plucky smile and
fistful of mood-altering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> obtained from the rich lay-abouts she thinks of
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> did not add.

            

            Incidentally, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror 's</ENAMEX> headline is not just arbitrary sensationalism; it is
sensationalism with a source, a description of the storm offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, a "public safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>."

            
               More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paladin</ENAMEX> Press
Extra:
            

            Despite it's legal
troubles, the embattled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> has an impressive list of fall titles (many
marked with the coveted symbol "Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource</ENAMEX>") as well as a solid backlist.
Shunning the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, fiction and nonfiction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paladin</ENAMEX>'s
catalog is arranged by categories including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sniping</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silencers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New ID</ENAMEX> and
Personal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Freedom, Action Careers, Combat Shooting, Knives and Knife Fighting</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revenge and Humor</ENAMEX>. Some sample titles:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JUSTIFIABLE HOMICIDE</ENAMEX>, The Intelligent Use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deadly Force</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Hansen</ENAMEX>: "When can you legally shoot an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intruder</ENAMEX> in your home? This
question is on every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s mind when he or she hears a loud bang in the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">middle of the night</TIMEX> or a knock on the door at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>."-- Actually, the question on my mind is. "When will <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henderson</ENAMEX> realize that no means no?"
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EAT WELL FOR 99¢ A MEAL</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kaysing</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This</ENAMEX> book could make
your Y2K experience a lot more palatable."-- Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Frugal Gourmet</ENAMEX> struck
you as just a little paranoid lately?
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EXPERIMENTAL HOMEMADE FIREARMS</ENAMEX>: 
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">9mm Submachine Gun</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P.A. Luty</ENAMEX>: "Imagine you live under a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> that has banned most types of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firearms</ENAMEX>--or controls them so tightly that they may as well be banned. Author
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.A. Luty</ENAMEX> lives in such a place, and he understands the frustration of
attempting to build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homemade firearms</ENAMEX> based on designs that are too complicated
or so <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> as to be undesirable."-- I have the same problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IKEA</ENAMEX>,
except for the blood stains.
               

               
                  THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARMED-CITIZEN SOLUTION</ENAMEX> TO CRIME IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">STREETS</ENAMEX>, So Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Criminals</ENAMEX>,
so Few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bullets</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mack Tanner</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner</ENAMEX> points out the most likely
pitfalls -- including getting around restrictive gun control laws, obtaining
concealed weapon permits and avoiding adverse publicity."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, you shoot a
few school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the press jumps all over you.
               

               
                  THE <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WORLD'S MOST DANGEROUS PLACES, The Hard-Core Adventurers Guide to</ENAMEX>
Getting in, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Getting Around, and Getting Out</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Young Pelton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coskun Aral</ENAMEX>: "This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> is packed with inside info on how to make your way
though hot spots, war zones and lethal lands, whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Botswana</ENAMEX> or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Bronx</ENAMEX>."-- I don't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Botswana</ENAMEX>, but for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> I suggest the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTRAPPING</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ragnar Benson</ENAMEX>: "Includes such mantraps as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malaysian Hawk</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Andes Mountain Trail Trap</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheepeater</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Fall</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cuban Water Trap</ENAMEX>. For academic study only."--I believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ragnar Benson</ENAMEX>
used the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian Hawk</ENAMEX> to trap that dreamy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Spacey</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            

               Clarification
            

            If media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> does choose to dine on human flesh, there are no kosher dietary laws
that need deter him: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> is not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Wrathful deity, woeful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, and (just like
every other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>) wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">penis</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
