
   
   
      
         
            Internet Envy

            The fact that the Internet will make life better
for all humankind has long been noted, even on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>. What seems to
have struck the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> only recently is that the Internet is making a
smaller subset of all humankind--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who start Internet-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or
join them before they go public--incredibly wealthy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
reported as much on its front page recently, so you know
it's probably true.

            Out here in cyberland, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been aware of
this fact for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. Indeed we have talked of little else since about
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1996</TIMEX>, which is the last time anyone mentioned a book except in the
context of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. The basic anecdote--variations on "When I knew him in
college he was stoned all the time ... <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> he was living in a
corrugated box on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>'s compost pile (we all actually pitched in to buy
him a new futon!) ... then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> they had their IPO, and now he's worth
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350 million</NUMEX>"--declined long ago from fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">conversational gambit</ENAMEX> through
staple to cliché.

            So what's new? Money has
always been a fraught topic. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who regularly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> his sex life
and longings for material begged off an invitation to write about the Internet
IPO phenomenon for 
                  Slate
                on the grounds that his feelings about
money are too personal and complex. And envy didn't just become a deadly sin
when its existence was acknowledged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . Nevertheless,
the arrival of Internet Envy on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> buzz axis is new in
several ways.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> used to be surprisingly immune to envy of
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> simply for being richer. A theory long propounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shapiro</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> and 
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contributor</ENAMEX>) is that the financial heights of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> are occupied by
high-salaried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, not by real accumulated or inherited
wealth as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. The lifestyle gap between the middle and upper class
does not yawn in front of, say, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX>--even print <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>!--and high-level civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> live in the
nicest neighborhoods. More important, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has--or had--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> status ranking independent of money. It's a place where puzzled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gazillionaires</ENAMEX> can find themselves snubbed at dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> by deputy
assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> and patronized by minor TV talking heads.

            Even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, where
money matters more, there are (unlike in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>) strong independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subcultures</ENAMEX> in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> or college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> or unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> can
take comfort in an independent value system. They could have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management consultants</ENAMEX> but chose not to be. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the top of those
heaps, earning plenty to live comfortably, honestly wouldn't trade being, say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Natural History</ENAMEX> for being just another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multimillionaire</ENAMEX> investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most days</TIMEX>.

            So what has changed? One element, obviously, is the size of
these Internet fortunes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>. As syndicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> recently pointed out, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers</ENAMEX> like this surging across the
Times business section, even investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> "feel like wage slaves
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>, poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>, these investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> generally
cannot find comfort in an independent value system.) Meanwhile, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
where even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-style fortunes are rare, it seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX> alone
(located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> suburbs) has created a vast new social stratum of
megamillionaires one has never heard of. Gives one pause.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, there's the
speed. It's one thing to console yourself that at least you didn't have to
spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> doing a job you would hate. That trick is a bit harder when you
read that someone (inevitably, someone with the same name as that bozo down the
hall sophomore year ... but it can't be ... look, here's his picture ... oh,
hell) joined some nothing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, sat there through the IPO, and cashed
out, all in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>. How awful can a job be?

            Answer: maybe not so awful at all. In fact, maybe it's
remarkably similar to the job you're doing now. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> startling difference
about Internet IPO wealth is that some of it is raining down on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>!
Writing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, no less, at places like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TheStreet</ENAMEX> and iVillage
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">dot-com, dot-com, dot-com</ENAMEX>). This is something truly new in the history of the
known universe. 
                  Slate
               's former "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX>
Yoffe observes: "You no longer can say, 'Sure I could have made a lot of money
if I'd decided to be a Wall Street money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grubber</ENAMEX>.' And it's not just [a famous
TV hack] spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> speaking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aluminum Manufacturers</ENAMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>. We're talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> getting seriously rich just by being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>."

            Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have
joined software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> and business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> in peddling the other basic
Internet Envy anecdote: variations on, "Oh yeah, they offered me the top job at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Somedamnedsite</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>--begged me to take it, offered me <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of the equity
plus options for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 75</TIMEX>--but I turned it down." Even during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first few</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of Internet frenzy, Internet Envy was not widespread in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>-D.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">buzzworld</ENAMEX> because the whole thing seemed to be happening on another planet--to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> one not only didn't know but could scarcely imagine. Only very recently
have lottery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> started popping up in one's own neighborhood.

            Internet Envy exists in cyberland itself, too, but it is
much more straightforward. Everybody is trying to do the same thing; some
succeed, and those who don't are envious. You don't have to pretend that you're
not. And there's no queasy feeling that you must have misplaced that notice
explaining how the rules were about to change. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Paragraph 19, Line 106</ENAMEX>,
replace the words <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Pulitzer Prize for Nonfiction</ENAMEX>' with the words 'seven <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty million dollars</NUMEX>.' ") Also, unlike back <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>, there's no vertiginous
obsession with how young these IPO-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> are, because almost everybody is
scandalously young.

            The rules have indeed changed. But they're always
changing, in a couple of ways. Some changes in personal values are simply part
of growing older. Then there are shifts in the values of the general
culture.

            To oversimplify: In high
school the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> are on top (unless, of course, armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> storm the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and mow them down). But the smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> tend to win in adult
life. The glow of that happy discovery can last for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX> Myrhvold
explained and simultaneously demonstrated in a recent 
                  Slate
                "."
These are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> lucky enough to be able to choose their careers and to have a
good shot at success at whatever they choose.

            At the crucial moment when they make their choices, many of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> honestly believe that money--beyond the cost of upper-middle-class
comfort--is not all that important to them, and most of them may turn out to be
right. But some are responding to the fleeting hormonal surges of youthful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">idealism</ENAMEX>, or to the special status hierarchy of the academic subculture where
they temporarily reside. In the most tragic examples, a charismatic professor
will entice them into a lifetime of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> medieval history, about which their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curiosity</ENAMEX> is exhausted before they get their Ph.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.s.</ENAMEX> In less extreme cases,
they become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. Then they discover, in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">30s</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40s</TIMEX>, that money is
important to them after all. This is the moment when reading about some
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28-year-old</TIMEX> who's suddenly worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> can have an effect that requires
medical attention.

            Sometimes this personal
process of maturity or decay (take your pick) is reinforced by what's happening
in the culture. Money is never unimportant, but there are moments when it is
more important than others. This is one of them. Actually, a graph of the
changing value of money in the status market would look a lot like a graph of
the Dow Jones industrial average: It rose steadily starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 1982</TIMEX>--the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> a star <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> shocked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist colleagues</ENAMEX> by
quitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> to become an investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>--crested and sank
briefly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, quickly recovered, and has been hitting new heights
ever since. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, when even the most softhearted and public-spirited
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> become venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX>, younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may find it hard to believe
there was ever a time when even an extremely ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, motivated
entirely by a desire to do well--rather than to do good, or to do anything in
particular--might well decide to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>. But it's true.

            Of course it's possible that the stock market and the
status market have peaked together again. Price-earnings ratios are perilously
high in both. A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400 million</NUMEX> fortune gets you about as much status as a mere
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> got you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speculators</ENAMEX> in status futures are rumored to
be pulling out of money and getting into undervalued properties including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kindness</ENAMEX>, musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, and short-term memory. The decline of money is also
expected to benefit blue chips such as physical beauty, according to some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>.

            So maybe this is the wrong moment to cash in your
reputation as a saint--based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half decades</TIMEX> spent bathing patients
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> leprosy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>--for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a job</TIMEX> (with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> equity stake) as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leper</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> (soon to be LPRC on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ</ENAMEX>). In this market as in others,
timing is everything.

         
      
   
