
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">282</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;It'll Take a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miracle&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               An inquiry into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> began in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> opted to
fast-track her canonization, waiving the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> post-death waiting period.
Beatification, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step toward sainthood, requires a confirmed miracle,
and one has already been "authenticated." Name that miracle.
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">281</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sign Here":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>, at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,200</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vicksburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, erected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> identical
signs. Now one has been spray-painted with the word "hypocrite," and the other
has been smashed to pieces. What do the signs say?
            

            "Three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peace, Love, and Music</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Novak</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sale--Soft Money Welcome</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Kenher</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vicksburg's Pledge: No Unnecessary Signs</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlin</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, please spray paint 'hypocrite' on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these signs, and smash the
other to pieces. Thank you."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nikonovich-Kahn</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Hastings</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonnie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McDermott</ENAMEX> )

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX>
Fordice hates sex, violence, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>! And he loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Fordice</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX>
Shearer Gabel
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s signs may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smashed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX>-painted--and where I grew up they were often pockmarked with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">buckshot</ENAMEX>--but this sort of treatment is generally reserved for public property.
It is surprising how seldom one sees enameled profanity splashed across a
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. There is the occasional graffiti-covered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van</ENAMEX> (and once the first
scarlet streak appears, others swiftly follow), but not many. Our vandals
apparently lack class consciousness. They are great respecters of private
property. They refrain from defacing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lexuses</ENAMEX>, these being objects
of envy, not resentment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> walks the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> unafraid that someone
will scrawl some harsh architectural criticism across his vast backside. Even
in the suburbs, where dogs run free, no poodle comes home with a hammer and
sickle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX>-painted on his side. There really is no Left in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic Pride</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home of Governor Kirk Fordice</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fordice</ENAMEX>, whose adulterous affair is nothing at
all like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s adulterous affair, continues to irritate the home
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Habeed</ENAMEX>, a city
alderman, wants to get rid of the signs "to remove the mixed or ambiguous
messages that are out there about marital loyalty." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wilbur</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governor's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, urges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mississippians</ENAMEX> to look at "the big picture."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Williams</ENAMEX>' World of
Signs
            

            A sign here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Dumping Whatever</ENAMEX>,"
but it's printed on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lines, so it's easily read as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Dumping</ENAMEX> (Whatever)."
By confusing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whatever" with "Whatsoever</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of this sign has created
a monument to late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -century</TIMEX> civic cynicism: the self-mocking
sign. No one's going to obey it anyway, so why bother? Embrace the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">futility</ENAMEX>.

            Others that come to
mind:

            "Speed Limit <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35 mph</NUMEX> (Yeah right)"

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Men Working</ENAMEX> (As if)"

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Falling Rocks</ENAMEX> (No
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shit</ENAMEX>)"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX>'s
Suburban Bliss
            

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of a Levittown
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>--it was my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> home! There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on the block. When my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mom</ENAMEX> made her weekly trip to the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> patch up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> injured in a game of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> or Catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX>, it
was a given that another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> would "look after" us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, even though we were
all running in opposite directions.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would drive to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones Beach</ENAMEX> to load up on sand for the sandbox that he built in the backyard.
The greatest thing about the price of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would say, was that it
included a washer and dryer. It was the only way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who didn't
have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nickels to rub together could own a home-- no down payment .
Mortgages ran <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $57</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>. The table where we ate every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> was a picnic
table! And, yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> stopped right in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. I had a
little chrome coin changer just like he did--I would click out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nickels and
he would click out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three pennies</NUMEX> change. Levittown was the happiest place on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kieran Healy</ENAMEX>'s
Erratum
            

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Errata"</ENAMEX> should read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erratum</ENAMEX>."

            [If you count the
"carybdis" spelling as one error, and "errata," the plural, as another error,
then there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mistakes, and thus errata, the plural is correct, in which
case there is only one mistake, in which case errata, the plural, is now
incorrect, in which case my head starts to hurt and I have to go lie
down.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>.]

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Some kind of crazy paradox.

         
      
   
