
   
   
      
         
            
<P>Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Sensation&quot; Art Worth the Fuss</ENAMEX>?</P>

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>,

            You accuse me of being overly literal and insist
that I'm not sufficiently sensitive to "surface, shape, color," and the formal
qualities of art. I make no apologies for my taste. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henrik Ibsen</ENAMEX> once wrote
that you can't chose whom you fall in love with; you can't choose what works of
art you fall in love with, either. To me, a great work of art is roughly equal
to a great phone conversation--it pulls you out of your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and allows you
to join with someone else.

            May I add that I find formalism entirely overrated?
I think it's led to a lot of arid, deadening art. It may sound old-fashioned to
say so, but I do want art to reflect lived experience rather than just
classroom questions. I think one of the problems of contemporary art is that it
has lost touch with the big themes --namely, love and nature and death.
These, of course, are literary themes rather than art themes, yet I think that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" are helping to bring narrative back into art.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, of course, is a literary culture, and basically I feel that the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> are grafting literary themes onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX> forms devised
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> (true to myth, we're all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX>) are
good at busting up established conventions, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brits</ENAMEX> (who actually read books)
are good at finding metaphorical meaning in the forms that we over here
conceived.

            Let's talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Hatoum</ENAMEX> for a moment (who I
realize is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> but who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and is part of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>"
generation). I loved her (wittily titled) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> --a real-life
dinner table chastely set for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. I looked at it and thought to myself, "It's
a 3-D <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Brookner</ENAMEX> novel." I think the piece says something about female
loneliness, but it does more than that, too, because the lung projected (via
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laser</ENAMEX>) onto the dinner plate brings <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anatomy</ENAMEX> into the equation. What does the
piece mean? Lungs allow us to breathe, but here the act of breathing seems to
guarantee little beside the likelihood of dining alone.

            And now I head off to
lunch (by myself)--

            Until
later,

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah</ENAMEX>

            P.S.:
What do you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Billingham</ENAMEX>'s photographs of his down-and-out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>? I think there's a lot of tenderness in his work.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.P.S.</ENAMEX>: I realize I will
never convince you of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Lucas</ENAMEX>' worth (I think of her as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchamp</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>), but are you at least willing to concede that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Saatchi</ENAMEX>
deserves points for taking a gamble on young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> instead of just buying de
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koonings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Stellas</ENAMEX> and the blue-chip stuff that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> favor?
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX> painting, they do not help the art world; they
merely help the art market. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saatchi</ENAMEX>, by contrast, has kept a whole generation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> from having to wait tables.

         
      
   
