
   
   
      
         
            Hail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry VI</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 th century</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ostentatiously pious</ENAMEX>, surrounded by
mediocrities, and oblivious to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s crumbling international prestige, he
managed to cripple the military and bankrupt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> simultaneously.
Contemporary accounts repeatedly emphasize his gullibility. Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lancastrian</ENAMEX> party judged him an unworthy successor to their
previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">standard-bearer</ENAMEX>, the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX>, identified in the popular mind
with the romance of chivalry and the tragedy of an early death.

            All <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> cheered when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VI</ENAMEX> was driven from
office by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward IV</ENAMEX>, an almost unbelievably charismatic and handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose
personal badge, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Splendor</ENAMEX>, evokes the image of a shining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hill</ENAMEX>. The elegance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX>'s court contrasted sharply with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>'s drab and
simple style, and the implied promise of a brighter future proved spectacularly
true. After a rocky <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first few years</TIMEX> in office, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> shored up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restored England</ENAMEX>'s presence abroad, initiated serious economic reforms, and
presided over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> of remarkable peace and prosperity. He was, however,
frequently distracted by attacks on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, who was seen as an extravagant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spendthrift</ENAMEX> and a sinister influence on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> was followed in office by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard III</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had been closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> than any other. Though renowned for his great
personal courage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> was widely disdained as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with no guiding
principles other than an instinct for power. Before long he had squandered his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predecessor</ENAMEX>'s magnificent legacy. The general dissatisfaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
spilled over onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorkist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, which had seemed so invincible with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX>
at the helm, and raised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lancastrian</ENAMEX> hopes of regaining the crown.

            Determined not to miss
this opportunity, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lancastrians</ENAMEX> swallowed their distrust of relative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> and turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Tudor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> was from the remote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, but he looked like a winner. And so he was. After ousting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> and
claiming the throne as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Henry VII</ENAMEX>, one of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official acts was to raise
taxes. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>'s tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Morton</ENAMEX>, who invented the notorious
policy known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fork</ENAMEX>": If you live extravagantly, then you can
obviously afford to pay more taxes. On the other hand, if you live frugally,
then you can obviously afford to pay more taxes.

            If history repeats itself, we ought to be able to
figure out who's destined to succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry VII</ENAMEX>
was followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VIII</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> best remembered for his gargantuan appetites,
his dissipative lifestyle, his troubled marriages, and his rocky relationship
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX>. The message is clear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX>, your time has come
at last.

         
      
   
