
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy Guys</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Bowfinger
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> reviews for
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX> comedy about a low-rent movie<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-maker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>) and
his ragtag stable of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>: "Perhaps the funniest movie for grownups so far
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>, out of desperation, hires a
painfully awkward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerd</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murphy</ENAMEX>) who has no film experience other than being "an
active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renter</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX>" but who bears a striking resemblance to action
star <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kit Ramsey</ENAMEX> (also played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>). "It's one of those comedies where
everything works," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). A few
find the film spotty ("likable albeit hit-and-miss"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ), but most agree this ranks with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>'s best
comic works. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> and here to find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokedown Palace</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox Film</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>). In a strikingly similar plot to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Beckinsale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Danes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> recent high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grads</ENAMEX> who
travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, on a whim; they get mixed up with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
con <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and wind up in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33-year</TIMEX> sentences for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> smuggling. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are unmoved: "just another lurid, contrived, xenophobic tale about
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> trapped in hideous foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ). A few call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danes</ENAMEX>' performance better than the rest of the film but
concede that even her nice turn can't save the film. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to see a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boatload</ENAMEX> of pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Danes</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Illuminata
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overseas FilmGroup</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Turturro</ENAMEX>
directs, co-writes, and stars in a story set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn-of-the-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
about an acting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troupe</ENAMEX> whose onstage and offstage lives intertwine. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> report mixed reactions: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]his handsome, airtight meditation on art,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrity</ENAMEX>, love, and rampant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">repertory-group</ENAMEX> horniness indulges in a lot of
very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> navel gazing" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> gives the film its most upbeat review, calling it an "enormously
fond homage to the world of acting, beguilingly presented and filled with
knowing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX> humor" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> get special
note for their performances: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Walken</ENAMEX> as a flamboyantly foppish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sarandon</ENAMEX> as an aging but still dynamite diva. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Turturro Shrine</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Woman Who Cut off Her Leg</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maidstone Club</ENAMEX>
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Slavin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Holt</ENAMEX>). In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slavin</ENAMEX>'s debut collection of fantastical and
surreal stories, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> fall in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, swallow their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawn</ENAMEX>-care
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, disintegrate (literally), and--as you may have guessed from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX>--cut off their legs at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chi-chi country clubs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamptons</ENAMEX>. Critics
respond positively for the most part: "even at their most outlandish these
stories never feel forced ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slavin</ENAMEX>'s uncluttered, room-temperature prose
renders the monstrous familiar, even beautiful" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Taylor</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). Others note that "[i]t seems to be a common,
almost universal, tactic in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> literature to depict the suburbs as a
duplicitous world where a safe, materialistic, blandly cheerful surface
conceals a dark secret life" and that the stories' predictable outlandishness
verges on becoming "precious" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Budnitz</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). Or as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirkus Reviews</ENAMEX> writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slavin</ENAMEX> has a warped sense of humor and enjoys
rubbing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s nose in it." (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> here.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Introducing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Dandridge</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halle Berry</ENAMEX>'s pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">biopic</ENAMEX> (she stars and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> produces) of
Dandridge, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> to earn an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar nomination for Best</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Actress</ENAMEX>, gets a lukewarm reception: "a devoted but ultimately dull hagiopic"
marred by "a flat script and uninteresting narrative" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Poniewozik</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Some of the more sordid parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dandridge</ENAMEX>'s life have been left
out, and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berry</ENAMEX> captures <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dandridge's</ENAMEX> beauty and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glamour</ENAMEX>, she lacks her heat and sensuality. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berry</ENAMEX> has said she hopes this movie
will launch her into the kind of leading roles that are (as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dandridge</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>)
unavailable to black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> seems to think it will, weighing in
with a great review: "an enthralling biopic ... her most heartfelt performance
to date" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Fries</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about the movie and here to
find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dandridge.</ENAMEX>)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Movie
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit Rock City</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). Pans for this
tale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and their quest to watch a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss</ENAMEX> concert: "loud,
vulgar, cartoonish, obnoxious, dizzying, disposable and more than a little bit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shrill</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim DeRogatis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). Highlight: a tongue-cam
point of view from inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Simmons</ENAMEX>' mouth.

         
      
   
