
   
   
      
         
             Do Nothing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>!

            It's not an idea that comes easily to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">movers</ENAMEX> and shakers, but in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital, a potentially powerful
interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is coalescing behind the cause of ... doing nothing.

            Not nothing in the
personal sense, of course. Nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> go about their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> business
just like anyone else: walking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, driving to work, thinking big thoughts,
making big deals, whatever. What unites them is their belief that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
interests would best be served if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would just pack it in.

            The guiding principle behind the movement was perhaps first
articulated by that pre-eminent oracle on things economic, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>. Given the current exuberant state of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, he told a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> that his preferred use of
any surplus in the federal budget would be to retire the federal debt. With
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> personal savings running in the negative range (net investment by the rich
being more than offset by borrowing by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> ever more
dependent on borrowing private capital from abroad, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> concluded it
would be prudent for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> to do a little saving for us. And, of course,
using surplus federal funds to buy back outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bonds and notes
frees up private capital for other investment.

            (Understand that any
money left over in the "general fund," i.e., money not earmarked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, is automatically invested in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bonds. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> would
not, in that case, need to do any new borrowing, those bonds would have to be
bought back from the public and retired. The same is true of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> trust funds--but only as long as the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX>, which it hasn't been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. Otherwise, the payroll tax surpluses
are used to cover borrowing done to finance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>,
weather forecasts, and all the other things that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does. So what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> is hoping is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will allocate no more for new tax cuts or
spending than it can cover with the remaining taxes.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> didn't spell out how he hoped that would be
accomplished. But other budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX>, from both parties, have come
increasingly to the view that, when it comes to direct action by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, less
is more. "We get to talking about the do-nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> as a bad thing, but
look at the alternatives," says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Cox Wait</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> for a Responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX>. Wait points to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s last-minute <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>
billion-plus "emergency" supplemental as a prime example of "what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> does
when it's under pressure to do something." Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reischauer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, agrees. "The salvation of the nation
may be in gridlock," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reischauer</ENAMEX>. "It's dangerous to let a pre-election
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> play with tax and entitlement legislation in a surplus
environment."

            That's especially so
when those surpluses are as incorporeal as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macbeth</ENAMEX>'s dagger. Calculations by
both private and official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> show that the existence of any <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX>
surplus in the non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> part of the budget depends upon a fiction:
It is that this and future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congresses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> will agree to cut domestic
and military spending (other than entitlements) by some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 10 years</TIMEX>. That fiction is embodied in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> balanced budget agreement
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> endorsed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">act</ENAMEX> sets a
limit on so-called discretionary spending (both domestic and military) for next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> that is lower than current spending. The limits are even lower in the
following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX> are required to assume the limits will actually be met
when they make their projections (a point generally overlooked). Budget
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> noted at the time the caps were enacted that they were absurdly
unrealistic, but the caution was lost in the general celebration.

            Now, even highly placed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
secretly subscribe to stalemate. "It won't be the end of the world," said one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, "It's not a bad outcome." But comments such as this are strictly not
for attribution. True, when pressed, top economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> have called the
spending caps "totally unrealistic," but they are loath to press this point too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loudly</ENAMEX>, lest it call into question both their own plans for additional
"investments" (read spending and tax breaks) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s embrace of the
limits in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. That coyness led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to issue a budget
that, by assuming the caps would be effective, showed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 trillion</NUMEX>
general fund surplus that triggered the current orgy on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> led off
the festivities <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by passing "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Financial Freedom Act</ENAMEX>." This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">effusively</ENAMEX> named tax cut would, even after some cosmetic improvements to
placate fiscal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, likely absorb more than the total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX>
surplus. (That includes interest costs on the extra debt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> will
incur if it doesn't buy back outstanding securities.) The measure is artfully
constructed to hide its full cost; big-ticket items, such as repeal of the
estate tax and the alternative minimum tax and across-the-board rate cuts,
aren't fully phased in until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2009</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> now calculates that over
the following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>, the tax cut will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $3 trillion</NUMEX>--this just at
the time that retiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> are starting to drain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
surpluses.

            Of course, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">piously</ENAMEX> embraced the notion of a "lockbox" for the trust fund surpluses, but
each doubts the strength of the other's padlock construction. And with good
reason. There is no box that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, with the acquiescence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, cannot unhinge in the dead of an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> when the budget is
finally nailed together. Remember that any overspending in the general budget
automatically results in borrowing from the trust funds--and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
despite its lip service to the spending caps (and the surpluses that depend
entirely upon them), is even now busy marking up appropriations bills that
exceed the caps by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of billions of dollars</NUMEX>.

            Consciously aiming for stalemate would not be
acceptable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Ever since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> mocked the "do-nothing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>," our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> have been sensitive to charges that
their time is spent only in pandering, politicking, and pot thumping. And no
one is suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> pack up and go home forthwith. That would
make for a mighty dull <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> for us news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX>. But after the requisite
barb-trading with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and a much-photographed round of
negotiations in which the sanctity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and the need to invest in
our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are duly invoked, it would be a blessing if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
would quietly pass a continuing resolution keeping spending more or less where
it currently is, and then take to the hustings, where each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> can blame the
other for doing what's best for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--nothing.

         
      
   
