
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=630250921-01071999><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beau Coup</ENAMEX></SPAN>

             

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> coup wasn't so bad. Deposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz Sharif</ENAMEX> was corrupt, using his power to punish political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> and undermine independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government institutions</ENAMEX>. But "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s
beaten-up constitution has been molested yet again," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> takeover
could inflame tensions with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. ... An article calls the defeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban</ENAMEX>
Treaty "a disaster for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s foreign-policymaking process." In an attempt
to humiliate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> exposed its "creeping isolationism" and
reckless willingness to hinder global security for partisan pleasure.

            

               
                  New
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 1</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story depicts retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Paxon</ENAMEX> as the "shadow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>." When he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>
to dictate legislative provisions. Now that he is a high-paid "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>" at a
lobbying law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX> serves as consigliere to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX>
and as one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pipelines</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX> is persuading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubya</ENAMEX> dictate their agenda. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
               's
of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Al.</ENAMEX>)
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        Wired
                     
                  
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>

            The
cover story marvels at iSmell, a computer device that manufactures scents using
a software program linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">odor wells</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DigiScents</ENAMEX> , envisions
that every PC will be hooked up to "reekers" so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> can enjoy
odor-enabled Web sites. The technology could also add the smell of gunpowder to
action films or burnt flesh to computer games.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 17</TIMEX>
            

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six millennium</TIMEX> issues centers on self-centeredness. An article claims
we are exiting the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me Millennium</ENAMEX>." Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past thousand years</TIMEX>, humanism,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX>, and the advance of capitalism have conspired to displace the worship
of God with self-veneration. (In the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitney Houston</ENAMEX>, "learning to
love yourself" has become "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Greatest Love of All</ENAMEX>.") ... An essay
explores the rule-free zone between college and marriage. "Most prevalent in
high-income urban ZIP codes," the period of career cultivation and serial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monogamy</ENAMEX> is unique in its absence of commitments. This uncharted period of
freedom teaches "loopy, chattering disconnected I 's" about the emptiness
of an unmoored existence. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> publishes an "album of
archetypal personalities." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faust</ENAMEX> is the prototypical transgressor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lassie</ENAMEX> is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwart friend</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18</TIMEX>
            

            An
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unabomber Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX> finds him good-humored
and sincere. He savages his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> for turning him in, claiming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
was seeking revenge for the attention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> got from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. The author
postulates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted hates David</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> got married while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> remained
alone. Weird details: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> receives The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of</ENAMEX>
Books , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and spends his rare
recreation time with fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX>.
... The cover story lionizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX> for his wizardry at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pixar</ENAMEX>. The article raves about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s new iMac and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pixar's Toy Story 2</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> is the same "brilliant man-child" he's always been. ... A piece
describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Learning Channel</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>-targeted reality TV shows: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wedding Story , A Baby Story , and A Dating Story</ENAMEX> , featuring
real-life marriages, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, and dates.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18</TIMEX>
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newsweeklies' Gen Y</ENAMEX> obsession continues with a cover
story on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tweens</ENAMEX>," the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-to-14-year-olds</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Banal conclusions: They love the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Backstreet Boys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Austin</ENAMEX>, and their "superficial sophistication"
hides insecurity. ... A piece warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s nuclear power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> are shabby and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decaying</ENAMEX>. An accident <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> times worse than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chernobyl</ENAMEX> is possible. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
nor the rest of the world will pay to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> safe or to close them.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fertilizer</ENAMEX> runoff from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi River</ENAMEX> has killed sea life
over an area the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf of Mexico</ENAMEX>, says an article . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Farmers</ENAMEX> are resisting calls to curtail fertilizer
use.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
18
            

            A
special report looks back at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> after the
fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' revolution that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX> envisioned
occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern Europeans</ENAMEX> overturned authoritarian rule.
Ultimately, the threat of nuclear combat eased the risk of hot war, and
quarrels among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> prevented <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> dominance worldwide. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> says the enclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> is declining. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shoppers</ENAMEX> are
moving from suburbs to urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and buying online or from big discount
chains. A sure sign that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> is outmoded: They just tore down the shopping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> that was the setting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fast Times</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ridgemont High</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  The
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18 and Oct. 25</TIMEX>
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next</ENAMEX>" issue. An article describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKinsey & Co.</ENAMEX> markets itself
to recruits as a halfway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for the best of the brightest. The
consulting-firm-cum-finishing-school allows risk-averse overachievers to learn
more about business by acting as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> for hire. ... A profile of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jason McCabe Calacanis</ENAMEX> portrays the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Alley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporter</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Winchell</ENAMEX> of the Internet age. The working-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> and business conferences for and about the
Web world. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Alley 100</ENAMEX> list defines who has made it in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberbusiness</ENAMEX>. ... In a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>" item, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Reagan Jr.</ENAMEX> praises
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX> . "For all its fictive excursions," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>' biography
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">captures</ENAMEX> "the contradictory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" he calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junior</ENAMEX> admits a
friendship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> of flip-flopping on
abortion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> staunchly opposed abortion and federal funding for it when he
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '80s</TIMEX> but reversed himself once he
entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Now he tries to pretend he was never pro-life. ... A
funny profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman-elect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Gargan</ENAMEX> finds
him refreshingly honest, though only slightly less nutty than the rest of his
party. (He's been a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-racing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX>, and handwriting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>.) He can't control the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reformers</ENAMEX> and doesn't know which of their wackos
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fulani</ENAMEX> ...) is going to come out on top.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> mocks the travails of shahtoosh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>. Shahtooshes are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> shawls
made from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> of endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antelopes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Socialites</ENAMEX> cling to their
shawls, even though it is illegal to sell or import them. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX> federal
court ordered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Brinkley</ENAMEX> and Nan
Kempner, to turn in their shahtooshes. ... The cover profile claims <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrey</ENAMEX> is more than the sum of his puerile jokes. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> of
physical comedy" is an intelligent, introspective lone wolf and a thinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX>. His virtuoso portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX> in the forthcoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon</ENAMEX> proves that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrey</ENAMEX> is more than just a "turbocharged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vaudevillian</ENAMEX>."

            

               
                  Business
                
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week, Oct. 18</TIMEX>
            

            A
special report applauds the rising incomes of the poor. After losing ground for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX> have enjoyed a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> increase in
inflation-adjusted income over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>. The pay hike is being driven
by taut labor markets and the revival of inner-city industry. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> examines <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s life after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> a speech,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> is expected to make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> just from blabbing. He has started a
corporate consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> on high-tech and health issues. His
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> pulled in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>.

            

               
                  The
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story denounces welfare reform. Welfare-leavers are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arbitrarily</ENAMEX> denied food stamps, child care, and transitional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>. Rather
than easing the transition from welfare to work, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> hoard block grants and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dodge</ENAMEX> their obligations to the poor. ... An article attacks an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Naturalization Service</ENAMEX>
program to root out illegal immigrant labor. Operation Vanguard subpoenas
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">personnel</ENAMEX> records and uses the information to target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> for deportation.
The piece argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> is deviously designed to lower wages.

         
      
   
