
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CREEP Show</ENAMEX>

            The delightful comedy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> defaces the memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most cherished political scandal.
It's a mustache on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Lisa</ENAMEX>--or maybe a big, crooked dick on the cover of
All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> . Simply put, the movie makes the charming
case that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>'s pseudonymous high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, was not
(as recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" columns have speculated) an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> honcho such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Mark</ENAMEX>
Felt, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bubble-headed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blondes</ENAMEX>.

            According to the film,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Williams</ENAMEX>) lived at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel</ENAMEX>, and she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirsten Dunst</ENAMEX>) were the ones who put the duct tape on the stairway lock that
led security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> to the burglars. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> were slipping out to mail their
entry to a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Win a Date With Bobby Sherman</ENAMEX>" contest.) To keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene</ENAMEX>
quiet about having seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Gordon Liddy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX>) at both the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Hedaya</ENAMEX>) made them "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Official White House Dog</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walkers</ENAMEX>"--in which capacity they stumbled on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shredding
documents and counting piles of payoff money. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> tells it, the
story got even weirder: Here at last is the druggy truth behind détente! And
you won't believe what was really on those <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18½ minutes</TIMEX> of erased Oval
Office tape!

            The amazing thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> (directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleming</ENAMEX> from a script he wrote with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheryl Longin</ENAMEX>) is that it manages to
burlesque the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> mythos without trivializing it. Under its slapstick
shenanigans, this modest movie offers a convincing vision of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
operations as a sordid buffoon show undone by a couple of painfully earnest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">innocents</ENAMEX>: It's nature's revenge on the overweening. The larger truths are all
there, and some of the smaller ones, too--like the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>
would extend even to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> (another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Checkers</ENAMEX>), or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernstein</ENAMEX>
might seem as vain and as clumsily ambitious as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> they're pursuing.
Post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, it isn't odd to think of wide-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airheads</ENAMEX> wandering the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Crowley</ENAMEX>, it isn't even odd to think of wide-eyed
airheads drinking in the wisdom of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>.) It's blissfully satisfying
to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene</ENAMEX>--who has replaced her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Sherman</ENAMEX> posters with those of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> and who fantasizes about romping on a beach with him in slow motion--come
to her senses and utter the immortal reproach, "You kicked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Checkers</ENAMEX> and you're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prejudiced</ENAMEX> and you have a potty mouth!"

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have
compared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick to Alexander Payne</ENAMEX>'s great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>), to
which it bears not the faintest resemblance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payne</ENAMEX> employs multiple points of
view, probes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' psyches, and edits with a snap. By contrast,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> is rather limp. The pacing is purposefully slack--the gags just
dribble out. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleming</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> face is perfect for making you giggle at offhand
insertions of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> minutiae or urban-paranoid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions cribbed</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan J. Pakula</ENAMEX>'s film of All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>). The movie's
sophistication hits you gradually. Maybe you have to be sophisticated to make a
picture so effortlessly, cheerfully facile about a subject so dark and
convoluted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunst</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene</ENAMEX> simple in ways that go
beyond dumb, so that their budding awareness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX>'s mendacity has an
unexpected emotional kick. Like many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of that era they're crushed,
they get their own back, and then they leap into the age of roller-disco. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogey Man</ENAMEX> goes down, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX> sends you home boogeying.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> ystery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> is one of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-straight,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-spoof comic-book extravaganzas that don't ever work, and what's neat is
that this one does--beautifully. The movie, based on the Flaming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrot/Mysterymen comics</ENAMEX>, unfolds in a dirigible-filled urban metropolis in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superheroes</ENAMEX> routinely mix it up with supervillains, and in which there
exists an entire class of nerdy superhero <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wannabes</ENAMEX>, each of whom struggles to
concoct a persona that will fully embody what he or she does most ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superheroically</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Stiller</ENAMEX>), calls himself Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furious</ENAMEX>
because his anger supposedly gives him powers undreamt of by mere mortals. He
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glowers</ENAMEX> and snorts like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Incredible Hulk</ENAMEX>--"I am a ticking time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX>!"--except that he doesn't transform. He is joined in his crime-fighting
efforts by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Shovel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William H. Macy</ENAMEX>), who wields the same, and the effete
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English Blue Raja</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Azaria</ENAMEX>), whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> is for operatically flinging wide
his cape and hurling forks, most of which end up sticking out of his companions
instead of his foes.

            The first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>,
who goes by the (superhero?) name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinka Usher</ENAMEX>, overloads the movie with
skewed angles and screwy lenses and grotesque special effects. What keeps his
work from becoming campily oppressive (like the last, dreadful <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">picture</ENAMEX>) is his respect for the untranscendent flatness of ordinary life. These
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> just can't quite get off the ground. More than that, they're inherently
suspicious of one another: They see through their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddys</ENAMEX>' superheroic
poses--and their own. Stiller, who struggles to turn his self-hatred into
other-hatred, makes a hilariously morose seether, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azaria</ENAMEX> is poetically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twitty</ENAMEX>--he recalls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlon Brando</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fletcher Christian</ENAMEX>. The earnest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macy</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whitest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> imaginable, has been given an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, to whom he
must constantly defend his unrealized ambitions: "I shovel well. I shovel
very well."

            These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> can never measure up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s most
superheroic crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Captain Amazing</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Kinnear</ENAMEX>), a preening egotist
who soars around on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> trashing supervillains, his uniform emblazoned
with product placements. When all the heavyweight bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are dead or in jail
(and his celebrity endorsements dry up), he contrives to have one of his old
nemeses, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casanova Frankenstein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Rush</ENAMEX>) released from the insane
asylum--a bad move, as it turns out, since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amazing</ENAMEX> has got rusty and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX> has had plenty of time to hatch a diabolical scheme. Among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misfits</ENAMEX> who join up with our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superheroes</ENAMEX> to liberate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Captain</ENAMEX>
Amazing are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Reubens</ENAMEX>, who brings a glittery-eyed intensity to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Spleen</ENAMEX>, a
pustuled lisper with toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">flatulence</ENAMEX>, and the wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janeane Garofalo</ENAMEX> as
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowler</ENAMEX>, who hurls a ball in which the skull of her murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is
ghoulishly embedded.

            The script, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX>
Cuthbert, deftly juggles the fantasy of what our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> want to be and the
reality of what they are. They don't show grace under pressure, but they
somehow rise to the occasion, and Mystery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> becomes a triumphant
celebration of nerdy aspiration. I might have complained that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stiller</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garofalo</ENAMEX>--who instantly rub each other the wrong way--don't end up falling in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX>, and that the film pairs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stiller</ENAMEX> instead with a conventional ingénue. But
since that ingénue is the meltingly gorgeous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Forlani</ENAMEX>, it would take
someone more superheroic than I to register a protest.

            The world didn't need a remake of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Thomas Crown</ENAMEX>
Affair (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>), an enjoyable piece of romantic fluff in which worldly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire thief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve McQueen</ENAMEX> matched wits with brittle insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">investigator Faye Dunaway</ENAMEX>. We didn't need it, but we got it anyway--and it's
pretty terrific. The old script has been smartly overhauled, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McTiernan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Hard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>), works with a master<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-craftsman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elegance</ENAMEX>. The climax, in which an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in trench coats and bowler hats
swap identical portfolios, is like a ballet designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magritte</ENAMEX>. (It's worthy
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, in which it takes place.) True, there's the
hollow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce Brosnan</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McQueen</ENAMEX> role, but he's not bad here: His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">passivity</ENAMEX> is archly amusing. And then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rene Russo</ENAMEX>. She makes her
entrance in furs and a pair of sunglasses, with creamy lips and mussed red
hair--both sleek and sexily bedraggled. When she cottons (almost instantly) to
the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brosnan</ENAMEX> is her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art thief</ENAMEX>, she toys with him, happy with the chase
and entertained by his effrontery. You can't spot the moment when she falls in
love: It must be when it dawns on her that she's the mouse and not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>.
Before you know it, she's roiling with doubt and heartbreakingly vulnerable,
and this slick thriller romance becomes more than an ultracivilized game. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Russo</ENAMEX>
has never been less than agreeable, but here's she's something else: a movie
star.

         
      
   
