
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">United Nations Under Fire</ENAMEX>

            The
role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> was increasingly called into question <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> as
blood continued to flow in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> of "total mismanagement" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> crisis. "The lesson of the
conflicts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is that problems need to be anticipated
and prepared for," it said in an editorial. "But again inertia is the name of the game and again
tragedy is the outcome." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also attacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for
failing to bring sufficient pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> published
an article regretting that "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of 'quiet diplomacy'
aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> ties with our huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> has been dissipated in just a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Post</ENAMEX> said that the atrocities being committed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>
showed the limits of the so-called "new international order." It said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
in an editorial: "The pending evacuation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
compound in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dili</ENAMEX> only highlights the impotence of the world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> in resolving
this conflict. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> support for military intervention, most countries
continue to oppose sending in a peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
approval." Economic pressure is therefore the only option for the international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> to pursue, but even this is opposed by several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, it said. Fortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> seem to be made of sterner stuff.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> but boycotted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J. Habibie</ENAMEX>, is going
on, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christchurch</ENAMEX> stressed the urgency of bringing peace to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, mainly
because "to allow the bloodshed to continue into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> would inflame public
opinion against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apec</ENAMEX>." It said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in an editorial, "One of the region's
smallest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>--a crypto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> with a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and minimal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>--is grabbing the headlines and the sympathies of the world,
sidelining the great issues of trade and commerce on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apec</ENAMEX>'s agenda." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> welcomed a resurgence of nationalism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> in response to
international criticism of its "ineffectual" handling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> crisis.
But, without expressing any sympathy for the plight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX>, it
also warned that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indonesians</ENAMEX> must realise that, in this era of globalization,
self-isolation and disregard of the accepted universal norms of international
conduct can lead to political and economic devastation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, Le Monde
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> agreed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> that the disaster in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> should have been foreseen, and it also strongly criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said: "By taking on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of the referendum, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> implicitly guaranteed not only the security of the voting operation but
also that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in the aftermath of the poll. It has betrayed their
trust; it has abandoned them without defence. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> comes out of this
affair humiliated and discredited." It asked, "Can the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> continue for long
with this impossible contradiction: being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of the rights of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> of the right to self-determination--without giving
itself the means to make them respected? The answer will determine the future
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>."

            Among
reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with the murder of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> and nuns and the stabbing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baucau</ENAMEX> by
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> militia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>. "The savage attacks are the first deliberate
violations of the sanctity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> rule and have robbed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX> of their last refuge," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the
Times ran a
front-page eyewitness piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marie Colvin</ENAMEX> from inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> compound in
Dili about the desperation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX> who know they are about to be
abandoned. "Last night, no one slept," she wrote. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> walked around
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aimlessly</ENAMEX>, crying, carrying their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> on their hip. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> huddled. I was
stopped every step, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> grabbing my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> pulling me aside to say: 'Can
this be true?' It was a hard question to answer. To say yes, to admit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>
was leaving and I was probably going with them, would be to start a panic. ...
To say no would be to deny them time to plan an escape."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press was dominated, however, by the confession of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Portillo</ENAMEX>, a
former defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX>,
that he had "some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> experiences as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>." Portillo, who is
seeking re-election to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> and is widely seen as an eventual contender
for the party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, said he wanted to put an end to untrue rumors about
his sex life--one being that he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> affair with another former
Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>--by instead volunteering the truth. He said he has had no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> experiences since he was at university and has been faithful to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> for all their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 years</TIMEX> of marriage. The press widely commended him for his
honesty, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said in a leading article that "[h]is frankness
in discussing youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> experiences does him only credit."

            
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> that it has
decided not to go ahead with the serialization of the memoirs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Hewitt</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, although it has already paid him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $500,000</NUMEX> and
has promised him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">another $500,000</NUMEX>. He is suing the paper and vice versa. The
paper gave no reason for ditching him except that it didn't like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>, which has already been leaked in other papers. The true reasons for
the change of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart</ENAMEX> seem to be an appeal by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX>, and
a ferocious campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewitt</ENAMEX> by the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>. From what we hear,
the book contains more about his exploits as a tank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>
than about his affair with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">princess</ENAMEX>, and it says that "the most satisfying
experience" of his life had nothing to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> but was the defeat of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
