
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">257</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big 'n' Sturdy&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veerabhadran</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institution of Oceanography</ENAMEX> was surprised by the extent, thickness, and
persistence. Of what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 256</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Artifact or Fiction?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  The list includes a paper shredder (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Shark 200</ENAMEX> personal security
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shredder</ENAMEX>), a leather picture frame (without picture), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> of Jockey®
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shorts</ENAMEX> (athletic midway pouch brief). List of what?
               
            

            "Items
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX> sought comfort in, to help relieve her mind-numbing bouts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> gifts of the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> ever."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            
"Evidence that will prove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jar Jar</ENAMEX> is gay."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Radosh
            

            
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing targets. 'We're weaning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> off slowly,' said a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

             

            "If
you're buying these as gifts for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, your shrink owes you a
refund."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fawn Hall</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ollie North</ENAMEX>!
Little did I realize, when I typed the charmed words "paper shredder," how much
I missed them. And, judging by your replies, you do too. And so my gift to you:
a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX> e-mail obtained by that wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Archive</ENAMEX>. (If you like this sort of thing, it has published an
entire book of it.)

            

               3/28/86
From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX>
To: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fawn Hall</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Movie</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contras</ENAMEX>

               
Originally classified secret; now unclassified.

               A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> is leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholder</ENAMEX> in a movie production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and
sent one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> to me to help package a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> budget for a
feature film called "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contras</ENAMEX>." It will be a credible work about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Kid</ENAMEX>
who gets thrown in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>, is freed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Contra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and eventually
sides with them for the right reasons. There is a script currently being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">edited</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Nouri</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flashdance</ENAMEX>) will be the male lead; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Brunner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>, Missing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action</ENAMEX>) will do the screenplay and probably direct. There are
a number of stupid films in the works on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Amer</ENAMEX>. that all come out on the
wrong side. I think we should help these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out if possible. I have met
them and they are serious, talented and well-connected in the industry. There
is no better way to grab those hearts and minds we need.

            

            The script, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calf</ENAMEX> , never got shot. But what can you expect? Look what
those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bastards</ENAMEX> did to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stern</ENAMEX> and The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chimp Channel</ENAMEX> . See below.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artificial Holiday Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            All are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX> gifts advertised in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .

            

               The paper shredder (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$39.99</NUMEX>) "offers peace of mind" and a tangible way to
say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, you've got something to hide."

               The leather picture frame (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX>) says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, you're not ashamed of your
sadomasochistic pornography."

               And the underwear (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.37</NUMEX>) says, "Oh, lordy, I'm
picturing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> naked, although forbidden to do so by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> and good
sense."

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts and Sciences Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Which of the following
describes a footprint discovered in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cave</ENAMEX>, and which describes
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chimp Channel</ENAMEX> , premiering <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, it is the oldest of its kind found in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Most of its jokes are
the oldest on television.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Presumably made by an
8-to-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Involves barefoot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primates</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just a few feet</NUMEX>
from invaluable paintings.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just a few</NUMEX>
channels from invaluable shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Evidence of advance
rise of civilization.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Evidence of decline of
civilization.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Demonstrates
determination to survive in harsh circumstances.

            10.
Demonstrates determination to make a great deal of money in degrading
circumstances.

            
               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cave</ENAMEX> footprint

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chimp Channel</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Both

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Both

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cave</ENAMEX> footprint

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chimp Channel</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cave</ENAMEX> footprint

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chimp Channel</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cave</ENAMEX> footprint

            10.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chimp Channel</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More About</NUMEX>
It
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cro</ENAMEX>-Magnon footprints were found in the
Chauvet cave in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ardèche</ENAMEX> region of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">southern France</ENAMEX>. The earliest human
footprints, discovered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, are believed to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">117</NUMEX>, 000 years
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chimp Channel</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour</TIMEX> sitcom performed by
costumed chimps with dubbed human voices, has been plagued by trouble on the
set. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stern</ENAMEX> was fired from the show after he "disrobed and broke a
bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and a bottle of beer" on the set. "Through improv comedy, I was
trying to get stuff off my chest about the wrong-headed direction the show was
taking," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> . "I was
willing to stand naked to show I had no shame or fear about making good
comedy." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> is said to have demanded more sophisticated jokes involving
farting costumed monkeys.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Madden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline</ENAMEX> Haiku
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish bar Yugoslavs</ENAMEX>,
Off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>.
Dosage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> isn't
set for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia Inquirer</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3, 1999</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX>
only)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Denominator</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
