
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-70</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-15</ENAMEX> between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 7, 1999</TIMEX>

            Brutal day. We have to drive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14½ hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to
stay on schedule, so I am being forced to write this dispatch from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
is in a pissy mood. I think I know why.

            A few words in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX> shopping: Let
the record show that I bought nothing at the outlet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, while Mr.
Why-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are-We-Stopping-Here</ENAMEX> became slightly unhinged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Creuset emporium</ENAMEX>,
acquiring several heavy cast-iron pots, which now burden our already
over-burdened car (see below).

            
               Re the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> "flasher":
            

            His penis really did appear to just accidentally
fall out of his pants. That's my story and I'm sticking to it.

            
               Re the handsome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7-11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> is on to something there.

            Back to the drive: It's snowing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockies</ENAMEX>
today, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> are slippery. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is laboring under the load of all my
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">worldly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">possessions</ENAMEX> and can't go very fast, even under favorable weather
conditions. In fact, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interstate</ENAMEX> seems to be making better time
than we are, even the pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> towing large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>. Right now, we're
being passed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> (or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> anyway, being carted to a foundation
waiting somewhere), and a large tree is gaining on us.

            It doesn't bother me though. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> is so
beautiful, I could stay here forever. I can't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
from this very state, was willing, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, to grind up the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rockies</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shale oil</ENAMEX>. Now, there was a case where sexual misbehavior was an accurate
indicator of poor overall judgement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> must be the most
bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> because his peccadilloes pale by comparison with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s and yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX> was driven from public life for them. But right now the
most bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> could well be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>. He's barely talking to
me.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six hours later</TIMEX>:
            

            We're halfway through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s mood has
improved. He sees a sign that says "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chain-Up Area Next Exit</ENAMEX>" and finds it
hilariously suggestive.

            I've had a recurring dream since I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. I'm
in a strange, barren, surreal setting and there are lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah</ENAMEX> looks
like my dream come true. There are lots of enormous rocks, anyway, which in my
experience tends to mean lots of enormous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>. I'm afraid to step out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. Also the rocks are not quite as red as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> claimed they would be. And we
haven't seen a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> since we entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hours ago</TIMEX>. How
could the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormons</ENAMEX> have practiced polygamy? It seems like it would be hard to
find even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> around here, let alone several.

            Total trip skunk count: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> (surprisingly
low).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hours</TIMEX> later:
            

            We arrive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, which is extremely
impressive for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 17 minutes</TIMEX>. We visit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Caesar's Palace</ENAMEX> and discover that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fabled Noshorium</ENAMEX> (which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> has been talking up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last day</TIMEX>) is no more.
We visit the much-hyped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellagio</ENAMEX> too late to actually see its collection of
modern art, or its supposedly sensational water show "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.</ENAMEX>" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> itself,
however, is almost unremittingly awful. Not just tacky, but uninteresting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tacky</ENAMEX>. Why doesn't somebody like casino <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Wynn</ENAMEX> spend the same amount
of money getting a good modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> to design a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> that would be truly
visually stunning and dispense with the imitation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> clichés?

            I'm feeling sort of down. I'm going to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> to
take me out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
