
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX> 

            The struggle among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenants</ENAMEX> for control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>
only looks like the clash of celebrity egos. Actually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> is
splitting along the fault line between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">progressivism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">populism</ENAMEX>--rival traditions represented most recently by presidential candidates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>). Natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> and
natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, progressives and populists simultaneously attract and repulse
each other. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, and to a lesser extent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> managed to unite
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> progressives and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> populists, but if history is any guide,
nobody will pull off that miracle in this election.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>'s progressive Republicanism belonged
to the distinctive political tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater New England</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> that
arcs from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> and was settled by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX>'s secularized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puritanism</ENAMEX> combines an enthusiasm for social reform--such as abolitionism,
Prohibition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s suffrage, civil rights, eugenics, and the anti-smoking
crusade--with an often-priggish moralism and an apocalyptic horror of
"corruption." Most third-party movements have originated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>. The name of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> launched during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> tells the whole
story: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonpartisan League</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scandinavians</ENAMEX> who settled in western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater New England</ENAMEX> reinforced the secular
puritan ethos, although they were more likely to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX> than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, whose fear of corruption has often made them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of big
government. And <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX> divided liquor-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern Protestants</ENAMEX> from
beer-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>. Even so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pietism</ENAMEX> of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germanic Americans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meshed</ENAMEX> neatly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX> religious culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Englanders</ENAMEX> and their
western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>, while socialist enthusiasms were easily merged with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gospel Protestantism</ENAMEX> in the northern<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">-tier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. It is no coincidence that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>, the standard-bearer for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germanic</ENAMEX> tradition in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, is of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish</ENAMEX> descent--nor is it a coincidence that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>, formerly a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Mondale</ENAMEX>, a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> populism, which earlier had produced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huey P. Long</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Watson</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jennings Bryan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spawned George Wallace</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Populism</ENAMEX> has more often found a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highland</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South</ENAMEX> than in the coastal "black belt," which has been dominated since colonial
times by the elitist conservatism of ruling-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bourbon families</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>. Drawing on the traditions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scots</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Appalachia</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ozarks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Highland Southern</ENAMEX> populism encourages a tribal approach to politics
and rewards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who are flamboyant and bellicose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX> was an
early example of this type; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick J. Buchanan</ENAMEX> is its latest incarnation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot united Anderson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progressives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> populists, but in an unstable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pairing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> were social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who favored activist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, as long
as it benefited them and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> were social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> more concerned with good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> than with expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> tended to be white working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> on their way into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anderson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> by contrast were often former liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in transit to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>.

            In the federal deficit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> found an issue that resonated
with both progressives and populists. In the minds of the skinflint
progressives, spending money one does not have is a form of moral depravity.
The deficit issue mobilized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacksonian</ENAMEX> populists because it spoke to their
fears about a remote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> dominated by the rich and powerful. Unlike
deficit reduction, the trade issue divided populist protectionists from
progressives, many of whom favor free trade.

            Thanks to his
deficit-reduction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> votes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> than any third-party
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> since "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull Moose</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Progressive Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX> of the total bettered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13.5 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. The core of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX>'s support <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> was New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater New England</ENAMEX>, with his best <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--no surprise--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>. While his rhetoric was populist, his positions were progressive. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progressives</ENAMEX> preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> rule; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> claimed that
"smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> already had the plans, all that was lacking was
the will to implement them. Progressive reforms such as initiatives and
referendums, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX>'s vague notions of direct democracy, tended to bypass
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">legislatures</ENAMEX> and to concentrate plebiscitary power in allegedly nonpartisan
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>, city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ignorant Perot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> called his technocratic approach
"fascism," when it was old-fashioned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> progressivism. The progressives,
like their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mugwumps</ENAMEX>--the independent-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
who spurned their party's presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1884</TIMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whigs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Federalists</ENAMEX>, have long favored fiscal conservatism.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concord Coalition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Englanders Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Rudman</ENAMEX>, were as horrified by the federal deficit as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mugwumps</ENAMEX> had
been appalled by the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryanite</ENAMEX> populists for bimetallism and as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Liberal Republicans</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a generation earlier</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilded Age</ENAMEX>, had been
frightened by paper money.

            Perot, then, has the mind
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater New England</ENAMEX> progressive but the heart of a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Highland Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populist</ENAMEX> (his native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texarkana</ENAMEX> belongs to the western fringe of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highland</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>). If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX>'s message appealed to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordic</ENAMEX> progressives in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northern</ENAMEX> tier, his anti-establishment populism, and no doubt his flamboyant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persona</ENAMEX>, appealed to the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> whose ancestors had cheered on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huey</ENAMEX> P.
Long and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sockless Jerry" Simpson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> did very poorly in the conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>--but his showing was best in parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> that had voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>.

            With the federal deficit removed as an issue by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snow Belt</ENAMEX> good-government reformism and give-'em-hell
hillbilly populism dissolved. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puritan crusaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> and the
alienated populists of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> may share common political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, but little
else. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A century ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> progressives such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godkin</ENAMEX> viewed populists such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jennings Bryan</ENAMEX> as barbarians, and they
returned the favor by viewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mugwumps</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> rather than as potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>.

            Then, as now, economic
policy divided rather than united the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of the two-party system. In the
1890s, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mugwumps</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godkin</ENAMEX> crusaded for free trade and against tariff
protection for corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, northern fiscal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tsongas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudman</ENAMEX> have backed free-trade
agreements such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>. For their part, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Highland Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">populists</ENAMEX> tend to
rally around harebrained economic programs, elevating them from an instrument
of policy into a symbol of a crusade against their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX>, the destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Bank of the United States</ENAMEX> was
the panacea; for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jennings Bryan</ENAMEX>, the panacea was
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver coinage</ENAMEX>; for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, supply-side economics was
the crackpot quick fix. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, the symbolic economic issue is a revival
of high tariffs on manufactured imports.

            The factional war within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>, then, represents
the decomposition of the movement into its Northern progressive and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
populist wings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> can be described as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX>, as can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Choate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>, whose populist sentiments appear to have triumphed over
their progressive principles. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lamm</ENAMEX>, who attempted
to wrest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perot</ENAMEX>, is a classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> progressive, as is former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowell Weicker</ENAMEX>, whose name
was circulated as a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> is the product
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> political culture, with its mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germanic</ENAMEX> reformism
and its long history of influential regional third-party movements such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonpartisan League</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmer</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. And it's not stretching to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assign Donald Trump</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> backs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, then the capture of the
Reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> by right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> populists is likely. At that point, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progressives</ENAMEX> will do what they have always done best: They're never happier
than when they are demonstrating their moral, political, and religious purity
by heading for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX> and starting their own small but pure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Englanders</ENAMEX>, fearing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> corruption and tyranny, provoked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Revolution. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">generation later</TIMEX>, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War of 1812</ENAMEX>, many New Englanders
considered seceding from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, whose federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was then
dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. In the antebellum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conscience Whigs</ENAMEX> denounced the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>'s pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Cotton Whigs</ENAMEX> as corrupt. After
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, high-minded liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> walked out on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>,
the sleazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stalwarts</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 20 th century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert La Follette</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, stormed out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> to form their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Party</ENAMEX>.

            So look for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>'s displaced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progressives</ENAMEX> to declare the purity of their principles, denounce the corruption
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populists</ENAMEX> who have taken over the party machine, and march out--to found
a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, perhaps, from which, in time, they can secede.

         
      
   
