
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Failed Recluse</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX> is inevitably described as "the most
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> ) or "the most private of literary
figures" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). In the introduction to his just-published
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> biography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Alexander</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX> the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX> who didn't want his biography written." Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> has
already been the subject of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> biographies.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> really wants to be left alone, he is
going about it in a very strange way. He doesn't live in a gated community. He
summons perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> into his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hideaway</ENAMEX>. He sues <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and then phones
the media to spread the story.

            Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> should take a page from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
Pynchon, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> letters' other famous recluse, who really wants to be
left alone. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday Times</ENAMEX> hireling bearded
Pynchon on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> and nearly got his head bitten off: "Get
your fucking hand out of my face!" Pynchon bellowed.

            Here's the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tale of the</ENAMEX>
Tape in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Battle of the Hermit Divas:</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Location

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Salinger</ENAMEX>
               :
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> has lived on the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, property for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 30 years</TIMEX>. Other
than a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Trespassing</ENAMEX>" sign, there is no particular barrier to entry, from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fictional Ray Kinsella</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoeless Joe</ENAMEX> to the notorious stalkerazzi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographer Paul Adao</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> , no one has ever had much
trouble finding the place. Up until recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> used to chat casually
with his doorsteppers--unless they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. The next generation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> won't even have to interrogate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> provides
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directions</ENAMEX> in his new book.

            On the one hand, it's churlish to suggest that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> should move just to protect himself from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. On the other
hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have moved for less.

            

               Pynchon
               : Until recently, no one was really
sure where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pynchon</ENAMEX> lived. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern California</ENAMEX>? Probably all of
the above. Much ink has been shed in proving that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pynchon</ENAMEX> spent several years
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mendocino County</ENAMEX> researching his novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vineland</ENAMEX> and
writing letters to the local newspaper under the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wanda Tinasky</ENAMEX>." But that
may have been a hoax.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Litigation

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Salinger</ENAMEX>
               : In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of an unauthorized collection of his stories and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
bookstores that stocked the book. Lest his filing go unnoticed, he phoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacey Fosburgh</ENAMEX> to alert her to the case. He made
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, he sued to block
publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Hamilton</ENAMEX>'s biography, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Search</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX> , and
forced the biographer to remove many quotations from the published work. This
kept his name in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, and forced him to give a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six-hour</TIMEX> long
deposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, a portion of which appears for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s book. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> forbade a nonprofit Catcher
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rye</ENAMEX> Web site from using quotations from the novel, garnering the
usual rash of publicity.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lady Friends</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Salinger</ENAMEX>
               : In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> wrote the notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> letter to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>, who had just written a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine cover story about herself. The rest is herstory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> wrote
similar letters to other young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female writers</ENAMEX>. He also had a fascination with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">actresses</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 62</TIMEX>, he wrote a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> letter" to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36-year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>, whom he had seen in the TV show Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlin</ENAMEX> . That resulted in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long-running</ENAMEX> affair. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years later</TIMEX>, he developed a fascination with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comely Catherine Oxenberg</ENAMEX>, then starring in the TV show <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dynasty</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and "had shown up on the set," according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographer Hamilton</ENAMEX>. "He had to be escorted off."

            

               Pynchon
               : As befits a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> guarding, as opposed
to flaunting, his privacy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> has kept his private life private. Past
girlfriends have spoken with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, mainly to report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pynchon</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">charming</ENAMEX> and a tad eccentric. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jules Siegel</ENAMEX>, a college
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>, wrote an article for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> titled: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Is Thomas Pynchon and</ENAMEX>
Why Did He <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take Off With My Wife?</ENAMEX>" The story praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pynchon</ENAMEX> as "a wonderful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lover</ENAMEX>, sensitive and quick with the ability to project a mood that turned the
most ordinary surroundings into a scene out of a masterful film ..."

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a decade</TIMEX> now, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> has been married to his
literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> and keeping to himself. Cunningly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> is hiding in plain
view. He lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> and escorts his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to and from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school many days</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine says he's active in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s activities and has
even been written up in the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> love him," he says.
Local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">literati</ENAMEX> know where he lives and they leave him alone.

            Why? Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pynchon</ENAMEX> left
alone and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> harassed? Theories abound. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> is
a cerebral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> are mature in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> and temperament. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>'s
great classic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Catcher</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rye</ENAMEX> is about an adolescent and has
visceral appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> of all ages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hinckley</ENAMEX>, were both major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Catcher fans</ENAMEX>.

            Another major difference is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> has continued to
publish. "Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been able to access <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pynchon</ENAMEX>, and his
evolution as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>," explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>, who has followed both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>'
careers closely. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> published an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> cover story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lauding Salinger</ENAMEX>'s self-imposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> as "his most powerful, his most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eloquent</ENAMEX>, perhaps his most lasting work of art."

            But I wonder: Is the wall really art, or is it an
act? And has the act now supplanted the art?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> announced plans to publish
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32-year-old</TIMEX> story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hapworth</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1924</TIMEX>," as a book. After some negative
publicity, he changed his plans. "The way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> handled the publicity he
said he did not want was a bit too contrived to get attention itself," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> concludes at the end of his new biography. He continues: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>
became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greta Garbo</ENAMEX> of literature, and then periodically, when it may have
seemed he was about to be forgotten, he resurfaced briefly, just to remind the
public that he wanted to be left alone . The whole act could have been
cute or whimsical; only, it felt as if it were being put on by a master
showman, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, a public-relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wizard</ENAMEX> hawking a story the
public couldn't get enough of."

         
      
   
