
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">289</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;No Problem&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Quoted in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wichita Eagle</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Graves</ENAMEX> said, "This is a terrible,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tragic</ENAMEX>, embarrassing solution to a problem that did not exist." What
is?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 288</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Futurific":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>'s present is rosy, with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second quarter</TIMEX> sales up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
percent and profits up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.25 billion</NUMEX>. And its future is even
better. Marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Flickinger</ENAMEX> sees something coming that is "the
best possible thing that can happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> and the worst thing that could
happen to every major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>." What?
               
            

            
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> has been declared 'Celebrate Sweatshops <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Month</TIMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>
Cornog
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>'s coup in being named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Gun Supplier of Choice</ENAMEX>' by both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crips</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloods</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My News Quiz Responses Cost Way Less To Make Than</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moonves</ENAMEX> has been named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of every major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Amoros
            

            "It
will be featured prominently in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Episode 2</ENAMEX> , as the place <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obi-Wan</ENAMEX> takes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anakin</ENAMEX> to get his first cheap, nonunion light-saber."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And</ENAMEX>
good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> to you, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. Can you point me to
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">housewares?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Foley</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> means sweatshop labor and easily available <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, but
it's so much more. It's censored music. And censored videos. And denying women
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">contraception</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> has declined to sell "stickered
music," i.e., pop songs whose lyrics are too saucy for your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>
still won't stock "adult videos," although it no longer carries its own store
editions of mainstream hits with the naughty bits edited out, as it was once
rumored to do. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> will not fill
prescriptions for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>-after pill <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preven</ENAMEX>. I'm no reproductive rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, but if this isn't overtly promoting infanticide as a form of
population control, it's coming awfully close. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crawl</ENAMEX>, little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>! Crawl for
your life!

            
               You Can't Find a
Cheaper Answer
            

            "A consumer downturn is the best possible
thing that can happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>," says the sanguine Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flickinger</ENAMEX>.

            The competitive advantage the world's largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> enjoys over its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> in a robust economy would be even greater
during hard times, when those puny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> would be battered by economic
gales, which to the mighty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> are but gentle zephyrs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flickinger</ENAMEX> breezily
implied.

            "Even if the consumer
environment does slow down, we still think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> is extremely well
positioned," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Feiner</ENAMEX>, a retail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehman Brothers</ENAMEX>. "In fact,
if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">meteor</ENAMEX> crashed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, sentencing everyone on the planet to a slow
and hideous death, I'd expect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> to do swell," he did not add.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riotous Assembly</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Can you name the mob
that fomented each of these recent riots around the world?

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riot</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Streets</ENAMEX> have been blocked by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mobs</ENAMEX>. No one has dared go out, even to buy basic needs in the nearest market,"
said an unnamed civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maluku</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX>. Speaking from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> bed, Mr.
Miricho, who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gakoe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mung</ENAMEX>'aria <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stormed his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, baying for his blood. "They said they
wanted my head because I had blocked their move to split the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,000</NUMEX>-member
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dar Es Salaam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Thirty people</ENAMEX> who participated in
a riot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tanzanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> were charged with unlawful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">procession</ENAMEX> and malicious damage to property. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rioters</ENAMEX> threw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>, bottles, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">iron</ENAMEX> pieces at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> fired tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistols</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> to disperse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> was seriously hurt
during a melee as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">around 150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> tried to charge across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">north Mitrovica</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> strung barbed wire across it.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Hondo, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> says a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dozen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> were hurt in fighting at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torres</ENAMEX> medium-security prison <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> remain hospitalized with stab wounds.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>. "They
apparently came to drink and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and have what they thought was a good time.
Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> mentality took over," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sgt. Neil Dryfe</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartford Police</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mob</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> who hate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> and vice versa

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tetu Coffee Growers Cooperative</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> who reject school uniforms

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> eager to storm the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> part
of town

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raza Unida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>
prison gangs

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews Band</ENAMEX>

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            The fashion gaffes of
the poor.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s Note
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX> will be the guest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> will take over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following week</TIMEX>, while I am on my
listening tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jockeys</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saratoga Springs</ENAMEX>.-- R.C.
            

         
      
   
