
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Anxiety</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mickey Blue</ENAMEX>
                
               
                  Eyes
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). Rather
grim reports for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Grant</ENAMEX>'s latest smirking, stuttering performance as an
upper-crusty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit</ENAMEX>. This time around, he gets mixed up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob family</ENAMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fiancee</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeanne Tripplehorn</ENAMEX>). Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>'s cute, but the movie's a stinker,
"little more than a series of stitched together gags" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> disagree about whose fault it is. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> says the scenes where Grant learns to
talk like a gangster are "so badly handled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> that the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">derails</ENAMEX> and
never recovers." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, on the other
hand, argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant "</ENAMEX>goes a long way toward saving [the film] from itself."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read the review by 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>.
Visit the official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> to see stills and clips from the
film.)

            

               
                  Teaching Mrs. T
               
               
                  ingle
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Williamson</ENAMEX>, high off his continuing success writing teen films
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scream</ENAMEX> ) and television ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson's Creek</ENAMEX> ), tries his hand at
directing. The results are disastrous. The plot? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> take revenge on a
sadistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>. (The film was originally called Killing Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tingle</ENAMEX> ,
but the title was toned down in the wake of recent school violence.) The film
"bludgeons the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> with broad, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, creepy developments" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebert</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ) and lacks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX>'s usual humor and panache. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>
Mirren, playing the evil Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tingle</ENAMEX>, rises above the weak material--which only
makes the film "even more painful" to watch (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> dissents: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> '
always easy-to-please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, flouts conventional wisdom and calls the film a
"knockout directorial debut." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  The 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jukebox Queen</ENAMEX> of 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Malta</ENAMEX>
               ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rinaldi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> enjoy this love story about a young
radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> and a local jukebox <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repairwoman</ENAMEX> who meet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malta</ENAMEX>
during the bombings of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX> praises the novel as "a
funny, melancholy, romantic, disturbing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>-rich window on the war" (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). But others complain that "the influences of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX>'s classic Catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis de Berni√</ENAMEX>®res' recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corelli</ENAMEX>'s
Mandolin are rather too blatantly present" and make the novel feel overly
familiar. Still, "if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX> hadn't existed we might be calling this a pretty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrific</ENAMEX> novel" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkus Reviews</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

            

               
                  Conduct
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unbecoming a Woman: Medicine on Trial</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turn-of-the-Century Brooklyn</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regina Morantz-Sanchez</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Press</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are intrigued by the dramatic story of successful
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gynecological surgeon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Amanda Dixon Jones</ENAMEX>, whose
career was derailed by a smear campaign. Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morantz</ENAMEX>-Sanchez
recounts the tale "in academic prose thick enough to thwart all but the most
persistent" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkus Reviews</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
agrees, complaining that "Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morantz-Sanchez</ENAMEX> is more interested in the
scholarly value of her story than its inherent drama and that will make the
book tough going for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>." But most say the interesting sociological
history and insight into attitudes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> make it worth the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slog</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Movie
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soldier</ENAMEX>: The Return
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
Pictures). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> groan at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Claude Van Damme</ENAMEX>'s sequel to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> action
flick about reanimated dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. It's all "bullets, bombs, and boobs--the
biggest boob being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Damme</ENAMEX>, natch" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Dreher</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ).
But "for those eager to bid adieu to their credibility for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">82 minutes</TIMEX>," at
least the action "rarely flags" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Van Gelder</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ).

         
      
   
