
   
   
      
         
            Go to Hell

            In his current 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX> column, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> compares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Quincy Adams</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Q.</ENAMEX>--as he was not
known--is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> so far to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> himself.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historian Greenberg</ENAMEX> finds many parallels but some differences. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q.</ENAMEX>
suffered a "lifelong case of clinical depression," whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.</ENAMEX> has come to
"believe that all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are bound for hell." While the parallel is unclear,
these are certainly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different things. As someone who has (based on
circumstantial evidence such as his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> mitzvah), I found this latter datum
especially interesting. And, of course, it is remarkable to learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> has actual opinions on any subject, let alone strong and controversial
ones.

            Unless you're a political junkie, or live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>,
you may have missed this story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> have reported it, but not with the
neurotic intensity you might expect. Why not? Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press critics</ENAMEX> often
complain that the media ignore the importance of religion. This may be a case
in point, though not one those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are likely to complain about. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
there is the inoculation phenomenon: Once a story has "been done," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> don't want to do it again. So, getting it done small is protection
against finding it done big. Finally, there may be a feeling among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>
that the whole thing's a bum rap. Which it is and it isn't.

            There's no evidence that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX>. After college he was even engaged briefly to a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Some have suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> may have dumped her because
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, but there's no reason to think he didn't know that all
along, if he cared, so the episode weighs in against the anti-Semitism charge,
not for it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has had many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. If he
believes they're all going to hell, he hasn't held it against them in this
life.

            So what does he believe? Like the Gospel tales themselves,
the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s views on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> has several variants. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, discussing his
decision around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 40</TIMEX> to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> as his personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> told a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> that--as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> paraphrased it--"heaven is
open only to those who accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>." So at worst, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> never condemned
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> specifically to hell specifically, but rather condemned most of humanity
(anyone who doesn't accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>) to what may be, depending on your point of
view, a wider geographical area (anywhere outside heaven). I'm not sure if
that's better or worse.

            Here's where the gospels
differ. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> then called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX> to straighten him out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> advised him to
"never play God" by ruling on who gets into heaven. But according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Howe</ENAMEX>
Verhovek of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s intervention occurred
earlier, during an informal theological discussion at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Sr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
And according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Herman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austin American-Statesman</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
actually made his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> comment in the course of recounting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> episode.
In this version, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelist</ENAMEX>'s advice was slightly different: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>
generally agreed with the theory but cautioned against spending much time
worrying about it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said."

            So, where does this leave us? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX> actually
convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> long beforehand that we don't know who gets into heaven, then
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Post</ENAMEX> report of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> was flat-out wrong and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> didn't
believe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were shut out of heaven even at the time. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has never
denied the accuracy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s paraphrase. Nor, needless to say, has he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">adopted Version 2</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s advice by declaring that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> won't get into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heaven</ENAMEX>, but he's too busy to care. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> now answers all questions on the
subject of heaven and its admission requirements with this catechistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">formulation</ENAMEX>: "It is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s role to decide who goes to heaven. I
believe that God decides who goes to heaven, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>."

            This won't do, I'm afraid. It was good enough to
get him a kosher certification from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX>, but it makes no
sense. No one is asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to "decide" or "rule on" who gets into heaven. We
can stipulate that God decides. (Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, for example--believe
in God, but not in heaven. Few, if any, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe in heaven, but not in
God.) The issue is whether God has an admissions policy that excludes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> has an opinion about what that policy might be.

            Surely he does. "My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX> tells me that acceptance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX> as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX> is my salvation,
and I believe that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says. Does he think that this principle only applies
to him? Does he think that it's possible for others to achieve salvation
without accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>? Even nonrecruiting religions such as Judaism claim to
be more than just a personal taste or preference. Born-again Christianity
claims to be the right answer to the most fundamental questions. So how can
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> possibly get into heaven without converting? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only two</NUMEX> ways that I can see.
One is if God allows exemptions. But to avoid offending any religious or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonreligious</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the exception would have to be that anyone who does not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accept Christ</ENAMEX> need not accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, which would destroy the rule. The other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> out would be if the entire belief system permits doubt about itself--for
example, if it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 50-50</NUMEX> that accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> is mandatory for salvation
for anybody, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> himself. Neither of these conditions applies
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s faith, as he describes it.

            And so what? Why should anyone care whether he or she will
achieve salvation by the terms of someone else's religion? What difference does
it make if you can't get into a heaven you don't believe in? As a nonbeliever,
I find the conventions of ecumenism baffling. I don't want to tell you people
how to run your religions. And obviously we want to avoid an outbreak of
religious war, or even lesser forms of intolerance, if possible. But why does
tolerance require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to pretend they don't believe what they do? Wouldn't
tolerance be easier if it only required agreement to disagree peacefully rather
than demanding actual sharing of religious doctrines at some level of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abstraction</ENAMEX>? After all, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> really believes that accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is the
only path to salvation, he is pulling a pretty dirty trick on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> by telling
them otherwise. Putting votes before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>: Talk about political
expediency!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> is lying either
when he professes his faith or when he denies its implications. Or he hasn't
really thought it through, which itself would cast doubt on the depth of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>. But I doubt this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dishonesty</ENAMEX> will keep him out of heaven,
since it is imposed on every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>--and even every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergyman</ENAMEX> with
ambitions.

            To be sure, there is a certain joy in watching a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol</ENAMEX> caught
in pandering gridlock. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> plays up his born-again faith to the religious
right. He uses it even more than bona fide <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>-right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> do, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> points out, in order to allay suspicions that he may be moderate or
indifferent on social issues. Then he has to fudge his faith so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
don't share it won't take it seriously.

            And if he gets this balancing act wrong, he must
pander even more furiously to make it up. Going for a twofer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "confided" to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Glass</ENAMEX> that "he
enjoys hanging out with country music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> [can you guess? well, obviously
...] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinky Friedman</ENAMEX>, who wrote [uh-oh] 'They <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ain't Making Jews Like Jesus</ENAMEX>
Anymore.' " Does W. agree with this sentiment? Does he have some problem with
the quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> being produced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?

         
      
   
