
   
   
      
         
            Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> on the election of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johannes Rau</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> during the last ever meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX> before
its return, after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>. Following the example of
the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>, who insisted during the final <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX>
session that the re-establishment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s capital doesn't
mean that "we are turning our backs on the values and basic principles of our
that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> don't want any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> than the
one they've got; they want ... the calm continuation of a national success
story after the greatest imaginable catastrophe."

            In an
editorial titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auf Wiedersehen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> said
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still worry about what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> might again become "once ruled from
the harshly beautiful, eastward-looking, centre of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prussian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> military
expansion." It said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Reichstag</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> has been rebuilt, all
glass and mirrors, to discourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delusions</ENAMEX> of grandeur and infuse old Prussian
authoritarian style with a taste of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX>-inspired transparency. Rule from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX>
is now history. But its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> should live on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>."

            Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with the failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> to resolve a dispute over terrorist disarmament, which is threatening
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> peace process. Despite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> of intensive negotiation
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionist Party</ENAMEX>, continues
to insist that he will not agree to share power with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, the political
wing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>, unless the IRA simultaneously starts
surrendering its hidden <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. In an analysis of the problem, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> noted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decommissioning</ENAMEX> is a key element in every peace settlement, but that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> stands out as a rare case where--by contrast, for example, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>--the issue was not resolved in the early stages of a deal and has been
allowed to fester.

            The
other big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was the formal opening by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth II</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>'s first national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">300 years</TIMEX>. She was hailed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>'s presiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX>," the first monarch to be
thus addressed since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1707</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> noted "a whiff of rebellion" in the spontaneous singing by the
entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Burns</ENAMEX>' anti-royal ballad "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for a'
that," which favorably compares the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yon</ENAMEX> birkie ca'd 'a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lord</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/Wha</ENAMEX> struts an stares, an a' that." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Express</ENAMEX> found
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> "upstaged" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of full
independence for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, who received "the biggest cheer of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>" when he
arrived in full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highland</ENAMEX> dress with kilt and sporran and announced menacingly,
"This is only the beginning."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
gave front-page treatment to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s announcement at a press
conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>--just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> after his marriage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy Deng</ENAMEX>--that his global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX> is to become "an
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>." He said he was starting a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called eVentures in
partnership with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Softbank</ENAMEX>, the world's biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backer</ENAMEX> of
Internet-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. "Big will not beat small any more," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> said.
"It will be the fast beating the slow."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>--in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to promote the latest volume of his memoirs--became the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> of a controversy about the interviewing methods of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>. A column in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> strongly attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Paxman</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s best-known
radio and TV interviewers, for being "insulting" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> when he asked him
if he felt "a fraud" on receiving the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> for "bringing peace" to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and whether he waited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 years</TIMEX> to produce these memoirs because he
wanted "to rewrite history." In a letter in self-defense published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paxman</ENAMEX> wrote, "It is surely unarguably true that the detente
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Kissinger</ENAMEX> so energetically promoted was built upon the assumption that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> would exist for the foreseeable future. He now claims it was
part of the process which led to the dismantling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> was due more to a mass psychological
problem than to anything wrong with the drink itself, according to research
reported in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> medical journal the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lancet</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> was banned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> after
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, many of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, claimed to have suffered severe
nausea and headaches after drinking it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> found "bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX>"
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> cannery and some fungicide on the outside of cans at another;
but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic University of Louvain</ENAMEX> now say that
most of the health complaints made after this was reported in the media suggest
a "mass sociogenic illness" requiring "social healing" rather than "medical
cure."

            The
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> working
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> haulage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heathrow Airport</ENAMEX> has been awarded
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $18,000</NUMEX> in compensation after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> called him
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>" over the public address system, shouted "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sieg Heil</ENAMEX>" when he walked
past, and referred to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panzer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
