
   
   
      
         
             Grade Expectations

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next month</TIMEX>, college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> around the country
will return to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>, hoping, among other things, to achieve high grades. Of
course, "high" is a moving target. I remember when C meant "average"; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
whenever I turn in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' final grades, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>'s office instructs me to
treat C as the "minimum acceptable grade." This side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Wobegon</ENAMEX>, we call
that grade inflation.

            It's a cliché that when grades are inflated they
convey less information. The cliché is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> true. On the one hand,
inflated grades fail to distinguish between the merely above-average and the
truly superior. But on the other hand, inflated grades do a super job of
distinguishing among fine gradations of weakness. When the average grade is B,
the strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are all lumped together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX>, while the weak ones are
sorted into C's, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D's</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F's</ENAMEX>.

            That's still a net loss
in valuable information, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> care more about making distinctions
at the top than about making distinctions at the bottom. Therefore, college
degrees, which derive their value from the information they carry, become less
valuable on average. Here's a quick example: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> the A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> is worth
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> the B <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX>; if grade
inflation makes it impossible to tell them apart, you might expect an employer
to offer them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX> apiece. But the inability to distinguish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary from Jane</ENAMEX>
makes it harder to assign them to appropriate tasks. That lowers their average
value to, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32,000</NUMEX>, which is what they both get paid. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> wins and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary</ENAMEX>
loses, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s loss exceeds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>'s gain.

            Does that mean that above-average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> should object to
grade inflation? Not necessarily, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> do not live by starting
salaries alone. There are advantages to living with less competitive pressure,
and those advantages could more than offset the financial losses.

            Besides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> don't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX> the full burden of those financial losses. As degrees become less
valuable, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> must cut tuition or lose enrollments. (Or, more precisely,
they must sacrifice some growth in tuition or in enrollments, both of which
have been rising for reasons that have nothing to do with grade inflation.) A
college that can distinguish itself from the pack by maintaining high standards
should be able to reap substantial rewards in the marketplace, because its
degrees are worth more.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> pay the price for grade inflation, why do they
allow it? Partly, it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> don't assign grades. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professors</ENAMEX> assign
grades, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> face perverse incentives. Being human, they tend to take
a special interest in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and are therefore tempted to give
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> a boost at the expense of the anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> who signed up
for someone else's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. Besides, easy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> are more popular on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>. The
costs of leniency--measured in lost reputation--are spread over the entire
school, while the benefits are concentrated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>.
Therefore the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> is biased toward leniency.

            The problem, then, is in
the gap between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s interests and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>'s. Any solution must
involve narrowing that gap. That's where tenure comes in. An untenured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> is like a corporate bondholder--as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> stays
above <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the short run he's happy. A tenured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> is like a
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholder</ENAMEX>--he has a permanent stake in the fortunes of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professors</ENAMEX> should have job security for the same reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> should have job security: It instills a healthy respect for the long
run.

            According to a widespread belief, grade inflation took off
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> era, in response to the idiosyncrasies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selective</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service System</ENAMEX>. According to an equally widespread belief, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '70s</TIMEX> were also a time when tenure became far more elusive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professors</ENAMEX>
began moving from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> school to another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every few years</TIMEX>, with little reason to
care about the reputational damage they left in their wakes. So perhaps the war
was irrelevant; grade inflation was the inevitable consequence of upheaval in
the tenure system.

            But tenure is at best a
partial solution to the incentive problem, because even a tenured professor
shares only a fraction of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>'s successes and failures. Let me
propose some improvements. First, college transcripts could show each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s overall grade distribution, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to interpret each
individual grade in context. Then, instead of damaging his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>'
credibility, the easy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> would damage only his own. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> could assign each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> a "grade budget" consisting of a certain
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B's</ENAMEX>, etc. Once you've awarded, say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX>, you can't award any
more till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. (To cover extraordinary circumstances, I'd be willing to
allow horse-trading among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B's</ENAMEX>, say--and perhaps
occasional borrowing against <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s budget.)

            A grade budget is not exactly the same thing as a mandatory
curve, because it would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> the flexibility to give more high
grades in one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> if they're willing to give fewer in another. Still, every
now and then, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> would have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> genuine A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> A's
to give out. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> would suffer unjustly. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A students</ENAMEX>
are precisely the ones who suffer unjustly from grade inflation. The question
is not how to eliminate injustice--which is, as always, impossible--but how to
minimize it.

            For the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, a grade budget is a
stifling constraint. That doesn't make it a bad thing. Economic theory tells us
that when everyone is polluting a communal stream, everyone can benefit from
enforced moderation. It always hurts to be constrained, but sometimes it's
worth it if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> are constrained too. With grade budgets, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>
would be forced to give fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> they gave would be more
valuable.

            If grade budgets are such a good idea, why don't we
have them? That's a question about politics, not economics, so maybe it's best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> to a different sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>. In cases like this, it's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>'s job to explain where we ought to be headed, and the political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>'s job to explain why we can't get there from here.

         
      
   
