
   
   
      
         
            
<P>Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Sensation&quot; Art Worth the Fuss</ENAMEX>?</P>

            

               
                  Click here to view the entire "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" show
online.
               
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah</ENAMEX>,

            Last time we chatted, it was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">TriBeCa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX> of
the abstract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Meyer</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> teas, and like her
work and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, our conversation was eminently civilized and stimulating.
I must say I'd rather spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple of days</TIMEX> thinking and writing about,
and hearing your views about, a single picture by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> than every piece by
every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>. Even though I'm
young and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> myself, born on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Whiteread</ENAMEX>, as it
happens, I have to confess to being as profoundly alienated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YBAs</ENAMEX> as
they seem to be from the kind of art that turns me on. From the kind of art, in
a word, that is about "little sensations" as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ©zanne</ENAMEX> called them, rather than
the tabloid sensationalism in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> show wallows.

            Of course, however wonderfully and sensitively you
and I were to write about one abstract painting, there is no denying that to
the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>--even indeed to the committed art aficionado--a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX>
debate about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX>'s (or anyone's) use of pink would get a little wearisome.
Whereas we could get hotter and hotter under the collar about the ethics of
displaying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s collection of new art in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, of public
subsidy for art the public is goaded into hating, of how blasphemy has become
an article of faith in an institutionalized avant garde, etc. etc. For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>--even for respectable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> like you and me--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>"
is great copy.

            I know 
                  Slate
                wants us to talk about
the art in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, not the kerfuffle surrounding it (and hats off to them for
wanting it so) but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point has to be made: It is irksome when art becomes a
moral cause. It is as if during a fencing match someone were to start hurling
bombs. It polarizes debate in such a way that aesthetic discernments become
irrelevant. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> and clergymen and animal-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> start
weighing in, the issues become freedom of expression, the meaning of images,
the ownership of icons (does the Virgin belong to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> or to everyone
touched by the concept?) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>, all fascinating issues, but leaving anyone
concerned with art obliged to argue for basic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>' rights rather than
attending to more localized and interesting issues, like is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Ofili</ENAMEX> any
good? But this in turn raises another issue: Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ofili</ENAMEX> want us to ask whether
he is any good, or does he not short-circuit the evaluative process by making
art contrived to raise hell with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> and excite a frisson of
old-time anticlericalism in the rest of us?

            It seems to me absurd to try and read an image like
The Holy Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> in purely formal terms, because it would be to
apply aesthetic criteria and art-historical comparisons to a work that draws
its power primarily from iconoclasm and irreverence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofili</ENAMEX> wants, surely, to be
raw, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, angry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad</ENAMEX>. It doesn't do much good to come along and say, well,
the encrustation of cut-out porno photos has a decorative quality that recalls
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gustave Moreau</ENAMEX>'s overloaded, quasi- (queasy) mystical images of the (last)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fin de siÃ¨cle</ENAMEX> ? Better would be to compare and contrast it with other
art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brut</ENAMEX> and with other blasphemous imagery. In respect of the former,
it competes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubuffet</ENAMEX>, and of the latter with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BuÃ±uel, DalÃ­</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Ernst</ENAMEX>. I'm
thinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ernst</ENAMEX>'s mock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> altarpiece of the Virgin spanking the Holy
Infant with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Breton</ENAMEX>, and I think Ã‰luard as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. On both
counts, prewar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-clericalism</ENAMEX> and postwar apocalyptic angst gave the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surrealists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dubuffet</ENAMEX>, respectively, historic urgency lacking in the
gratuitous neo-primitivism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofili</ENAMEX>. Unless we want to argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofili</ENAMEX>'s art
is about the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> that gives meaning to the kind of gestures
he deploys.

            The problem remains: Do
we, should we, bother with evaluative comparisons and contextualizations
with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Ofili</ENAMEX> whose agenda seems to be anti-aesthetic, and
whose context is much more the current sensations of pop music and fashion with
which he vies in terms of energy and verve, than the old masters, the "strong
and durable" art admired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ</ENAMEX>©zanne in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Louvre</ENAMEX>, and by many of us in the
permanent collections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>?

            Best
to you,

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
