
   
   
      
         
            Attack of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Killer Tomatoes</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 19</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story demystifies genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> are skeptical because they believe genetic manipulation is unnatural,
dangerous, and bad for the environment. But nearly all produce is a product of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>-bred <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX>, genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> isn't toxic, and genetic
manipulation reduces the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are not bothered by the
food fuss because they're ignorant about what they eat, optimistic about
technology, and trusting of their regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> asks why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>, are
expanding abroad when most international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> still get their highest
returns at home. Expectations of economies of scale encourage globalization.
But few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> can source globally, and retailing requires tinkering for
local tastes. ... An editorial decries the troubling turnout in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> elections. Even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> is adopting a new currency and
thinking of marshalling an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 49 percent</NUMEX> bothered to vote. Low turnout
suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> identify more with their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> than with their new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story derides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> as beloved "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Doormat":</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.R.C.</ENAMEX> won't succeed as a solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> because she has a tin ear for
politics and a likability deficit when not acting as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stooge.
... A piece offers a unique suggestion for avoiding school
shootings--remove the disincentives against dropping out. Forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">miscreants</ENAMEX> to
attend high school is pure folly, based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> untruths: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> can be
taught; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) dropping out will turn a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> toward crime; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) without a
high-school education you can't get a decent job. Allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> to quit
school would contribute to schoolhouse peace and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> learning.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s environmentalism collides with his livability
agenda, according to an article. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Activists</ENAMEX>, partially funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, wage
war on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> being built or expanded by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">localities</ENAMEX>. Highway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> are held
up and commuters get caught in the constricted traffic.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story claims that the ingratiating ways of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> manifest an instinct for
survival, not a love of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>. Proto-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> started hanging out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> produced an exploitable ecological niche filled with warmth and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">garbage</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> genome projects reveal that inbreeding for pedigree locks in bad
recessive traits. Maintaining genetic diversity is the best way to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed man</ENAMEX>'s
best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. ... A piece agitates for a progressive
pro-school-voucher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>. Voucher programs currently cover <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 0.1 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, so school choice is an untried solution to education's ills. A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX>-student trial of publicly funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> vouchers, accompanied by an
increase in traditional school spending, could break the stalemate in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> debate. ... An article laments the practice of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">liberating Sudanese</ENAMEX> slaves by buying their freedom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Slave redeemers</ENAMEX> provide a
strong financial incentive for the continuation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> business, which
would otherwise be unprofitable, and have spurred an increase in the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> being enslaved.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story claims new technologies will revolutionize
political campaigns. The Internet, consumer databases, and sophisticated
software help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to identify the fattest fund-raising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> and to
customize their campaigns to individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> through e-mail. Personalizing
politics might boost voter participation, but it could diminish candidate
accountability and threaten voter privacy. ... Despite the peace plan's
promise to demilitarize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> is turning itself into a standing
army, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> dispatch . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> are manning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">checkpoints</ENAMEX>,
policing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> to show their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, and voicing their reluctance to disarm.
... An article explores the handiwork of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Christenson</ENAMEX>, a
foreign affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> (and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>), who digs up
embarrassing information on administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> and campaigns against them
with critical op-eds and by otherwise purveying damaging tidbits. His most
successful effort to date involves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX>, who has endured
confirmation limbo for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full year</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 20</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story on racial profiling by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> presents the conventional wisdom:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profiling</ENAMEX> is a blunt instrument; too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX> are harassed solely on the
basis of race; and profiling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poisons</ENAMEX> the citizenry's relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profiling</ENAMEX> is also self-fulfilling: Pull over more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and you'll find more
guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is a certainty, according to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, but sovereignty will be a sham. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> settlements have been
inextricably integrated into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> depend on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> for
employment, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will insist on controlling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>'s international
borders. ... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jurvetson</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33-year-old</TIMEX> venture
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX> who seeds Internet startups, predicts he will prosper even though
Internet IPOs no longer promise exponential returns. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurvetson</ENAMEX>'s winning
formula is to back original ideas, not "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me Too</ENAMEX>" products such as
drugstore.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               and 
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> takes both
covers. The cover head shots reflect the stories inside. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time 's</ENAMEX> is
soft-focused and warmly lighted; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek 's</ENAMEX> is much harsher.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> concentrates on the obstacles to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s much-touted candidacy. According to the
mag, one reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't know much about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> is his
Clintonian penchant for sophistry. When asked what he stands for, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> replies,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honesty</ENAMEX>, integrity, serving for the right reasons." When asked what those
right reasons are, he elaborates, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> stands for." But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               analysis suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s Clintonian nature might help
him meet the "greatest expectation" for his candidacy: that he can bend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
back toward the political center. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's enthusiastic package echoes the familiar line about why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>: The breadth of his support among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>
and his landslide re-election victory wowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s "sheer hunger
for victory" overwhelms ideological concerns about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> candidacy.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports
that high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now offer marriage-education electives. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courses</ENAMEX>, which often involve role play, teach "active listening" and "conflict
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> mandates marriage ed and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> may soon follow
suit.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>
            

            The
magazine alerts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to another disease they didn't know they had:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> anxiety, formerly known as shyness, affects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.
Clinics invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> for treatment, but many are too bashful to attend. The
treatment for those who do show up: learning to withstand embarrassment.
Therapists make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> spill <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> and walk through public places trailing
toilet paper from their shoes ... A piece says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana Republican Party</ENAMEX> will allow
online voting in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX> presidential caucus. Several other states
will let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">absentee voters</ENAMEX> cast online ballots <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21 and 28</TIMEX>
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fin de si√</ENAMEX>®cle fiction issue prints stories by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty best</TIMEX>
young fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>" as well as glossy portraits of them. The introductory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that a similar list compiled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX> would not have
included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Wharton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Dreiser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack London</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Willa Cather</ENAMEX> because
all wrote their best work after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 40</TIMEX>. The stories include: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Saunders</ENAMEX>'
mock reply to a customer-service complaint, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman Alexie</ENAMEX>'s tale of a
hitchhiker, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Eugenides</ENAMEX>' narrative of a sex anthropologist, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vollman</ENAMEX>'s imagined account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>
            

            A
piece warns about the popular culture's fixation with hairless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. To be buff
but shorn of chest hair is to manifest male vanity and the desire for prolonged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adolescence</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> symptoms of male homosexuality, according to the
Standard . The proliferation of pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> without chest pelts signals
the degree to which gay values have distorted mainstream notions of manliness.
(No mention is made of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX>' shag-rug chest.) ... An article
celebrates rhetoric about God as a political tool. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Professing</ENAMEX> faith allows
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to woo the religious right without being locked to its
agenda on abortion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> discusses God to distance himself from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
scandals. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> writes that there aren't many qualified
female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> don't like science, just as they don't like
playing sports. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> are innately less aggressive, and affirmative action
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> should abandon their "harangue against female tastes."

         
      
   
