
   
   
      
         
            Look for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Doctor</ENAMEX>

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> filed an antitrust suit against the merger
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX> applauded the suit and took
credit for urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to file it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Insurers</ENAMEX> were "intent on capturing
the medical marketplace," seeking "too much power to dictate the health care
options offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randolph Smoak</ENAMEX>.

            Two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> voted to set up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' union and to lobby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for
an antitrust exemption allowing all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> to bargain collectively. Cynics
suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> were abandoning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hippocratic</ENAMEX> oath for hypocritical
politics. To deflect this criticism, the AMA associated itself with favorable
images of organized labor while dissociating itself from unfavorable ones.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. We're on your side. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chip Kahn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insurance Association of America</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIAA</ENAMEX>), which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobbies</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>, accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> of seeking bargaining power to raise their incomes "at the expense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>." To thwart this charge, the AMA portrayed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> as the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, implying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> were taking on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> in defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Dickey</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> would
"battle insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and managed care plans that put healthy profits
ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healthy patients</ENAMEX>." "Patient care is not at the top of health plans'
list of priorities," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smoak</ENAMEX> asserted. "Our objective here is to give <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
physicians the leverage they now lack to guarantee that patient care is not
compromised or neglected for the sake of profits."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. We're the little guy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> depicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cartel</ENAMEX>, accusing them of pursuing "collusion" and "price fixing." At a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
argued that exempting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> from antitrust laws would stifle "competition,"
limit "consumer choice," raise costs, and reduce "quality." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> ducked this
critique by casting itself not as a business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> but as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> alliance
of working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> are waging a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David versus Goliath</ENAMEX>" battle against
the "abusive and unfair practices of insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company giants</ENAMEX>" in a valiant
effort "to level the playing field between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smoak</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> like "ditch diggers churning through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>," added
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickey</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. We're not greedy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unions</ENAMEX> have a reputation for shutting
down important services and ignoring public inconvenience for the sake of
greed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> wants to avoid this reputation. "I don't really believe [the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionization</ENAMEX>] is being done for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>," one academic health care
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . "This is happening because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>'
incomes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' sense of autonomy, are getting killed."

            To
sidestep this complaint, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> promised never to strike (though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickey</ENAMEX>
conceded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> might resist bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> by "being a little slow in
completing some of the paperwork" required by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>) and avoided the word
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>," instead calling their proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> "an affiliated labor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX>'s disclaimers underscored the liabilities of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>"
label. "This will not be a traditional labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> will not
strike or endanger patient care," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smoak</ENAMEX> assured the public.

            The
basic political equation in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> expect better care than
they're willing to pay for. When they're deprived of options and benefits that
exceed what they've paid for, or when they're obliged to pay premiums
sufficient to cover the options and benefits they expect, they figure some
special interest is ripping them off. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX>'s goal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was to increase
its bargaining power without appearing to be that special interest.

            And what is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s
verdict? Unionization shows "how aggrieved many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> feel," says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . It changes the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> who have "sometimes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrogantly</ENAMEX> presented themselves as part of an elite profession as opposed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and it "may turn
out to be a strong force against health plans that unfairly use their market
power to limit quality of care." Whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' latest prescription will
cure their ills remains to be seen. But they look great.

         
      
   
