
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Dynasty</ENAMEX>?

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> led
its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with questions about the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Gandhi</ENAMEX> after she
led the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Party</ENAMEX> "through its worst ever electoral performance
since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX>." It said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of assassinated former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rajiv Gandhi</ENAMEX> now faces challenges to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> following the
comfortable general election victory of incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atal Bihari</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vajpayee</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Democratic Alliance</ENAMEX>. The first challenge will be over
her selection as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.
"There is bitterness in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> over her complete failure to bring in votes,"
it went on. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leaders</ENAMEX> returning from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> after countering ...
propaganda against her foreign origin are visibly worried about this factor
which they see as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'handicap</NUMEX>.' "

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>'s "lack of political
experience, her weak grasp of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX>, her foreign birth and a certain lack of
cultural sympathy with her adoptive land--despite many strenuous denials--all
took their toll." But it said it is unlikely that anyone will be so rash as to
run against her for the party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. "In the longer term, the party may
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">lean towards Priyanka Vadhera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mrs Gandhi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, who campaigned very
effectively in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uttar Pradesh</ENAMEX> for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>." An editorial in
the Financial Times
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">welcomed Vajpayee</ENAMEX>'s victory. "[A]s the exuberant response of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX> stock
market showed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, there are some grounds for hoping that the new
administration may enjoy a longer life than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>. If so, it will
have a chance to proceed with economic reforms that could secure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> a still
higher growth rate."

            The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> reported <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> reluctance to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> sanctions against it
waived. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> thinks current moves in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> to lift
the sanctions imposed on both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> after their nuclear tests
would benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> more. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> buys very little military
equipment from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say that arms acquired
by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> have always been used against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vajpayee</ENAMEX> has
written to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Ackerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India Caucus</ENAMEX>, saying
that a resumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> sales to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> "would be viewed as a very
negative development."

            In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> said it was a tragedy that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laila</ENAMEX> has decided to follow her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s example and
take up boxing. "[S]he doesn't have to look farther than her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> for the
debilitating effects of being pounded on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>," it said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>,
who was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> during his heyday, is now a walking shadow of
his once-imperious self. ... To hear him mumble his way through a conversation
and hesitantly shuffle around is a surefire promo for the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brigade</ENAMEX>.
He may have been the greatest, but now he's reduced to a pathetic bundle of
nerves."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were all dominated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> by the aftermath of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s
train crash in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 127</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died. There was a fevered
debate about rail safety, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> reporting that rail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> were
formally warned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX> about problems with the visibility of a signal at
the approach to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paddington Station</ENAMEX> that was apparently missed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice</ENAMEX> train
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX>. The other main story was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservative</ENAMEX> opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hague</ENAMEX>, who called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>, a
fraud, and the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of a systematically hypocritical and deceitful
government.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is now the world's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>-largest nuclear power. Quoting a
"secret document from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Department of Energy</ENAMEX>," it said in its lead
story that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 kilograms</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plutonium</ENAMEX>, which
means it can produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 250</NUMEX> nuclear weapons." It added, "For comparison,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">140 tons</NUMEX> of the material, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">85 tons</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.6</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7 tons</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.7 to 2.8 tons</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150-250 kg</NUMEX>) and of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23-35 kg</NUMEX>)."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s Frankfurter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> told a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> that it will not accept any
international interference in its war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, Izvestiya
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> have plans to storm the Chechen
capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX> in what would mark a huge escalation of the weekold invasion
of the rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> has "operational plans and a
detailed timetable of movement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX> and even of the storming of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said.

            
               Komsomolskaya
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pravda</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> carried an interview with former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for its "hysteria" about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>.)
Discussing his recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> said: "No one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
understands what is going on [in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>]. They stamp their feet on us, pour
dirt from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> to toe. Up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>! It has come to the point where they
call <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> a refuse pit!" He continued, "And I told the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, in your
country they steal more. And for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years</TIMEX> already. ... Why are you
pestering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>? We know ourselves what is bad here. You'd better help
us."

         
      
   
