
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Monk</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gucci Shoes</ENAMEX>

            The
main story around the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> was the terror in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, for which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> joined papers everywhere in putting most of the blame on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> of perpetuating the errors of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who ordered the invasion of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>. By
continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military rule in the territory, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> provoked the East
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Timorese</ENAMEX> into overwhelmingly rejecting his offer of autonomy within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. It also talked of a looming political crisis in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX>
is likely to lose the support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Post</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX>, after repeatedly promising to keep the
peace, was either being duplicitous or had lost control of his senior military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, who were vehemently opposed to independence for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. "Either
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, the status quo is intolerable," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial. "Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> are reluctant to dispatch their
own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> without an invitation from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>. But they should seek that
permission actively and be ready to follow through. Meanwhile, they should tell
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> and other loans are blocked until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
honours its many pledges to maintain order and let <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> have the freedom
it chose."

            Around
the world, opinion hardened not only against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> but also against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> called on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> in, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said there was no longer any alternative to foreign
intervention. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> decision to pull its current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> "a grand <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pontius Pilate</ENAMEX>-style washing of hands" and
"a treacherous abandonment for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Timorese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX> of "letting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> in chaos"; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX> , calling it "an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>," named <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> which are morally obliged to form the kernel of a rapid intervention
force "to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> carrying out a new crime against humanity." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> ran a front-page commentary by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noam Chomsky</ENAMEX> blaming the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
for the fate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX> because of its failure to withdraw support
from its "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>" or to tell it that its game was up.

            
Following the drubbing received by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX> in two
state elections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> (a subject that naturally dominated the German
press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX>
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said the outcome was predictable. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schröder</ENAMEX> has
presided over a thoroughly muddled and quarrelsome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> since he defeated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s general election," it said in an editorial.
"The main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victors</ENAMEX> [in the east <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandenburg</ENAMEX>] were the reformed
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communists</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party of Democratic Socialism</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 per cent</NUMEX> of the vote,
and the extreme nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Volksunion</ENAMEX>, which will sneak into the
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.2 per cent</NUMEX>." In a brief comment published on the front
page of Corriere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elie Wiesel</ENAMEX> expressed
alarm at the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Volksunion</ENAMEX>, which he said exploits
unemployment to stir up racism. "It would be useful to know the percentage of
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who identify with the German extreme right," he wrote. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> must
hope it is not a large percentage. All those who put their faith in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">German</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> must encourage them not to be seduced by simplistic and unworthy
solutions to real problems."

            

               Corriere 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera</ENAMEX> also reported on its front page a claim by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cornwell</ENAMEX> that he has found evidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archives</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Pius XII</ENAMEX> was a visceral <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX> who helped and supported
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> from when he came to power until the "final solution." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> was
referring to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX>'s new book
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pope: The Secret History of Pius XII</ENAMEX> that was omitted from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> edition. It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jesuit</ENAMEX> church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> Giacomo
Martina, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gregorian University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, as saying that the
claim was "shameful." "How, for example, can it be reconciled with the fact
that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> learned of plans by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> to kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, he passed the information on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>? To understand
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s caution in denouncing the persecution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, it would be
useful to analyse the similar caution shown by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX>. The same reasons for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prudence</ENAMEX> guided both of them."

            
Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> article led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>--an
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> in which the media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> referred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX> as "a very political old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk shuffling</ENAMEX> around in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gucci</ENAMEX> shoes." In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> (which is locked in
bitter competition with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ) called his comment "almost
endearingly wicked," having no purpose but to strengthen his business links
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. "What Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> is profoundly wrong," the
paper said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> have treated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> abominably since they
invaded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ran editorials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> welcoming the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
Court of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> that some of the rougher interrogation methods used by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> are illegal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> could take pride in the decision, even though it made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>'s
work more difficult. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said, "It is difficult to think of another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that would be
willing to take such a bold step to protect the human rights of suspected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrorists</ENAMEX>, at a time when the threat of terror is still so very real."

         
      
   
