
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> Still on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fence</ENAMEX>

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a pledge by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military to support
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. Military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman Maj.</ENAMEX> Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sudrajat</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> should accept it to avoid
international condemnation. But in an opinion piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Makmur Keliat</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lecturer</ENAMEX> in international
relations at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> still
seems to be playing for time and that its acceptance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> does not mean
it will recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX> independence.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, which is to lead the peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> said,
by contrast, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> intends "to respect the will of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their clearly stated choice of freedom." It said in an editorial, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> stands shamed before the world for its
armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>' encouragement of, and participation in, the killings and
destruction in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> led its front page on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security</ENAMEX>
Council authorizing its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> "to use all force necessary" to rein in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a disclosure that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million pounds</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $210 million</NUMEX>) in public money has been spent within the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hawk fighters</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> front-paged
the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Byers</ENAMEX> overruled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> by allowing financial help to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> before militias
started massacring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>: A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 million</NUMEX> loan helped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>
buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> engineering products. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is already under attack from
the left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> for breaching its own much-vaunted "ethical"
foreign policy in its relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, where terrorist bombs have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Izvestiya</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aleksander Lebed</ENAMEX>, a former
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, is hoping to take power as acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> loses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. It said he appears to have the support of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX>, the financial and media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX>, who recently visited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebed</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Krasnoyarsk</ENAMEX>, where he is regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. "Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berezovsky</ENAMEX> holds the
opinion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebed</ENAMEX> is capable of coping with the chaos in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," the
paper said, adding that "many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> hoped that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebed</ENAMEX> would be a
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>." Reporting on the tightening of security following
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> bombs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rossiskaya Gazeta</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,000</NUMEX> personnel
had checked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26,560</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">415</NUMEX> hostels and dormitories
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous 24 hours</TIMEX>.

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, in an editorial expressing "heartfelt sympathy" for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>--and also for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> "lumbered with yet
another crisis"--warned, nevertheless, against an abuse of power. It said there
is no need for a further law on full emergency rule, "nor should <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> police
fall prey to the traditional temptation to arrest every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dark-skinned</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the
capital." The editorial concluded: "A survey <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> shows that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 6</NUMEX>
per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muscovites</ENAMEX> want a draconian state of emergency. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s leaders
must heed their wishes and refrain from going too far." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> said in
an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>'s offer to
help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> fight terrorism is "a cheering indication of how close the two
world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> have come since the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a decade</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mainichi Shimbun</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>'s agreement with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to suspend plans for further test-firing of long-range
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> "by no means constitutes a fundamental solution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX>
missile problem." Noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> hadn't agreed to refrain from
missile-launching in the future, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in an editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> shouldn't lift economic sanctions against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> until it has. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> 's editorial was about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> killing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to claim
insurance money. There have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> such murders in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 15 years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, it said. "The lamentable moral degradation that
leads some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to exchange human lives for money has its roots in our
materialistic society, characterized by badly swollen egos," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claimed.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX>
Times ran an editorial sharply criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> for letting the yen
strengthen "dangerously" against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar. It called on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> "to act decisively, now," and asked, "Why on earth does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> not buy
the dollars itself, allowing the domestic money supply to expand in the
process?"

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
Post called on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> "to think hard and decide slowly" before
starting a gambling casino in the territory. "The goal is to offer something
quite different from the rather tawdry centres of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX>," it said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in
an editorial. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. There, some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s most pretentious and absurd architecture beckons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> from around
the world to see such sights as in-house acrobats or an art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, a battle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">full-size pirate ships</ENAMEX>, or to tour an ersatz <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> or other improbable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">replication</ENAMEX>. Near such fantasies, of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>' main line of business
always beckons, ready to extract huge sums from the unwary." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> noted
the findings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States National Gambling Impact Study Commission</ENAMEX>:
that while gambling produced <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34 billion</NUMEX> in government revenues and created
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 700,000</NUMEX> jobs, it also cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> million
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> suffer from pathological gambling addiction, causing costly social
problems, especially for the poor and the young," it added.

         
      
   
