
   
   
      
         
            
<P>Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Sensation&quot; Art Worth the Fuss</ENAMEX>?</P>

            

               
                  Click here to view the entire "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" show
online.
               
            

            I think you may be aware, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah</ENAMEX>, that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>"
had outings in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">before</TIMEX> arriving in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World</ENAMEX> (you rap my knuckles for
a supposedly unseen critique). I saw the show more than enough times at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Academy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> to form an enduring impression of it, and you
will note that I confined specific criticism in my letter to a painting ;
unlike sculptures or installations, a painting is essentially the same object
wherever it's exhibited. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofili</ENAMEX>'s work was featured in depth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tate Gallery</ENAMEX>'s exhibition for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1998 Turner Prize</ENAMEX>, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> won.

            I like your suggestive angle on the negritude of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofili</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>. And your anger at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> for picking on a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> may
well be justified. (You'd think he'd have learned a lesson about taking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pot</ENAMEX>-shots at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> in the outer boroughs.) But even if we accept that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofili</ENAMEX>'s dung motif is not to be read as shit but as an exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">artefact</ENAMEX>, what
about those porno-cutouts? Of course, we don't want to get caught up in the
intentional fallacy, and a work of art of strength should be open to a variety
of interpretations, but I think there's a danger of missing the plot (and
incidentally patronizing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> culture) if we deny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofili</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> its
subversiveness, iconoclasm, and sheer naughtiness.

            It's good, too, that we should get straight on the
case of national differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neo-conceptualism</ENAMEX>. You are
quite right that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> are dead against coming over as theoretically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">highbrow</ENAMEX>. If anything, they veer in the opposite direction--"dumb enough to be
a conceptualist," to paraphrase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchamp</ENAMEX>--but is banality the only antidote to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aridity</ENAMEX>? Almost as painful to my sensibility as the pomposity of
Derrida-quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> Program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> is the smarmy, too-clever<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by-half</NUMEX> wit
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YBAs</ENAMEX>. What on earth is one supposed to get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Patterson</ENAMEX>'s
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Bear</ENAMEX> , which appropriates the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> Underground map (a classic
of '30s graphic design incidentally), replacing the tube stops with a seemingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> array of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>, historic and current? I don't think that
meaningless pretension is any less offensive than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-meaningful
variety.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damien</ENAMEX> as dangerous" is a new one on me. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
he is known as an affable restaurateur. (His urinal in the gents at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pharmacy</ENAMEX>,which he owns, a vitrine stuffed with detritus, is a masterpiece of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">décor</ENAMEX> with attitude .) He is, for sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the YBA
pack, even if he has been surpassed in sheer nastiness by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chapman twins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Lucas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alain Miller</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirst's</ENAMEX> is a stylish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nihilism</ENAMEX>--abjection on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. Sure it references <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> minimalism, and sends
it up, but that's hardly his unique achievement: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde art</ENAMEX> has
been doing that almost since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judd and Morris</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer minimalists</ENAMEX>, hit the
scene. And do we really think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirst</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shark</ENAMEX> in the tank would have been
possible without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Koons</ENAMEX>?

            You say there are some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> in this show. I say there are a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pussy cats</ENAMEX>. I take some credit for
writing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Saville</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX> , which
brought her work to the attention of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saatchi</ENAMEX>. I'm also on record as a fan
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiona Rae</ENAMEX>, and even have a soft spot for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Coventry</ENAMEX>, irritating though
he is. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>' gentle purring is drowned out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>' hysterical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yapping</ENAMEX>. At least that was so in the way the show was packaged in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. I'm
ready for a miraculous transformation at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>, however. And to
be converted by your enthusiasm.

            
Best,

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
