
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=630250921-01071999><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronkite</ENAMEX> in a Speedo</SPAN>

            

               
                  New
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 26</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story welcomes the decline of rational-choice
political science. Rational-choicers, who have dominated the field for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, sought to explain political behavior through mathematical modeling.
The theoretical fad permanently handicapped political science by encouraging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> to disengage themselves from the practice of politics. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>
have now proved that rational choice is based on dubious assumptions about
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>' motives. ... An article explores the workplace <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consultants</ENAMEX>
profit from advising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> on how to prevent office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rampages</ENAMEX> and training
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to spot unhinged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, but office homicides are declining, and all
the fretting may just exacerbate fear.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 17</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover editorial argues that free trade benefits the
environment by increasing economic growth and giving poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to clean up. The related cover story applauds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>'s
efforts to find common ground with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> should consider
the environment but not use trade sanctions to enforce environmental
agreements. ... An article questions the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s liberation. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worldwide</ENAMEX> poll found that while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">93 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> feel they are in a better
position than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was, a majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> say that they
are no happier than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granny</ENAMEX> was.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s
                
               
                  Content , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story identifies the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who most influence what
we read, watch, wear, and think. Predictable picks include the managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX>. Surprising choices include the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX> ads, the managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of Yahoo!, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>.
... An article details how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> muffed its coverage
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> "scandal." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> got the facts wrong, played down
dissenting views, and inferred the worst from the leaks it received. The
Times acknowledged too late that it did not know how much information
was stolen or whether it had any impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s nuclear program. ...
An item reports that an unidentified major cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> is negotiating to air
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bare Essentials News</ENAMEX> --a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> national news program featuring anchors
in bathing suits.

            

               
                  New
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 10</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story, adapted from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">depicts Jim Clark</ENAMEX> as the personification of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>'s spirit of
relentless reinvention. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than 20 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Graphics</ENAMEX>,
Netscape, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Healtheon</ENAMEX>. His latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> aims to put medical records online
and to allow Web-based insurance payments. ... An article hopes that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confrontational Cardinal John O'Connor</ENAMEX> will be replaced by a more conciliatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archbishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, traditionally the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>, is expected to step down soon. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> should be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacemaker</ENAMEX>
who can bridge the ethnic differences that increasingly divide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Talk
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>
            

            A
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> reveals that he contemplates running for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>--and that he loves to paint pottery. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX>
decorates his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, and hearts. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> enlisted for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> out of fealty to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and distaste for draft dodgers: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> deplored "the inequity of the rich
not having to serve." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is not asked what he thinks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
draft ducking. ... Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration Commissioner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kessler</ENAMEX> describes how an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R.J. Reynolds</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Cough"</ENAMEX>--leaked
the feds information about the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s manipulation of nicotine
levels. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> also found a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who was silenced
and fired after his research demonstrated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nicotine</TIMEX>'s addictiveness.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story marvels at the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild Bunch</ENAMEX>" of egotistical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrities</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>) who are pondering
third-party runs for the presidency. The quasi-candidacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beatty</ENAMEX> proves that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica Madness</ENAMEX>" collapsed the distinction "between the serious and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">circus</ENAMEX>." Unsurprising conclusion: The appeal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provocateurs</ENAMEX> stems from
disaffection with two-party politics. ... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> argues that the former
"sideshow freak" of the "political carnival" has become the ringmaster. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is courting his support, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX> consults with him regularly.
... A piece reports on a new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">treat</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>: yogurt in a tube.
"Go-Gurt" rang up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37 million</NUMEX> in sales during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first year</TIMEX> of limited
distribution. Expect a torrent of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foodstuff</ENAMEX> in tubes.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story is ambivalent about laser eye surgery. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are expected to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2,500</NUMEX> per eye to have their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">corneas</ENAMEX> sliced open and reshaped. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-minute</TIMEX> surgery immediately improves
the vision of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>-to<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-15 percent</NUMEX> have to undergo a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> procedure, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>-to<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-5 percent</NUMEX> suffer permanent impairments such
as double vision. ... A disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laser-surgery patient</ENAMEX> relates how
she must apply artificial tears every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> or have her tear ducts
surgically plugged--and she still can't see her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> clearly. ... A
profile applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX> for a fearless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first year</TIMEX>. The
supposedly timid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> pushed through bold HMO reform, an aggressive
assault-weapon ban, mandatory high-school exit exams, and peer review for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
&
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX>
            

            
Critically ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are being misled into acting as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guinea pigs</ENAMEX> for
experimental treatments, frets the cover story . Pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> to test
new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutes</ENAMEX> pressure them to recruit human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> sometimes prey on patient desperation and fail to obtain informed
consent. In one drug trial, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 2-year-old</TIMEX> died even though traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemotherapy</ENAMEX> could almost certainly have cured her <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> ridicules the recent spate of books on human
behavior. Books on the cultural and biological roots of crying, love, disgust,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laughter</ENAMEX>, and gossip fuel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' self-obsession.

            

               
                  The
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> hypes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s interest Web site iVillage for its savvy marriage of
content and e-commerce. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> by offering
"integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsorships</ENAMEX>"--that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> contributing content. By
offering free e-mail, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> horoscopes, and online discussions with sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>, the site has recruited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. All those eyeballs have
given unprofitable iVillage a stock valuation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $2 billion</NUMEX>.

            
               
                  
Business
                
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week , Oct. 11</TIMEX>
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profile of India</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> finds that young middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> are
zealous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> who idolize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. High-paying technology work has
displaced the civil service as the most desirable career. ... A
sympathetic profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s biggest asset
is his appeal to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA Dads</ENAMEX>," independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> unattached to either
party.

            

               
                  The
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story predicts that spending on federal campaigns in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> could reach <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.5 billion</NUMEX>, while issue advocacy ads will inundate the
airwaves. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are right that campaign finance reform is "class
warfare": It would wrest from the hands of the moneyed elite the
disproportionate political power it now wields.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX>
            

            A
piece accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde artists</ENAMEX> of "cultural blackmail."
They demand subsidies and threaten to brand the middle-class with philistinism
if it resists. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" exhibit is "just the usual ... celebration of
the blasphemous, the criminal and the decadent." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on the exhibit.) ... An article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assesses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s chances of clinching the
general election by winning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spanish-speaking W.</ENAMEX> appeals to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> and has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of money for advertising. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of high-tech
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> is pumping <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> for donations, while even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
honchos are buddying up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
