
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Buckley Quotes Himself</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Self-Defense</ENAMEX>

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley Jr.</ENAMEX> read a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club</ENAMEX>"
about his latest novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Redhunter: A Novel Based on the Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe McCarthy</ENAMEX> , and decided enough was enough. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
Clubbers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Alterman</ENAMEX>, had called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>'s book "a lumbering, themeless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pudding</ENAMEX> of a novel that forces one's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">eyelids</ENAMEX> shut like an invisible vise." The
other, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Radosh</ENAMEX>, had described it as "heavy and plodding, without any real
juice to it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> weighed in, defending his work against all charges
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aesthetic</ENAMEX>, historical, and ideological, and quoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> writing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> who deemed the book "wonderfully
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">readable</ENAMEX> ... a witty, fast-moving yarn." Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> has asked
Slate to run the following excerpt from the book, so that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for themselves. We are delighted to oblige.
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 45</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acheson Collects McCarthyana</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX> was cutting up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in his law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Covington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burling</ENAMEX>. However fastidiously he discharged his duties
as a practicing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, his mind was on other things, not least his reputation
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> during the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX>'s presidency.
His daily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stimulant</ENAMEX>--"If you can call it that," he remarked to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and
close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Epison</ENAMEX>, "--the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> ingestion of poison I inflict on
myself"--was what he referred to with some scorn as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> page" in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morning</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. He had been reluctant to evidence a formal interest in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unspeakable senator</ENAMEX>. But in fact he read all references to him and, though only
out of sight, collected voraciously choice items. He had taken to scissoring
out clippings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> (when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> wasn't in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>), and
tossing them into his briefcase. But after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> he decided that it would
be better to undertake his project in a more orderly way. That was when he told
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Gibson</ENAMEX>, it is possible that when I do my memoirs I shall
have in them a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> on the ... grotesqueries of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>. For that
reason, I shall ask you to clip out of the papers those articles or editorials
I designate with the initial 'M.' These are to be clipped and put in a manila
folder, in the bottom drawer"--he pointed down from where he sat--"over
there."

            Day after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week after week</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>,
the folder grew in size. The methodical Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acheson</ENAMEX> took to classifying the
entries according to his estimate of their ranking. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-O-3</ENAMEX>" parsed as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy-Outrageous</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At</NUMEX> 3rd level." "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-P-1</ENAMEX>" parsed as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Preposterous-1st</ENAMEX> level." He had other categories, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> (for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasonable</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> (for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laughable</ENAMEX> ). He also reserved a
classification for criticisms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> that he especially savored. His very
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">favorites</ENAMEX> earned, as one would expect, a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>," whence "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-C-1</ENAMEX>." Such a discovery
in a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> would put him in a very good mood and sometimes he would
even drop a quick note of commendation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton</ENAMEX> said
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> that he was a "hit-and-run propagandist of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> model," Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX> had filed the remark as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-C-2</ENAMEX>, and dropped a note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>,
nice score <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMenace</ENAMEX>. Well done."

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX>'s reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearson</ENAMEX> in his column had caused him to glow. "What he is trying to do is not
new. It worked well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>; all voices except those
officially approved were silenced in those lands by intimidation." But he
decided against dropping a note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pearson</ENAMEX>. He would not wish to run the risk
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pearson</ENAMEX>'s quoting him. He could hardly countenance any public appearance of
an ongoing contention between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean Gooderham Acheson/ Yale/</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
State/ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe McCarthy</ENAMEX>/ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicken Farmer/ Marquette</ENAMEX> --wherever
Marquette was--/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Junior Senator</ENAMEX> from --a state that had lost its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">senses</ENAMEX>.

            He had dined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week before</TIMEX> with defeated
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai Stevenson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX> enjoyed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> but thought him indecisive. Acheson relished the story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai</ENAMEX> had told him, over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Club</ENAMEX>, about the dinner with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> was then living across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> was being rebuilt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> had summoned him when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> was still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>.

            "I walked in the door and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> said, I
mean just after barely saying 'Hello,' he said, 'Adlai, I want you to run for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. You should announce <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third week</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>'--this dinner was in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January, 1952</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>--'and say that you will seek a leave of absence as governor
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>.' "

            "I told him I was very flattered by the suggestion
but that I was committed to run for re-election as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>--"

            "What did he say?"

            "He didn't even acknowledge what I had said.
He went on and talked about this and that but at dinner repeated exactly
the same instructions--I was to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, announce <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third week</TIMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, etc. I gave him the same answer. After dinner he walked me to the door
and, you guessed it, said the identical thing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time, and I gave back
the identical answer. Then you know what he said, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>? 'The trouble with you,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai</ENAMEX>, is you're so indecisive !' "

            They both laughed.

            Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX> had looked up.

            "You know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> was quite correct,
you are indecisive."

            But at least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai</ENAMEX> wasn't equivocal about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX> had given an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-C-1</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai</ENAMEX>'s designation of McCarthyism before the
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">club</ENAMEX> as a "hysterical form of putrid slander" and as "one of the most
unwholesome manifestations of our current disorder."

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Epison</ENAMEX> came in to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of his
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>, just after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, it was in order to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> on the
appeal he was shepherding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appellate Division</ENAMEX> on behalf of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Iran</ENAMEX>. But he began by asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> whether he had seen the
reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>--"I caught it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> , which I
sometimes see. It wasn't in any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>"--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lattimore?</ENAMEX>"

            No, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX> hadn't seen it.

            "Somebody apparently asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lattimore</ENAMEX> after a speech
what he thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>. He said--I have this in memory, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>!--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> is
'a base and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">miserable creature</ENAMEX>.' "

            "That is a thoughtful summary," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acheson</ENAMEX> said. He
then paused. "Rather a pity it was done by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Lattimore</ENAMEX>. He is not exactly a
disinterested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> question. As a matter of fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>--obviously to go no further--it hurts me to say this--I think that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">miserable creature</ENAMEX> was substantially right on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lattimore</ENAMEX>. ... But that hardly
vitiates the soundness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lattimore's</ENAMEX> summary on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>." He made a mental
note to write down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lattimore</ENAMEX>'s characterization and slip it into his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">folder</ENAMEX>.

            "You may be interested to know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>, that a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who are well situated, think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> has gone far enough."

            "Surely the question is, What does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX> think?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX> turned his heard slowly, as if to say that
the words he would now say were sacredly confidential.

            "He is, I am I think reliably informed, prepared to
move. ... That is enough on that subject."

            "I agree, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>. How're you getting on with your
book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            "I write <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times a week, I try to
do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> words a day."

            "Have you got a title for it yet?"

            "Yes. I'm going to call it, A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Looks</ENAMEX> at
His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> . We've lost a lot of spirit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>, in the two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX> came in. Of course there's a lot of disequilibrium in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. You will find, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>, that this is always so after a society
completes a major effort--in this case, winning a world war. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>'s defeat
was a symptom of that kind of--letting your breath out. The surprise here was
that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dewey</ENAMEX>. But that also meant that the opposition never
got a chance to exercise its muscles. Not until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX>'s victory in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>."

            "So your book is intended to do what?"

            "To put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> back on its feet, as
the civilized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, the intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. A worthwhile project, wouldn't you
agree<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            "Of course. But you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>, I hope you will
confront head-on the foreign-policy problem. I agree with everything you say
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>. You know that. But it is a fact that we had to fight a
war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> ended--"

            "Yes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">war</ENAMEX> ended officially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> was elected--and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> died."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>, you are being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> now. We <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
did get into that war, we did--I know hate that word, 'lose' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--"

            "You are correct that we have to focus very
carefully on what is happening in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. We don't know what the
triumvirate that's in power now, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khrushchev, Bulganin</ENAMEX>--I continue to refer to
it as a triumvirate though they executed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Beria a week ago</TIMEX>, good riddance. What
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">the successors to Stalin</ENAMEX> are going to do we don't know, but there are no signs
they are giving up their commitment to rule the world. But yes, I am
ready to say this, with great care: I will show you the draft of that chapter.
I will say that it is correct that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> can't be allowed to go any
further. Well, didn't Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> say that? By engaging them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>?

            "But the challenge will be to distinguish between
the right kind of anti-Communism and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>'s anti-Communism. A big
difference. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>, did you see what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Reuss</ENAMEX> said about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> the other
day? Reuss was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>. I think I may
just have a copy of the clipping."

            Acheson leaned over and pulled out the bottom left
drawer on his desk. "He said, 'Senator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> is a tax-dodging,
character-assassinating, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">racetrack</ENAMEX>-gambling, complete and contemptible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>.'
"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX>'s face brightened. He gave the closest he
ever gave to a giggle. "I wish I had said that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
