
   
   
      
         
            It's in the Genes

            The
world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> ran out of new things to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> tragedies many years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, and all the old clichés were revived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in the massive coverage of the
tragic loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> in a plane crash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>--the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>" on the
family, its love of adventure, the "end of a dynasty," etc. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> peddled a new
theory. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> are not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>-crossed, cursed, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unlucky</ENAMEX>," it said in a
front-page report. "They undoubtedly bear the novelty-seeking and risk-taking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX> discovered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> impulsive, adventurous, and tend
to take chances with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, sex, speed, and other potentially dangerous
activities." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> was quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ebstein</ENAMEX>, a molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geneticist</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herzog Memorial Hospital</ENAMEX>, who headed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that discovered
the gene. "If I were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, I would consult the best psychological experts
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> to discuss what normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> are and how to control their
risk-taking urge," he told the paper. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebstein</ENAMEX> discovered "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">serotonin</ENAMEX> transporter promoter gene" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "He more recently
found that it increases the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bearer</ENAMEX>'s risk of getting addicted to hard drugs
(although several genes are probably involved), can cause <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to seek
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensation</ENAMEX>, and makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newborns</ENAMEX> as young as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> more alert and curious
about the outside world."

            There
was widespread reluctance in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>-obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to write off
the future of the family dynasty. Corriere della
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> pegged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Kennedy Townsend</ENAMEX> on its
front page as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to his "sceptre." "It would be good if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camelot</ENAMEX>, the
mythical realm of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>, were to end in the hands of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> above
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suspicion</ENAMEX>," it said. "It would be poetic if the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> president
were to be called not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere</ENAMEX> also carried an
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay Talese</ENAMEX>, "the troubadour of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>," dismissing the idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>. "I think, on the contrary, that
there burns inside them a feeling of invincibility, an obsession with
challenge, an arrogance of power that drive them to take risks all the time,"
he was quoted as saying. Asked if he thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jr.</ENAMEX> had been different from
the others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talese</ENAMEX> replied: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Different</ENAMEX> in the sense that he wasn't a sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predator</ENAMEX>, like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, nor addicted to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, like other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. ... But otherwise he was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>--sure of himself and convinced of his immortality."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jr.</ENAMEX>'s problem was that he knew he wasn't
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> at heart and that he had crashed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> because he wanted to be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. "He didn't manage to live like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, but fate allowed him at least to
leave this world as one," it concluded. (But what does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
know about it? Another characteristic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> is that they invite
reckless psychological examination.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> led its front page
with a headline saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jr.</ENAMEX> shouldn't have flown at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> because he
wasn't certified to do so. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX> announced in
huge letters that he had "had a death wish." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro 's</ENAMEX> headline was
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Accursed Kings</ENAMEX>" ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Rois Maudits</ENAMEX> "), and its front-page
editorial compared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jr.</ENAMEX> to the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>. "Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Di</ENAMEX>," it
said, "fate struck because, according to one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elizabethan poets</ENAMEX> of whom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> always kept a quotation in reserve [not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabethan</ENAMEX> actually:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Shirley</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1596-1666</TIMEX>], 'There is no armor against fate;/ Death lays his icy
hand on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>.' "

            In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jr.</ENAMEX>'s fate recalled another
myth--that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oedipus</ENAMEX>, who fulfilled a prophecy by killing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and
marrying his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> without knowing who they were. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oedipus</ENAMEX> story survives,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "because it embodies the deep human sense that free will is a
fragile thing, and no inheritance, however noble, frees <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from the mark of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sin</ENAMEX>. ... The fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy Jr</ENAMEX> reinforces in every mind that melancholy
truth." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> also made the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
comparison, saying that her myth, like that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>, was not solely the
property of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> country. "It would be a fitting legacy if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Junior</ENAMEX>'s death
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reminded America</ENAMEX> and the world of the high ideal of public service and liberal
values than run through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> rhetoric," it said in an editorial. "It is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> greatness to call us to a higher moral purpose, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
tragedy that none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> could fulfil that promise."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>
commented in its editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jr.</ENAMEX>'s death "helps slow down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> trend toward a new kind of dynastic democracy, then some good will have come
from this grim news." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar Qaddafi</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, as
reported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>, on its front page. While expressing his "deepest regret"
about the tragedy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qaddafi</ENAMEX> said he was "even more sad" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
has been unable to locate his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> claims to know how to find a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mustard seed</ENAMEX>, either on earth or in space, thanks to its extraordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capabilities</ENAMEX>," he said. "Or perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is negligent and not serious in
searching for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kennedy dynasty?</ENAMEX>"

         
      
   
