
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">283</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Storm Warnings&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               The current issue
of a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> lists these warning signs: stain, unusual odor, the
sound of broken glass or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, what danger? (Question
courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim O'Grady</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">282</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It'll Take a Miracle":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  An inquiry into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> began in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> opted to fast-track her canonization, waiving the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX>
post-death waiting period. Beatification, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step toward sainthood,
requires a confirmed miracle, and one has already been "authenticated." Name
that miracle.
               
            

            "Tears
streaming from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
Lerangis
            

            "Black
Hole of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX> now 'only a little gray, more like brown, really.'
"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Transformed Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> from semicoherent socialist into gibbering
right-wing tattletale."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "Oh, I
know! She tortured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> until they either converted or died! Or was that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">beatified Father Junípero Serra?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            "Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>'s death, there have been no movie sightings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penis</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Something happened
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1968</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes ago</TIMEX> that transformed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag from
hallowed symbol to fabric pattern. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> would not televise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbie Hoffman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag shirt on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dick Cavett Show</ENAMEX> ; last week
it was available at a street fair in my neighborhood in the form of silk
underwear. (Surprisingly comfortable.) This seems like increasing liberalism,
but it's only encroaching commerce, less a commitment to free speech than a
determination to sell paper plates, cups, and napkins for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">kicky Fourth of July</TIMEX>
fun. Similarly, if more slowly, the term "miracle" has evolved from sacred
mystery to a substitute for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mayonnaise</ENAMEX>. There is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Miracle Mile</ENAMEX> for shopping,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Miracle</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ice</TIMEX> for sports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miracle-Gro</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. But here it seems less a
chance to make a buck than something akin to grade inflation. Either way,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> is a shoo-in. And she'll look great on a medallion, boxers, or
briefs.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wondrous Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miracles</ENAMEX> have already been attributed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>, and the investigation has just begun.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry D'Souza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archbishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX>, said a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Bengal</ENAMEX> claimed that a tumor disappeared after he was blessed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>. D'Souza said the case has been authenticated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> who broke
several ribs in a car accident reportedly healed when she wore a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">medallion</ENAMEX> around her neck.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> says she
was cured after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> appeared in her dreams and said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child</ENAMEX>, you are
cured."

            It does not count
against Mother <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teresa</ENAMEX> that she's concentrated all her miracles into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> field,
medicine, failing to appear well-rounded. It does count against your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> that
they are unlikely to provide any of these valuable services.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jenning</ENAMEX>'s Give
Me a Sign Follow-Up
            

            Near where I used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, there is a
road along the bottom of a cliff where a series of signs says:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALLING ROCKS</ENAMEX>

            DO NOT STOP

            Driving past, we used to
comment, "Damn right they don't."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Cenedella</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charybdis/Carybdis</ENAMEX> Follow-Up
            

            Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Newman</ENAMEX>
has taken too much <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX> is written in ancient
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>. (P.S.: On the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglophone</ENAMEX> spelling, somebody should inform the
Greeks that they've misspelled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hellas</ENAMEX>.")

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Bitterman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Class-Conscious Vandals</ENAMEX> Follow-Up

            I don't know about your
'hood, but here, the prettier the car the more likely it is to be "keyed"--that
nasty, deep, full-length scratch (or scratches, if it is keyed by multiple
pissed-off proletarians) when one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is parked on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. Also, in a
sort of tribal downsizing, budding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> no longer have to steal your car
radio, they only have to steal the brand logo insignia from the hood or trunk
of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> (less likely to set off the alarm, which makes it more likely that
they can steal badges from all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> on a block) in order to prove their
inherent gangsterness. With all these options, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX>-paint-wielding taggers are
free to concentrate on the stationary objects that will mark their turf, or to
defile the stationary objects in the turf of the other.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            The affliction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX>, the triumph
of various ball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
