
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wine Web</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject:
Illegal Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wine</ENAMEX>

            
               From:

               Paula
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oct 3</ENAMEX>

            As a liquor store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, I'm not so concerned about
my fair <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> losing out on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of tax dollars through Internet sales.
What does concern me greatly, however, is the fact that I pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> annually
to my local selectmen for the privilege of selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. Why should
someone from across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, having paid no licensing fees whatsoever, be
able to take potential business away from me? Granted, some locations are state
regulated, but for those of us who are privately operated, the idea of someone
being allowed to compete with us for free is insulting. I have no problem with
competition; just make sure that it's a level playing field.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Inquisition</ENAMEX>

            
               From:

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Inquisitor</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oct 1</ENAMEX>

            This whole unsavory episode brings back memories of
skits with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monty Python</ENAMEX> ! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my favorite lines was, "You are guilty
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>--no, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>--charges of heresy. Of course, the limits of television
broadcasting prevent me from presenting a shred of evidence to support
them."

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer and the Press Sharks</ENAMEX>

            
               From:
pdbrophy

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: Thu
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sept</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>

            If the behavior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> was so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indefensible</ENAMEX> in your mind, why aren't they identified by name? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional</ENAMEX>
courtesy?

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anti-Semitism</ENAMEX>"

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spirit</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: Thu
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sept</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>

            Nowhere does 
                  Slate
                prove
that the following definition (from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anti-Semitism"</ENAMEX> ) has anything to do
with the examples cited in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s book: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Anti-Semitism</ENAMEX>] is an
ideology--an interlocked set of principles and prejudices--in which certain
nefarious traits or practices are ascribed to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, even when few
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> exhibit those traits or when other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> engage in those practices."

            
               
                  Slate
                proceeds to name
very specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, presumably <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, whose policies Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> takes
to task. Where is the generalization to "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>"? Where does he
impugn that only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> subscribe to such policies? Which of his examples involve
"traits or practices"? The examples simply do not support his premise that Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is prejudiced.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diversity" Doesn't Mean</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>"

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Fittin</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: Thu
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sept</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> 

            The uproar by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> is understandable.
Catholic bashing is OK since it is, a priori , art. Doing the same
thing to, let's say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, is hateful and mean-spirited ...

            I do not want my tax money to support trash art, or
any art for that matter. If I want to enjoy art, I go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX>. I pay my admission for the privilege. We have no more business supporting
art precisely because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s art is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s trash.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Art" Does Not Equal</ENAMEX> "Beauty"

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Bartlett</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oct 1</ENAMEX>

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> and dung are certainly (and
certainly intentionally) inflammatory, I think there's a bigger and older issue
still unresolved. Namely, that the art world thinks that the purpose of art is
to expand the boundaries of human perception and to confront our cultural
limitations while hoi polloi would be far more likely to define it as to render
beauty with skill.

            Until <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> manage to convince the
great unwashed that beauty and skill are irrelevant (or even antagonistic) to
art, we will have these contretemps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year or two</TIMEX>.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Intrusive</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Literary Devices</ENAMEX>

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jon</ENAMEX>
Ihle

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""



            
               Date: Thu
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sept</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>

            So a literary device fails if it is intrusive,
destroys the illusion of transparency and calls attention to itself as a
construct? Like the final scene of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Winter's Tale</ENAMEX> , or the last speech
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tempest</ENAMEX> ? This standard for literary achievement would also
discredit any work in the modernist tradition--for example <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brecht</ENAMEX>'s and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckett's</ENAMEX> plays. You might also have to dump a few classics on the order of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paradise Lost or Tristram Shandy</ENAMEX> .

            It is only a very narrow and very recent tradition
in literature that demands we prop up the notion that art should resemble life
as closely as possible and in all its probabilities. This doctrine of
expressive realism is a nineteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> notion that most historically aware
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have moved beyond. At least <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> isn't pretending, like most
traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX>, that he is in command of some untainted objectivity
beyond authorial presence or beyond fiction. The subjectivity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is
indelible--at least <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> has the guts to expose it.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Normal" Weather</ENAMEX>?

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McKibben</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: Mon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sept</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>

            I thought Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s article was very funny. But I
think he is factually incorrect on the question of whether severe storms are
increasing. Across this hemisphere, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> at the National
inches of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rainfall</ENAMEX> in a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> period--are up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20 percent</NUMEX> compared with
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> average. That's an enormous increase in a baseline physical
phenomenon; it's as if you woke up and everyone was suddenly <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven feet</NUMEX> tall.
It begs for explanation, and the most plausible explanation, according to the
climatologists, is global warming.

            Warm air holds more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> than cold air. Hence, a
warmed environment (and we've seen the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten warmest years</TIMEX> on record since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>)
will see both more aridity (due to increased evaporation) and precipitation
(when those clouds finally let loose). This may make me a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greeniac</ENAMEX>, but I think
it actually makes me more like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX>. If you add more heat energy to a
confined space--the atmosphere--that energy is going to express itself, and one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> it will do so is with increased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rainfall</ENAMEX> and storminess.

            (To reply, click here .)

         
      
   
