
   
   
      
         
            Who <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Were Those Masked Men</ENAMEX>?

            Here is a sampling of improbable movie moments from
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 1999</TIMEX>: A young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> takes a sudden notion to hump an apple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>; a
gargantuan crocodile inexplicably migrates from its tropical habitat to set up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> in a frigid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> lake; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed documentarians</ENAMEX>, being stalked in
the woods by a furry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch</ENAMEX>, never stops filming and videotaping themselves even
as they are supposedly jumping out of their skins with terror; the search for
an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> cure leads to the inadvertent creation of oversized mako sharks
with brains so enhanced they are able to apply the principles of hydraulic
engineering to their deadly advantage, to say nothing of operating commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> equipment.

            All these scenes have earned their place in the
annals of inanity, but nothing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Pie</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Placid</ENAMEX> ,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project , or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deep Blue Sea</ENAMEX> could rival an early
scene in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> where a silver-haired <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> smoothie dancing
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX> purrs into her ear, "I'm delighted to meet you, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alice</ENAMEX>. Did
you ever read the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ovid</ENAMEX> on the art of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">love?</ENAMEX>"

            The chances of meeting a
sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> who would fall for a line like
that are about as remote as encountering a singing possum in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> continues to flirt with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX> during the longest and
most excruciating dance scene in movie history. OK, OK, she is drunk,
having just chug-a-lugged a glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> off a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">waiter</ENAMEX>'s tray, but
why is she drunk? There is no motivation behind her furious
determination to get soused at this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>; in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> seems
to exist in a motivation-free environment all its own.

            Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have been chewing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide</ENAMEX>
Shut for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, its reality problems are so severe that I have decided to
call myself in as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX>. Let me state at the outset that I am not one to
deny a master such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX> all the logical wiggle room he needs
(never once have I complained about the majestic incomprehensibility of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Odyssey</ENAMEX> ), and I am perfectly aware that there is a case to
be made that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> is a masterpiece of dreamy and purposeful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distortion</ENAMEX>. But after sitting through it twice, I must report that the stronger
case is that it's just a really dumb movie.

            The longest stretch of
Eyes Wide Shut features <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Harford</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX>) on an endless
nocturnal prowl, perturbed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s needling confession that she once had
a sexual fantasy about a naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> she saw in a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>. Walking the
lonely <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of not-quite-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (the movie was filmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>), Harford
is accosted by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yahoos</ENAMEX> who harass him for being a "faggot." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>?
There's no discernible reason why they should suspect him of, as they put it,
"playing for the pink <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>." Certainly the snugglesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> he encounters
on the next block has no such impression when she invites him into her
charmingly messy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. "Don't worry," she says, "I don't keep track of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>"--a singularly carefree strategy for a volume business.

            B ut it's what happens to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harford</ENAMEX> after he leaves the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prostitute</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> that forms the bewildering centerpiece of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide</ENAMEX>
Shut . A former medical school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX>-turned-lounge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> tips him off
to an exclusive orgy, one that requires a password and must be attended in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tuxedo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hooded cape</ENAMEX>, and carnival mask. Harford procures these items from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX> of a surreal costume <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and then takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> to a wooded estate.
Upon uttering the password his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> has revealed to him, he is escorted into
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> where some sort of high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> dressed in red is swinging incense and
rapping a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> on the marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> as lugubrious choral music drones on in the
background. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> is surrounded by a circle of masked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who, upon his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">command</ENAMEX>, doff their cloaks, kneel reverentially for a while longer in their
G-strings, and then are sent off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Their sacred mission: to get it on
with the male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party-goers</ENAMEX>, all of whom are still wrapped in their own cloaks
and whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> are hidden under studiously grotesque masks.

            "You don't belong here," one of these altar girls
says as she takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. How does she know? Later in the movie it will
be revealed that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> has met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harford</ENAMEX> before, when he treated her for a
drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overdose</ENAMEX> at the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was dancing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungarian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX>. But how does she recognize him here? In his mask and hood he's
indistinguishable from everyone else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

            "You are in great
danger," she persists as he escorts her down a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>. When he asks why she is
telling him this, she responds, "It doesn't matter," and when he asks who she
is she says, "You don't want to know."

            Soon this unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is called away on other business,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harford wanders</ENAMEX> alone through the many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>, observing an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">orgy</ENAMEX> as elaborate and stylized as the mating dance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attwater</ENAMEX> prairie
chicken. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Begowned</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men escort</ENAMEX> slinky naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> down endless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX>, with
weary disinterest they observe isolated tableaux of coupling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and, when
their frenzy reaches a crescendo, they engage in joyless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballroom</ENAMEX> dancing.
Danger, indeed, seems to lurk in every corner.

            Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harford</ENAMEX> is found to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interloper</ENAMEX>. Unmasked
at an impromptu <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>, he is ordered to take off his clothes.

            "No," cries his helpful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX>, dramatically
reappearing on the balcony above them. "Take me! I am ready to redeem him!"

            She is hauled away,
presumably to be killed. Why is she sacrificing her life? All they've asked him
to do is remove his clothes at an orgy, which seems not unreasonable.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harford</ENAMEX> is allowed to leave, though he is given a stern
warning: "If you make any further inquiries, there will be the most dire
consequences for you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harford</ENAMEX> makes further inquiries. He travels around
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, obtaining information by flashing his medical license to waitresses
and hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>. "I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>," he announces, as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are required to
speak to him under penalty of law. The "dire consequences" spoken of earlier
amount to the following: a brusquely worded note, a rude stare from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>,
and the apparent confiscation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harford</ENAMEX>'s carnival mask, which results in a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> replacement fee.

            Who is behind all this
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">mischief?</ENAMEX> "If I told you their names," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sydney Pollack</ENAMEX>, playing a
mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> who befriends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harford</ENAMEX>, "I don't think you'd sleep so
well."

            OK, so they're really scary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. They may even have
actually killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, who Harford, flashing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> badge
again, has discovered lying dead from an overdose in a mortuary drawer. But why
would they go to such extreme lengths to cover up their romps in the first
place? They don't appear to be doing anything particularly illegal, and with
their liturgical solemnity they seem far less a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic</ENAMEX> than,
say, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Finley</ENAMEX> performance piece or happy hour at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hooters</ENAMEX>. Wouldn't it
make more sense just to offer <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Harford</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> to the haunted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">club</ENAMEX>?

            "You've been out of your depth <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last 24 hours</TIMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollack</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> says. Harford, resigned and weary, returns home, only to
discover the missing mask on the bed next to his sleeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. Who put it
there? That's the question that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX> no doubt intended us to ask each other
late into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>, just as we once endlessly pondered the meaning of the
black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monolith</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> . But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> was a mystery, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide</ENAMEX>
Shut , for all its atmospheric high-mindedness, is just a muddle.

         
      
   
