
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Crisis Management&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "I didn't even
want to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate-chip cookies</ENAMEX>, really. I shaved my beard and
stopped wearing hats." Who said this about what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 269</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coaching Staff":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sometime Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX> will take off her crown, put
on a purple and green dress in a thistle pattern, and step into her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriage</ENAMEX>.
Where's she going?
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slumming?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Defevers</ENAMEX>
            

            "Even
farther back in time."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To</ENAMEX>
the guillotine."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Kurtz</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Another one of those suspiciously long 'lunches' with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To</ENAMEX>
kick off her bid for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat. 'In my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, we've always rooted
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>,' said the queen. 'Well, except for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George III</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Martin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Mnookin</ENAMEX> had similar
answers.)

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Many responses pivoted
on the amusing contrast between uptown swells and downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">schlubs</ENAMEX>, but this
reliable device, the mighty comic engine that generated so many terrific
Depression-era comedies and dimwitted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lampoon</ENAMEX> movies--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snobs</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slobs</ENAMEX>--is as false and anachronistic as the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capra</ENAMEX> movie. The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct worlds of upper-class and lower-class culture have merged into a
single megaworld of pop culture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> doesn't yearn for
the violin virtuoso; she wants the rocker. It was not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavarotti</ENAMEX> who sang at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s funeral, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX>. And even if it had been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavarotti</ENAMEX>, he'd
have brought along the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tenors, assuming they could get time off from
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> commitments and their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> bookings. In the romantic comedies of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'30s</NUMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Happened One Night , My Man Godfrey</ENAMEX> --the wan,
indifferent upper-class beauty is humanized by her contact with ordinary
working-class life, but those days are over. In modern romantic
comedy-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> --we're meant to applaud the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heroine</ENAMEX>'s rise from working-class to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class, with the confidence that she
can still listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX>. It's the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One World</ENAMEX>, and its
pseudosophisticated anthem is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You're the Top</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deeply Held Nationalist</ENAMEX>
Yearnings Answer
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> the queen went to the opening of the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Parliament</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 300 years</TIMEX>.

            Although the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots MPs</ENAMEX> took an oath of
allegiance to the queen, there was no singing of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God Save the Queen</ENAMEX>," but they
did sing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Burns</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Man's a Man for A' That</ENAMEX>."

            An old hand at this sort
of thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX> opened the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh Assembly</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 26</TIMEX>. The opening of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West 94 th St. Parliament</ENAMEX> will take place in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> as soon as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> arrives. We won't sing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God Save the Queen</ENAMEX>," we will sing Gershwin
favorites.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jew du Jour</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the nicest things about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>--along with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uma Thurmond</ENAMEX>, knishes, and irony--is its traditional lack of proselytizing
zeal. But the arrival in the mail of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flier</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society for the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advancement of Judaism</ENAMEX> may force me to rethink my proselytizing position. Some
highlights:

            

               Reassuring words on the cover: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Meaning</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Tradition"</ENAMEX>--each,
as I recall, a particularly moving song in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fiddler</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roof</ENAMEX> .

               Disconcerting words on the cover: "modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>," which, for my money, is
the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> magazine, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> journey," which generally meant
stopping a lot so my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Rose</ENAMEX> could reject another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esso</ENAMEX> station <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">restroom</ENAMEX> for
falling short our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s traditional standard of cleanliness. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>. A
lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> journey. You <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> OK back there? You want another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peach</ENAMEX> or maybe a nectarine?

               Disconcerting jargon inside: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adults</ENAMEX> can "enhance their relationships to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX> in a dynamic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of learners." I'm no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, but they're
talking about some kind of group sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swingers cult</ENAMEX> thing, right?

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAJ</ENAMEX> is run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Julie Schonfeld</ENAMEX> who, we are told, graduated from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>. Not just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>, an Ivy League <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rabbi</ENAMEX>--which, coincidentally, is next
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summer</ENAMEX>'s big teen comedy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX>. (Some mix-up
over the rights.)

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Schonfeld</ENAMEX>'s most impressive credential: "taught playwriting with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Shakespeare Festival</ENAMEX>." It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Wasserstein</ENAMEX> rewrite of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jazz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX> . Which path will <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Schonfeld</ENAMEX> choose--<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> or God's way,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cats</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katz</ENAMEX>?

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conflict Resolution in the Bible</ENAMEX>." Sounds good. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> factor in the decline
of the labor movement is its unwillingness to use stoning as a bargaining
technique. No stoning and very little smiting. Except the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>.

               The "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Experiential Hebrew School</ENAMEX>" offers various programs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, so
good that "Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> won't want to leave!" OK, now I'm sure about that cult
thing. And I like it!

               Also for der <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinder</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Ethics</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Fiction</ENAMEX>." Ah, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and their rigorous traditions of scholarship. I smell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>
money.

               Recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAJ</ENAMEX> projects include "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish Environmentalism</ENAMEX>." Please make up your
own joke. ( You send 'em, I'll run 'em. )

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX>, hell.

         
      
   
