
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999>Wine Whine</SPAN></SPAN>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover editorial applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welch</ENAMEX> and the management trend of "creative destruction" he popularized.
Creative destruction creates tauter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that can quickly respond to
market changes. ... In an essay , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> urges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to reach a consensus that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> should intervene anywhere
human rights are being abused, regardless of territorial boundaries. ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winemaking</ENAMEX> is being corrupted by numerical review ratings, according to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> . Vintners are providing unrepresentative
samples to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> the system and underproducing good but low-rated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  New
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX>
            

            An
education cover package. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> article argues for vouchers and disputes studies
critical of them. Private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> do not skim off the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from
struggling public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and voucher <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are not suspended at higher
rates. ... A piece touts the benefits of charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Studies
indicate that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,684</NUMEX> charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are providing a better education to the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350,000</NUMEX> public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> they serve. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> studies suggest that charter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> also stimulate conventional public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to innovate and improve.
... Online continuing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> education programs are a rip-off,
according to an article : Brand-name bricks-and-mortar universities
receive lots of revenue from them, but the quality of instruction is poor.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 19</TIMEX>
               
            

            In the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six millennium</TIMEX> issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> depict <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> with predictably
burlesque results. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cockroaches devouring</ENAMEX> a tomato
symbolizes the destruction of the new world by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> conquistadors.
... The environmental consequences of the industrial
revolution are caricatured by a picture of a bear and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">coyote tethered</ENAMEX>, like
cliffhanger heroines, to a pile of logs in the path of an oncoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>.
... A collage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> costumed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medici</ENAMEX> together with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> outside a fairytale <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> represents the way "culture rode the
coattails of money" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story marvels at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> phenomenon. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">best-selling British</ENAMEX> book series about an orphan who transcends the tedium of
suburban life through his adventures as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizard</ENAMEX>-in-training has enchanted both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. In upcoming books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> will take an interest in girls,
and the villain will kill a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX> books.) ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> trails <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> around his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. He shows
off his basketball trophies and his black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little League</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20</TIMEX>
            

            A
special issue examining "the dawn of e-life" rehashes
conventional wisdom on the transformative potential of the Internet:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> will be revolutionized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and
by online auctions that enable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to sell oddball items to distant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> or bid for services from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with excess inventory. E-mail is making the workplace more egalitarian by enabling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">minions</ENAMEX> to send suggestions to higher-ups. Campaigns are using the Internet as an organizational and
fund-raising tool.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
20
            

            In a
late addition to the media fuss about the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> anniversary of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s resignation, the cover
story highlights his achievements, including creating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX>, increasing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits, opening <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and
seeking détente with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
                discounts claims
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> has been rehabilitated in ".") ... An article reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> eliminated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a fraction of the</TIMEX>
mobile targets it claimed were destroyed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s withdrawal of
support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and the bombing of power grids and transportation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are what really caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> to cave.

            

               
                  The
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20</TIMEX>
            

            The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" special issue lionizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elsa Klensch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, who
was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to "bring cameras to the catwalks" and force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> to
explain their clothes for a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. Unlike fashion magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, she
doesn't accept freebies from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> in exchange for product placement.
... An essay celebrates the emergence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nobrow</ENAMEX> culture. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX>-marketing of well-designed consumer products collapses the distinction
between highbrow and lowbrow. Now we are all "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>." ...
An article warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> might be massing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to brutally
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">subdue Montenegro</ENAMEX>, the democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> struggling to separate
itself from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1999</TIMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> tops the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s annual ranking of the new media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>,
followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sumner Redstone</ENAMEX>. ... In an interview, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> details his overdue midlife crisis: divorce, a move to a
downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX>, a nubile new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and an avowed attempt to dress like
his twentysomething <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>. ... A book excerpt condemns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pius XII</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>," for his complicity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Solution</ENAMEX>. Before ascending to
the papacy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eugenio Pacelli</ENAMEX> neutered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> opposition to
Nazism, campaigned to remove black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhineland</ENAMEX>, and
contemptuously declined to help persecuted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, he placated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>,
never protested the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, and didn't complain when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were sent
to certain death.

            

               
                  Talk
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1999</TIMEX>
            

            A
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Taylor</ENAMEX> focuses on her bizarre relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>,
who showed up to meet the diva for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time holding his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chimp</ENAMEX>'s hand. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloved One</ENAMEX> adoringly describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> as "a warm, cuddly blanket that I love to
... cover myself with." ... A self-congratulatory <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-page spread
celebrates the Talk launch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>: "In the distance, beneath Madame
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty</ENAMEX>, feline <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Moss</ENAMEX>, fearsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX>, bronze-bodied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brosnan</ENAMEX>." ... A profile peels away <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gomer Pyle</ENAMEX> exterior
to reveal the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s Machiavellian core. He ruthlessly spread
rumors about the sanity of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> when he sought to take her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state Senate</ENAMEX> seat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> is finally blessing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> candidacy of Mayor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>, but only because he is maneuvering for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>-presidential nomination.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20</TIMEX>
            

            In a
review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> revisionist books, the cover
story rethinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. Intervention was necessary
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> could not abandon a nation resisting communism. Had
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> maintained its support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> would not have collapsed. ... An editorial worries that the election of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is no
sure thing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fatigue will be a less compelling reason to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> wins the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> run
would undercut <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s support.

            

               
                  The
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story condemns schoolhouse commercialism. Sponsored
educational materials ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to count <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tootsie Rolls</ENAMEX> or plan how many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domino</ENAMEX>'s pizzas are needed for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. Districts lease advertising space in
school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX> and collect a percentage of vending machine revenues.
... A poem explains why mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> wish to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevent Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> from bolting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Folks</ENAMEX> who hate what's
foreign/ And like their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors white</ENAMEX>/ Are vital to the party/ In any race
that's tight."

         
      
   
