
   
   
      
         
            Getting Personal

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Re your asinine
column, are you always such a self-righteous snob?
            

            

               --VP
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear V</ENAMEX>,

            Pretty much.

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I thank you! No
matter how heavy the cares of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, your witty responses evoke hearty
laughter in most instances, and thus a lighter spirit. You are positively a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">riot</ENAMEX> and a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> to boot!
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, honestly
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mic</ENAMEX>,

            There's a small
difference of opinion here ... but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, in her wisdom, has decided you are a
more reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Marry me! Well, not
really, because I already am. But really, the was stellar. Oh well, if we're
not destined for matrimony in this lifetime, perhaps circumstances will someday
allow me to buy you a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dr Pepper</ENAMEX> or something. Your job must be fun, and
all the more so because you do it so well.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biggest Fan</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike C.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Big</ENAMEX>,

            Oh, stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> ... and
both named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is blushing.

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Do you make this up,
or do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually write to you about stupid, everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>? Prudie must
tear her hair out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> dealing with the petty moral dilemmas your clueless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> experience. God love ya!
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               Fan From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Fan</ENAMEX>,

            Pause for a moment and
contemplate the possibilities for chaos in the human condition, then question
no more the authenticity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX>. How wonderful that you are
not beset by stupid everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> and petty moral dilemmas. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> no doubt wish they had all your clues.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, with all her hair

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               You are getting
older by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the minute</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> soon you will be looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as old as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> (see the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX> column), and it may be your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, so don't lose the
information, dearie. You will want it soon.
            

            

               --Snowtop
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Snow</ENAMEX>,

            So noted.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hey,</ENAMEX>
Prue,
               
            

            
               Please pass along to
"Ricespring" my deep appreciation of the sentiment expressed and my full
agreement, along with bemusement. I believe the most unsettling image currently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extant</ENAMEX> in popular culture is that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> under the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>. I
don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should be allowed to view this ad. The craggy old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pervert</ENAMEX> is just plain scary, particularly when he smiles that
beyond-the-grave--and now sexually aroused--smile. No wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liddy</ENAMEX> spends so
much time hoofing it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               --Wolfman
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Wolf</ENAMEX>,

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> checked in
to say that they applauded the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s forthright approach to a real
problem. The following <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, however, was not one of them.

            

               
                  Prudie,
               
            

            
               Not to belabor the
point, but I have often thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX> had better put a pillow over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> if she expects to be elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. I am so sick of his whining and
sniveling over his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. You know, there are a lot of single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX> in
this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> who manage to stay happy without the constant focus on erections.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> for you to get a life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>. Try reading ... or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate cake</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
sock it to 'em!
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott W.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Scott</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is going to
change the subject, though to stay in the moment, the next letter is political,
as well.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, oh,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wise One,</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               What's up with that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neanderthal Jerry Springer</ENAMEX> having contemplated running for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>? (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>!) I was shocked that such a thing could even be a possibility. I share
the sentiments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> who said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Was Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> busy?" Say it's all a goof.
            

            

               --Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Resident</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Poor</ENAMEX>,

            It is, indeed,
dispiriting that someone with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springer</ENAMEX>'s history might have been considered
simply because of name recognition. There is precedent, however, and it is
regrettably recent. "Dubya," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, has no particular
qualifications aside from being merely appealing and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was elected when he was known to be irresponsible. And don't forget
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, of whom it could be said he wasn't really a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> but played
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on television. We are seemingly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> for "charisma" and exercising an
electoral death wish.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, resignedly

         
      
   
