
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Choking on Family Ties</ENAMEX>

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About 10 years ago</TIMEX>, after growing up in a
family without an appreciation of "family values," I decided I didn't have much
use for my relationships with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are deceased, and after
numerous efforts to get along with my sibs, I just quit having any contact with
them. This has alleviated a lot of stress in my life, and I really don't miss
them at all. I have a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> whom I consider my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. They
are there for me like my actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> never were, and they understand the
lack of contact.
            

            
               The problem is that
I run into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who, after knowing me for a while, are dumbfounded to find
out I am not an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, and they act like there's something wrong with me
because I'm not in contact with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX>. I keep hearing, "But they are your
family!" I just figure I feel better mentally without the connection, and I
should keep things the way they are. But all these "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think I
should call and reconcile with them. Is there something wrong with me? Just
because I'm related to them, am I really missing something by not having them
in my life?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               Happy Without
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Hap</ENAMEX>,

            Yes, you are missing something: Sturm und
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drang</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thought this one through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> because of a kindred
situation, though not with your particulars. If a relationship is troublesome
or destructive for whatever reason, and it's comfortable to sever
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>, there is no reason to stay yoked to a bad situation as though
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> were part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of mules.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is familiar with
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>" offering the advice that you should just fix it up. Perhaps, in
your case, it would be simpler to tell new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that you are an only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> ... because that is what you've made yourself, and this would end the
awkward conversations. Nowhere is it written that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the same mother
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> have anything more in common than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who push the
issue belong in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for the intrusive.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, experientially

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have been dating a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who, unlike myself, still resides under the watchful eye of his parental
unit. Although his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are very open and mostly mind their own business,
there is one issue that leaves me in a tight spot. Coming from a conservative
background, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> has stated on many occasions that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> won't
allow him to stay over at my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, even though on some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> this would
be preferable to his making the long drive home. We have been camping numerous
times but always with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> "approve of." Trying to plan a
weekend getaway for our anniversary has been particularly trying, as his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would be upset, and he refuses to lie to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> about where he is
going. Should I push the issue, or just let sleeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> lie and wait for him
to act like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and make his own decisions?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               Trouble in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> (well, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Trub</ENAMEX>,

            You don't say how old you both are, but you're
clearly old enough to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> together ... and obviously have. Prudie
is getting definite vibes that your young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s "parental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>" comes with
strong apron strings.

            You have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> options.
You can insist that your fella--whom I presume to be over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>--sit his parents
down and tell them about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX>. It seems to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are free to follow their own moral code, but so is he. If they invite
him out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, that might not be such a bad idea. If he is unwilling
to stand up to them and assert himself, then perhaps, to use your phrase, he
should lie, alone, with the sleeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> ... I mean the parental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, autonomously

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               The end of the world
must be nigh. There was a news story about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> who paid
for their <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34,000</NUMEX> wedding by selling advertising space at the ceremony and
reception! Everything, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>, "from the wedding rings to a week
at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">penthouse</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cancun</ENAMEX>" was donated after the groom got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to
sponsor the nuptials in exchange for having their names appear <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times--from
the invitations to the thank you notes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> drew the line at having
advertising banners draped across the aisle, but her perfume came from a local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar de la Renta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> was provided gratis from a
neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX>. Well, you get the idea. What do you think of all
this?
            

            

               --Brooksie
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Brooks</ENAMEX>,

            Gauche, gauche, gauche,
and tacky. This cannot be the wave of the future, though, so calm yourself.
This is just the act of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tasteless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clods</ENAMEX> who fancy themselves "business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">minded</ENAMEX>." Prudie hesitates to think of when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> arrives ... so she
won't.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, gapingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I would like your
take on workplace etiquette concerning paychecks and benefits. I am beginning
to wonder if these are things we earn or gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>. Currently, I work
for a law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, but I have had this experience with every job I've had in my
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20-plus</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of working--even when I worked as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Employers</ENAMEX> act like
it's taboo or in bad form to speak of paychecks, as in, "Are the checks in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (on pay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>)?" Are we supposed to just keep checking our mailbox or under
our desk blotters to see if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> was good to us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>? What's with this
hush-hush attitude when it comes to being compensated for a job well
done?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin Cities</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Twin</ENAMEX>,

            You must be the queen of
coincidence to have worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 20 years</TIMEX> at different places where the
delivery of paychecks was erratic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would suggest that you go to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office manager</ENAMEX> where you work now, or whoever writes the checks, and ask that
the time for their distribution be regularized. You need not be shy. If anyone
tries to close you down, or makes you feel as though your are talking about
things best left unspoken, just tell that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> assertively that if you are
interested in guessing games you will pull out your Ouija <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks
if you make an issue of it you will get results.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, huffily

         
      
   
