
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spiritual Void</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s banning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> Law) religious sect was strongly
condemned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an
editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is facing more than enough crises
already, from the economy to relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, and it should focus on
these problems rather than "launch a massive crackdown against a group which
has never done anything more harmful than organise peaceful protests." The rise
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> is a byproduct of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s new materialism, it said. "The collapse
of the ideological basis for communist rule in the rush towards a free-market
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> has left a spiritual void. It is inevitable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thrown out of
work or otherwise unsettled by the sweeping changes on the mainland should seek
solace in some form of religious-like activity. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> should consider
itself fortunate that the popular desire for spiritual inspiration took such a
benign form." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX>'s only sin was to build a mass organization
independent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>. "This is something the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> is still
not prepared to tolerate. For all the changes that have taken place in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s arrests were a reminder of how far freedom of expression
remains curtailed on the mainland." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were arrested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ji Liewu</ENAMEX>, a mainland
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">40s</NUMEX> who was responsible for bringing the sect to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>.

            
Announcing the ban <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX> said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sect</ENAMEX> had engaged in illegal activities: advocating superstition and spreading
fallacies, hoodwinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, inciting and creating disturbances, and
jeopardizing social stability. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Ministry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spokeswoman Zhang Qiyue</ENAMEX> as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> had been banned because it
had not been registered in the manner required by law. She also claimed that
the sect had a declining membership of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 2 million</NUMEX>, while other estimates
have put it <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as high as 100 million</NUMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> urgently pressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> to
make implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wye River</ENAMEX> accord his top priority and to carry out
agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> pullbacks from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> administration
decided to go easy on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> postponing a planned
telephone conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez Assad</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> that "an air of suspicion is clouding the whole issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX>"
and that "before this suspicion becomes mythology, it must be dispelled and
understanding must be reached."

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> featured an interview with former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>, who has been under house arrest for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> awaiting the
outcome of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s request that he be extradited and tried there for murder,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">torture</ENAMEX>, and other human rights violations. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> interview
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> has given since his arrest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, was with the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> , which opposes his
extradition. The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , by contrast, wants to see him tried,
and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, a former human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>, noted that his fingers are
"flat and meaty like those of a butcher." The general's answers in both
interviews were almost identical. He categorically denied all charges against
him and complained about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s treatment of him. "I wasn't in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> as a
common bandit," he said, in reference to his arrest. "I was here as a
diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> and had been welcomed as such."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, the Frankfurter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNICEF</ENAMEX> report that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are
now born in poverty than ever before, and the paper discussed the growing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
catastrophe in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are infected with the disease.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> led on a new
birth control patch, developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson & Johnson</ENAMEX>, which it said would
offer strong competition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> when it is put on the market <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SÃ</ENAMEX>¼ddeutsche
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitung</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> led on a new drive by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to get
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> admitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, provided its human rights record is
acceptable.

         
      
   
