
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999>The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oddest Men in the World</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegfried</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX></SPAN></SPAN>

            

               
                  
                     
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
                     
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17</TIMEX>
            

            Not
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> editorials compare <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatami</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX> must muffle his reformist impulses in order to
avoid provoking hard-line <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. The first piece cautions him against alienating his core
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, but the other predicts that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> will survive the
current uprising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who toppled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shah</ENAMEX> were both more alienated
and better organized than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s lot. ... The next <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> war will take
place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montenegro</ENAMEX>, predicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. The tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> is itching to
secede from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>, chary of further destabilizing the
region, are urging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montenegrins</ENAMEX> to bide their time.

            

               
                  
                     
                        New
                      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story complains about the pathologizing of normal
personality traits, a tactic used by pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to drum up
business. The latest example: the classification of shyness as "social anxiety
disorder." <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> underwrite research into "social phobia" and stoke
public hysteria with slogans such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Imagine Being Allergic to People</ENAMEX>." If
you, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donny Osmond</ENAMEX>, are among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-in-8 distressingly diffident <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
a new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> can treat you. ... An article condemns the simplistic and snide cultural coverage in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , which is corrupted by commercialism and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
obsession with reporting news. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> covers what <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> might have
done for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy Loman</ENAMEX> rather than the artistic significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Salesman</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1999</TIMEX>
            

            A
profile of eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> animal illusionists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegfried</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> describes
life inside their "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jungle Palace</ENAMEX>" on the fringes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. It is nearly
impossible to convey how breathtakingly weird they are. They live with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tigers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> sleeps with the young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Siegfried</ENAMEX>
has a mural of himself naked, with cheetahs, on his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> walls. They greet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sarmoti</ENAMEX>"--an acronym for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegfried</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX> of the
Impossible." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> deflect the question of whether they are gay but do
claim a friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>. Still, they draw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a year
to their stage show. ... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX> traces her
career as a manipulative, self-destructive femme fatale . After she
failed at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> marriages and at attempts to leverage wealth and connections
into a career as a political powerbroker, she wed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelman</ENAMEX>. Now
that marriage is kaput, and she has run through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> during the divorce
and custody proceedings, and is now battling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perelman</ENAMEX> over issues such as
whether <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36,000</NUMEX> is an adequate annual clothing allowance for her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-year-old</TIMEX>.
... An article on celebrated death-row <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mumia Abu-Jamal</ENAMEX>
condemns his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> for ignoring the clear evidence of his guilt.

            
               
                  
                     
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX>,
                      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 18</TIMEX>
               
            

            The
cover story explains how a con <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> peddled 200 forgeries of modern masters
through top auction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Drewe</ENAMEX> "authenticated" paintings by
infiltrating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> archives and inserting documents about artworks'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">provenance</ENAMEX>. This scheme corrupted art history and undermined the reputations of
auction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, whose "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>" sold some obvious fakes. ...
An article describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX> began confusing himself with his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>. While living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, he formed a spy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> and even
hunted for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> subs in his fishing boat. His writing never recovered after
this series of misadventures.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX>
            

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> celebrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> win. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
cover
story says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soccer Mama</ENAMEX>" mania was carefully orchestrated by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sport</ENAMEX>'s steering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> and sponsors such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> but that the enormous
crowds shocked even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> cover story reveals
the gender-specific coaching strategy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> women's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. Assuming that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> internalize tough criticism, the male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> tried positive reinforcement
instead. He tacked inspirational quotes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>' doors, emphasized what each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> did right, and provided an "imaging" tape for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, consisting of
her best moves set to her favorite music.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> special
report revises the conventional wisdom about which <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> are good for the
heart. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cholesterol</ENAMEX> isn't necessarily unhealthy, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">margarine</ENAMEX> is as bad as
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>. Saturated fat is still evil.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> explores how hate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are exploiting the Internet to recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Online games, comic strips,
and downloadable music, such as "Go Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>," entice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. White
supremacists are developing their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmasters</ENAMEX> to spread their message on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> explains a new musical hybrid: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock 'n' rap</ENAMEX>, a k a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hick</ENAMEX>-hop," in which white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Limp Bizkit</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kid Rock</ENAMEX> combine
hard rock with the violent themes and outlaw imagery of rap.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX>
            

            An
analysis
suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is just dimwitted enough to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
factual errors on the campaign trail are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reaganesque</ENAMEX>, underscoring that he is
not a detail-oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">drone</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. ... The cover story ranks
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. The top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> are: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayo Clinic</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX>. ... An article agrees
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s poverty tour brought necessary attention to the
genuine suffering of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Appalachia</ENAMEX> but argues that his package of investment
incentives is not an economically efficient way to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX>
            

            A
piece calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s campaign kickoff "cunning" and "brilliantly
staged." The cover cartoon, however, depicts her as a tourist ambling through
Central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Park</ENAMEX>, about to be mugged by a truncheon-wielding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>.
... An article explains how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Business School</ENAMEX> has remade itself
from corporate prep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> into entrepreneurial boot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. New offerings
include a course titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Women Building Business</ENAMEX>" and field trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">startups</ENAMEX>. ... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cuomo</ENAMEX> argues that he has
brought his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX>'s brand of liberal zeal and moral grandeur to his post

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story
declares that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is in the midst of a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay Moment</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homosexuals</ENAMEX> are
demanding cultural attention, and the debate over homosexuality has shifted
from morality to "is he or isn't he?" Pro- and anti-gay polemicists debate the
sexual proclivities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jar Jar Binks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Lincoln</ENAMEX>. (To read

                  Slate
               's authoritative evaluation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX>'s sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">orientation,</ENAMEX> click .) ... A piece asks where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> stands on affirmative action. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> says he wants to
eliminate racial preference but to guarantee "affirmative access." His record
is equally wishy-washy. Even so, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delphic</ENAMEX> statement of principles might
hoodwink <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> is a deft <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX>. Her "listening
tour" effectively reinforces the perception that she was dragooned into running
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and makes it easier for her to deflect uncomfortable
scandal-related questions. ... The editorial defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> say the veep is doing the bidding of the pharmaceutical
industry by preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Africans</ENAMEX> from obtaining cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. But
evisceration of patent protections could slow the development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> need.

         
      
   
