
   
   
      
         
            Peaceable Pagans

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>
Pru,
               
            

            
               I've got a very
wicked idea about who you really are. I think you're a fat, balding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in his
middle 50s who smokes cigars while reading those heart-rending missives from
perplexed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. Très cool.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick St. T.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Rick</ENAMEX>,

            And what do you plan to
read now that you've finished Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonelyhearts</ENAMEX> ? Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">knockout</ENAMEX>. (And modest, too.)

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, laughingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               What you really need
to tell "" is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wicca</ENAMEX> and paganism are simply other religions. Of course
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> don't believe in evil or worship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX> created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>--so he's their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, not ours. To be evil is to go
against everything you're taught by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiccan</ENAMEX> religion.
            

            

               --Just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concerned</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear Just,

            Talk about toil and
trouble ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> was inundated by lotsa mail on this subject. Interestingly,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wiccan</ENAMEX> mail was friendly, polite, and informative. Blessed be. The few
stinky letters were from clergymen. Go figure.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, bewitchingly

            

               
                  Prudie,
               
            

            
               I recently married a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who is a devout
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon</ENAMEX>. Needless to say, she has spent a fair amount of time trying to convert
me. I believe that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s views on religion, divinity, and so on are
individual. I respect the right of anyone to believe as he or she sees fit, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honestly</ENAMEX>, I find the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Latter Day Saints</ENAMEX> faith a load of dingo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kidneys</ENAMEX>--restrictive, racist, and condemnatory. I also find their attitudes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sanctimonious</ENAMEX> and superior and in line with many fundamentalist "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">faiths</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               So, how do I tell my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">young</ENAMEX> (much younger) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> that I want her to cool down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rah-rah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mormon</ENAMEX> bit?
I love her dearly, but this is driving me nuts.
            

            

               --Alisdair
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Al</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is astounded that you and the little woman
did not discuss this rather loaded subject--on which you differ
profoundly--before the strains of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here Comes the Bride</ENAMEX>" filled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. And
she wonders if resolution will even be possible ... what with the Mrs. trying
to convert you to her religion ... which you view as a load of dingo kidneys.
If you love her dearly, as you say, it will be necessary to reach an agreement,
probably with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX>, whereby you both hew to your own beliefs and do not
discuss them. You might tell the beloved that you have decided to become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
just to end the discussion. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is kidding.)

            It is a storm signal,
however, that you use the words "racist, restrictive, condemnatory,
sanctimonious, and superior" about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s faith and her fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> can only hope that, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterbalance</ENAMEX>, her personal
qualities are "gorgeous, loving, brainy, witty, and rich." Not to be
pessimistic, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> envisions another letter from you down the line.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, worriedly

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am a gay divorced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who also happens to work in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. I am out to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>,
family, and some close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> but am hesitant to come all the way out for fear
of the implications. I do not care what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think about me, but I don't want
to bring any negative publicity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. I love education and would hate
to leave it. I want to find a life <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> to share <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my days</TIMEX> with, but my
current employment prevents me from doing so. I am tired of living in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">closet</ENAMEX> and want to be me without having to live <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lives. Can you
help?
            

            

               --Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mr.</ENAMEX>,

            Closets are for clothes, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lives mean split
personalities. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would encourage you to reorganize your life so that it is
honest. The first thing to try would be to talk with someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> at
your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> about your sexual preference to ask if it poses a problem. The
answer may well be in the affirmative, seeing as how one parochial school
sacked a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> because she was divorced . But this will at least
be a start. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is a little unclear as to why your being gay would bring
publicity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, but only you know why you think this is so.

            Because you say you
would hate to leave the educational field, why not move to a public or private
school if your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> finds homosexuality a problem? Take it from
Prudie, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have gay and lesbian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. It's a percentage
thing. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> wishes you all the best in your private, romantic life.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, openly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> is a really great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
I've ever had. There's just one problem: He whistles incessantly.
            

            
               I find whistling
irritating at best, but it is positively nerve-wracking when I'm trying to
concentrate at work. My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> doors down from his, so there's no
escaping the sound. I've tried to discreetly play music, but it doesn't drown
him out. I've also tried shutting my door, but in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> culture, that's
considered uncomfortably secretive and standoffish. Any ideas on how I can save
my sanity (and my job)?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whistler's Brother</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Whis</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> finds whistling annoying, too. It is an odd
sound and, like chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>, should best be done in private. You may have blown
the problem out of proportion, however. Surely this "really great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>," the
best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> you've ever had, could not be so unreasonable--or thin-skinned--as to
take umbrage at your request for a whistle-free workplace.

            Make your remarks
positive. Tell him, in your own words, that it pleases you that he manifests
such happy feelings, but the musical expression of his joy distracts you and
keeps you from putting out your very best work. A really great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is not going
to react with anything but understanding. Unless he is so dense that light
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bends</ENAMEX> around him, he will accede to your request and be grateful that you spoke
up.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, fearlessly

         
      
   
