
   
   
      
         
             It's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time To Keelhaul U-Haul</ENAMEX>!

            Like all superheroes worthy of the title, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> has an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Achilles</ENAMEX>' heel. In the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>,
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Achilles</ENAMEX>' heel is not animal, vegetable, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mineral</ENAMEX> but something less
tangible.

            An explanation: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the magazine you are
currently reading forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> at gunpoint to read a series of
treacle-filled self-help books, and then to . The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, who can
withstand radiation, extreme heat and cold, hail, bear attacks, and Eyes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wide Shut</ENAMEX> , almost succumbed to terminal jejuneness after reading these
books. Except for one thing: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the books, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Art of Happiness</ENAMEX> ,
which collects and simplifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s philosophy, got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenger</ENAMEX> to thinking. This, in a way, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Achilles</ENAMEX>' heel:
thinking. Perhaps it is wrong, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> thought, to complain about
the petty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insults</ENAMEX> and inconveniences of life in the materialistic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'90s</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> felt that perhaps he should counsel those who write seeking
help to meditate, to accept bad service the way one accepts the change of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seasons</ENAMEX>, and to extend a compassionate hand of forgiveness to those who provide
poor customer care.

            But then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avenger</ENAMEX> sat down, and the feeling passed.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> does not make light of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>
or of the notion that there is more to life than the impatient acquisition of
material goods. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> were not, for a superhero, extremely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonjudgmental</ENAMEX>--as opposed to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alter ego</ENAMEX>, who is considered insufferably
judgmental by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alter ego</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> would tell the
occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> to let go of his petty grievance and get a life.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
also believes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> has never tried to rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>.
If he had tried to rent from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>, he never would have escaped from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>.
(For the complete back story, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shopping Avenger"</ENAMEX> column and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.)

            The complaints about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>'s nonreservation reservation
policy continue to pour in through the electronic mail. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.R.</ENAMEX>, wrote in with this cautionary tale: "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last weekend</TIMEX>, I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> to help my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> move into their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had reserved a moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the big day</TIMEX>. I warned my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>'s 'not really a reservation per se' policy that I learned
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>. He didn't believe such a thing would happen to him,
so he didn't act on my warning."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.R.</ENAMEX> continues--as if you don't know what happened
already--"I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> to get our 'reserved' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">store</ENAMEX> had many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> standing around looking frustrated. When we got to the
front of the line, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> informed us that our 'reserved' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> had not yet
been returned. We asked if we could rent one of the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> sitting idle in
the parking lot. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> laughed and said the keys to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> were
lost."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.R.</ENAMEX> and his chastened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenger</ENAMEX> is resisting the urge to gloat--went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX> had a truck
available for us. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX> who helped us at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX> prides itself
on being everything <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> is not."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> has still not received a call
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johna Burke</ENAMEX> explaining why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haul</ENAMEX> refuses to provide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who reserve <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> is pleased to
note that several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> have written in over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past month</TIMEX> saying
that, based on what they have read in this column, they will be taking their
business to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> or elsewhere.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
will undoubtedly return to the sorry state of affairs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> in the next
episode, but now on to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> debacle.

            Before we begin, though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> nearly forgot
to announce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s contest, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> were asked to
answer the question, "What's the difference between pests and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>?"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>, who wrote, "You can hire someone to kill pests." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle Wax</ENAMEX>, and he will receive his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> just as soon as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> figures out how much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle Wax</ENAMEX> actually constitutes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s
supply. The new contest question: How much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle Wax</ENAMEX> comprises <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s supply
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle Wax</ENAMEX>?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> in the spotlight is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>. Loyal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will recall that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> praised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX> for its "sterling" customer service. This brought forth a small number
of articulate dissensions. The most articulate, and the most troubling, came
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX>, who wrote, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, flying from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> with my entire
family (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> really little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> included), we set down at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX> in a rainstorm.
And waited for our bags. And waited for bags. And waited for bags."

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">An hour later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX> says, the bags showed up, "soaked
through. We took them to baggage services at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SW</ENAMEX> and were faced with the most
complicated, unclear, and confusing mechanism for filing a claim we experienced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flyers</ENAMEX> have ever seen."

            When they arrived at
their destination, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX> and her family made a terrible discovery, "We discovered
that our clothes were soaked through--the top clothes were so wet that the dye
had bled through down to the lower levels, destroying lots of other clothes.
Obviously, our bags had just been sitting out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runway</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>. To
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX>, I've never heard a thing from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SW</ENAMEX>, despite calls and letters."

            This, of course, is where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> steps in.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> knows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> is different from the average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX>, in
that it doesn't go out of its way to infuriate its paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> (see: ), so
I expected a quick and generous resolution to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX>'s problem.

            What I got at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, though, was a load of corporate
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hoo-ha</NUMEX>.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX>'s policy,
which is consistent with all contracts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriage</ENAMEX> at all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, requires
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> file a report in person for lost or damaged luggage within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of arrival at their destination," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rutherford</ENAMEX>, e-mailed me. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX>] indicates she called for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>, but did not
file a report in person until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days later</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>, as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courtesy</ENAMEX>, took her report anyway and asked for follow up information and
written inventory of the damage." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rutherford</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX> should have submitted
detailed receipts and photographs of the damage in order to make a claim.

            Harrumph, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> says. It is a bad hair day
at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> when its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> defend themselves by comparing their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>. I forwarded this message to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX>, who replied:

            "Wow. Well, of course I didn't file it at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9 th</NUMEX> because I didn't know the clothes were ruined at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. I didn't know until I opened the baggage at my hotel and saw the
ruined stuff. (And it's worth noting that we had already waited for about an
hour for our luggage with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and impatient in-laws nipping at our
heels.)"

            She goes on, "I did call that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> ... and was
told that that sufficed. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I've been told that I had to
file a complaint in person within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX>. ... When I filed on the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12 th</NUMEX> , I was never told that I needed any receipts or photos or other
type of documentation. The baggage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> seemed pretty uninterested in all of
this. ... They know that the type of 'evidence' they want is impossible to
obtain. They also know that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 9</TIMEX> they screwed up the luggage retrieval
and left bags out in the rain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>'s response
actually served to anger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX> more than the original problem. "Before, they had a
mildly annoyed but loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> (who would have been placated by an apology
and thrilled with some modest token of their regret). Now they have a
pissed-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>."

            Things do look bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>, don't they? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenger</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX>'s response to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rutherford</ENAMEX>, who e-mailed back saying she thought
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> was asking for "policy information." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
e-mailed back again, stressing to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rutherford</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Court of Consumer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> would, if this case were brought to trial, undoubtedly find for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plaintiff</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> serves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Court of Consumer Justice</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> are represented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>), and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> was precipitously close to feeling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> of
retribution at its neck.

            But then she came through, provisionally, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yep</ENAMEX>, you
can be sure if [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX>] will call me we will get everything squared away. I'm sorry
it's taken this long for her to get someone who can help, but we will take care
of it from here."

            Stay tuned, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>, to
hear whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> makes good it promise to compensate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.</ENAMEX> and apologize to
her for her troubles.

            The story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX> reminds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> of a central
truth of consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>: It's not the crime, it's the cover-up.

            Take the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX>, who found himself waiting in
vain for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX> to repair his television. Televisions break, even
1-year-old televisions, as is the case with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K's</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX>, where he
bought the television, gave him a terrible runaround. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
dispatched his sidekick, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tad</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avenger</ENAMEX>, to get to the bottom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K.</ENAMEX>'s
story. This is what he found: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX> grew concerned, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tad</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avenger</ENAMEX>
reports, after his television had been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>.
When he called, he was told to "check back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>." When he asked if someone
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> could call him with more information, he was refused. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weeks</ENAMEX> went
by. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX> told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> that he really would like to get his
television back, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX> says, asked him, "Don't you have another
television in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>?"

            More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month later</TIMEX>--after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours and hours</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of telephone calls and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> missed at work--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX> received his television
back.

            Mistakes happen, but not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tad</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avenger</ENAMEX>
found out, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX>. The case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX> was told by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>,
was "handled perfectly." Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan Stewart</ENAMEX> in public relations,
assured Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avenger Tad</ENAMEX> that "We got to be a big and successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> by
treating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> better than the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> and his
loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sidekick</ENAMEX> would like to hear from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>: Does
Circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX>, in fact, treat its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> better than the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>?

            Stay tuned for answers.
And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> special: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> screws with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hasidic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rabbi</ENAMEX>'s travel plans, leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> crying at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. Find out
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> can save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> from certain heavenly punishment, in the
next episode.

            
               
                  Got a consumer
score you want settled? Send e-mail to shoppingavenger@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
               
            

         
      
   
