
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blues</ENAMEX>

            One thing that separates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intuitive artists</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>" is their difficulty doing even
mediocre work when their cylinders aren't firing. In the absence of true
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inspiration</ENAMEX>, they can't fall back on a crafty understanding of what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> wants because they don't really know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> wants. They
follow their instincts and pray that they'll connect. When they don't, the
result is something like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Muse</ENAMEX> , which left me more dispirited than
any movie in ages has. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Brooks</ENAMEX> is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, and I don't like the thought
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seeing this dud satire and concluding that he has lost his way. More
to the point, I don't like the thought that he has lost his way.

            At least The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muse</ENAMEX>
tackles this subject <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on--the loss of one's way in a culture as venal as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Phillips</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>), is a middle-aged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> whose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-picture deal is terminated by a callow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feuerstein</ENAMEX>) who tells him he no longer has his "edge." When other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> show
no interest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> goes to cry on the shoulder of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Warrick</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bridges</ENAMEX>), a vastly successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-producer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanned</ENAMEX> and beaming after a
string of recent triumphs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> decides to introduce his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> to his
"muse," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX>)--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of inspiration supposedly descended
from the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>, we learn, played a part in the latest hits of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Reiner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cameron</ENAMEX> (all of whom show up to pay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">homage</ENAMEX> and bring expensive gifts). Although he's incredulous, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> can't
afford to pass up a chance to get his "edge" back, especially with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andie MacDowell</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pacific Palisades</ENAMEX> to maintain. In no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> orders him to put her up in a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,700-</NUMEX>a-night <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> on a high floor
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons</ENAMEX> (she's an ultrasensitive sleeper), provide a limousine, and
be ready to work at whatever hour she feels the urge to inspire him.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first half-hour</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Muse</ENAMEX> plays a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flatly</ENAMEX>, but that's not too troubling--artful flatness has always been a
component of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. The camera stares, unblinking, at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> in
conversation with uncomprehending or contemptuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>. The message is
that there's no escape from the ignominy, not even through the (often <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>)
one-liners he employs to win them over. When he goes for a meeting with "Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> is denied "drive-on" privileges; the camera holds on him as
he makes the long, grueling hike through the studio <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>, and a passing
tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> draws attention to his lowly "walk-on" status. Then he finds
the meeting is with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Spielberg</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scraggly-haired</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Wright</ENAMEX>), who
hasn't seen his famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and doesn't even know what he's
supposed to be doing there. This is familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brooksian</ENAMEX> territory: impotence
prolonged and stylized until it turns into <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater of the Absurd</ENAMEX>. The universe
exists to humiliate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>' protagonists, to remind them of the precariousness
of everything that they'd smugly assumed was fixed--the steadiness of a job,
the permanence of a relationship, the support of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, the benign regard of
the universe.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Muse</ENAMEX> ,
however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">masochism</ENAMEX> feels a little too reflexive, and the picture's flatness
gets flatter by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the minute</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> is baking with dead <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX>. As it turns out,
the movie isn't about the mystery of creativity but rather the New Age idiocy
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who'd accept the idea of a muse--or, by extension, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gurus</ENAMEX> or smart
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or the power of cabala. For some reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> and his co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, have made their protagonist an unbelievably uninteresting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--a
mopey, scattershot hack. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> might disagree. He told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gavin Smith</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film</ENAMEX>
Comment that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> is a "good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> going through the exact period
that tons of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> are. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety-nine percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> write [for
hire]. ... They all get scared when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> become younger than their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; they get worried that they're not going to get those jobs anymore, so
they start writing things that maybe they don't love or they're not close to."
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> hasn't provided any evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> was ever a decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.
His screenplay ideas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of the muse are pathetically feeble, and
when she encourages them--and when they find favor with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> who'd previously spurned him--the point seems to be that
everyone in the film industry is a moron.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>, who is often accused (wrongly) of playing himself,
has left himself too far out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Muse</ENAMEX> . At least I hope he has: How
else to account for this bland, pasty, not terribly funny protagonist? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Life</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Romance</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>) have their jerky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> (emotionally squeamish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> tend
to find them repellent), but they also have compensatory gifts--chiefly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>'
urgent babble, in which pleas are made and then restated and then turned inside
out in a way that brilliantly (and hilariously) distills neurotic thought
processes. His advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost in America</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> insight
into himself, but he's still an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX> who boldly attempts to live out the
escapist fantasies of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>: He has--as buffoons go--enormous stature.
With his next film, Defending Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks</ENAMEX> tried to make his
alter ego more palatable to a mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>--to seem "vulnerable" instead of
"insecure." (See my 
                  Slate
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> movie Mother for
the quotation.) The result was often charming, but the upbeat, go-for-it ending
felt simple-minded. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>' best scenes operate on an X-ray level of honesty,
so that shortcuts, formulas, easy ways out of dramatic jams--stuff that slicker
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmakers</ENAMEX> can get by with--seem in his work embarrassingly exposed.

            
               Lost in

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is a road movie that suggests the impossibility of travel;
perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks</ENAMEX> conceived of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Muse</ENAMEX> as a movie about the creative
spirit that would subversively suggest the impossibility--at least in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>--of creation. That might have worked if his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> showed signs
of having deeper yearnings, the way they do in many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Mazursky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>-set satires, so that there would be some tension between what they
think they want and what they actually need. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in The
Muse are dull-witted materialists, and limp encounter follows limp
encounter until the movie seems populated by pod <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. A hint that something
is off comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> receives a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">humanitarian"</ENAMEX> award. (A nice touch:
It's presented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cybill Shepherd</ENAMEX>, who did some of the most attractive scenes
of her career opposite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi Driver</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> gives a
winning, perhaps too self-deprecating speech, then holds his plaque high and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crows</ENAMEX>, "I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>!" And no one laughs--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> stares at him,
puzzled. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> has spent too much time by himself if he thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> wouldn't get that joke; even the non-English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">busboys</ENAMEX> would be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cackling</ENAMEX>.

            How is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX> at comedy? That's a trick question,
because her best performance, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Instinct</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>), was essentially
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic</ENAMEX> turn--a lusty, glittery-eyed sendup of film noir femmes fatales .
Here she starts promisingly, looking odd and imposing in her caftans,
childishly impervious to the absurdity of her demands. But she's
heavy-spirited, and it isn't long before she runs out of invention and starts
pulling goofy faces--like the one where she sucks a drink through a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> and
rolls her eyes skyward like a distracted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX>. She isn't mercurial enough
to be funny: She's just a narcissistic dope, and you come to feel contempt for
anyone who'd swallow her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bull</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX>'s scenes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacDowell</ENAMEX>--whom she inspires
to bake <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>--are the deadest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> has ever directed, and his own
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacDowell</ENAMEX> are only marginally more lively. (If you want an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> to flesh
out an underwritten <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, don't hire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacDowell</ENAMEX>, who tends to sound as if
she learns her lines phonetically.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bridges</ENAMEX> does a relaxed and confident
turn, but he's acting with his tan. The only scene that completely works is
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Opinato</ENAMEX>) who doesn't understand a word
he says--an exhilarating throwback to the radio-comedy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Einstein</ENAMEX> (also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkyakarcas</ENAMEX>).

            Since I saw The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muse</ENAMEX> , I've been struggling to
figure out why it went so wrong--why the muse deserted the movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>. Has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>, lost his edge? Maybe the reasons aren't so dire. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>
obviously shares his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>'s insecurity about his position in the
industry (in common with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>, he never knows if he'll get the money to make
another film), but the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have little in common where it really
counts--artistically. They barely overlap. From the start, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>' impulses
have taken him to the source of his darkest <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX>. As a stand-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic</ENAMEX>, he
was less interested in jokes than in the desperate, needy impulse behind the
jokes. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, he has been less preoccupied with gags than
with the fear and helplessness out of which they <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>. How could he possibly
be inspired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Phillips</ENAMEX>, who thinks of nothing but writing a summer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blockbuster</ENAMEX> comedy set in a ramshackle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">aquarium</ENAMEX> and starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>? I'm
not saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> doesn't dream of being popular and having status--only
that he'd have to do it his way, working outward from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>. Maybe it's
reassuring that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Muse</ENAMEX> is so bad, since a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could
have made it (and made it better). Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks</ENAMEX>' muse is showing him what
happens when you satirize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are so far beneath you.

         
      
   
