
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">259</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Even Educated Fleas Do It&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> and middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do it, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say that's fine, as long as
they do it for "health purposes" and not to "promote superstition, spread
rumors, engage in sedition, destroy social order or hold mass assemblies." Do
what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 258</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> Dis":
            

            

               Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Levrat</ENAMEX> assesses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s referendum on
asylum-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX>: "There is a side to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> that is very generous, giving
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, and a stricter side that wants to make sure that people
coming in are not ____________."
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Er</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">litigious</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "Under
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>, unless accompanied by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guardian</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tullis</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning</ENAMEX> to stay past <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Terns</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Simon</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Underwood</ENAMEX> had
similar answers.)

            
"Fugitive rape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are bankrolling their ski trips. That was
embarrassing last time."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Going</ENAMEX>
to upset our delicate multicultural balance."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> things we know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX>.

            First, they're boring, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and chocolate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> a lovely place to massage your money. Everyone
(especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent Curtis</ENAMEX>) knows what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Lime</ENAMEX> says in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Third Man :</ENAMEX>
"In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borgias</ENAMEX> they had warfare, terror, murder, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bloodshed</ENAMEX>, but they produced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da Vinci</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> they had brotherly love--they had 500 years of
democracy and peace, and what did that produce? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cuckoo</ENAMEX> clock."

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, they're a refuge, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard</ENAMEX>, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travesties</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zurich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, home to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tzara</ENAMEX>: "Oh,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>!--unfurled like a white flag, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pacific</ENAMEX> civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>--the
miraculous neutrality of it, the non-combatant impartiality of it, the
non-aggression pacts of it, the international red cross of it--entente to the
left, détente to the right, into the valley of the invalided blundered and
wandered myself when young--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr</ENAMEX> of the Consulate!"

            Of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr</ENAMEX> was quite dotty, and neutral does
not mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pacific</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McPhee</ENAMEX> makes clear in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Place de la Concorde</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suisse</ENAMEX> , his book on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> bit of alpine lore: Their
armed neutrality includes universal military training. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has a gun,
and none of your sissy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistols</ENAMEX>; these are assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> are based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> model, the hedgehog, designed to extract
a high price from any invader--<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">artillery presighted</ENAMEX> on every important <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>,
shelter space for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>, cool <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> whose pilots
train to take off from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> things--those
red-handled multi-blade ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> things--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swatch</ENAMEX>. And the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>
thing we know--the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX>. Numbered bank accounts would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>.

            
               Neutral
Answer
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> want to make sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming in are
not abusing the law.
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 70 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> approved
tougher rules restricting asylum-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> and rejected a proposal for maternity
leave, presumably concerned that some incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> might abuse the law.

            The new law limits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>' rights to appeal
individual persecution, and it speeds up the process of ejecting those without
identity papers.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> law requires new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> to take an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-week</TIMEX> leave, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> have rejected financial assistance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> four
times since the maternity leave law was enacted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levrat</ENAMEX> works for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> called Aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Refugees</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gina Duclayan</ENAMEX>'s
Dissent
            

            I beg to differ, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>!
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the favorite movies of my youth, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Randall</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dreyfus</ENAMEX>
vehicle called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sub a Dub Dub</ENAMEX> , a k a Hello Down There , features
the amusing antics of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in their undersea
lab-home. Or perhaps you consider this movie to be evidence for your statement,
not against it? Pshaw!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savvy Traveler</ENAMEX>
            

            You will recall that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Calvin</ENAMEX>, the granddaddy of fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preachers</ENAMEX>, founded his
theocracy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Geneva</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>. This has left more of a mark than you might
expect. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine was driving from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lyon</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Geneva</ENAMEX>. A few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX> after he crossed the border, his little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> asked, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, what happened to
all of the billboards with naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> on them?" It was an acute observation:
The prudish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> countryside did indeed lack for any of the casual skin that
covers <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.

            
               Misplaced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modifiers Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Which of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjectives</ENAMEX> appear in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> piece describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> at
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> campaign appearance, and which are from the World
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encyclopedia</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>) article on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">beaver</ENAMEX>?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hard-working</ENAMEX>

               useful

               personable

               adorable

               charismatic

               interesting

               vague

               intelligent

               fuzzy

               thickset

            

            
               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>: personable, adorable, charismatic, vague,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fuzzy</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaver</ENAMEX>: hard-working, useful, interesting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intelligent</ENAMEX>, thickset.

            The choice is yours. See
you at the polls in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
