
   
   
      
         
            Sieg Haider

            The
electoral surge of the far right in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> made the front pages of most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, it led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SÃ</ENAMEX>¼ddeutsche
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitung</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX>, but curiously not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX> , which confined the story to an inside page.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers raised the loudest alarm. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">columnist Bernardo Valli</ENAMEX> said the achievement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Party</ENAMEX> in
getting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 27 percent</NUMEX> of the vote in the general election was "a slap in
the face" for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JÃ¶rg Haider</ENAMEX>, who has praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
and described former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> as "decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>," won a share of
the vote almost double that ever achieved by the xenophobic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Marie Le Pen</ENAMEX>, he said. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Pen</ENAMEX> has never got <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 15 percent</NUMEX>.) The
result could only be regarded as worrying, even "obscene," by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, especially since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>,
which espouses principles quite different to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haider's</ENAMEX>.

            

               Corriere della
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sera</ENAMEX> ran a front-page cartoon showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> as a jack-in-the box
making the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> salute and shouting, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sieg Haider</ENAMEX>!" Its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-column headline
was: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX> of the extreme right." Much of the press comment
stressed the importance of keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Party</ENAMEX> from joining a new
governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haider</ENAMEX>'s result "has thrown the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s politics into turmoil, frightened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and brought closer to
power the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the largest and most radical far-right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>,"
said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in an editorial that it is a disaster for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Social Democrat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Klima</ENAMEX>, an embarrassment for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, and "a triumph for a man
whose political prejudices have shattered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s cosy and often corrupt
consensus." If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klima</ENAMEX> cannot form a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haider</ENAMEX> is next in line, it said.
"For much of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, that would be unthinkable: the ghosts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> past
have never been properly exorcised in the land of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s birth, and the image
of the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, denouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> as criminal, calling for the
expulsion of asylum-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> and denouncing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, would make the
international storm over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Waldheim</ENAMEX> seem nothing by comparison."

            
Following the close of polling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> elections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, Corriere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera</ENAMEX> announced on its front page that, according to exit polls,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Gandhi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of the assassinated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rajiv</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>, has clearly lost to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX>, although the official results
won't be known until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> led on the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
violence during the final phase of polling, about which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> quoted
the chief election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>'s conclusion: "It's gone off well." In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot</ENAMEX> air, floods, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, death and abuse--these are
the abiding images of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election '99</TIMEX>. ... Not all is well with the polity." The
editorial described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Gandhi</ENAMEX> as "stiff and inarticulate" and said many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> considered her "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventriloquist</ENAMEX>'s puppet and an instrument of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">self-serving coterie</ENAMEX>." The future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> dynasty, it suggested, rests on
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Priyanka</ENAMEX>, whose "strength is her charm and her seeming ability to
communicate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." But she will have to prove "she has a mind of her own
and intends to use it regularly."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fisk</ENAMEX> led the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a scare story about health-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">endangering</ENAMEX> contamination in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> caused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX>. "After insisting throughout its air
bombardment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> that its use of depleted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DU</ENAMEX>] munitions
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> forces posed no hazard to human health, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
now admit that particles from their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shells</ENAMEX> may have contaminated soil near
targets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and could cause 'inhalation' problems, especially for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>," he wrote. In briefings to international aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX>, one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>-For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> warned of "contaminated dust" at the scene of depleted uranium
munitions explosions and urged aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to stay <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150 feet</NUMEX> away from targets
hit in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> cannot--or will not--say where it used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DU</ENAMEX>
ordnance against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisk</ENAMEX> wrote. He said that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> fired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 860,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DU</ENAMEX> rounds during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">doctors</ENAMEX> subsequently found "an exponential increase in child <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deformities</ENAMEX>" among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> living close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s
report in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Basra</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> recorded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> born without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> with abnormally large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> born with no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> with short limbs," he added. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1998</TIMEX>, another baby
was born without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> with oversize heads."

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with warnings from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> that
dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish Republicans</ENAMEX> are planning a series of high-profile terrorist
attacks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dome</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. The planned bombing campaign by the Real IRA, as the
renegades call themselves, is considered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to be "a serious
threat," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, and is designed to coincide with any millennium bug
computer problems.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>
before he emigrated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>, returned
to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fleet Street</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of his biweekly columns for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> on the
presidential election campaign is about the battle between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination and how they are both currently
campaigning as underdogs. "The problem for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in the odd
game of chicken they are now playing is that neither will be electable if they
act the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> for too long," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> wrote. As a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evans</ENAMEX>
seems proud to use language that few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will understand, as in
this explanation of why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> relishes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> status: "He has happy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX> of those electric <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> when he caught the opposition
napping with a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-second</TIMEX> slam dunk."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> fronted
a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> have been killed in the River Marne
by a surfeit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, mainly pike, roach, and tench, died when
the residue of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> from the last pressing was washed into the river by heavy
rains <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
