
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Steamed</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). Thumbs go up, down, and every
which way for the final film by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>, who died shortly
after wrapping the movie. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> as a married couple
entangled in sexual jealousy, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> focus largely on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s work.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ) labels it "a worthy final chapter
to a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s career," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> )
raves that it's his riskiest film and "a spellbinding addition to the Kubrick
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">canon</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) begs to differ,
complaining that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s "meticulous, detail-oriented approach has
sucked all spontaneity and passion from the picture." Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> pillory
the film's highly publicized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>-sex scene, in which human figures were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digitally</ENAMEX> inserted to avoid an NC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> rating: "the most pompous orgy in the
history of the movies" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ), and "one of the
least erotic orgies ever filmed" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">critic David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review
and for an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explainer</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schnitzler</ENAMEX>, who wrote the novella that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> is based on. Click here to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artisan Entertainment</ENAMEX>). A big hit at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sundance Film Festival</ENAMEX>, this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> feature produced by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
film-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> steals some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s opening-weekend
thunder. Its mockumentary premise: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> disappear while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trekking</ENAMEX> through the woods of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> in search of a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch</ENAMEX>; a year
later, their footage is found and presented as The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> get increasingly suspicious of each other as they hear eerie sounds in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> and find mysterious bundles of sticks hanging from <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and by the
end they're running for their lives. With its tiny budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX>, the film
cleverly keeps the evil off-screen: "Most of the time, it's what the three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch-searchers</ENAMEX> don't see--but fear--that gets our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">petrified juices</ENAMEX> flowing or
curdling. This is low-tech inventiveness at its best" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BWP</ENAMEX> is "the new face of movie horror" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
Travers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> ), and it ends with "as heart-stopping a climax as
any the genre has seen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX> demurs, knocking it as "a clever,
entertaining stunt, no more, no less," but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX> (the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ) advises, "Don't see this ingenious first feature if you believe in
ghosts." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
to see the movie's official Web site, with more back-story on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mockumentary</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Placid</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kubrick</ENAMEX> nor
the first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project have much to fear in
the way of competition from this flaccid <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> feature, written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Practice , Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> ). At a fictional lake in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>--not the real <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Placid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Fonda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Pullman</ENAMEX>
take on a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30-foot</NUMEX> migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crocodile</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Movie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> seem to have a
hard time telling a crocodile from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">alligator</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> (the New York
Times ) does find bright spots in the dialogue, the "divinely cheesy"
special effects, and the supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, which includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Platt</ENAMEX> and
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Gleeson</ENAMEX>. But "since even the gator horror satire
is old hat (remember <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Alligator</ENAMEX> ?), there's no remaining way to make this
interesting." Or, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Knowles</ENAMEX> ( Ain't
It Cool <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> ) neatly puts it: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placid</ENAMEX> is "the worst giant
alligator movie known to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to play the official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>'s wacky <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Croc Drop</ENAMEX> game.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Short History of Rudeness: Manners, Morals</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Misbehavior</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Caldwell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picador</ENAMEX>). No one argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caldwell</ENAMEX> is
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> to survey the origin and use of manners, but whether he
adds much to the discussion is another question. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowman</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> ) calls Short History "an amusing but lightweight read" and
notes that "even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mick Jagger</ENAMEX> had a more rigorous take on the subject ... in
'Sympathy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>.' " The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Eder</ENAMEX> takes a harsher
line: "These broader <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> are treated in books and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and the slow
sections of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>." Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> notice <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caldwell</ENAMEX>'s positive spin on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">much-maligned Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>--that she democratizes civilized living by making
it not a matter of class, but simply of good habits, which anyone can learn.
"It's difficult to recall a single book in which [manners] are discussed as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comprehensively</ENAMEX> and intelligently as in this one ... the definitive book on the
subject--at least for now" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to buy the book.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  
                     Significant Other
                  
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Limp Bizkit</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flip-Interscope</ENAMEX>). The notoriously potty-mouthed rap/metal quintet matures a
bit on the follow-up to its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> debut, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y'All$</ENAMEX> . The
band occasionally departs from its hard-core speed metal and ventures into
"melodic interludes, user-friendly grooves, and actual harmonious vocals"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorraine Ali</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> ). The lyrics, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Durst</ENAMEX> (who
clambers out of a toilet during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s stage act), are "still the stuff of
monochromatic dude talk," but sometimes they hint at something deeper--like
when "the formerly promiscuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> confesses his shame for past recreational
nookie sessions" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>). "The unholy matrimony of metal and rap celebrates
another victory on this superb sophomore effort" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Sciarretto</ENAMEX>, College
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music Journal</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to buy Significant Other and here to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y'All$</ENAMEX> .)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap Judgment</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Book
            

            
               
                  
                     Inside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Tapes From FDR</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
                  
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doyle</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodansha International</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doyle</ENAMEX>'s look at the audio-taping practices of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> is a "valuable history and comparative survey" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doyle</ENAMEX>, a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of crackling prose"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard R. Roberts</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis Star</ENAMEX> ), provides insightful
transcripts from key <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> missile crisis and the final
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to buy the book.)

         
      
   
