
   
   
      
         
             Sins of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tongue</ENAMEX>

            During the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> scandal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> values were often invoked--but only those concerning sex. What no one
talked about was that from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reformation</ENAMEX> era,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> moral theology, both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>, has upheld other
principles relevant to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>: above all, that "nemo tenetur detegere
turpitudinem suam ." That does not translate as "thou shalt not lie with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interns</ENAMEX> (nor lie about it thereafter)." It means "no one is compelled to reveal
his own secret sin." A corollary holds that no one--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>--has a moral right to compel another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to disclose his private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shameful</ENAMEX> acts. As the eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ames</ENAMEX> wrote in
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conscience and the Cases Thereof</ENAMEX> , "[H]e whose offence is hidden has ...
as yet right to preserve his fame that it should not rashly be laid open.
Neither is it the part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to search into hidden faults."

            You may not agree with this principle, but it was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>'s position for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>. According to medieval canon law, "private
and shameful acts," the sorts of things a penitent whispers to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>, lie
outside the jurisdiction of public tribunals. Moreover, both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> argued against compelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to answer specific
incriminating questions under oath--because, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> explains, it is "against
nature" to expect "that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> should betray or defame himself." Even this
stiff old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX> never supposes that it is only weak, unprincipled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who lie
under such circumstances. To put someone on oath, and then ask if he has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masturbated</ENAMEX> or committed adultery (both mortal sins according to traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> ethics), is merely to "give occasion of horrid perjuries." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julius Clarus</ENAMEX> says much the same, adding "as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> experience
teaches."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional Christian</ENAMEX>
morality even supports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s slippery answers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>'
questions. It was precisely to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> a way out of the
perjury trap that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX> distinguished between a lie and a misleading or
equivocal statement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Mason</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> writing in the early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 th century</TIMEX>, points out that in traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
ethics "if there be just cause for concealing of a truth," one may use words in
a "less known and common signification, and in another meaning than it is
likely the hearers will understand them." Like, say, using "sex" in a sense
that excludes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fellatio</ENAMEX> (though that's not an example that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> gives).

            Traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> moral theology does not view attempts
to hide one's private sins and shame as grave offenses. What it does view as a
fundamental violation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> is detractio : disclosing
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>'s private failings and weaknesses in order to ruin his good
name or otherwise bring him into discredit. According to the Summa
Theologica of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Aquinas</ENAMEX>, to harm someone this way is a mortal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sin</ENAMEX>--even if the allegations are true--since "defamation is not a distortion of
the truth but the destruction of a reputation." Or, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> puts it, he is
"truly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractor</ENAMEX> who revealeth a true sin of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s ... spoiling the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s reputation to the intent to hurt him."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquinas</ENAMEX> considered
detractio more seriously wicked than theft, because "reputation is more
valuable than riches." Citing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Augustine</ENAMEX>, some penitential manuals classify
it as a type of homicide, while others make it a sin against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Spirit</ENAMEX>
and thus unforgivable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> takes an equally hard line: "The
unjust revealing a secret hath in it oftentimes the pernicious violations of
trust, friendship, and honesty," and is therefore "not only in the common
esteem of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, but in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripture</ENAMEX> also, reckoned amongst the most odious
sins."

            To be sure, there are times when one has a moral right and
duty to reveal damaging information about another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> notes, "every
citizen" is bound to notify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> of "faults which do either
immediately hurt the public good ... or which hurt heavily any innocent." But,
he adds, as long as "the fault itself is not pernicious to others ... then
charity and justice require that, setting aside accusation, we content
ourselves with private correction."

            In other words, the release of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year ago this week</TIMEX> was, by traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> standards, the big sin of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. Disclosing every last humiliating detail of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sex life
occupies the dead center of what traditional Christianity means by sin--and is
perhaps even more deeply wrong than either committing or concealing adultery.
If, as many said, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> reflects the erosion of traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> values,
it is not because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> committed adultery and lied about it--which is nothing
new. The evidence of eroding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> values is that compelling a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to
publicize his hidden faults and punishing him for not cooperating in his own
disgrace are no longer considered by many to be sins at all.

         
      
   
