
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cups</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bras</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athletic Supporters</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX>
Rule!" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">screams Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s victory
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s sports take giant leap," exults <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> . Everyone agrees the tournament was a cultural leap forward--but in
which direction? Beneath the celebration lurks a struggle between equality
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feminists</ENAMEX>, who think the tournament proved that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can be just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and
difference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>, who think it showed how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are different and better.
The spin contest covers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> issues: individualism , sex ,
careerism , and playing dirty .

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individualism</ENAMEX>. Equality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> want each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to assert herself. One
school of egalitarians sees the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> as a demonstration that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can be
"independent." Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, illustrated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gatorade</ENAMEX> ad that shows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia Hamm</ENAMEX> battling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> at various sports, pushes the idea
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should embrace competition. "Anything you can do, I can do better,"
goes the ad's jingle. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, influenced by male sports marketing,
selects certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> on the women's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and pitches them as solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.
Several male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> ignore most of the championship game and focus on the
game-ending goal by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandi Chastain</ENAMEX>--"a shootout, womano a
womano," with "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>, everybody holding their breath."

            
Difference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> draw the opposite lessons. They reject the rampant
individualism of "loutish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball and baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>," as the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Vecsey</ENAMEX> puts it, and they celebrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> women's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squad</ENAMEX> as a collectivist countermodel. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team</ENAMEX>--Collective
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selflessness Culminates in Title</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>," beams the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's front-page headline. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , picking up the "selflessness"
theme, praises <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> who "accepted diminished roles" and offered "to do
anything I'm asked for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>." Contrary to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gatorade</ENAMEX> ad, the magazine
reports with admiration that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamm</ENAMEX> "sees herself as a solid cog in a remarkably
powerful machine" and "refuses to acknowledge that she's a player with unique
gifts."

            Some
difference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> suggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are born this way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vecsey</ENAMEX>, for example,
calls them "innately good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>." Others attribute their selflessness to
environmental programming. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>'s preparation, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Roommates</ENAMEX> were switched at every stop on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>
road to prevent cliques from forming. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tourney</ENAMEX> progressed, the imaging
tapes, designed to be watched in private, were shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>." The resulting
collective consciousness is captured in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> ads that depict the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> doing
everything together. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ad, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> goes out on a date, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>
tag along. In another, a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> who has given one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> two
fillings stares in amazement as one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammate</ENAMEX> after another rises, zombielike,
to declare, "Then I will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fillings!"

            
Equality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> find this celebration of selflessness creepy, but it's not
just being foisted on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> by male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Cup Chairwoman Donna de</ENAMEX>
Varona lauds the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>' "humility." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> praises "their unassuming ways." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristine Lilly</ENAMEX>, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> is "like a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> family. Female sports are different. You do a lot better
when you care about each other. We are nurturing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, caring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. ... We
all want to see each other happy."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
Sex. Many difference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> celebrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s sex appeal,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recycling David Letterman</ENAMEX>'s descriptions of the team as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Babe City</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soccer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamas</ENAMEX>." The icon of these pro-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chastain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> who posed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nude</ENAMEX> (but not lasciviously) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gear</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, kicked the winning goal,
and then tore off her jersey and bounded around the field in a black sports
bra. Equality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> worry that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>' exploitation of their physiques
is self-objectifying and retro.

            
Pro-sex difference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> find their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> under attack less from the left
than from a scandalized news media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chastain</ENAMEX> in a tone of polite disbelief what in God's name prompted her to tear
off her jersey. "What are you thinking ? What are you doing ?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stammered ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Roberts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chastain</ENAMEX> had posed for "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lowbrow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Gerhart</ENAMEX> calls it "the frat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> ." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> calls her jersey-removal flourish a "strip" and
jokes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, her name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chastain</ENAMEX>, not Chaste." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Purists</ENAMEX> prefer to praise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Akers</ENAMEX>, the less flashy midfield workhorse who has pronounced herself
"a bit uncomfortable with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandi</ENAMEX>'s deal."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chastain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> offer several counterspins. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> there's the pro-choice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>, which says every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s choice should be respected, whether it's
running marathons or posing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gear</ENAMEX> . Then there's the "sexy to be
strong" defense, which praises the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for adding muscle tone to our
idea of feminine beauty. Then there's the "have it all" defense. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Lieber</ENAMEX> puts it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s "message" is that "you can
have it all. ... That if you're also driven, determined, aggressive, tough and
committed, you can captivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Letterman</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> with
your brawn and your brain, your femininity and sexuality, your athletic skills
and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'babeness</ENAMEX>.' "

            Some
equality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> also take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chastain</ENAMEX>'s side. Their superficial spin is that
male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players whip</ENAMEX> off their shirts all the time, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should be able to do
the same. Their subtler spin, well-expressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhart</ENAMEX>, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chastain</ENAMEX> "has
brought instant attention to a piece of clothing that is humble and
practical--not a traditional bra of shine and lace and cleavage, but a sturdy
compression garment. The sports bra is the cloth symbol of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Title IX</ENAMEX>'s success."
The crudest egalitarian spin is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chastain</ENAMEX> is using her sex appeal to get
attention but that this is OK because she's using the attention to make money,
just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> do. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">essayist</ENAMEX> puts it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is "having some
fun--not to mention making some profit--with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s sexual obsession."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
Career and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Equality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> measure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s success by its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paychecks</ENAMEX>, complaining that its salaries are "meager by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s standards," and
its bonuses for winning "pale in comparison" to what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> get. Noting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s
decision to arrange its own tour of promotional matches, contrary to plans made
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Soccer Federation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are "determined
to promote and pay themselves better than they believe the [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSF</ENAMEX>] has."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , agreeing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has boosted its negotiating leverage,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beams</ENAMEX>, "Welcome to the big time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>."

            
Difference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> reject "the big time" as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, ugly, and destructive
male pursuit. They celebrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> women's comparative innocence. "In an era
when the egos of male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> are dwarfed only by their paychecks, the World
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cup</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, minimum wagers by pro-sports standards, reminded the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that
sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstars</ENAMEX> can be gracious and grateful," coos <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Morton</ENAMEX> observes approvingly that unlike male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>, the female players
don't "have million dollar contracts or big shoe deals. They actually seem to
play because they love their game."

            
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> coverage exalts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> who focus on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
Several articles applaud "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> moms" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Overbeck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy Fawcett</ENAMEX>, as well
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamm</ENAMEX>'s devotion to her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> overseas ("We've sacrificed so much,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamm</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marla Messing</ENAMEX>, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glowingly</ENAMEX> profiled for stepping aside to stay home with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. She "plans to
turn her attention from filling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> nationwide to bringing a much smaller
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> together: her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports. Now "her most serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambition</ENAMEX> is to get reacquainted with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> ... and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
Playing dirty. Difference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists portray women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> as more civil
and noble than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vecsey</ENAMEX> puts it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> eschew "the cynical fouls
and flagrant flops of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>." Equality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> draw a different lesson: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Cup</ENAMEX> showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can body-slam, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>, and cheat just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            Each
of these vices has an exemplar on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akers</ENAMEX> has been elected to
represent body-slamming, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Gildea</ENAMEX> calling her "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Butkus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>." A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> interviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> pays her the ultimate adolescent male compliment: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akers</ENAMEX>, she's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chastain</ENAMEX> represents <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> language as well as physical immodesty. Before the
championship game, she was notorious for defending her Gear spread by
observing, "I ran my ass off for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>." After she kicked the winning goal,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> put a microphone in her face and asked her to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akers</ENAMEX>.
"She's the toughest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddamn player</ENAMEX> I've ever played with or against," Chastain
blurted. Sportswriters chuckle at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chastain</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">salty</ENAMEX>" language and call it
"another step" toward gender parity in athletics.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goalie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Briana Scurry</ENAMEX>, represents cheating. It was she, more than
Chastain, who won the game by blocking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> kick in the shootout. Scurry
did it by sneaking forward, against the rules, to narrow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>'s angle
before the kick. Far from chastising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scurry</ENAMEX>, male sportswriters are
congratulating her on her "savvy." "Yes, she said later, she knew she was
breaking the rules," concludes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Plaschke</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> .
"But because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referees</ENAMEX> didn't call it, it apparently falls under the heading
of gamesmanship. 'Everybody does it,' she said. 'It's only cheating if you get
caught.' Sports equality indeed."

         
      
   
