
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Killing Fields</ENAMEX>

            In a
report picked up by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post</ENAMEX> to lead its front page
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer of London</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of documents
discovered after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> retreat from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> prove that the ethnic
cleansing there had been "meticulously planned and ordered from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>." "The
papers provide crucial evidence linking massacres that claimed an estimated
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX> lives to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> and police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> all the way up to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX>. It
said most of the documents are now in the hands of the intelligence service of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX>, which has claimed that "nothing happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
without it being planned and organised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>."

            
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> led with pictures of the eccentric young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">violinist Nigel Kennedy</ENAMEX> performing a "concert for peace" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sava Concert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> said several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> by a leading Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> since the war--but were
barred from visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">musician backstage</ENAMEX> by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> "who wanted to avoid
an embarrassing photo-opportunity." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> told his ecstatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> were "a warm, friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who did not deserve to be bombed." "I
came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> to see if you were all right and succeeded in staying alive,"
he added.

            With
regard to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Srinagar</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 500</NUMEX> "personal bodyguards" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most
wanted terrorist, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>, were fighting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kashmir</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> side. They had fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> began to close in on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. The whereabouts
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> himself is not known. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
believed he could be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kargil</ENAMEX> area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> but added there was not any
concrete evidence of this.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> ,
another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX>, reported <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s concern about its future relations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> after the state-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX> called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> for an "immediate ceasefire" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> said this was clearly a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> comment and a
departure from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s neutrality in the dispute. It suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
might be changing its tune because of growing fears of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' meddling
in the region. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> added: "If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is really worried about possible
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> gains from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kargil</ENAMEX> crisis, it should hardly be advocating a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ceasefire</ENAMEX>. Instead it should be demanding that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> withdraw the armed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aggression</ENAMEX> and remove any excuse for Western intervention."

            The
crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> led the front pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> . With <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> having set <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 30</TIMEX>, as the "absolute"
deadline for agreement on implementing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> peace deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers
were pessimistic. The problem has been a refusal by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protestant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican Catholic</ENAMEX> Sinn Fein <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> a role in the newly
developed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> unless its military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>, starts handing in its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.

            The
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in an editorial that the
decommissioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> has not begun because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> "knows that its power
derives from violence and the threat of violence, and so it does not want to
sacrifice that power." The paper strongly supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist</ENAMEX> refusal to
share power with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> under these circumstances. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> come into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, something new in the history of our parliamentary
democracy will have taken place," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said. "An armed group
will be taking part in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The power of a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> will, for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, be exercised through out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reported,
meanwhile, that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist terrorist groups</ENAMEX> are both preparing for
new violence.

            The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> took the same view, saying that a power-sharing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> without an IRA
commitment to disarmament "would be less a democratic political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> than
bureaucratic cover for a protection racket." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> , however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticized Blair</ENAMEX> for setting an unreal deadline for the peace talks. The
situation was not like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, where a compromise between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> would have been a disaster, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist leaders</ENAMEX> haven't reached agreement by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, "[t]he sky
stays where it is," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "They simply have to keep trying, and Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> will have lost an important modicum of credibility."

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> to stand by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> during a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Senate</ENAMEX> campaign that would see "the dirty laundry of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past eight years</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recycled</ENAMEX>," new tensions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, and "a hot reception, no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">punches</ENAMEX> pulled" from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>. Feeling betrayed and
humiliated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> business, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> had considered a
separation, but "in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> she stayed and supported her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> when he needed
her most." "Message to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>: as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> heads for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, it's payback time,"
concluded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
