
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dog Days of Summer</ENAMEX>

            The
traditional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> "silly season" finally arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fleet Street</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> when
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> chose as their top news story a claim that sunbathing is
good for you. A report published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Medical Journal</ENAMEX> by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bristol</ENAMEX> epidemiologists infuriated cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> by saying there is
"evidence that the potential benefits of exposure to sunlight may outweigh the
widely publicised adverse effects on the incidence of skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>." The report,
which led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> and made the front pages of the
Times and the
Independent , said that sunbathing could protect against heart disease
and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple sclerosis</ENAMEX> and that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would die from keeping out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX> than from being in it. The report also made the banal observations that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find lying or sitting in the sun enjoyable and relaxing" and that "this
subjective sense of well-being may be important in itself in improving the
quality of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s life."

            An
even sillier "silly season" story, appearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> on the front pages of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> , concerned the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s decision
to establish a task force to study the threat of an asteroid hitting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> and
destroying all life on the planet. The FT said that a plan to avert
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> has been demanded of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> by an opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lembit Opik</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Estonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernst</ENAMEX> had an asteroid
named after him. Asked whether the proposed establishment of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Near Earth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Object Task Force</ENAMEX> wasn't rather a limp response to such a cataclysmic threat, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Ministry</ENAMEX> said defensively, "It's not as if there are
asteroids hovering above the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>."

            Other
prominent stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> included <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 million</NUMEX>
record-breaking sale at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> of a famous art collection looted
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschilds</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> and recently restored to
their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>, and the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX> hunting is almost certain to be
abolished in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> has said he will
support legislation against it.

            The
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> ran
editorials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s re-establishment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> of diplomatic
relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripoli</ENAMEX> following <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>'s belated admission of responsibility
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1984</TIMEX> death of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policewoman</ENAMEX> who was killed by shots fired from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. The FT said this was the right decision,
not because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar Qaddafi</ENAMEX> was now "a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jeffersonian democrat</ENAMEX>" but because "he
has started to come into line with international law enough to justify a policy
of engagement rather than isolation." The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , however, said that behind this decision and an earlier one by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to exchange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassadors</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> lay "an unwillingness to stand up to
terror-sponsoring regimes that have large commercial contracts in their gift."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s current cozying-up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> distances
it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and "exposes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s proclaimed Atlanticism
as increasingly questionable." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> , on the other hand,
supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> decision on the opposite ground--"that
by establishing dialogue, we are differentiating ourselves from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>." It
said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> too often comes across as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>'s-paw."

            A
report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX> said that conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerics</ENAMEX>
have struck a blow at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s reforming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatami</ENAMEX> by closing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salam</ENAMEX> , which helped his rise to power. There were now
fears that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sobh-e-Emrouz</ENAMEX> and
Kordad , will be closed down. A bill that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerics</ENAMEX> pushed through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> restricting press freedom is expected to compel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> to reveal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> and to bar many opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
from "any form of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> activity," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> led its international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with accusations that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> executed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> before they were
brought to trial. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Punjab</ENAMEX>, the home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz Sharif</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 850</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been shot by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> since he came to power <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Punjabi</ENAMEX> paper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> explanation of
these killings is often that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> died "in cross-fire" during street
battles with criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> say
the killings are deliberate and authorized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said. It also quoted what it said was a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. State</ENAMEX>
Department report on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> saying that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> committed numerous
extra-judicial killings and tortured, abused and raped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>" and that
"there is no evidence that any police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> were brought to justice."

            The same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX> promised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that he will hand over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> at
the earliest opportunity, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Age</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. In
its main front-page story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>--where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
stopped to meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> on his way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--that this was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conditions for brokering a peace deal between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> over the disputed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. Another was the early withdrawal
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim mujahideen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, whose incursions there are the
cause of the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> military conflict. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>, accused by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> of masterminding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> bombings of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> missions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, is hiding in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> under the patronage of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>-supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Age</ENAMEX> said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has
demonstrated its seriousness about getting its hands on him by announcing
simultaneously with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX>'s arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that it is freezing trade
with "all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taliban</ENAMEX> control or influence."

         
      
   
