
   
   
      
         
            Remembering the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fine-Tuned</ENAMEX>
Instrumentalization
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note: What follows in an exchange between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Novick</ENAMEX>, author
of The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Life</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Young</ENAMEX>, one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s "," in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novick</ENAMEX>'s book was discussed. Both
letters are reprinted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' permission.
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>,

            I am appealing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> at leisure to overturn the
judgment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX> in haste. I apologize for the fact that, as with many
appellate briefs, detailing the grounds for the appeal will require a fair
amount of space.

            In your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Gourevitch</ENAMEX> about my
book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Holocaust in American Life</ENAMEX> , you wrote the following, apropos of
what you termed "the so-called 'lessons of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>,' or why we recall the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX> at all": "I would suggest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contra Novick</ENAMEX>, that not every
institutional memory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> is a deliberate instrumentalization of it
toward cheap and self-interested ends." You add that I am "actually quite good
at ferreting out many of the instances where this is, indeed, the case."

            I'm not sure what the word "institutional" means
here--i.e., how an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> remembers. Holocaust memory, of course, becomes
"institutionalized" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">curricula</TIMEX>; in a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">canon</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> literature; more
diffusely, institutionalized in popular--particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>--consciousness.
Let's turn to "instrumentalization"--a word which appears to carry a strong
negative charge for you. As you know, I never myself use that word (or its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cognates</ENAMEX>) concerning collective memory. The reason, made clear more than once
in the book, is that I think collective memories that really take hold
always do so because they serve a present or continuing purpose. That is
to say, memories take hold to the extent that they are--if one wants to use the
word--"instrumental" for some purpose. As you will recall, I make a partial
exception for certain forms of religious (or civic-religious) commemoration at
the very beginning of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> on "lessons": "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Remembering the Holocaust</ENAMEX>,
especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, needs no pragmatic justification. It is an act of piety
analogous to reciting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mourner's Kaddish</ENAMEX> on the anniversary of a relative's
death, to the remembrance of war dead on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day</ENAMEX>." In the introduction, I
point out that historically, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> memory--even religious memory--has been
selective: Events that seem to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> to point up a useful contemporary
lesson are incorporated into collective memory; those that don't seem to teach
useful lessons recede, though they may be recovered later, as perceptions
change about what lessons are useful. And, a fortiori, this is true of secular
memory. Thus, for me , to say that a collective memory is "instrumental"
is to say nothing that isn't implicit in its being a collective memory.
For me , to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> memory is "instrumentalized" says nothing
worth saying, and certainly nothing invidious or discreditable.

            For you (and others)
"instrumentalization" is invidious--and discreditable. By not explaining
why it is invidious--simply taking this for granted--and saying that I
treat <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> memory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> as all "instrumental," you attribute to me
the view that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Holocaust</ENAMEX> memory is somehow discreditable. I think we
ought to explore how you use the word, and thus the view you're attributing to
me. Are you saying that memories in general, or memories of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> in
particular, are "instrumentalized" when they are used for unworthy , or
at least inappropriate purposes? Let's consider those purposes for which
the memory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> has been invoked, which are the ones I discuss
most in my book. These include both "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-specific" and "general"
purposes:

            

               To rouse the conscience of the world about perceived threats to "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> missed" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.

               To reinforce <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> solidarity, so that having survived <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> will
not disappear through assimilation.

               To warn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> to watch out for early warning signs of rising anti-Semitism
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--signs that were ignored in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.

               To urge that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> intervene against atrocities abroad which
are said to resemble the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.

               To teach tolerance and brotherhood--especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            

            Can we agree that these are the "lessons of the
Holocaust" to which I devote the most space in the book? Which of them do you
think unworthy or inappropriate--and why? I wouldn't myself describe them that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>--and in the book I don't. To be sure, in invoking the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> for these
(to me) worthy and appropriate purposes, those doing so were often led to
excess: for example, exaggerating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s peril or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> anti-Semitism.
But that was my point . As I wrote in the book, "Once <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> starts using
imagery from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>--that most extreme of events--it becomes impossible
to say anything moderate, balanced, or nuanced; the very language carries you
along to hyperbole." But the ends for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> was (to use
your word) "instrumentalized" seemed to me then and seem to me now both worthy
and appropriate.

            Or perhaps, for you, "instrumentalization" hinges
on motive : Perhaps you believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> was invoked for these ends
"cynically" or "insincerely"? This may, in isolated instances, have been true,
but I can't recall ever either saying or implying that this was the case.
Certainly, overall, I repeatedly underlined the sincerity of those who
have invoked the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. Indeed, I extend this to some of the less
"mainstream" invocations--those that many, perhaps including yourself, think
unworthy or inappropriate. As you may recall, I underlined the good faith of
those who saw an analogy between the denial of the humanity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> slogan "life unworthy of life." I am myself conventionally
"pro-choice," but I would think it a dubious procedure to make that the
criterion of when it was illegitimate to invoke the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, reserving the
mantle of legitimacy for causes--like humanitarian intervention, or the
promotion of brotherhood and tolerance--of which I approve. If you differ with
me on this, it would have been appropriate for you to say: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novick</ENAMEX> is
excessively tolerant of invocations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> which I and many others
think quite intolerable." But you didn't say that: You said that I believe that
"every institutional memory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> is a deliberate
instrumentalization of it toward cheap and self-interested ends."

            Let's turn to "cheap and self-interested." There
are indeed invocations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> to which I'd apply this description. In
a section devoted to miscellaneous ways in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> had entered
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> discourse, I listed a few cases in which I thought this was so,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mentioning Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>, and a handful of others. To this one
might add the single paragraph I devote to the origin of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust Museum</ENAMEX>, which, as you wrote in your <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust Memorials</ENAMEX> in
History , was "proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">then-president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> to placate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> angered by his sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-15</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter planes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>." In all,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pages of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">281</NUMEX> pages in the book.

            You write that I am "quite good at ferreting out"
instances of "instrumentalization of [the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>] toward cheap and
self-interested ends." Ferret that I am, I indeed accumulated quite a
collection of such instances, along with instances of what you elsewhere term
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>'s "commodification." There was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, selling <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>
jewelry to raise money for her (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> and vulgar) painting cycle on the
subject. There was--my personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>--the travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> advertising a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Singles Weekend</ENAMEX>," the high point of which was a visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust Museum</ENAMEX>. Of these, or the many other similar examples I've collected,
there is no mention in the book . The reason that I didn't mention them
was that to do so seemed to me "a cheap shot"--concentrating on the ephemeral
and the inconsequential--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scummy</ENAMEX> froth atop the waves of any discourse.

            There are real differences between us in
interpreting the rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> memory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. As an
alternative to my approach, in which the growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> memory is to be
explained by the contemporary purposes it serves, you suggest a focus on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tradition of remembering catastrophes. These traditional reasons, you
say "explain its significance for many [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>] at a preconscious level, whether
we like it or not." I think there is something to this, which is why I
discussed it, albeit briefly, in the book. For various reasons, I don't think
this explains much about the evolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jewish</ENAMEX> memory of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. Still, yours is certainly an arguable position, which we can discuss
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime</TIMEX>. If you'd said in 
                  Slate
                that you thought I didn't talk
enough about this, that would have been a reasonable comment. But you went way
beyond that--counterposing your traditional/cultural hypothesis to my alleged
view that "every institutional memory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> is a deliberate
instrumentalization of it toward cheap and self-interested ends." Is that the
only possible alternative to your view?

            I can suggest a possibility about how such an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unjust</ENAMEX> and demonstrably false characterization of my views came to appear in
your message to [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gourevitch</ENAMEX>. That possibility has to do with the
rapid-fire e-mail exchange format of 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club</ENAMEX>" in which
it appeared. You wrote in response to an e-mail by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gourevitch</ENAMEX> "postmarked" just
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours earlier</TIMEX>. You were in fact offering it, as you'll see if you go back
to the original, not as a considered characterization of my views, but as a way
of introducing your own "traditional/cultural" explanation.

            But of course, once made, and available for
excerpting, it became a (highly quotable) characterization of my views.
The "conversational illusion" that e-mail promotes seduces us into the kind of
careless hyperbole common to conversation. In real conversations, a
raised eyebrow can be enough to make us backtrack. Something like this happens
in private e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>. I can't count the occasions on which I said
something in a message that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> challenged. In the next message
I'd find myself saying something like, "Of course, you're right. I overstated.
What I should have said, meant to say, was ..." But in your e-mail exchange
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gourevitch</ENAMEX>, your characterization of my views wasn't challenged.
And unlike hyperbolic remarks in private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>, buried in the innards of
our computers, this one went out to God-knows-how-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many thousands</NUMEX> of
"eavesdroppers." Can you have any doubt that given your reputation as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX>-minded and circumspect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> on these matters your characterization
will be widely quoted as an authoritative summary of my views?

            If you want it to be so
quoted, you'll of course let it stand. If, on reflection, you want to withdraw
what I hope you'll acknowledge was a hasty and careless characterization, you
can do so here.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Novick</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of history

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Peter</ENAMEX>,

            Given the narrowness of both my hasty
characterization of your position (vis-à-vis "instrumentalization") and of your
own objection to my characterization, I'm glad to be able to come back and say
now that my words were unfair to your much more complex approach to "the uses
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>." It was especially unfair to put a word in your mouth,
"intrumentalization," which you have taken pains to avoid--and for very good
reasons. I'm sorry.

            At the same time, I wouldn't characterize my own
position as reflexively knee jerk against instrumentalization, in that I find
every memory, institutional or otherwise, "instrumentalizes" to some degree.
Which is partly why you wisely dispense with the term.

            In this, it would be a little too easy to blame the
rapid-fire format for my misstating of your approach to the
"instrumentalization" (my word, not yours) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. I take
responsibility, apologize for my haste, and accept your raised eyebrow. As a
format, I think 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Book Club</ENAMEX> can provide just the kind of
fresh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-response to books and ideas that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> had in mind. But along
with these rewards come risks in such a rapid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, something both the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> need to keep in mind.

            The conversation
continues ... Until next word, I send

            --Very best wishes,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E. Young</ENAMEX>

            
               Race Matters
            

            I found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Brus</ENAMEX>' comparison of racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profiling</ENAMEX> and affirmative action (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>") simplistic and misleading. He fails to
provide a realistic definition of affirmative action and does not address the
issues that would provide a context for it.

            Affirmative action allows that, given <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> of equal qualifications, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> may favor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> that
helps it achieve its affirmative action goals. The legitimacy of these goals
comes not only from notions of "social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>" but also from the desire to
offer a more effective educational environment, a more hospitable workplace, or
a more effective school system. In public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, for example, the
effectiveness of offering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> with similar ethnic or racial
backgrounds is widely accepted.

            But the defect in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brus</ENAMEX>' article is not that he
fails to recognize these benefits, or even disagrees with them, but that he
never gets to how this reasoning is implemented in affirmative action programs
in a manner that is quite different from what goes on with racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profiling</ENAMEX>.

            Racial profiling (as practiced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>)
simply singles out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of color for harassment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. It is a convenient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to select <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> for traffic stops that happens to accord with the racist
notions that seem to flourish in law enforcement.

            Affirmative action
celebrates the cultural diversity of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and seeks to create a more
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">inclusive</ENAMEX> economy and public life. It recognizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and ability are
distributed across the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and that it requires extra effort to avoid
excluding parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that have traditionally been excluded. Racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profiling</ENAMEX> is merely a way for racist police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to express their bigotry
at the expense of our civil rights. It doesn't stop crime and it doesn't build
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Brus</ENAMEX> can find no difference between these practices--or
that he is willing to attribute it all to the "fudge factor"--shows he doesn't
get it. He does us all a disservice by offering up this superficial
comparison.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Pressler</ENAMEX>
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brunswick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blasting Bloat</ENAMEX>
            

            Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuman</ENAMEX> must have got his Ph.D. in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.S.</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>, if "" is his typical output. I assume his purposes were to keep
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ingratiating</ENAMEX> himself with the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> as well as getting a lot of reader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feedback</ENAMEX>.

            I have been on quite a few development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and
was waiting for a few honest comments. They were there but buried. The truth,
as I have seen it, lies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SWAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that tried to keep code trim, combined
with the greedy rush to keep ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>' introductions.

            Given enough skill and time, good programmers could
write much, much smaller programs with the same or more features, including
backward compatibility with older products. It is rushed, lazy, or incompetent
coding that takes the easy ways out.

            These programs are
flabby only partially because of their feature sets. Marketing-driven decisions
and programming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shortcuts</ENAMEX> are the road signs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flabby Software City</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ball</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
