
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">309</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Lost in Translation&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               " <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'EIN Nod:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bodlonrwydd Llwyr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I Gwsmeriaid</ENAMEX>' is not the snappiest slogan to those who speak
no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welsh</ENAMEX>. Yet the banner inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX>'s aero-engine servicing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Wales</ENAMEX>--'_____________'--is a fair approximation of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>
has been up to in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nantgarw</ENAMEX> since it bought the business from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>." 
               Fill in the blank in this lead from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> by translating that slogan from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. (Question
courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Solovay</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 308</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Praise With Faint Damns":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               According to remarks made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, it is characterized "by greed and
lust for power, by hot-blooded hatreds, and stone-cold hearts." Who was
describing what?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
Maslin, both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Gavaghan</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Stern</ENAMEX> spotlights the selling points of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Anyone describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s new book."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tyrrell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Everyone, high school."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Meyerson</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Frankly, I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaican Tourist Board</ENAMEX> should go back to that old 'Come
Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX>' slogan."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> responses
are any guide to popular taste--a ludicrous proposition, but play along--the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most greedy and lustful and savage realms are <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX>
pageant and inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. So here's my pitch to whomever replaces
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Tarses</ENAMEX> (and I pray it will be well reviewed by whomever replaces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
Maslin, even though she reviews movies not TV shows). Beauty-contest time
travel: like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Owens</ENAMEX> story but in heels and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">virgins</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>.
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Universe</ENAMEX> contest. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX> with any kind of a shot are Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--a surprisingly leggy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Germany</ENAMEX>--an unexpectedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amiable Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX>. During the swimsuit competition, while helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
glue his modest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-piece to his modest ass, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> learns that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> is
a pretty nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who wants to do no more than conquer <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and kill all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. Not such a terrible thing, thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, and certainly nothing to
start a war over. So <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> is avoided, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of lives--you know, the
right sort of lives--are saved, and history is transformed in ways so utopian,
you'd never recognize the present. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX>: high-speed maglev trains
that run on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sorkin</ENAMEX> TV shows that aren't sentimental twaddle. Brave
new world. Bold new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>. (Did I mention that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second season</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>
travels back in time to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln</ENAMEX> even deader? After a romantic interlude? A
three-way with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson Davis</ENAMEX>?)

            
               Stepping on Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mighty Big Toes Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was describing the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>. Apparently he doesn't like it. Or, more disturbingly,
does.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Assembly</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> moved beyond vague generalities and into
comforting platitudes as he discussed poverty (against it), health care for all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (for it), and outbreaks of widespread killing (should do something to
stop them). Courting opprobrium, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> raised the touchy issue of
weapons of mass destruction and bravely declared that it would be bad if they
were used.

            
               Inspiring Yet
Empty Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> were
invited to provide campaign slogans for these presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> whose Web
sites lack such soul-stirring baloney.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McSaw, McConquered</ENAMEX>"-- Juris
Odins
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Want a Piece of This, Pal?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carvell</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight K. Lemke</ENAMEX> )

            "Not an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Idiot Like the Other</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trust Me</ENAMEX>, After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viet Cong</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Those Candy-Asses</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seem So Tough"</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
Solovay
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>
            

            "No, really."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Gisselbrecht</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quayle 200</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            "Now with more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn</ENAMEX>, Not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary"</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juris Odins</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>
            

            "I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Giddy for Liddy</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Free me</ENAMEX> from that albatross around my
neck."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde Gibson</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spontaneous From</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:55 to 12:00</TIMEX> Every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight K. Lemke</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blow-Free</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth"</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, look, I only work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ah</ENAMEX>, Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hell</ENAMEX> Not"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Solovay</ENAMEX>
            

            "He didn't brand his fraternity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">buttocks</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Crawford</ENAMEX>
            

            "So you think I'm dull
and cautious? I'll show you dull and cautious, you goddamn cocksucking
motherfuckers!!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Meyerson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Any Candidate
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meaningless Rhetoric</ENAMEX>
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Better Tomorrow</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Perspective</ENAMEX>
            

            "You didn't ask, but my
all-time favorite slogan comes from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race between
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> (and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX> grand wizard) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Edwards</ENAMEX>,
an (ahem) ethically challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who had been indicted--but
not convicted--for mail fraud, obstruction of justice, and public bribery. The
slogan? 'Vote for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX>--it's important.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
