
   
   
      
         
            Gross <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conduct</ENAMEX>

            
               
Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Pie</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews but a
boffo box-office turnout for this teen sex comedy about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> high-school
seniors determined to lose their virginity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> take one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> positions.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The gross-out scenes (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> shtups an apple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>; another drinks
a beer laced with semen) are just "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> bait to entice teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> into
the tent to see a movie that is as sweet and sincere at heart as anything
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Rooney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Garland</ENAMEX> ever experienced" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grossness</ENAMEX> is the film's essence: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>]irty jokes are
inserted at regular intervals like pop songs to perk up the action ... an
upper-middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porky's</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Pie</ENAMEX> is unable to transcend
its own dirty mind. Among <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s bumper <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> of teenage movies, it is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shallowest</ENAMEX> and most prurient" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The
most positive take comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>,
who writes that it's a "warped, hysterical and--believe it or not--sweet little
gem of a movie." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in

                  Slate
                and here to see the
trailer that includes footage of the teen-pastry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arlington Road</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Screen Gems</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are
unimpressed by this thriller starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bridges</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> who becomes
convinced that his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Robbins</ENAMEX>, is a domestic
terrorist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ) speaks for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
when he complains that the film "begins well and makes good points, but it
flies off the rails in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last 30 minutes</TIMEX>. The climax is so implausible we
stop caring and start scratching our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
Maslin departs from the pack, calling the film a "crackerjack thriller ... well
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paced</ENAMEX> and cleverly constructed." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to watch the trailer.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  True at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Light</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX>, edited by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Hemingway</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scribner</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> heap scorn on this edited version of an
unfinished "fictional memoir" left behind by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> and crucify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for their now routine desecration of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s reputation (see
the line of furniture, eyeglasses, and shotguns licensed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemingway Ltd.</ENAMEX>).
The prose in this "literary violation" reads "like a parody of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre Donahue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). It "reflects a marvelous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s
disastrous loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth S. Lynn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> ); a "sad,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bloated</ENAMEX>, inert so-called book" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.S. Klepp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, after opening her review with an
embarrassing parody of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX>'s style, writes that "his angular language has
turned maudlin and flabby." The most positive review comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wood</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Book Review</ENAMEX> : "The famous style occasionally flares into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fineness</ENAMEX> ... the book is never quite uninteresting." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to find out about
the legality of publishing a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s unfinished work, here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of this book, and here to check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' special on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX>
including photos, interviews, and essays.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metaphysical Touch</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Brownrigg</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). Positive reviews for this philosophical novel about an
e-mail romance. Although the plot seems ripped from You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> , the
novel is far more sophisticated in its execution--a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> Kundera-like inquiry
into ontology, the uniqueness of e-mail communication, and human existence in
general. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownrigg</ENAMEX>'s forte is her ability to emulate the "curiously banal,
clever-clever, quasi-poetic style that seems to afflict so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberspace</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoff Nicholson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ) in the
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">epistolary</ENAMEX> sections of the book, and she "wonderfully captures the ghostly
dance of presence and absence that can characterize digital relationships"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Davis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice Literary Supplement</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

            

               
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Better War: The Unexamined Victories and the Final Tragedy of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Sorley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harcourt Brace</ENAMEX>).
A retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorley</ENAMEX> posits a new theory on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> won, but the military victory was immediately
undercut by diplomatic backtracking and congressional cowardice. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> assigned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Record</ENAMEX> to review the book, which
seems an odd choice considering that Record just published a book titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The</ENAMEX>
Wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>: Why We Lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> . Record predictably refutes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorley</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thesis</ENAMEX> ("How does one explain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saigon</ENAMEX>'s fall when, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sorley</ENAMEX>, we had
won the war by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1971</TIMEX>?"), but he concedes that "A <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Better War</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> and long-overdue examination of the immediate post-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tet offensive</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, perhaps the most fascinating years of the war." Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> praise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorley</ENAMEX>'s research and writing: "A first-rate challenge to the conventional
wisdom about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military performance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>

            

               
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. K.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowling</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholastic Trade</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> installment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
series went on sale in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX>, resulting in after-school
stampedes on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>. Although not available in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> for another two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, advance orders have already placed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azkaban</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 6</NUMEX>
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> best-seller list--and positions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and two</NUMEX> are held by the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> titles. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> list has the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> available
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX> books at positions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and four</NUMEX>.) The subject of the new volume is the
same as the rest of the series: the life of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX>, who
attends a boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for sorcerers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call this one the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX> adventure yet: It "blends the banal and the fantastic, the everyday and
the magical, all with a devilish humour and a timeless sense of style.
Spellbinding, enchanting, bewitching stuff" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Davies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> ). A few gripe that the series is just a formula boys'
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">boarding-school</ENAMEX> adventure story gussied up with magical trappings (see last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s discussion in 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s</ENAMEX> ), but young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> don't
seem to care: According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloomsbury</ENAMEX>, the book's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azkaban</ENAMEX> broke an opening-day sales record--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,853</NUMEX> copies in the first
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">100 minutes</TIMEX> on sale. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to order an advance copy.)

            

               Music
            

            
               
                  Friendly
Fire
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lovano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Osby</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Note Records</ENAMEX>). Excellent
reviews for the collaboration between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s'</NUMEX> most acclaimed jazz
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saxophonists</ENAMEX>. "The telepathy flows on this much-awaited meeting. ... Both men
are noted risk-takers and cutting-edge improvisers whose penchant for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">maniacal</ENAMEX> makes them ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Stark</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inquirer</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Seymour</ENAMEX> writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> that "there's a sense of
play between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that's almost kinda sweet. Both are assertive. Neither
gets in the other's way." The only sour note comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Heckman</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , who objects not to the music so much as to the
structure: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he basic jam session format ... simply fails to sustain interest
for the entire album." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lovano</ENAMEX> and here to find out
more about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osby.</ENAMEX>)

         
      
   
