
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayatollahs</ENAMEX>

            The
crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> was the top story across most of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, though in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> it was overshadowed by those two
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' frantic efforts to save the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> peace settlement, and
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>'s imminent visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. In the
Far <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>, the big issue is the tension between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> over the
latter's abandonment of the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>" principle.

            The
student riots in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX> were taken most seriously by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>,
some of which led their front pages with dramatic headlines--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Day</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
War" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fist of the Ayatollahs</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>)--and devoted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> pages to
their coverage of the unrest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> ran an interview with Reza
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ciro Pahlavi</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shah</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, who expressed
eagerness to return to his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as a constitutional monarch. He criticized
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> for understanding too late the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s yearning for
democracy, saying that this was the cause of his overthrow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX> and now
of the student revolt against the ayatollahs. He called on the West to support
the pro-democracy movement and said that what matters most for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> now is
"faith in secularism, the separation of religion and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>." He hopes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> will "become the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to embark on the road of
democratization."

            
Historical comparisons proliferated in the comments on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pahlavi</ENAMEX> compared
the reformist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatami</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, saying he was
attempting an "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> perestroika." Corriere della
Sera likened the situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX> to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> referred to the repression of the student protests as "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
in an editorial that the uprising was reminiscent of the student revolt in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> that led to the overthrow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Suharto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>.

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq al-Awsat</ENAMEX> , urged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX> to slow the pace of his political reform program rather than play into
the hands of the hard-liners. "The latest developments vindicate earlier
warnings that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> might resort to provoking acts of violence,
followed by a harsh crackdown on free debate and freedom of expression," the
paper said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s only chance of finding a way out of its current crisis lies
through institutional politics, not the politics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. It would be
better for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX> to play a long-term game and not let his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>
dictate the pace at which he should implement his reform program."

            But in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahrain's Akhbar al-Khaleej</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assayed Zahra</ENAMEX> wrote that
"reform, openness, and liberty" are now inevitable in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. The only way
widespread civil strife can be avoided is "by the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> realizing
that time is not on their side and--should they decide to continue the struggle
through to its bitter end--they would be leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> to catastrophe." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Samaha</ENAMEX> wrote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arab al-Hayat</ENAMEX> that
the events in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX> show how much further <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> has gone down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> toward
democracy than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world has, because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> the movement for political
reform apparently enjoys mass popular support.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that, in the view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theocracy</ENAMEX> is still not in serious danger of
being toppled, but that if it were overthrown, it would have enormous
implications for the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> said, "We can only
hope that if the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> gain the upper hand in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, they will manage
to do so before the ayatollahs get their hands on strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that could
harm <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>." On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> saying
in a private meeting that the events in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> could change the face of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> in a "revolutionary" manner and might already have an impact on his
government's peace negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> believes that, while there
will be no revolution in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> in the short term, "changes will take place
faster than expected," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> led their front pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with headlines
saying there are "high hopes" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> wants "to connect with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in a way that will
allow him to extract a promise that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will not intervene in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> permanent status negotiations, nor make policy statements
without first coordinating positions with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX>
said he
hopes to "find a common language with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, a sympathetic
ear at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>, and a sense that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of tense <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>
relations are over." The paper quoted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> as saying he was
seeking only "an exchange of ideas and positions" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and was not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intending</ENAMEX> to commit himself to any timetables on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process,
but it added: "The sense that there is no rush is something of a facade. In
fact, time is of the essence. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming year</TIMEX> is crucial for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Daily</ENAMEX> , the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government newspaper</ENAMEX>, said
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Teng-hui</ENAMEX> was "overrating his strength, like an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant</ENAMEX>
trying to topple a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>." As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> continued to threaten force to halt
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s pretensions to independent statehood, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
Post of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> of pursuing a "dangerous course." Saying it
was unclear what he hoped to accomplish by ending his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy, the
paper commented in an editorial that what he had done was "weaken the
constructive ambiguity which has marked relations across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strait</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> or more, and which has kept them essentially peaceful." It said it
hoped that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>) "may yet find ways
of maintaining the useful imprecision of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is
missing an excellent opportunity to attack his leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s policies toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> began by embracing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, gushing about the
booming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> stock market and bragging about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of 'property
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>' created by the dream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anatoly Chubais</ENAMEX> and his privatizers," the
paper said in an editorial. "Now, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few short years later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> is defensively and guiltily struggling to ignore the world's largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and top <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> disingenuously profess not to be worried by the
sight of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">blackjack bombers</ENAMEX> flying over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> in a nose-thumbing
gesture at the West." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "so far does not seem to have the stomach for
what is really required on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>: an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> apology (of the sort <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> so
loves to hand out for the long-dead practice of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> slavery, for genocide
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>, and for other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> moral lapses) and a rebuilding, from the ground up,
of this key strategic relationship."

         
      
   
