
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> of the Paks

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> rejected the nuclear test ban treaty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">treaty</ENAMEX>,
which needed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> votes for ratification, was defeated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51-48</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only four</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> sided with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in favor of it. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
vowed to continue to fight for its ratification, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>
said it would not be reconsidered during his term. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> had promised
to follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> lead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> let politics trump
international security. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> spin: A treaty that flawed would never
have worked. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> reply: It certainly won't work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspapers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variously</ENAMEX> said the vote hurt <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s ability to set foreign policy
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s global leadership
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centrist</ENAMEX>, bipartisan politics (
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
               ).

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s military ousted its elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Coup leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pervaiz Musharraf</ENAMEX> suspended the constitution and declared the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to
be under military rule, but did not announce plans to install a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musharraf</ENAMEX> accused former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz Sharif</ENAMEX> of weakening the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>,
crippling the economy, and tolerating corruption. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> worried that
military rule would exacerbate: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the region's instability ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the fragility of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s democracy; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the ascendancy
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">militants</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakistanis</ENAMEX>' reaction: After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, anything will be
an improvement ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilt Chamberlain</ENAMEX> died. "Wilt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stilt</ENAMEX>,"
widely considered the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> of all time, is the only one ever to score
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> points in a game. He captured national attention in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> through an
intense rivalry with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Russell</ENAMEX> and again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> with his claim to have
bedded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chamberlain</ENAMEX>'s dominance as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center</ENAMEX> forever "changed the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> is
played." The 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX>
                declared that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamberlain</ENAMEX>'s skill
and popularity "saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>. ... Had there been no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilt</ENAMEX>, there would have
been no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J or Bird</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magic</ENAMEX> or--perish the thought!--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>."

            

               The world's population reached <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 billion</NUMEX>. It has doubled since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, but growth is slowing as urbanization, education, and family planning
increase worldwide. Most of the continued growth will occur in the developing
world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> will level off near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late in the next century</TIMEX>. The rosy spin: Despite what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomsayers</ENAMEX>
predicted, overpopulation hasn't caused global catastrophe. The gloomy spin:
Well, not yet.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> endorsed 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s presidential
bid. The endorsement lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s resources and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> for political organizing. The optimistic spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>'s support
gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> a great boost . The jaded spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>'s support for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> is a non-story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> spin: Either way, the
attention shows we're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to be reckoned with.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> remain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s playoffs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> are vying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> title. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> are
competing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX> championship. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Martinez</ENAMEX>
threw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six no</NUMEX>-hit innings in the final game against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sox</ENAMEX> only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> ever to overcome a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-game deficit in the playoffs' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX>, who barely made the playoffs after a dismal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-season</TIMEX> performance, are
competing with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> for recognition as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinderella</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> are fighting for recognition as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>.

            

               A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> grand jury issued no charges in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX>
case. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 months</TIMEX> of investigating, the jury deemed the evidence
insufficient. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Owens</ENAMEX> said he would assemble a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to continue the investigation. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> charged that the lack
of an indictment revealed that the police work was botched. Others said that
the continued investigation of a rich, white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s death showed that race
and class influence the justice system.

            

               A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> could be
extradited. If his appeals fail, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> could
stand trial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> charges of torture and conspiracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s spin:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is violating the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chileans</ENAMEX> by imposing foreign laws.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX>' spin: Look who's
talking about violating the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chileans</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacGregor</ENAMEX> won the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-vs.-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> boxing
match. The undefeated, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5-foot-4-inch</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unanimously</ENAMEX> won all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> rounds against male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loi Chow</ENAMEX>, who is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 foot 2</NUMEX> and has a record of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0-3</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> objected to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> hitting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacGregor</ENAMEX>'s supporters
said she had landed a blow for 
gender equality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detractors</ENAMEX> complained that she should have picked on
someone her own
size.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> criticized congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. First he said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> shouldn't "balance their
budget on the backs of the poor." Then he said his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> often neglects the
disadvantaged by focusing on economic wealth. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> a 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>'s clothing. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> of running for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on the backs of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said his comments made a "positive case" for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> compassion, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> said he was astute to recognize that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "revolution is dead" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). (
                  Slate
               's "" analyzes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "triangulation" strategy.)

         
      
   
