
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> on a Roll

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> earthquake continues to lead world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, though the focus has now
shifted to the inadequacy of rescue efforts, the difficult conditions for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>, and the apportionment of blame.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> and
Mail accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, which spends <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> on
armaments, of not having "the forethought to stockpile the heavy equipment
needed to dig <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out at quake sites." Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
contrasted the armed forces' success in battling the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish Workers' Party</ENAMEX> with its
failure to help quake <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>: "It turned out that while they could assault the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKK</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>, they could not even set up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup kitchens</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> after the earthquake."

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> took an unusual position, claiming that the carelessly erected <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of the
1980s, which have been blamed for the quake's massive death toll, represent
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s "attempt to escape from stagnation and backwardness by letting private
enterprise rip." During this building boom, "Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got rich quick, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corruptly</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> had taken a great, stumbling stride towards 'modernity,'
towards the unprotected free-market economy which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> enforces
on nations hoping to join it." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> defended the "fast-buck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>"
as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who carry within them the potential to bring about real changes
for the better after this catastrophe." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> concluded, "It's hard not to
conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> needs an old-fashioned, democratic, middle-class
revolution, in which these new social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> would take the political power to
which they are entitled. Only they can complete the transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
into a law-bound, stable and open <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. And the
earthquake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> would be remembered as a beginning, not only as a
tragedy."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
Post praised the response of emergency services staff to the
crash landing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chek Lap Kok Airport</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. Although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were killed and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 200</NUMEX> injured in the
incident, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that the prompt response undoubtedly saved lives. But
the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reported a contradictory sentiment from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> passenger, a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>: "I heard rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> talking on walkie-talkies
directing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to come to help. It sounded like they were not familiar with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>." According to the paper, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 230</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been killed in
accidents involving this model of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonnell Douglas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD-11</ENAMEX>--in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> has warned about wind <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shear</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX>, which opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African National Congress</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s hard-line stance
on pay raises has brought about its first showdown with public sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> general strike has been called for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24</TIMEX>, with the
participation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. Essential service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> who are forbidden to strike are expected
to come down with "white flu" on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has offered a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
percent wage raise for nonteachers and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.5 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educators</ENAMEX>, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> demand a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.3 percent</NUMEX> increase and more involvement in the budgetary
process. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg Star</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s refusal to negotiate "has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">united unions</ENAMEX> across the ideological and race spectrum for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>."

            Citing
a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX>
reported that there is strong evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
military has "worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia groups</ENAMEX> to sabotage" the upcoming vote for
autonomy there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Harkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, told reporters that he will call on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to "support the sending of armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to
the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>," even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
refused to allow international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> for the ballot. In
the Straits
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Reed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
should tie its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> aid to the referendum. He told the paper, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]f the
election is full of intimidation and it is not fair and there is retribution
after the election, then I think we will have to re-evaluate our assistance to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> in a very negative way."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX>
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of racing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pigeons</ENAMEX> sent out
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> of the recent solar eclipse have gone missing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Owners</ENAMEX> believe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> were confused by the blackout. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> pigeon fancier told the paper, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
don't know for sure whether the eclipse has scrambled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>' brains. But
whenever the sun and moon are in close proximity we have a very bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> with
lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> going missing." According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , this is the
worst disaster to befall the pigeon world since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> homing pigeons
were killed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">torrential rain</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">English Channel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1997</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
