
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Genetic Super</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Babies Storm&quot</ENAMEX>; 

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX>
               
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> on the tension between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> over genetically modified (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>. It reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s leading animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, have formed
a pact against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> soya <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX> imported from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
Glon-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bourgoin</ENAMEX>, have put together a scheme with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exclude GM</ENAMEX> soya from the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said that even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are beginning to show anxiety about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> foods. "The American
administration, which has collaborated with industry from the start to promote
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> foods, seems to be in an uncomfortable position," it said. "It is being less
threatening toward <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, which oppose these products." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s papers were largely dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doogie</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> mouse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
Mail underscored not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doogie</ENAMEX>'s possible role in helping old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
memory loss but the risk that he might give rise to an elite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> of high-IQ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetic Super Babies Storm</ENAMEX>" was its front-page splash.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
Figaro
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> money-laundering
scandal and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' threat to oppose any further loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers dwelt on the harm the
scandal may cause to the presidential ambitions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. In a
report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> said that "the risks to his
presidential bid are considerable." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> blamed Western reporting
of the scandal on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> machinations against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tycoon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, Nezavisimaya
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazeta</ENAMEX> , said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are "engaged in killing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> state and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> as possible economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>." Their
campaign has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main purposes, it said: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, to find a pretext for the West
to distance itself from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, whom it no longer needs as a bulwark
against communism; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, to dump <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> as a contender for the
presidency.

            As
anarchy continued in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> for
the breakdown of law and order in the territory. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, it said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> should be made to
pay "a very heavy price" if it continues to fail to deliver on the promises it
made so confidently before the referendum. "All aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> should be put
on hold until it has brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia groups</ENAMEX> under control," it said.

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> arrived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> to join the tense
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> peace negotiations, various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> press
drew parallels between the current state of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> politics and the indiscipline,
score-settling, and violence that marred the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-week biennial</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arab Games</ENAMEX>
which ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arab al-Hayat</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Samaha</ENAMEX> described some of the scenes shown on television during the
games: "One <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> assaults another. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> invade a pitch. A coach
curses an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> martial arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> attacks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bodyguard</ENAMEX> draws his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> fires tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> wreck the seats in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> or hurl them on to the pitch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Players</ENAMEX> are bombarded with bottles. A
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are wounded." They showed, he said, that there are some people
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world who refuse to lose--or even to draw--under any circumstances
whatsoever.

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the coup in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripoli</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, that brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qaddafi</ENAMEX> to power was marked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> by an interview with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-time <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giulio Andreotti</ENAMEX> (now on trial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> for
alleged connections with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> murder), who said that while in office he was
given false information about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence services. On one
occasion, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> touring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to convince their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qaddafi</ENAMEX>'s responsibility for a terrorist massacre at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>'s
Fiumicino <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1985</TIMEX> offered as evidence the fact that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> were carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tunisian</ENAMEX> passports stolen from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tunisian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andreotti</ENAMEX> replied that he knew for certain they were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> passports
as they were in the possession of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. "Are you doubting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retorted</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andreotti</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qaddafi</ENAMEX> had once given him a copy of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green</ENAMEX>
Book and asked him to hand it on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, which he subsequently
did. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> accepted it and said he would read it, but I don't know if he ever
did," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andreotti</ENAMEX> said.

            Among
many features in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> linked to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60 th</NUMEX> anniversary
of the outbreak of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> ran an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denis Mack Smith</ENAMEX>, who
said he has evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s invasion plans
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1939</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini hated Hitler</ENAMEX> and wanted him to be defeated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> said, but he eventually entered the war as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> because he was
frightened that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> would otherwise invade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>.

            An
interview given to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>, the queen of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>'s youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, brought down the wrath of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s British
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>, interviewed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> where he was trying
to drum up commissions for his TV production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, said he preferred doing
business in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> "they hate anyone who succeeds." The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> of letting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and its royal family down "with a
casual insult" made all the more distressing by the fact that the interview was
designed to promote his own commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> may feel it is
appropriately ingratiating to tell his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that there is a 'much
greater openness and willingness to take us for what we are over here,' " the
Times said in an editorial. "But does he pause to consider what effect
such a dismissal of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> will have, what outmoded stereotypes of a crabbed,
cobwebbed, and unenterprising <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> his words will perpetuate<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s mass-circulation tabloid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> went further. In an editorial
which both agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>'s comments and excoriated him for making
them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> called him "a pampered, privileged young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has
achieved nothing, despite being born with a royal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver spoon</ENAMEX> in his mouth,
despite all the undeserved advantages he has been handed." Then, praising
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s classless meritocracy, it said: "Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> should have got rid of
the royals too." This statement perpetuated doubts about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s attitude to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> on a commemoration ceremony for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">229</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sept. 2</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swissair</ENAMEX> Flight 111 crashed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nova Scotia</ENAMEX>. For the purpose of "adding to the closure" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>
of the deceased, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mountie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Arsenault</ENAMEX>, stepped up to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">microphone to sing</ENAMEX>. "Love will be our legacy," he sang. "When dreams get
tossed, we'll share the cost, and lay the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX> on the rocks."

         
      
   
