
   
   
      
         
            Thunderballs

            Early in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Spy Who</ENAMEX> Shagged
Me , the stumpy, snaggletoothed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Myers</ENAMEX>) survives
an assassination attempt by his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Hurley</ENAMEX>), who
turns out to have been a "fembot" programmed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nemesis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> (also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX>), to blow up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s honeymoon <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> rounds of zealous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humping</ENAMEX>. Following a suitable period of mourning for his exploded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> greets his restored bachelorhood with a frenzy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exhibitionism</ENAMEX>--romping nude through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> of his posh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, pointing out
his privates to assorted female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passers-by</ENAMEX>, and launching into a lengthy water
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ballet</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Williams</ENAMEX>-style chorines. Watching this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX>, I thought of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Niven</ENAMEX>, who, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1974</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
Awards ceremony, saw a streaker charge across the stage and brought the house
down with an ad-lib about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> "showing off his shortcomings." Niven
wouldn't get a laugh here: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> has rendered himself invulnerable to the
incinerating one-liners of prudes and sniggerers. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> might be oblivious to
his own ridiculousness, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> isn't. He has made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>'s "shortcomings"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s strongest suit and the act of showing them off both smashingly funny
and--yes--attractive. Forget about defeating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> represents
the exuberant conquest of shame.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spy</ENAMEX> Who Shagged
Me is better than anyone dared hope: bigger, more inventive, and more
frolicsome than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, with a grab bag of scatological gags that are
almost as riotous when you think back on them. I'm laughing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>: The movie
gives infantilism a good name. Let me add that I wasn't a fan of the first
installment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Man of Mystery</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), which
tanked after a lively opening. It was rife with overextended jokes--and the
strange thing was that the joke wasn't the joke, the joke was the overextension
of the joke. The terrible, flaccid timing was what was supposed to be funny. I
wondered: What does it say when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted performer</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> sets out to
make a "bad" movie, the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheeseball</ENAMEX> '60s Bond imitation that untalented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> made by accident? But I underestimated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX>' connection to the
material. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, he evidently fantasized about living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s
"swinging" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'60s</TIMEX>, portrayed in movies as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> when ugly, posturing little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
could routinely make it with long-haired, short-skirted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie chicks</ENAMEX> who'd
dance ecstatically while the camera zooms in and out. TV shows like
Laugh-In and movies like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino Royale</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Like</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flint</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>) must have got all mashed together in his wet dreams. His
resulting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alter ego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> before the Fall--provided you see
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fall as the mid-'70s</TIMEX>, when embarrassment returned to the culture with a
vengeance.

            It helps that in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Spy Who Shagged Me</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>
has soared in stature, becoming nearly as heroic a throwback as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
himself--the supervillain seeming far more vulnerable to the slings and arrows
of ridicule than the superhero. The bald, curdle-faced pinky-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> is still
locked in excruciating combat with his teen-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Evil</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Green</ENAMEX>),
who never misses a chance to jeer at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s grandiosity, and who in turn
is dismissed as "quasievil ... semievil." A partially successful cloning
attempt by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>'s henchman, Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wagner</ENAMEX>), has produced a true
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>: a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-eighth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil replica</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verne J. Troyer</ENAMEX>) dubbed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mini-Me</ENAMEX>" who's
like a distillation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">archvillain</ENAMEX>'s most feral impulses. This snarling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">munchkin</ENAMEX> gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> scenes--which still run long--a blast of
energy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>'s subtext of
sexual jealousy has become his motive. Covetous of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX>' lack of
inhibition, he contrives to go back in time--to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, when both he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX>
were cryogenically frozen--and steal the source of the secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>'s appeal:
his life <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, or "mojo." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mojo</ENAMEX>-less, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> panics when the opportunity comes
to shag <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicity Shagwell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Graham</ENAMEX>); mojo-laden, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>
leaps into bed with his heretofore lesbian henchwoman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frau Farbissina</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mindy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sterling</ENAMEX>) but, post-coitus, cannot maintain a guiltless hedonism: "It got
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weird</ENAMEX>, didn't it?" he murmurs.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Roach</ENAMEX>, keeps the picture bumping along,
refusing to give the gags more weight than they warrant. Actually, he rarely
gives them any weight: The bad jokes don't fall flat so much as blow
away like onion skins. The commercial tie-ins--for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heineken</ENAMEX>--aren't as oppressive as one might fear, although
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>'s AOL e-mail address is a cybernetic badge of uncool. You go to a movie
like this for the cameos and in-jokes, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Robbins</ENAMEX> popping up as a harried
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Bacharach</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Costello</ENAMEX> emerging to croon
(beautifully) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Do You Get When You Fall in Love?</ENAMEX>" In the credits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowe</ENAMEX>'s name is superimposed over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX>' bare butt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrelson</ENAMEX> appear, largely because their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names are euphemisms for "penis."
Now there's a riff on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Only Live Twice</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>), now a hyperbolic
parody of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thunderball</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>), now a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> slapstick involving an
electrical swivel chair. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> dispatches a new henchman, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400-plus pound</NUMEX>
kilt-wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotsman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fat Bastard</ENAMEX> (also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX>) to poke a long needle into
the frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>'s crotch. Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin</ENAMEX> mistakenly pours himself a cup of
"coffee" from a jar containing a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fat Bastard</ENAMEX> stool sample. There are also more
sophisticated, interlocking parodies, as when grim-faced NORAD radar operators
tune in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX> and find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> in the middle of a
show called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"My Father Is Evil and Wants To Take Over the World</ENAMEX>"--a segment
that degenerates into bleeping and fisticuffs when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">archvillain</ENAMEX> rushes an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indignant Klansman</ENAMEX>.

            No doubt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Graham</ENAMEX>
is one of prettiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. Her face has the freshness of a
junior-high-school yearbook photo--it might be the apotheosis of the
junior-high-school yearbook photo--and there's more than a touch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> in
her long thighs and high bottom. She knows how to move and she's sweet and
she's game. But, let's face it, she's a twittering blank--a bore. I miss the
witty poise that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Hurley</ENAMEX> brought to the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> .
More than that, I wish that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> had it in him to cultivate his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic actress</ENAMEX> and then let her rip--an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> who could be nerdy and
alluring at once, who'd have a comeback for, "I put the grrrrr in
swinger, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>." I nominate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Kudrow</ENAMEX>, but there are probably others. You just
have to be brave enough to look. For all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX>' fearlessness, he has yet to
prove his manhood by letting an equal into his bed.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> imbo , the latest effort from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sayles</ENAMEX>, strains
to be a great movie, to the point where it breaks into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different
movies--neither fully successful, but both with huge compensations. The first
is a grimly sardonic portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> as a kind of Third World melting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pot</ENAMEX>--full of desperate poverty and crime and on the verge of a transition to a
tourist-based economy in which the interior will be cleared of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">timber</ENAMEX> but an
illusion of wildness maintained. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, we're promised, will turn into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant</ENAMEX>, neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. The other story is the love affair between a
luckless torch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Elizabeth Mastrantonio</ENAMEX>) and a luckless ex-fisherman
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Strathairn</ENAMEX>), in which the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>--through a series of melodramatic
contrivances that testify to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sayles</ENAMEX>' lack of ingenuity as a storyteller--end up
together with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>'s brilliant, desperately unhappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> (Vanessa
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>) on a remote island, where they're prey to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold</ENAMEX>, starvation, and drug
smugglers with shotguns.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotting</ENAMEX> was never Sayles' forte. What he did have
from the start was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s insight into how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dramatize themselves and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>'s insight into how they actually appear. He can write sharp, funny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spiels</ENAMEX> and interlocking monologues in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> misrepresent themselves but
somehow--miraculously--communicate their essence. At some point, though, he
decided to become a saint of leftist independent filmmaking, to turn away from
his real gifts, suppress his craftiness, and make movies about ordinary people
crushed by an economic system that sets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>). He
cultivated a wanness in himself; he labored to locate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> within.

            At its worst, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Limbo</ENAMEX> is about when bad things
happen to good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and its ending is cruelly abrupt (although maybe
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">merciful</ENAMEX> if it means what I think it does). But its best is really good. I'm
not sure I totally buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strathairn</ENAMEX> as a diffident loner with an aching
conscience over a tragedy that wasn't his fault--the quintessential guiltless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sinner</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sayles</ENAMEX> has written some gorgeously tender and funny encounters
between him and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mastrantonio</ENAMEX>. And she is simply extraordinary. Always a superb
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> who never quite had the stature for a leap to stardom,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mastrantonio</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Lane</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Walk on the Moon</ENAMEX> --has developed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">layers</ENAMEX> and an edge. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna De Angelo</ENAMEX> (I hate that tart/angel name) is both
desperate to grab onto a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and smart enough to watch in horror as she's
grabbing. She has a torch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>'s simultaneous immersion and distance--a
talent for watching herself fall and for commenting on it exquisitely. This is
a major performance, one of the comebacks of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
