
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">255</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Sorry, Right Number&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parris Glendening</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances</ENAMEX>, released a statement
that began: "Early <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, we received a call that every parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dreads</ENAMEX>."
What did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> say?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 254</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too True To Be Good":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               I give the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> headline; you give a one-sentence summary of the story:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presidential Hopeful Displays Humanity</ENAMEX>."
            

            

               
                  (A tip of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatlo</ENAMEX> hat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

            "In an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unscripted</ENAMEX> campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">moment yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> was seen taking a sip of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Douglas</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> brought a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pygmies</ENAMEX> to a press conference just because they
looked 'so brown and cute.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> was arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> for exposing himself during a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Daughters</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Revolution</ENAMEX> luncheon."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> befriends a crippled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, predicts this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> will be 'the best
ever.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Anne Townsend</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon LaRouche</ENAMEX> to wed."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James M. Frisby</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Like cartoon
superheroes, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has but a single attribute, generally as useless as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Lantern</ENAMEX>'s illuminability, or greenability, or whatever freakish power
he had. Has? Had? Is he still running? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> is rich. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is
cruel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> is hollow. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is wooden. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> lacks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spontaneity</ENAMEX>, which is a lot like being wooden only if you poured a few drinks
into her, she'd loosen up, but he'd dissolve in some hideous yet unspectacular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemical</ENAMEX> reaction. But just as most comic book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> move on to other forms
of literature (despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Spiegelman</ENAMEX>'s unconvincing plea that "they're really
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">illustrated</ENAMEX> novels"), most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in a mature democracy demand more from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> than a packaged personality and a glib slogan. Wait, sorry, excuse
me--as it turns out, no, they don't.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>
Schweitzerian Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John R. Kasich</ENAMEX> stuck around after a meet-and-greet
to help his hostess bury a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.

            Backing out of the driveway to go get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> long shot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Kaiser</ENAMEX> ran over her Shetland
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep dog</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>. Not wanting to delay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kasich</ENAMEX>'s march to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser put Magic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>.

            After the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> had
departed ... well, let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> tell it: "I killed my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and he buried him. He
said, 'If I ever told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> I left without burying this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, we'd be
divorced. Get a shovel.' He's human, a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. He revealed himself as a
real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. I can't imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> burying my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bedroom Farce</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            All dialogue taken from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Conference on Mental Health</ENAMEX>. All stage directions
unfairly imposed.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>. THE PRESENT.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COSTUME</ENAMEX> NOTE. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> all wear unattractive blue suits; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wear
unattractive navy blue dresses, or vice versa. Everyone remains fully dressed
throughout.

            
(CURTAIN UP on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX> in a comically oversized bed, the sort of thing
you'd find in a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feydeau farce or on the Sonny and Cher Show</ENAMEX> . She looks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">radiant</ENAMEX>. Something is moving beneath the bedcovers.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VOICE</ENAMEX>
(from under the covers): I don't want to monopolize this ...

            TG
(ecstatic): I'm happy to say that it worked.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIKE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WALLACE</ENAMEX> emerges from under the covers, his "hair" tousled. He looks pleased
with himself.)

            MW: I
was lower than a snake's belly.

            TG: No
one could do that any better than the sunshine of all our lives, our first

            
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX> emerges from under the covers, happily disheveled.)

            HRC:
If I had any voice, I'd break into "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Are the Sunshine of My Life</ENAMEX>" and
dedicate it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tipper</ENAMEX>.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> emerges from under the covers.)

            BC:
It's been so long since we've come together.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GORE</ENAMEX> emerges from beneath the covers. He looks a little uncertain.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AG</ENAMEX>:
I'm anxious to follow instructions carefully, but to depart from my destruct
... or, to depart from my instructions, I want to say I hope you can see how
proud I am of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tipper</ENAMEX>.

            
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIPPER</ENAMEX> points to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s lap.)

            TG:
You might want to go over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AG</ENAMEX>:
Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ma'am</ENAMEX>.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GORE</ENAMEX> disappears back beneath the covers.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TG</ENAMEX> (to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AG</ENAMEX>): It's important. Because you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and you come forward and you can help
so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            BC
(with rising delight): No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in public life has ever done as much to try
and figure out how to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AG</ENAMEX>
(from under the covers): What I hear you saying is that anyone who talks about
how important it is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to stay together and be strong ought to also
be supportive of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in this situation.

            BC: I
sort of feel like an anticlimax!

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIKE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WALLACE perches</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s shoulders.)

            MW: I
feel better up here than ever in my life.

            BC:
How much did you weigh?

            (All
laugh affectionately and begin singing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie Wonder</ENAMEX> songs. )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CURTAIN</ENAMEX>.

            
               Merciless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quibbling Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            " 'All
the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jacksons</ENAMEX> now go by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>, simply because of one
androgynously desiccated freak,' asserted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M Pesca</ENAMEX> in his wrap-up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. Or
not ... You'll notice on the front page of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> a
reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt. Gen.</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gina Duclayan</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> who hasn't relinquished his name is a well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
Angeles talk radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard A. DeCamp</ENAMEX>
            

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Madden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline</ENAMEX>
Haiku
            

            Say hello to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sucker</ENAMEX> for kissing.
Obsession with vacuuming
Has complex roots.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
Inquirer , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3, 1999</TIMEX> (Features only)

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            They'll show you theirs.

         
      
   
