
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert</ENAMEX>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
               
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kings</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). Excellent
coverage all around for this offbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> adventure-drama directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O. Russell</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flirting With Disaster</ENAMEX> ). The "blisteringly funny" story of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who plot to steal hidden <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> bullion "works both as a
rousing action adventure movie and as a subversion of the genre" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ice Cube</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Wahlberg</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike</ENAMEX>
Jonze, all give excellent turns, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> is universally singled out:
He has created "some kind of weird masterpiece" that "sings with the
exhilaration of pure filmmaking" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ).
Strangely enough, the one negative review comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> '
usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chipper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, who complains that the wacky camera style and
tricks with film stock are "inadvertently distracting" and that the film
doesn't pick up speed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX>, when it's "too little, too late."
(Visit the film's
official site.)

            

               
                  Mystery
               
               
                  , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>).
A "glorified <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mighty Ducks</ENAMEX> for grown-ups" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> ) pretty much sums up the reaction to this tale of a small-town hockey
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> that gets a chance to play the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Rangers</ENAMEX>. It's clichéd and corny,
and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> wonder why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David E. Kelley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of so many successful
TV shows ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Law , Ally McBeal , The Practice</ENAMEX> ), has had
such a bad run in film (see <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Placid</ENAMEX> ) and why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Crowe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX> agreed to star in it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>--speaks up, calling it
"a dandy little epic" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowe</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Stiffed
               
               
                  : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Betrayal of the American</ENAMEX>
Man
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William Morrow</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s follow-up to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">best-selling Backlash</ENAMEX> draws a few laudatory reviews, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
consider it far below the standard of her previous work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Faludi</ENAMEX> sets out to
discover why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are so resistant to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s advancement but ends up with a
sympathetic portrait of the sorry state of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> manhood, faulting the
culture of "ornamentation" and the economy's removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from meaningful
jobs. On the positive side, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s reportorial and literary skills unfold
with a breathtaking confidence and beauty" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Gleick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ).
More often, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call the book "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">didactic</TIMEX> and highly simplistic"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX> finds a flaw at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center of Faludi</ENAMEX>'s thesis: She "assumes something that's no longer true: that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is in the throes of downsizing and loss"; and her focus on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marginalized</ENAMEX> and downsized distorts her view: "she should have said she was
talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>; she claimed to be talking about gender" (the New York
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Review</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to listen to an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Memoir</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>
               , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). Early reports of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' heresy (he inserted a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fictional</ENAMEX> version of himself into the story) appeared before the book was
available, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> picked up on it like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks sensing chum</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>
bit <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, snorting that the "the futile search for the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> had driven
his biographer barking mad" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ) retorted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> "seems incapable of a genuinely
serious thought" and commanded her and others to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shut yo</ENAMEX>' mouf" until they had
read the book. After <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> became available, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy Noonan</ENAMEX> derided it as
"a base botch of a book ... at turns bilious and cold, corny and cynical, manic
and flat" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ) and declared (as do many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>)
that the book represents a tremendous lost opportunity, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> had 14 years
of unlimited access to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. A few defend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>: His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unorthodox</ENAMEX> technique captures <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s contradictions and makes for "a very
strange, very interesting, very exasperating book, full to bursting of both
lies and honesty" that calls to mind some of fiction's most masterful
unreliable narrators, such as "the madness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Kinbote</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hendrik Hertzberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lehmann-Haupt</ENAMEX> writes a
solidly positive review: "I can think of few conventional political biographies
that bring their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>' pasts so richly alive" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' other reviewer voices the conventional wisdom, calling it
"a bizarre, irresponsible and monstrously self-absorbed book" (Michiko
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kakutani</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read a discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Club</ENAMEX>.")

            

               
                  The
               
               
                  Big <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Test: The Secret History of the American</ENAMEX>
Meritocracy
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). Critics
adore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of Lemann</TIMEX>'s history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX>. But when he turns in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the book to the conflict over affirmative action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
they wonder, "what does all this have to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.A.T.</ENAMEX>?" (Lehmann-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haupt</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Seligman</ENAMEX> writes in the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> is "a dazzling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in the clutches of a bad idea."
Others are kinder but note that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> decries the unfairness of the
present system (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' scores correlate directly to the wealth and
education of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>), "he doesn't altogether define what should take its
place" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lacayo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> .)

            

               Art
            

            

               "Sensation
               " (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum of Art</ENAMEX>). The brouhaha
over this show of young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, which appeared at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Academy of</ENAMEX>
Art in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, began when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> blasted
the exhibit as "sick" because it included, among other things, a portrait of
the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> splotched with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant dung</ENAMEX>. Now the reviews of the exhibit
are in, and although most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s right to exhibit what it
wants, few defend the art : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appallingly</ENAMEX> witless and stupid" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kramer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Teachout</ENAMEX> calls it "strictly
adolescent stuff" that reveals that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> ... are still trying, poor
dears, to be outrageous" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Whiteread</ENAMEX>'s work
gets a sprinkling of praise, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics weakly</ENAMEX> contend that "the best
work in the exhibition basically does what all good art should do: It makes you
think" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). But the lack of
enthusiasm is palpable. And what's more, many in the art world are less
disgusted by the art in the show than by the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Saatchi</ENAMEX>, the ad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> who owns every piece, has found the perfect way to increase the return on
his investment, as many of the works will go on the auction block at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie's</ENAMEX>
when "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" ends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read a debate in 
                  Slate
               
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> whether the show is worth the fuss.)

         
      
   
