
   
   
      
         
            Gunned Down

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild Wild West</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). No debate on this one--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
hate it. (A sample jab, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>: "The film is an
unmitigated disaster.") Despite the winning combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Smith</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Sonnenfeld</ENAMEX>, who struck <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> together with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> can't overcome the horrendous script. The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX> calls it "an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-legged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX>,"
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> writes that it's "just not there."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ) sums it up: "[It's] a comedy dead zone.
You stare in disbelief as scenes flop and die. ... There are moments when all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">artifice</ENAMEX> fails, and you realize you are regarding desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, trapped on
the screen, fully aware they've been left hanging out to dry." Or, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wloszczyna</ENAMEX> advises in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Handle West</ENAMEX> like an old boot:
Sniff at your own peril." (Visit the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bigger, Longer &</ENAMEX> Uncut
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>).
After emphasizing just how gross this film version of the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy</ENAMEX>
Central series is ("the potty-mouth on this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-rated cartoon is pretty
mind-boggling"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Dauphin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> go on to
praise it: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilarious</ENAMEX>, willfully filthy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ) calls it "tasteless, irreverent,
silly and smart." Nasty highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) A torrid gay affair between <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) An enormous talking clitoris. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) A series of musical
numbers, one of which is titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bitch</ENAMEX>." Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> do not
admit to being offended, save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, delivering a far more negative
review than most, admits he laughed all through the film but says, "I did not
always feel proud of myself while I was laughing. ... A lot of the movie
offended me." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read a less positive review of the film: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> is another movie straight from the smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pits</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hell</ENAMEX>," and for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s rave in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  Summer of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sam</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX>'s
latest worthy but deeply flawed. The film follows an insulated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian-American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1977</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> killer
was terrorizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. On the upside, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leguizamo</ENAMEX>'s performance as a
philandering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairdresser</ENAMEX> is "raging, startlingly visceral" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s evocation of the tension that gripped the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blackouts</ENAMEX>, looting, and violence--is enthralling. On the downside, the film is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX>, wandering, and something of "a glum and unpleasant experience" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
Turan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> also say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s
direction tends toward the heavy-handed. Ebert departs from the pack, giving
the film <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and a rave review: It "vibrates with fear, guilt and lust."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX> Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933-1938</TIMEX>
                  
               , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanche Wiesen Cook</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>). Reviewers praise the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s
biography as well researched, thorough, and fascinating. Many also take it as a
point of departure for talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>'s review in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> is largely a laundry list of the
differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and her admitted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>] did not engage
in the shadowy manipulation practiced by other opinionated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Ladies</ENAMEX>. ...
Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> ignored personal insults, sloughed off negative news."
Dowd ends her review by asking, "Are you listening, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>?" Most notably, the
book reveals excerpts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s letters that confirm suspicions, raised
in the previous volume, of her amorous relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reporter Lorena Hickok</ENAMEX>. Also of note are explicit examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s
anti-Semitism both in her private life and her public life: She was an advocate
for the oppressed in all corners of the world--except, apparently, in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to listen to an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, courtesy of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .)

            
               
                  
                     Wonders of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invisible World: Stories</ENAMEX>
                  
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Positive
reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> story collection (after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
novels, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize finalist Jernigan</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> calls it "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' best so far." The stories range in topic from a gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who takes in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> while she checks into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rehab</ENAMEX>, to an old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s religious awakening after a stroke. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> writes in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> "delineates his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' predicaments
with a pitch-perfect ear," the collection suffers when "a certain authorial
smugness creeps into the narration," which leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> "feeling superior
to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, irritated with their solipsistic mind games and
self-inflicted wounds." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
read one of the stories in this collection.)

         
      
   
