
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> Juice

            I still have my notes from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that morning</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, in the Q <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wing</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State Prison</ENAMEX>: steak, broccoli, hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Lipton tea</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last meal</TIMEX>. The lights go off, throwing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> into darkness, as the
prison switches to its own generator. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 a.m.</TIMEX>, the door in the back of the
death chamber opens, and there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Tafero</ENAMEX>--slender, bald, white--standing
between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> and looking at the chair like he can't believe it's real.
I'm attending his execution as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> and covering it for my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami Herald</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tafero</ENAMEX> sit down and tie him to the chair
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather straps</ENAMEX>. He says his last words and then stares out at each of us,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> stuff a gag into his mouth. "He is defiant," my notes
say, as if I can read his mind. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> slip a black leather hood over his
face and screw the head electrode, with its circular sponge, down onto the top
of his skull. Ready, set, go. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six minutes past 7</TIMEX>, the electricity hits Jesse
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tafero</ENAMEX> and his head bursts into flame.

            Some things you can't
escape--can't burn them, can't box them up, can't run far enough or fast enough
away. I thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Tafero</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> when I read about the
execution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Davis</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> electric chair. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> started to bleed
when the electricity hit him, soaking his shirt bright red, scaring the
assembled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. "The chair functioned as it was designed to function," is
what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> said.

            And in a way, that's absolutely true. If tidy executions
were the point, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> could have switched over to lethal injection a long
time ago. Pretty much all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> has been insistent about
keeping its lethal furniture, even though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last nine years</TIMEX>,
beginning with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Tafero</ENAMEX>, the chair has gone awry. Fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, fire in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, and now blood. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> continues to fend off legal challenges
to its right to electrocute, behaving as if death itself weren't punishment
enough.

            It's no coincidence that
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> was born of electricity--without air conditioning, none of it
would be possible, not those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course condos</ENAMEX> or tall beach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> or trailer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parks</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> spreading across the shallow limestone shelf that separates
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> soil from the sea. Down there, more than in other places, electricity
is power, the fine bright line between life and no life, which is the same
thing as between life and death.

            The electric chair came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the middle of the
first great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> land boom, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> was conjuring itself up out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX> of grass. Back then, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> executed by hanging, which wasn't a foolproof
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> either. Some of the noosed choked to death in those dusty
jailhouse courtyards, but that wasn't what bugged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> about the method. The
problem was that hangings were popular and sometimes drew huge, raucous,
picnicking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>, an image that didn't quite mesh with the orange-blossom
gentility the land <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX> were trying to create. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX> moved death indoors to the chair, away from the curious and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mayonnaise-smeared.</ENAMEX>

            Somehow, the electric throne made death seem
civilized. But those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">carefree days</TIMEX> when frying someone was a sign of progress
are long gone. The chair has become an anachronism, an unpleasant physical
reminder that the death penalty involves death . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, starting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> switched to lethal injection. Only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> still
electrocute, and of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> is by far the most enthusiastic.

            You see, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
likes the chair. Its collective blood-thirst hasn't changed much since
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of public hangings. Following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' bloody demise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
proclaimed that the execution let everyone know that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> was against the
murder of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. After the chair misfired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attorney General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Butterworth</ENAMEX> similarly explained that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't want to burn up while
being electrocuted, then they should commit their capital offenses somewhere
else. Burn 'em up and warn 'em off: The only thing unusual about the chair,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX> thinks, is that it isn't used often enough.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Outsiders</ENAMEX> think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executioners</ENAMEX> are sadistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morons</ENAMEX>. Nothing could be further from the truth. If anything, they're
frustrated home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>. Consider for a moment the "science" of
electrocution at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State Prison</ENAMEX>. When flames erupted from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Tafero</ENAMEX>
during the execution I witnessed, prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> blamed the fire on the
water-filled <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sponge</ENAMEX> attached to his head that was placed there to conduct
electricity from the electrode. The sponge, purchased by maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at
the local five-and-dime, was highly flammable because it was synthetic ,
they determined. To demonstrate their theory, they bought another synthetic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sponge</ENAMEX> and stuck it in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen toaster</ENAMEX>, where it caught on fire. A simulated
execution was conducted with a fire-resistant sea sponge: a tub of water
standing in for a human body and a colander for a human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. After that, only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX> sponges could enter the death <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>.

            But when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Medina</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> caught fire during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1997</TIMEX> execution, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Corrections</ENAMEX> to write down its electric chair
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protocol</ENAMEX>, previously just a folksy word-of-mouth operation in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Q Wing</ENAMEX>. The
ruling came out of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> lawsuit filed by condemned inmate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo Alexander</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, who argued that the electric chair was cruel and unusual punishment. The
state, by way of saying thank you, ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> to watch the chair's next
trial run. This time, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal salad</ENAMEX> bowl played the role of the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> to keep the
chair, with the dissenting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> comparing the chair to the guillotine.
Since then, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> have left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them from the pro-chair
side. It's hard to imagine that this latest "incident" won't have an impact on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, which is currently reviewing another legal challenge to the
chair.

            Heavy use of the chair--43 executions in the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>--has put some wear and tear on the device. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corrections</ENAMEX>, which had previously told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that the chair was in good
shape, up and called a structural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and paid him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> to inspect the
chair. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> reported that the chair itself, the wooden part, needed
replacement. It just so happened that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Corrections</ENAMEX> had another
electric chair, a full-size replica that it had had manufactured and then
placed on display at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s tiny and strange <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tallahassee</ENAMEX>.
While still in the death <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> had snapped a few quick
pictures of himself sitting in the chair, and he is planning to use them as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s concern
wasn't the condemned: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> were worried that if the chair broke apart
during an electrocution, the thick, black, high-voltage wires screwed to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inmate</ENAMEX> might rip loose and electrocute everybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flames</ENAMEX> , my notes say, about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tafero</ENAMEX>'s
execution. Flames and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX>. It is impossible to put into words. What
does it look like when someone catches fire while strapped to a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>?
The flames are nearly a foot high, they arc out from underneath the black
leather hood; there is smoke, the huge buzzing sound of the electricity, there
are white walls and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian</ENAMEX> blinds and linoleum underfoot. There's ash falling
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tafero</ENAMEX>'s shirt and he's nodding his head, he's heaving his chest in and out,
tied down with those thick leather straps. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executioner</ENAMEX> turns the power on
and off, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times in all, and in between the jolts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tafero</ENAMEX> is moving, he's
nodding, his chest rises and falls. He looks like he's still alive. Then the
electricity hits him again, and the fire rises from his head, from the black
leather mask, and he shudders forward and is slammed back against the chair. It
takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven minutes</TIMEX> before the prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> pronounces him dead, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven minutes</TIMEX>
of heaving, nodding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX>. You can't see his face because the mask
covers it, but as you walk past him on your way out you notice his hands there.
There's a sore on his right pinky finger, a raw spot, flesh rubbed off to blood
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oak</ENAMEX>, from where he was clawing the chair.

         
      
   
