
   
   
      
         
            CuteFella

            After his notorious arrest
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> vice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Grant</ENAMEX> showed up on talk shows to
promote a new film and--it couldn't be avoided--offer an explanation for his
"crime." Well, not an explanation precisely. Asked about the incident, he'd
wince, bite his lip, bat his eyelashes, shrug sheepishly, and look adorably
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abashed</ENAMEX>. His contrition was so winning that one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> suggested he could
make big money as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> accused of human rights abuses.
(On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s gassing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>: "Rather a bad move ... terribly
sorry." On the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>-led slaughter in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarajevo</ENAMEX>: "Most embarrassing ... frightful
lapse in judgment.")

            In the gangster farce
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mickey Blue Eyes</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> takes adorable abashment to delirious new
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">heights</ENAMEX>. He plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Felgate</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX>-like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> auction house, who proposes to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gina</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitale</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeanne Tripplehorn</ENAMEX>), and then discovers she's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and niece of
powerful crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>. Suddenly forced to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vito</ENAMEX> and
Vinnie, to bury a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East River</ENAMEX>, and to make like a gangster
with a voice that's a cross between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tweety Bird</ENAMEX>, the squeamish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman winces</ENAMEX>, bites his lip, bats his eyelashes, shrugs sheepishly, and
looks--yes--adorably abashed. The shtick would be irritating as hell if it
weren't so ... adorable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> does abashed the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogie</ENAMEX> smoked, the way
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn</ENAMEX> flared her lips. He's not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> of range (to say the least), but his
charismatic discomfort--his breezy uneasiness--makes him a marvelous
romantic-comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>.

            And the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mickey Blue Eyes</ENAMEX> give
him an excellent pedestal. It's the stuff of classic farce, which puts the
wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the wrong place at the wrong time and then fiendishly ups the
ante. Pressured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gina</ENAMEX>'s spooky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> (a superbly restrained turn by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX>) into auctioning off a paranoid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s painting--a resurrected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
putting holes in disloyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> with a submachine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> must
simultaneously keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> happy, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> (who'll pull the plug on
the engagement if she finds out he's enmeshed in the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>) in the
dark, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> from discovering the collusion, and--most important in farce--a
semblance of dignity. His upper-crust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> is forever escorting a potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, so that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> can walk in on him in poses that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> vice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> would find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Makin</ENAMEX>, hits
the gags hard--he turns punch lines into slug lines--but his timing is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crackerjack</ENAMEX>. The trick in pulling off this kind of comedy is to wind a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jack</ENAMEX>-in-the-boxes in full view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> yet still make it a surprise
when they start--at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> of peak pandemonium--springing up. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screenwriters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Scheinman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Kuhn</ENAMEX>, have boned up on their Feydeau
and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fawlty Towers</ENAMEX> --not to mention the slew of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> movies to which
they cheerfully make reference (and from which the filmmakers have hired most
of the supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>).

            What goes wrong? In the
last <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX>, the farcical pulse gets lost amid the crosses and
double-crosses and triple-crosses and erupting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood squibs</ENAMEX> and dud psychology.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Caan</ENAMEX> begins hilariously as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gina</ENAMEX>'s hearty, lunkish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, but then has to
get all noble under the weight of the picture's dumb, melodramatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contrivances</ENAMEX>. Worse, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linguistically</ENAMEX> hapless gangster--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Blue</ENAMEX>
Eyes--never makes a climactic reappearance, so the filmmakers waste their best
invention. As long as I'm carping, even the movie's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX> has problems. I
found the basic setup--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> has no inkling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gina</ENAMEX>'s family
ties--implausible, since where I come from you don't ask a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to marry you
(you don't even get past <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first date</TIMEX>) until you've explained to her the ways
in which your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> screwed you up and have expressed tender sympathy for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> in which her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> did likewise. Am I the only one who thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Drama of the Gifted Child</ENAMEX> is the dating manual of the
'90s?

            While I was on vacation, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> wrote to say that
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch Project</ENAMEX> hadn't scared them but, oh boy, did they freak
out at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sixth Sense</ENAMEX> . Here, they said, was one skeeery movie!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Backlash</ENAMEX>, shmacklash ; The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project messed up my head
more than anything since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night of the Living Dead</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>), so The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sixth Sense</ENAMEX> had me shivering in anticipation from its opening credits. Two
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> later, I emerged with tear-stained cheeks and a lot of admiration for the
"gotcha!" ending (the clues are there, but one shakes them off as arty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mannerisms</ENAMEX>) but not especially frightened. The ghosts were seen too clearly--I
could practically smell their greasepaint and mascara. The larger point is that
the movie, directed and written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Night Shyamalan</ENAMEX>, belongs to a different
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre than Blair</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Witch</ENAMEX> , which traffics in the irrational, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unseen</ENAMEX>, the terror of malevolent nothingness. The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixth Sense</ENAMEX>
uses the supernatural for reassurance. For all its bogey<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shenanigans</ENAMEX>, it
wants to leave you with faith in a higher order--in the possibility that even
after death wrongs may be avenged, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX> protected, and the loose ends of
one's life tied up. Ultimately, it has less in common with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX>
than with such quivering lumps of sentiment as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ghost</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Field</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dreams</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>). The film could be subtitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nightmares</ENAMEX> .

            It's often wrenching
anyway. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX>' damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child psychologist wanders</ENAMEX> through an autumnal
universe from which the warmth has been bleached (the pale yet deep-toned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cinematography</ENAMEX> is by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tak Fujimoto</ENAMEX>), social intercourse is vaporous, and sounds
seem piped in from another dimension. (A bus accelerating and decelerating is
like a lonely groan.) As the haunted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in his charge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Joel Osment</ENAMEX>
regards the therapist sadly, as if seeing into his (lost) soul. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osment</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pinched</ENAMEX>, old-young face suggests an ancient's insight without an ancient's
defenses--a sensitivity so exquisitely morbid that you worry more for his
emotional than physical well-being. You worry, too, for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, played with
tremulous fierceness by the wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Collette</ENAMEX>. "Look at my face," she
says, when her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> ventures the idea that she must think he's crazy. "I
would never think that. " Maybe I've spent too much time with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Drama</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gifted</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Child</ENAMEX> , but that part reduced me to a puddle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mush</ENAMEX>.

            More post-vacation catching up: The rave reviews for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twin Falls Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowfinger</ENAMEX> made me eager to see them, but
neither really floated my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is an absorbing, low-budget art movie
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> conjoined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>, the weaker of whom is dying and mordant, the other torn
(so to speak) between loyalty to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and a tenuous connection to the
external world--embodied in part by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Hicks</ENAMEX>) who looks like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Fonda</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampira</ENAMEX> and acts like a slightly less wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">porn star</ENAMEX>. You
can't exactly say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ho-hum</ENAMEX>, another sentimental Siamese-twin flick," but
somehow I felt as if I'd been here before. It isn't just the willful echoes of
Basket Case (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead Ringers</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>). It's the way the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twins</ENAMEX> (played by co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Polish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Polish</ENAMEX>, who also directed
the film) are photographed to look so wanly beautiful and dear , like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of the play (not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX> movie) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Elephant Man</ENAMEX> . They seem
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enigmatic</ENAMEX> when whispering in each other's ears, but when you actually hear what
they're saying it's so humdrum that you wonder why they even bother to talk.
There are brilliant <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX>--a flickering, black-and-white dream, in which
they're separate and riding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX>, is like a gorgeous home movie from the
'20s unearthed from someone's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX>--but the mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Arbus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freakiness</ENAMEX> and heart-tugging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bathos</ENAMEX> finally feels a little cheap.

            Cheaper still is most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowfinger</ENAMEX> , a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-joke movie that's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Wood</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>) without the poetry or emotion
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Burton</ENAMEX> managed to coax out of re-creations of Grade Z genre flicks.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> joke--a bunch of untalented, impoverished filmmakers devise a movie
around a paranoid action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX>) who has no idea that he's even in
it--is occasionally a hoot, but it also requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> to act like a
scaredy-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat Negro</ENAMEX> out of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'30s</NUMEX> ghost movie. I laughed, but I came out
depressed. On the basis of his script and performance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>'s vision of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moviemaking</ENAMEX> is of a scam perpetrated by hustling morons. Has he been spending
too much time with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
