
   
   
      
         
             Culture War

            After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> tragedy, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> held guns
responsible for the slaughter, and another blamed the culture. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
question has been debated into the ground, I confine myself here to the culture
question.

            The culture that was blamed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> was never
clearly defined. Its nature was suggested by terms such as "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>,"
"liberal," "permissive," "sex and violence," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, television, and
video games," and it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that bore most of the complaint. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
was told to clean up its act, and theater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> were urged to enforce the
ratings system, to avoid exposing young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to sex and violence.

            Then along comes the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX>, who earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> killed a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korean-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and wounded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> (coming out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX>). This time around, nobody
is blaming the culture--at least, not the culture that supposedly caused
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> killings
were categorized as "hate" crimes. Hate crimes include crimes not only against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> but also against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
City), and the technological <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX>). They are not crimes against
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> known personally to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perpetrator</ENAMEX> or against whom he has a
grievance. (If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> shoots his brother-in-law that is not called a hate crime,
although there is probably hate involved.) They are crimes in protest against
the culture, intended to make a statement of their hostility to the
culture.

            Of course, nobody can blame the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> culture or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
for these crimes. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s'</NUMEX> slogan was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Make love</ENAMEX>, not war," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
culture is a culture of acceptance--of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. In fact, it is
that very culture of acceptance that infuriates these madmen.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>, on
the other hand, shot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they knew, some of whom they had real or imagined
grievances with. But they also fancied themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>. They were making a
deadly statement against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dream, of respectable, middle-class,
suburban life. To that degree <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> was also a hate crime.

            According to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> poll, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two weeks</TIMEX> bracketing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbine</ENAMEX> incident, the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who thought that the country
was on the wrong track rose from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent to 60 percent</NUMEX>. This remarkable
swing is commonly attributed to shock over the shooting. While I can understand
the national bewilderment the event caused, I cannot understand why it should
be interpreted as a judgment against the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is going. Two
estranged young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX>--which they certainly did not
get from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>--made a deadly protest against the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is going.
This is not a sign that something is going wrong, except for the ready
availability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>.

            If you compare the
murders linked to hate crimes with the murders linked to street crimes, the
most obvious thing you notice is how the number of street killings dwarfs that
of hate killings. But despite this, street killings do not cause revulsion
against the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is going, though they may more legitimately raise a
question about the media than hate killings do because they more resemble
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depictions</ENAMEX>. Most cinemaland murders are committed by bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> whose
motives are pragmatic, not symbolic. Also, these murders are marked by
indifference: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perpetrator</ENAMEX> does not value life, and he feels neither guilt
nor glory at having killed someone. The hate killer values life and thinks he
is committing a great deed and making a grand statement when he kills.

            Despite these similarities, one should be cautious about
assigning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> responsibility for the culture in which street crime
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flourishes</ENAMEX>. The screen is not the only place--and probably not the most
influential place--where young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> acquire ideas of what is acceptable
behavior. They learn these ideas at home, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, at the shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street corner</ENAMEX>, and everywhere else where they observe life and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the ghetto don't have to go to the movies to hear shooting.
What they see on the screen seems real to them because it conforms to what they
see in life. Otherwise it would have no more effect on them than seeing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feud</ENAMEX> and swordplay between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montagues</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capulets</ENAMEX>.

            When I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> we used to go to the movies on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and watch the
violence between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>. We knew it wasn't real. Though we played
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cowboys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, we did not kill any real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX>. The
reaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> to those movies may have been different.

            There is something in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> attitudes that condones or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glorifies</ENAMEX> murder, at least more so than in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. If we want to
change that attitude, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> should not be the main place we look.
(Remember, most of the rest of the world watches <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movies without
engaging in orgies of violence.) We have to try to do something about the real
world in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are growing up. The crucial part of that world is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> relate to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. What to do about that, I don't know.
Probably there is little that public policy can do. But the fixations on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> culture do not help in the search for remedies.

            It would also help our thinking if we could avoid
the "sex and violence" mantra. Sex on the screen, or the abundance and
explicitness of it, has only a distant connection, if any, with the homicides
that worry us. Context isn't everything, but it's worth noting that the TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> that shows the most violence is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">History Channel</ENAMEX>, with its endless
replaying of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>: I have not heard anyone say that is an encouragement
to crime.

         
      
   
