
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cad</ENAMEX> Is Back

            On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the eve of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> anniversary of the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, her
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover Maj.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hewitt</ENAMEX>, received an astonishing torrent of abuse from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> press. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> largest circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> vied
with each other to damn him in the most extravagant terms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
called him a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judas</ENAMEX>," a "heartless <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>," a "rotter," a "love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>," and a
"repulsive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> described him as a "cad" and a "love rat [who] gives other
rodents a bad name." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewitt</ENAMEX>'s offense is that he has written a book of memoirs
and sold the rights to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , for a
reported <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750,000</NUMEX>.

            The
book is presumed to draw on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">64</TIMEX> love letters written to him by the late princess
during their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> affair that, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> , she
implored him to burn. Instead, they were stolen from him by a subsequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Ferretti</ENAMEX>, who tried to sell them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> for a
large sum. Instead of publishing them, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> handed them over to
the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewitt</ENAMEX> then successfully sued to get them back but promised
to keep them private. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that he intended to keep his
promise, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> reported that "hurtful claims" based on the
letters have already been published in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. It also noted
coolly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferretti</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>, is "extremely ill" with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in the south of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> warring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> were united in pious indignation against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> for buying the serialization rights. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> called the
paper treacherous and hypocritical, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> said: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
begs everyone to refuse to pay out for the book. And we urge every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> to
tell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewitt</ENAMEX> to get lost." They were divided, however, about whether a statue of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> should be erected as a memorial to her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> , which
is pro-statue, has attacked the queen for having expensive monuments made to
several of her dead dogs but refusing to support one for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>. It claimed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in its front-page lead that the pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX>, who sang at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s funeral, is supporting the campaign. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> said in an
editorial, "The fact is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princes William</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> do not WANT a statue. They
don't WANT the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to go on mourning their mum. ... And that, really, is the
end of it."

            The
Independent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> marked the anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death by examining the effects of her crusade to abolish land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>. It
said the greatest test is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where she spearheaded her
campaign. "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX>, government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Unita</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> are again laying mines
more intensively than ever," it said. While the land mine has been proscribed
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> (not including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and--most
important--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX> remains "its macabre <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> window," the
paper said. It and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that have seen most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> laid
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> published an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonas Savimbi</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Unita</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>, who was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> but has now been abandoned by it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savimbi</ENAMEX>, who still controls <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>, blamed his
loss of international standing on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> opportunism. "Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, we were
useful for fighting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX>," he said. "And,
without false modesty, by comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, we were
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>'s best 'freedom <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>.' But once the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> left,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had no use for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unita</ENAMEX>. Since the big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> change of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>
[the election of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>], it has contacted us only to ask us to sign our
surrender, and to consent to our political, even physical, liquidation." The
interview, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> claims is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savimbi</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>,
contained no reference to land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>.

            As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on their future, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> ran
a comment from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> blaming the West for exacerbating the
tragedy by its "romantic passion for encouraging the pettiest of nationalisms,
not least that of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a small island in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">archipelago</ENAMEX> populated by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 million</NUMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Bowring</ENAMEX>, said that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> is "in the grip of self-righteous moralising" over preserving colonial
boundaries left by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>. "If the issue here is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Timorese</ENAMEX> identity, why
not a chance for independence for all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>?" he wrote. "Or is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>
defined not by geography and its own ethnicity but by its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> past and
the backgrounds of its independence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>?" In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Herald</ENAMEX> said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that, while the vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timor</ENAMEX> marks a new beginning for the territory, this is also "a day full of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreboding</ENAMEX>." The last say over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>'s future is with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX>, who
must be forced to pay a price for any failure to honor the result of the
ballot, it said.

            As the
prospects for implementing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> peace agreement remain gloomy,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> attacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for appeasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>,
which has reportedly "exiled" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 432</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> since the
signing of the agreement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. Calling this "a systematic flouting of
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>, a murderous form of gangsterism by which republicans seek to
exert their illegal authority over 'their' areas," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an
editorial: "If one could imagine such a process applied across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isles</ENAMEX>, that would be equivalent of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> violently evicted from
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. The methods of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> are being practised in the
country <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> governs. Peace is mocked in our time."

            On its front page, the
Times ran a story about an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who astonished the
chess world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> by becoming the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to beat a grandmaster. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howell</ENAMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Nunn</ENAMEX>, one of the world's leading chess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>, in a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10-minute</TIMEX> match during an official tournament.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nunn</ENAMEX> shook the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s hand, but then abruptly left the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
