
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">307</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Scotch and So ...&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Graham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Queen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Carnegie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Wallace</ENAMEX>--what's the
connection?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Faintness, Nausea, Disneyness":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Something in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> is irritating both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>. What? ( Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaffin</ENAMEX>. )
               
            

            "The
adorable cartoon character <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader Chipmunk</ENAMEX> (TM) who sings 'Gee, I'm glad I
have a foreskin!' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Solovay</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Continuing series of 'land for peace' deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea World</ENAMEX> trivializes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East</ENAMEX> problems."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Defevers</ENAMEX>
            

            "
'Zip-a-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dee-Doo-Dah</ENAMEX>' is considered to be a totally inappropriate soundtrack for
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mickey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wailing Wall</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goofy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
addition of the words 'and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>' to the sign: 'To ride <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Mountain</ENAMEX>
you must be this tall.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX> had a
similar answer.)

            "The
centuries-old conflict over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epcot</ENAMEX> is the vacation <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestine</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> interesting
fallacies are debunked by this little contretemps. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pseudomoderate</ENAMEX>'s mantra: "If both sides are mad at us, we must be doing
something right." I believe that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> said about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>. It wasn't persuasive then, and I don't believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> will find it rhetorically effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. When both sides are mad at you,
it's seldom because you are a model of fairness. What you probably are is
simply wrong. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> is the exciting but all too often disappointing notion
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can unite against a common enemy. At least for very long. Although
it would be gratifying if mutual loathing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> brought about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
peace. Or mutual loathing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Martin Short Show</ENAMEX> brought about a
reformed TV season. But don't count on it.

            
               Kicking

               off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Atonement Season Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Epcot Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
will open <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Millennium Village</ENAMEX>, featuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s patented phony-baloney
cheerful view of all the little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the world.

            Among the national displays is a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journey to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>," a simulation ride partly financed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, that
either does or does not acknowledge that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> capital, depending
on whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> has met with most recently. But either way, somebody's
going to be mad.

            "Their statement ignores all the important issues
we put before them" said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein Ibish</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Anti-Discrimination</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>.

            "We understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> would like to have it a fun
world after all, but it isn't," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Foxman</ENAMEX>, national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the
Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League of B'nai B'rith</ENAMEX>.

            "We are an entertainment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and we do not take political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX>," declared a delightfully
disingenuous company statement.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Eager to show concern for the right kind of people
and to make it clear that he won't shed a tear (or spend a dime) on the--you
know--bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> have been promiscuous with the
phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working Families</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Victorians</ENAMEX>'
"deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX>."

            Which of the following are actual displays of this
determination to smile at the good and frown at the bad?

            

               "I want to share some good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>."-- Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> often lack the most precious of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commodities</ENAMEX>: time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; time to teach them right from wrong;
time to pass on their values."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
               

               "We need to support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> by providing the afterschool
programs they want to give their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a safe place to learn and enrich their
lives with positive values."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 14</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Russell</ENAMEX> endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s leading role in improving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
educational system and addressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who is talking about real change to improve the
lives of working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Boc</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, citing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s leading role in improving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s economy and
his tireless efforts on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>: "He has been a
tireless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for the working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> has a great tradition of community and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and I
look forward to working with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to further <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s goals of
revolutionary improvements in education, livable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, continued
safeguarding of the environment, and bringing positive change for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> will continue to work for a balanced approach and fight for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> and healthy environment for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiki Moore</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>.

               "With this new enforcement tool, we can better
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protect America</ENAMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> against drug trafficking, illegal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immigration</ENAMEX>, and threats to our ocean environment," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> said.
"And as far as I'm concerned, the rest of you bastards are on your own," he did
not add.

            

            
               Answer
            

            All, of course, are
genuine. And pandering. And condescending.

            
               Ongoing

               Extra
            

            There's still time to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">submit</ENAMEX> badly needed campaign slogans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>. Answers to run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            It's a bad, bad song.

         
      
   
