
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Death Penalty</ENAMEX>

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa Public Television</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> was asked to summarize the
message of his campaign. "I understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> don't create wealth," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
began. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Governments</ENAMEX> create an environment in which entrepreneurship and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> can flourish. That's why I support cutting the tax rates. That's why
I support getting rid of the death penalty."

            Hold
it right there. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> just say he's against the death penalty? And what on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX> does that have to do with creating wealth?

            He did
say it, and it has everything to do with creating wealth. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> not only supported the death penalty; they campaigned on a promise
to apply it more often. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s victory in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> elections,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>-to-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> pledged to bring every plank of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor, including "an effective, enforceable death
penalty; beginning to phase-out the marriage penalty in the tax code; allowing
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $39,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> without penalty from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>; a capital gains cut and indexing."

            Along
the way, the two "penalties" merged. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> began to use the phrase "death
penalty," like the phrase "marriage penalty," to describe a tax pegged to one
of life's most sacred passages. The inheritance tax, which had been known as
the "estate tax," became the "death tax"--which in turn, by association with
the hated "marriage penalty," became the "death penalty."

            Two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Chamber of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> he would do something about "unfair" taxes, starting with the "death
penalty." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, declared
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could use the surplus to address "a serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unfairness</ENAMEX> in the tax code, such as the marriage penalty, the death penalty,
taxes on senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last weekend</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> adopted the same phrase.

            The
transformation of the inheritance tax into the "death penalty" provides more
grist for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">satirists</ENAMEX> who wonder whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, having condemned the
"marriage penalty" for discouraging marriage, now worry that the inheritance
tax is discouraging death. (For a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> start on the satire, check out the work
of 
                  Slate
                necro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> and .) But the true import of the new
"death penalty" is the demise of the old one. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>, and Armey
would never have called the inheritance tax the "death penalty," because the
death penalty meant something else. Today, they can speak out against the
"death penalty" without confusion or irony--and without being asked for
clarification--because the traditional meaning of that phrase is no longer
plausible. Capital punishment is no longer a live issue.

            What
killed it? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> things: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incomes</ENAMEX> went up, and crime went down. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> stopped
feeling scared and started feeling comfortable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> stopped talking about
saving your life and started talking about your life savings. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>,
they don't complain much about the death penalty anymore. The last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who did
that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX>, and look what happened to him. Now every serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> either supports the death penalty and makes a show of it, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has, or keeps his mouth shut.

            The old death penalty
debate was profound and heated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> called the practice murder.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> called it the only fitting punishment for unspeakable crimes. It
was a moral struggle of the highest consequence. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, unspeakable
crimes are no longer spoken of, murder is what happens to your portfolio on a
bad day, "family values" are debated through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX> code, and the
"death penalty" is a tax issue. It may be a perfectly worthy topic in an age of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affluence</ENAMEX>. But it's hardly a matter of life and death.

         
      
   
