
   
   
      
         
            Nuclear Terror in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s major nuclear
accident was the world's top story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and reignited the debate about
nuclear safety. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> painted a picture of great confusion and official incompetence,
prominently reporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s admission that it reacted too slowly and
that there wasn't enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at the site to handle the crisis. In one report,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX> close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokaimura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> processing
plant heard on television they had been told to stay indoors when in fact they
had received no instructions whatsoever. When they telephoned local government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in a panic, asking to be checked for radiation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> they had
been ordered not to leave, they were told the checks were being done only at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village community center</ENAMEX>.

            
In another story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the disaster would deal "a serious blow" to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s much-criticized nuclear energy policy. It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> as
saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokaimura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> wasn't equipped to handle a critical mass
accident and lacked automatic controls over the flow of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>. In an
editorial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> had never before
been exposed to such radiation from a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. Calling for an
exhaustive inquiry, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "The future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s nuclear energy
program now rests in large measure on how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> responds."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> comment, it was often recalled that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to
have suffered the effects of an atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>, the
paper's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, wrote: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> ends with the
return of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX> ... to undermine the dominant belief of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> culture,
the certainty that it's enough to obey one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX> for
everything to turn out all right. It crushes the heart of someone who knows
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> a little and loves it a lot to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokaimura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> come out of the building infected by the out-of-control chain
reaction, bowing and apologizing for their betrayal of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> abandoned on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> islands for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> who asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>'s
pardon for having lost the war."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX>
said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has changed beyond recognition over the past
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">half-century</ENAMEX>: "A backward and semi-feudal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> has been transformed into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s fastest-growing economy, and is well on the way to achieving superpower
status." But the paper deplored the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s continuing "intolerance of
dissent" and said that until it reverses its official verdict on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen</ENAMEX>
massacre "it will be hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to take its place among the ranks of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>." Calling for political reform and free elections, the
paper said: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing</ENAMEX> still is not an option. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has achieved much in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The challenge now for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> is to build on these achievements
and prove that it can win a popular mandate through the ballot box."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Herald</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with the death of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 5-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> after he was hit by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> food parcel. He was struck during the same
emergency aid drop that caused a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> to have his leg amputated.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airdrops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> were cancelled after these incidents, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX> has started taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> into remote regions by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, the paper
said.

            
A claim by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>--to have found proof
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Neanderthal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was a cannibal was fronted in Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.
In a cave in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ardeche</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alban Defleur</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marseilles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim White</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California at</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> discovered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100,000-year-old</TIMEX> human bones mixed up with those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, all of them looking like the leftovers from dinner. Searching for
meaning in this discovery, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> concluded in an editorial that "[a]t the very
least the wary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit</ENAMEX> might understand the feral roots of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>--of the
steak tartare seeping blood onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limoges</ENAMEX>, of ortolans devoured in one
bone-shattering mouthful. One might even dare at last to enter a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurant</ENAMEX> and order a waiter."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> reported the launching at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">University</ENAMEX> of a student
campaign to fire the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> from his position as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX> on the grounds that he is a "bigot and racist." He caused outrage
during a factory visit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX> when he said that a defective fuse box "must
have been installed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an Indian</TIMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Age</ENAMEX> fronted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s disclosure that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
origin have achieved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> status.

         
      
   
