
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buggin</ENAMEX>'

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s papers don't know if they should try to explain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s actions
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>--his sudden dismissal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Stepashin</ENAMEX> and his naming
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifth premier</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 months</TIMEX>--or write them
off as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">silliness</ENAMEX>. Most conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is
democracy-impaired. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX>
blamed his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> past. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is "essentially a party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hack</ENAMEX>, schooled in the arts of personal survival through manipulation of rules,
arbitrary acts and unpredictable alliances. In this he is in the dark company
of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Duma</ENAMEX> and provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX>, a generation
of former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> thrown into democratic forums for which they have no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instinct</ENAMEX> and little respect. It will take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> of a bureaucratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> give way to those of a liberal democracy,
whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s legal framework says." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
concluded that the "episode only shows how abnormal a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> remains,
utterly unschooled in the orderly democratic transfer of constitutional
power."

            Some
papers pointed out the essential contradiction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s repeated
protestations about his commitment to democracy and his selection of a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>" with little chance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legitimately</ENAMEX> winning a presidential election.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>
Times said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s problem seems to be that he wants to
be remembered as having overseen the first democratic transfer of political
power in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>--but at the same time doesn't want to give up power. This is
the intractable contradiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> keeps bumping up against."

            The
escalating violence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagestan</ENAMEX>--where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last week</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> militants from across the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> border seized several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">declared Dagestan</ENAMEX> an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--was described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petersburg Times</ENAMEX> as "the other crisis." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
Times said, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>]nce again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> are bombing Chechen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guerillas</ENAMEX>--with the same dismaying inaccuracy that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> claimed so many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and roused so much anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> sentiment." The same editorial asked,
"Why are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFOR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> should be
brought home and redeployed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> south."

            
Another border dispute flared up again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> shot down a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> crewmen. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> claims the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spy</ENAMEX> mission in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> airspace, accusations <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> denies. In an editorial
titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamikaze Tactics</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> described the incident as "a
regrettable necessity" and said that "[f]or the sake of peace and security in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> and beyond, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> has to sensitise the international community to
the new threat posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> took a parallel track when
it editorialized, "This latest incident ... should serve to open
eyes and minds in the western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">world</ENAMEX> and give <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX> their useful
insights into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>'s unreconstructed hegemonic intentions." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu of</ENAMEX>
Madras, on the other hand, recommended that both nations call a cease-fire in the spin war:
"The danger at the present time is that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>--one facing crucial
elections and ready to reap the rewards of chest-thumping triumphalism and the
other confronting a resurgent fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militancy</ENAMEX>--seems in a hurry to
help de-escalate."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX>, who is under a death sentence,
announced that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdistan Workers' Party</ENAMEX> has renounced violence and is
willing to surrender its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> rights. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> said
that the offer "gives <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> another chance to deal with its largest and most
fractious minority in a reasonable way. With luck and wisdom, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> could now
end a bloody insurgency that has cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 31,000</NUMEX> lives, slowed economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> and given <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> one of the world's worst records in the human
rights field. But doing so will demand more tolerance and flexibility than any
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has shown to date. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX>'s preferred attitude towards its
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> is to deny they exist, in an ethnic sense, by contending they
are really something called 'Mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>.' " The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> says that now
"there is a chance to reverse this sorry record."

            A
feature in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> described a debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> over vending
machines that dispense ... beetles. According to the piece, "collecting live
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX> has a long tradition in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>," but with increasing urbanization and
the loss of wild habitat, they are becoming more difficult to find. As of this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, there's no need to schlep out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> just to stock up on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bugs</ENAMEX>:
A pair of live horned beetles can be purchased from a vending machine for
around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.50</NUMEX>. The machines have been tremendously successful--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,500</NUMEX>
beetles were sold from them in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservationists</ENAMEX> complain that
"automated bug sales are a step too far and teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that living
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> are of no more value than tamagotchi electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> in the
beetle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> department store (who has a pair of okuwagata stag
beetles captured from the wild "on sale" right now for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $43,000</NUMEX>) told the
paper that the bugs "might actually like it in a machine because they seem to
be comfortable in dark, narrow spaces."

         
      
   
