
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> Cultural Fallout

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> blames <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s uranium accident in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokaimura</ENAMEX> on misguided
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> cultural values. "In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, technical association codes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethics</ENAMEX> put the greatest emphasis on protecting public safety, health and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX>. Loyalty to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> on the list. Quite probably the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokaimura</ENAMEX> accident could have been avoided if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> among those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX>, company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> had applied such a philosophy."
Despite admissions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> had flouted government-approved guidelines
for the handling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> and comments reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> from Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> that
"safety practices in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> are 'a bit lax,' " the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> restated
its commitment to commercial generation of nuclear power <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.

            The
seizure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myanmar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burma</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, by
pro-democracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> "achieved precious little to advance the cause of the
hobbled pro-democracy movement in that benighted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," the Straits Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> said in an editorial. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> demanded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myanmar</ENAMEX> military
regime release its political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> and start a dialogue with dissident
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aung</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Suu Kyi</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> be allowed to
convene. Although the demands were not met, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> taken at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX> were released unharmed, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> were allowed to escape.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myanmar</ENAMEX>, arguably one of the world's harshest military regimes, is bound to
crack down even harder on political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> after what happened," the paper
argued, adding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burmese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> could now lose their safe haven in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> since the sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> cannot be seen to support
terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The editorial encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to press <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myanmar</ENAMEX>
to break its stalemate. It concluded, "It is far better that the military
regime drops its state of siege and deal with Ms <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Aung San Suu Kyi</ENAMEX>, who espouses
non-violent principles, than let the situation fester."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> had called on pro-independence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> to give up their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.
An editorial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMH</ENAMEX> said, "In the overall
interests of peace and stability, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Interfet</ENAMEX> [the international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>] must have a monopoly of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for the foreseeable future." Admitting
that it will be difficult to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falintil</ENAMEX> to disarm while
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> remain, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "When the last <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> has
left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, the rationale for the guerillas remaining a fighting force
will be gone as well. It is then that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falintil</ENAMEX> should hand over its
weapons."

            At the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX> conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> made what the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> called a "jingoistic" speech blaming all
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s problems in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 60 years</TIMEX> on continental <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>."[I]n my lifetime
all our problems have come from mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> have come
from the English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of the world that have kept law-abiding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberty</ENAMEX> alive for the future," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> said. A party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> told the
Times the flap was a "storm in a teacup ... in her lifetime <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> have been the major threats to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>." An op-ed in
the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>'s legacy has proved "positive" for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tories</ENAMEX> it has been "little short of catastrophe." Once
the luster fades from the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the column said, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> "had better be standing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centre ground</ENAMEX>. For if, when people
turn around to look afresh at this strange anachronism called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative</ENAMEX>
Party, they find it where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX> wants it to be--clinging to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>'s skirts
on the far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Right</TIMEX>--they will simply turn straight back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX>."

            Lino
Oviedo, who fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> after he was accused of involvement in
the assassination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paraguay</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, was exiled to a remote
Patagonian island <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> for violating the terms of his asylum, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buenos Aires</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> . Oviedo, who had agreed not to make political pronouncements,
broke his pledge by declaring that he should be running <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paraguay</ENAMEX>. Now from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tierra del Fuego</ENAMEX> he's complaining that the harsh climate might endanger his
recent hair transplant. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> editorial said, "The
argument that his hair implant needs more time to take root was not only
legally flimsy but also highly unbecoming for his rugged martial profession and
his tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> image." More berugged than rugged, perhaps.

         
      
   
