
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rieff</ENAMEX>

            If "intellectual" were a title like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">baron</ENAMEX>" that
could be inherited, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have a stronger claim to it than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Rieff</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, most notably, of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Freud: The Mind of A Moralist</ENAMEX> . His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essayist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>, filmmaker, and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sontag</ENAMEX>, as iconic
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> as our resolutely anti-intellectual culture is ever likely to
recognize.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of their brief marriage, may
well prove to be the most influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. He is certainly the
most visible, holding forth in the pages of everything from the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salmagundi</ENAMEX> . More than any
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX> has tried to mold the lessons of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> into
a coherent worldview. For him, these wars exposed the political bankruptcy and
strategic incompetence not only of Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> but, even more starkly,
of the international do-gooder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Committee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX>, and the proliferating nongovernmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> that provide relief on the ground in times of emergency.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX> has relentlessly
argued that the prevailing paradigms of humanitarian assistance and
international law are inadequate to the brute realities of the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
world. A willingness by the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX>--in particular the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>--to
intervene on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side in military conflicts rather than treat them as
quasinatural disasters is the only way to advance the causes of democracy and
human rights. While his response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> has been, as
we shall see, ambivalent, the decision to intervene is evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX>'s
arguments have, for the moment, prevailed.

            There is an obvious irony in the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of one
of the most implacable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> imperialism in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> should
emerge as one of its most vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. More amazing still is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX> couches his saber rattling in the language of dissent. He takes
strong, uncompromising positions that leave him curiously unaccountable. When
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, she returned with the conviction that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> victory was the best outcome for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and for the
world. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> since, she has had to grapple with the consequences of
that position. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX>'s interventionist stances on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> evade such
reckoning. He is always ready to take a position on what should have been
done.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX> has also
short-circuited criticism by making arguments that, if they are not flatly
self-contradictory, can only be the stages of a grand dialectical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">work-in-progress of Hegelian</ENAMEX> complexity. He has hailed those who work for NGOs
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, while decrying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGOs</ENAMEX> themselves as "feudal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX>" of "the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">medievalism</ENAMEX>." He has heralded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the nation-state</TIMEX> and dismissed rumors
of its death as exaggerated. He is a self-described "Neo-Wilsonian" who is
skeptical of liberalism, hostile to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, and suspicious of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">empire</ENAMEX>. He has called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of civil society "the useful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> of
globalization" even as he has co-edited a new book-- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Crimes of War</ENAMEX>: What the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX> 
               Should 
               Know --that seems to rest its hope for a humane
international order on the shoulders of transnational, extra-governmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. The only position he consistently advances is that he is right
and everyone else is wrong.

            Before he became the intellectual conscience of the new
world order, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rieff</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, reviewer, and travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
books, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Going to Miami: Exiles, Tourists</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Refugees</ENAMEX> in the New America
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX> of the Third World , relate his discovery that
the cultural geography of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> was being transformed by a new wave
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from the Third World. Apparently, he made the discovery all by
himself. The nonimmigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rieff</ENAMEX>'s
books to be, if not entirely clueless about what's going on around them, then
at least hopelessly unable to explain it. "Everyone I knew was taking the
transformation of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in stride," Rieff marvels in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> . Not him: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Often</ENAMEX>, I would sit in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and be literally
unable to follow the conversation going on around me, so mesmerized was I by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Laotian</ENAMEX> busboy, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX> parking lot attendant, or the Haitian
dishwasher--our new fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX>. Who are they? I thought. Who are we? I
thought." What the hell are you looking at? thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Laotian</ENAMEX> busboy.

            Even then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rieff</ENAMEX> was
thinking on a global scale, pondering the decline of the nation-state, the
transformation of the international economy, and the obsolescence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>. He was also indulging his taste for grandiose pronouncements:

            
               The great lesson of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s decline was that the curtain comes
down just as surely on historical periods as it does on individual lives. ...
And what could be said about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> seemed to me to apply also to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> as
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a whole</TIMEX>. In retrospect, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganism</ENAMEX> had been less a period in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> reassumed the mantle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in which new empires--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Community</ENAMEX>--began to take their proper role in the
world.
            

            In retrospect, this is nonsense, but at the
time it no doubt seemed prophetic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX> might have reread these passages
before he wrote a scathing review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas L. Friedman</ENAMEX>'s The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> and the
Olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Tree</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, in which he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ridiculed Friedman</ENAMEX> for just this kind of naive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extrapolation</ENAMEX> of the future from
the present. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> may be guilty of the fatuous contention that no two
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX> have ever gone to war with each other, but
Rieff, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> , indulges in some fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mysticism</ENAMEX> of his own
when he sees a harbinger of our globalized, miscegenated, Third World future in
the advent of the pita fajita.

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
aims an occasional rhetorical jab at the left, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> book on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exile</ENAMEX> , was an act of defiant apostasy, sympathetic to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">émigrés</ENAMEX>' sufferings and aspirations, and contemptuous of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. In
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">precincts</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> left that still dream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Maestra, Rieff</ENAMEX>'s book was greeted with murmurings of disapproval--the
kind of murmurings that had greeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sontag</ENAMEX>'s famous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town Hall</ENAMEX> declaration of
the moral equivalence of communism and fascism <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years before</TIMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rieff</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to explore the transformation
of its cultural geography by Third World immigration. He ended up,
fatefully, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarajevo</ENAMEX>, just as the first details of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian</ENAMEX> genocide were
becoming known. His experience in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> awakened his conscience, and made his
career.

            The book that resulted,
Slaughterhouse: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and the Failure of the West , is an unrelenting
indictment of the international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s inability--or unwillingness--to
step in and stop the killing. It is an odd piece of reportage, with no interest
in the evocation of place. This is post-traumatic journalism--repetitious,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impatient</ENAMEX>, and emotionally raw. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnians</ENAMEX>--in whose name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rieff</ENAMEX> brings his
indictment against an indifferent world--function as a kind of abstraction. We
see very little of their lives, and only rarely hear their voices. They are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laotian</ENAMEX> busboy, only more like us. At the heart of the book is the claim that
by treating a political cataclysm in strictly humanitarian terms, Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> assured the destruction of a democratic,
multicultural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and abetted the cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fascism</ENAMEX>. Those who protested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> because it lacked a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
mandate should read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> to see what an earlier mandate
produced: ethnic cleansing superintended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in blue helmets.

            Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> was the West's attempt to compensate for
the failures outlined in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as last September</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rieff</ENAMEX> opposed military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> in an op-ed, calling such
intervention unwarranted because the sufferings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> "pale in
comparison" with the starvation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>.
"Unless one believes that the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> are intrinsically more
valuable than those of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX>, the humanitarian justification for military
intervention is unsustainable," he wrote.

            Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rieff</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contradict</ENAMEX> himself again? Has he already forgotten that Slaughterhouse
castigates former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX> for making a
similar formulation, describing as "racist" the world's attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and
disregard for the sufferings of the Third World? Didn't Boutros-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghali</ENAMEX> earn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX>'s undying scorn when he told the besieged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sarajevans</ENAMEX> he could name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
places in the world where things were worse?

            But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last autumn</TIMEX>'s dove became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>.
Shortly after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombs stopped falling and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> capitulated, Rieff
assessed the lessons of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> in a short <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> piece that made the
case--from the safety of retrospect, naturally--for ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. The question
of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> was not strategic, but moral. "Had the West been willing to
unleash a ground war to secure its military, humanitarian and human-rights
objectives," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rieff</ENAMEX> argued, "there would be more room for optimism." So much for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern Sudan</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> piece did allow that, in
spite of having "to fight a just war with one hand tied behind its back ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> actually succeeded to a greater extent than might have been predicted."
"Might have been" is either disingenuous or overly modest, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rieff</ENAMEX> himself
had, almost from the start, pronounced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s action an unambiguous failure. In
a cover story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rieff</ENAMEX> painted a grim picture
of "lost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>." "The real question," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rieff</ENAMEX> insisted, "is whether the refugee
emergency is going to be permanent ... or whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> actually intends to
fight a war that will allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>."

            If that question has, for the moment at least, been
answered, you won't hear it from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rieff</ENAMEX>. Don't expect to see him marching
in any victory parades. But don't look for him at any protest marches either.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months ahead</TIMEX>, you'll most likely find him in the pages of the opinion
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> or across the table from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rose</ENAMEX>, heaping scorn on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and, of course, the left, whoever they
are. He will continue to lecture us on the importance of choosing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>, and of
fighting to win. He will remain passionate, eloquent, and sure of himself. But
I, for one, can't read him without hearing the strains of an old marching song
from my own left-wing childhood. Which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> are you on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>? Which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> are
you on?

         
      
   
