
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danforth</ENAMEX> on the Case

            

               Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Danforth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Mo.</ENAMEX>, will lead an independent inquiry into
the assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> appointed him in
response to revelations that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> lied about the use of tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>. Everyone
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">agrees Danforth</ENAMEX> is principled and independent. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> say his appointment
will rebuild support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>, who has done an "extraordinary job ." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> is still incompetent
and should resign . (
                  Slate
               's and assess
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s performance.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> is in chaos. Military-backed
militias have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> and forced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> to flee since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> territory voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> for independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. Martial law
has been declared, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> has rejected a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> offer of peacekeeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. The international community is debating whether continued inaction
would be: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) prudent because it is important to maintain good relations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) foolish, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s inability to maintain peace makes
intervention inevitable; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>) hypocritical in light of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>' active role in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. (For more, see 
                  Slate
               's ".")

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is suspected of taking bribes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> say that a construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> may have paid him over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>
in exchange for contracts to renovate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> denied the charges.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> hinted that it doesn't believe him. Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> expressed
weary distaste and suspicion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is mixed up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">money-laundering</ENAMEX> scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> speculated about whether he will quit early
and whether he will name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> as interim <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or
force an election.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> is buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> . The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 billion</NUMEX> marriage would be the
largest media merger ever and would join television's highest-rated network
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX>' spin: It's a perfect fit , since the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would control the
creation, production, and distribution of TV shows and movies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX>'
spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>'s ascendancy reflects a new
balance of power --niche programming beats out shows aimed at wide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX>' spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yaaawn</ENAMEX>. Let's just hope they don't cancel
Touched by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angel</ENAMEX> . (
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moneybox</ENAMEX>" the merger.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> signed a peace
deal.
                The deal modifies the previously signed but unfulfilled Wye
agreement. The rosy spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> at last! The skeptical spin: That's what they
said when the last deal was signed. The cynical spin: Now that the peace
process is back on track, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> are staging bomb attacks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to make
sure it's derailed again. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> shocked everyone by
restricting the authority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to use force against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">detainees</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" explains the between
peace and terrorism.)

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s clemency
offer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> linked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
bombings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, agreed to renounce violence in exchange for
their freedom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> had announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that she no longer
supported her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s offer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicos</ENAMEX> disagree about which was clumsier:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s offer of clemency to cultivate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> support for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign; or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s rejection of that support in an attempt to
cultivate her own identity.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> declared his candidacy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. He
emphasized his small-town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">upbringing</ENAMEX> and his distance from the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> scene. The pessimistic spin: He can't beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, who
is well-funded, well-connected, and leads in the polls. The optimistic spin: He
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trails Gore</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a few</NUMEX> points in crucial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and will take off as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
fatigue grows.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisneros</ENAMEX> pleaded guilty to a misdemeanor charge of
lying about payments to his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>. He accepted the plea bargain
just before being tried on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> felony counts. The unanimous spin: Yet another
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> has wasted vast sums of money trying to prove a flawed case
against a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, home. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX>
McAuliffe, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX>, used his own money to secure the
loan for the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. Pundits whether the assistance was an
apolitical gesture of friendship or an attempt at improper influence.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comets</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's National Basketball Association</ENAMEX>
championship.
                They have won the title in each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>. Everyone now agrees they're a "dynasty." The pessimistic view:
This robs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WNBA</ENAMEX> of suspense and makes it boring, which a fledgling league
can ill afford. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WNBA</ENAMEX>'s view: Having a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dynasty</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> helps the league
market itself. The long view: Relax, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dynasties</ENAMEX> haven't killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s
game.

         
      
   
