
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cows Eat</ENAMEX> <EM>Merde</EM> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die</ENAMEX>

            
Biological horrors dominated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The main subject was the
food war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, which has refused to import <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> in defiance of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> decision that it is now safe and doesn't carry mad cow disease.
British anger with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> was compounded over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> by the revelation
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> are partly fed on processed human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">excrement</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> is "furious" with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Brown</ENAMEX> for his "personal decision" to boycott French
food. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> is apparently worried this could precipitate a "full-scale trade
war."

            
According to the front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brits</ENAMEX> have already declared a "war
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarkets</ENAMEX>" against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. This referred to a decision by some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> supermarket chains to ban <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> produce. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> , in a
front-page editorial, called for a compromise. It admitted that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s
flouting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> rules is not "good for our image," and it said it would be in
the interests of neither <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to embark on a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hundred Years' War</ENAMEX>.

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , in an editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Down With the Baguette</ENAMEX>," pointed
out--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> did--that the balance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglo-French</ENAMEX> trade in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foodstuffs</ENAMEX> is vastly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s favor. Rejecting calls for an official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> imports, the paper nevertheless urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. "We are well placed to win a trade war with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> if they do not
see sense," it said. "If we stop eating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX>, the pips will soon start
to squeak on the other side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Channel</ENAMEX>." In an unusually outspoken editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX>
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> described the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> practice of "mixing sewage into
animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX>, in defiance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> law," as disgusting--"[t]hat is the only
word for it." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> was also against bans on foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> imports,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>. "[L]et the consumer decide," was
its conclusion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>'s lead front-page story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> said
that advice of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to ban <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> had been
rejected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            The
main story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> said top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> are launching a series of
class-action suits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> to demand "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of millions of dollars</NUMEX>" in
damages from the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> involved in the production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> seed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>. Targets of the actions on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> are likely to include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX>,
AstraZeneca, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Novartis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AgrEvo</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. The actions would allege
"anti-competitive behaviour" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX> market, "questionable corporate
behaviour," and abuse of dominant positions in the marketplace. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Independent</ENAMEX> said in an editorial, "This legal action may be the best way
to force the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to do what they should have done from the start:
prove that their innovations are in the public interest."

            The
Daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the news that
British transplant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>' hearts or lungs will have to sign
a pledge never to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. They will also have to agree to have their
current and future sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> registered and monitored by the medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, to "use barrier contraceptives consistently and for life," and
never to give <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. Because of a shortage of human organs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
authorized research into the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> for transplants, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> already
has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herd</ENAMEX> of "humanized" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pigs</ENAMEX> at the ready. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> plan to
introduce the stringent safeguards to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig viruses</ENAMEX> do not spread to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. So far, nobody has applied for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> organ transplant
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> led on efforts by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celera Genomics</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> biotechnology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, to
patent segments of the human genetic code before <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-led moves are
implemented to prevent the "human blueprint" becoming the private property of a
few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. It said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> "stunned the scientific world" by
claiming to have decoded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-third</NUMEX> of the entire blueprint--the human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genome</ENAMEX>--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">little more than a month</TIMEX>. "The unravelling of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of coded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (the chemical base of all genes) is expected to
revolutionise <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, and pave the way to genetically based cures," the paper
said. "It could also open up limitless opportunities to influence human
evolution by manipulating genetic codes."

            The
visit of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> proceeded with a similar
amount of protest to that which he encountered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>--and with equally
strong police efforts to protect him from it. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> at dinner discussing human rights issues with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Chirac</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> in an
interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that "in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> human rights should be managed by its
own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in full independence" and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> opposed
any foreign interference in its internal affairs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> reiterated that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> would use force if necessary against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX>" and against
"foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> which try to impede the reunification of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>
estimated that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will need "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 100 years</TIMEX>" to become a developed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            The shock success of
right-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">winger Christoph Blocher</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> parliamentary elections led many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, since it came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only three weeks</TIMEX> after the triumph in
neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jörg Haider</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who has praised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX> and called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> "decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>." Blocher, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union of the Center</ENAMEX> appeared set to win <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX> of the vote
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haider</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>), making it the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>,
refuses to be identified with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revisionists</ENAMEX> but is in other respects
typical of the far right--he is against immigration and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>. The
daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genève</ENAMEX> called his victory "unpleasant," but said in an editorial that
he might be "contained" by a coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
