
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dysfunctional Dole</ENAMEX>

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               This is a political
concern, not personal. Each time I see the erectile dysfunction ad with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, I cringe. What happened to his statesmanlike demeanor? Is it entirely a
coincidence that we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who can get it up (for each and every one
who asks), instead of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who can't? Do we need to know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s
penile trouble in order to go forward? Must we be a party to all his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">witherings</ENAMEX>? Surely someone agrees with me.
            

            

               --Ricespring
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Rice</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie guesses Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
and her campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> agree with you. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is reminded of the old
vaudeville joke about an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX> who tells a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that he finds sex
at his age terrific. Especially the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, neutrally

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Your advice to the
seemed fair and balanced. How rare. I thought, however, I might take the
opportunity to chime in and mention that I have got wind of the existence of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">herb</ENAMEX>, indigenous to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, which reportedly stimulates the actual growth of
existing breasts. I've heard only scattered reports about it, and those mostly
relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s efforts to quell its export. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who
are currently considering artificial augmentation (which as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I find
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">repugnant</ENAMEX>) may just want to wait a while. I'm sure a fistful of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> money
will have the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> throwing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> over the border in no time.
            

            

               --Ameer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Am</ENAMEX>,

            After an inquiry
regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s ... well, anyway, your letter is most interesting. Prudie
has heard nothing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">herb</ENAMEX>. It is hard to imagine, though, why any
government would embargo such a product, unless the plastic surgeons' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> has
already got to them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes your information is correct--if only so some
health food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can market a product called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gingko Bilbooba</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, naturally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I grew up being
taught that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should not make loud noises when eating in public. I am
quite bothered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> who eat loudly at their desks, which are very near
to mine. (It is common practice in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to eat at one's desk, since
there's no nice place to eat on the premises.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in particular always
comes over to talk while loudly snacking on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato chips</ENAMEX> and other items.
Trouble is, I can't think of any remotely acceptable way to convey my
unhappiness with this behavior. I'd be very grateful if you could.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.W.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear J.</ENAMEX>,

            You are correct that you
cannot come right out and say, "It is gauche to come over and serenade me with
your potato <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chips</ENAMEX>, so please go away." Here are a few options that are not
confrontational. You might have something to read during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch</TIMEX>, sort of a de
facto "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do Not Disturb</ENAMEX>" sign. You could hook up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Walkman</ENAMEX> earphones. You might
inform everyone that you are meditating, or simply say you'd love to visit
during a coffee break, but lunch is when you've decided to catch up on your
checkbook/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> lessons/letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>/fill in the blank. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> sees no
reason to be held <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> to a potato chip. As for the sounds from other
desks, use earplugs or the above-mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Walkman</ENAMEX> to drown out the sounds of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">celery</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, tactfully

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I are
gearing up for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. We had a blowout (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>) for her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, a pretty large to-do for her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>), and
have decided that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> will be for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year-olds</TIMEX> and close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> only,
thank you. Many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are relieved, I think, not to have to give up a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. But, of course, there are those who expect to be
invited, and I don't know how to break it to them that they are not welcome. To
make things worse, they have already told me about the ridiculously expensive
gifts they have purchased for our irresistible little birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. I am
looking for a delicate way to get the gifts but stand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> on the
invitations.
            

            
               --Not Entirely
Unselfishly,
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Daddy</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will try not to
be too judgmental about your delicacy, though your wish to grab the gifts with
no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> attached leaves something to be desired. In addition to looking
askance at your rather material approach, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has long disapproved of
elaborate birthday parties for tykes ... going back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> to a celebration
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 1-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> engaged a chimp and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX>, and
the animal bit the birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. But back to your deal: Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
already mentioned their gifts and their plans to launch your darling into year
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, you may be stuck for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more over-the-top party. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests,
therefore, that you say on the invitations, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Ann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Birthday Party</ENAMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grown-ups</ENAMEX>." The inference will be clear that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, she will have her own circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> from ... well, somewhere. If you are
absolutely not up to having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chums</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, tell them that it's just
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">playmates</ENAMEX> from now on--and be prepared to forgo some loot.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, directly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> recently
graduated from high school after a successful year of captaining the winning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">softball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. During the softball season my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I got to know many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and were particularly taken with the extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ninth-grader</ENAMEX>, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the school year</TIMEX>, I called
to invite this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, their young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, and her older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>--also a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graduating</ENAMEX> senior--to our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for a cookout with the softball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> before
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> left for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> study abroad. I did not intend this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> to be a
graduation or a bon voyage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. We were quite taken aback
when various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this other family brought gifts and graduation cards
for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> ... including cash totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $200</NUMEX>! We had prepared no
graduation gift for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, whom my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I do not know well. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> expressed gratitude and is writing thank-you notes and plans to bring
the family a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. I wonder if I should have done things
differently--perhaps whipped up a card and cash between serving courses? Should
we send a gift as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> prepares to go to college? Should I have anticipated
the interpretation of my invitation as a gift solicitation, given the timing?
Or should I just relax and consider their gifts a generous expression of their
appreciation for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and mentoring of the younger player
throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jule</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> votes for
"relax." Your motives were pure and a good time was had by all. It may be a
personal bias, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> has long wished the tit for tat principle would fall
by the wayside. The giving of gifts simply to even things up is just another
version of "You look lovely"/"So do you." Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s present from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
will be very meaningful, and the timing will be perfect.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, genuinely

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               You missed something important about the
problem of "." Vague or unintelligible phone messages, with a clear reply
number, are now a tool of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telemarketers</ENAMEX>. Some of them do this just to get the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> to call an expensive toll number. Many refer to correcting a credit
problem, which is fictitious.
            

            
               Of course, Slurred
Off could have had a simple garbled message, I suppose. How boring.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim S.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jim</ENAMEX>,

            What an interesting take
you have offered. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Prudie</ENAMEX> harbors hostility toward intrusive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">telemarketers</ENAMEX>, she is most happy to pass the word. And she does not want one
letter from the offending telephone pests arguing with her. She knows it's a
tough way to make a living, but unsolicited pitches are just junk mail
delivered by a human voice.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, feistily

         
      
   
