
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">314</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chaucer</ENAMEX>, Not an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Fill in the blank
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mixner</ENAMEX>, a gay rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>, praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black-tie</ENAMEX> fund-raising dinner in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>: "Ever since 'The Canterbury
Tales'--strange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> that was--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been judged by their ____________.
And we picked a good one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>."
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 313</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What's That Smell?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               It was caused by "a poisonous mix of greed, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>, jingoism and bad
taste," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Hannigan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s former executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. What
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>; what happened?
            

            "Was
Jakob the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liar</ENAMEX> really that bad?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
            

            "Those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> family reunions are getting a little out of hand."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Salzman</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "The
failure of the attempted merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jedediah Purdy</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> was heckling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">17 th</ENAMEX> green of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder Cup</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Pollino</ENAMEX>
            

            "Is it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simhat Torah</ENAMEX> again already?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>, jingoism,
and bad taste. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannigan</ENAMEX> didn't sound so grouchy, I'd say he was describing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, or perhaps one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> show in particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Kuntash</ENAMEX>'s "Splash!"
In the big finale, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in tiny swimsuits perform a nearly
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pornographic water ballet</ENAMEX> in a giant glass-walled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX>, a row of topless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">showgirls</ENAMEX> roars onto the stage on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harley Davidsons</ENAMEX> while lasers trace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Icons</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX>, profiles of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, the
flag-raising on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwo Jima</ENAMEX>--onto the wings of the stage, and a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15-piece</NUMEX> pit band
plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Born</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.A.</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>, jingoism, bad
taste, and utterly compelling entertainment.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teed Off Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            Hannigan of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Golf Association</ENAMEX> decries the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s premature and boisterous celebration on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
green during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the final day</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder Cup</ENAMEX> competition, "the climax of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Hubris</ENAMEX>."

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rise of the Golf Hooligan</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times op-ed, he regrets the rough treatment dished out to the European
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>: "spectators taunted them." Even worse, "One <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>, positioned
inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>-restraining ropes, exhorted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>. The nonsense of
allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> (in garish uniforms, no less) within the bounds of the arena
in sports is unprecedented."

            I'd say he presumes on
the marital status of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego Chicken</ENAMEX>. But I'd say it in a quiet, polite,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> tone of voice.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>' All
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gall Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Attention, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>:

            According to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> has rejected an appeal from exiled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paraguayan</ENAMEX> coup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lino Oviedo</ENAMEX>
to delay his banishment to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tierra del Fuego</ENAMEX> until his hair transplant can take
hold.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Oviedo</ENAMEX> fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paraguay</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> amid accusations he
plotted the murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Maria Argana</ENAMEX>, a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> who
was gunned down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of Asunción <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oviedo</ENAMEX>, once the army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman</ENAMEX> behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paraguay</ENAMEX>'s disgraced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raúl Cubas</ENAMEX>, said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oviedo</ENAMEX>'s plastic surgeon
doesn't want the general's scalp exposed to sun or wind for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX>.

            I just thought you
should know.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Is</ENAMEX>
Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Going To Be Another Complaint About How Badly Hollywood Treats the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novelist" Ongoing Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Warren Adler</ENAMEX>
writes about how his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Random Hearts</ENAMEX> was made into a movie.
("Published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> and translated into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 25</NUMEX> languages," if he does say
so himself, and he does.)

            Near the end of his article, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adler</ENAMEX> is explaining
why it's taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> for his book to reach the screen, even after being so
extensively translated. The problem, you see, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phonies</ENAMEX> aim
movies at teen-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>.

            "My novels, in contrast, explore the mysteries
behind love and hate, the darkly amusing, deeply disturbing and ultimately
unanswerable questions that they inspire."

            And I have a thicker forearms than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Durrell</ENAMEX>.

            Your News Quiz challenge is to find a more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shameless</ENAMEX> line of self-stroking whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> was able to wake up after its
publication, see it in print, and not kill himself with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>.

            Answers to run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Buchananite tendencies.

         
      
   
