
   
   
      
         
            Double Trouble 

            

               (Note: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life and Art</ENAMEX>" is an occasional column that compares fiction, in
various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, with the real-life facts on which it is ostensibly
based.)
            

            {
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">{Boys 1#36194}} Boys</ENAMEX> 
               Don't
Cry --a just-released dramatic film about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was raped and murdered
in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for pretending to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--hews fairly closely to
what really happened to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Teena</ENAMEX> (nee <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teena Brandon</ENAMEX>).

            In the film--as in life--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> (who never used
the last name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teena</ENAMEX>; he was called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Teena</ENAMEX>" only posthumously) had
already been wooing young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> before
arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falls City</ENAMEX> (population <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1993</TIMEX>. He begins dating a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana</ENAMEX> and quickly becomes part of her circle: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, a
few female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ex-cons named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lotter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Nissen</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> weren't old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> as the film makes them out to be. They met only a month
before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>'s murder.) The marginalized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> spends its time drinking,
playing cards, and "bumper-skiing" from the back of a moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup truck</ENAMEX> by
holding a rope attached to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>, who has a history of forgery, ends
up in the women's section of jail. Lana helps post his bail.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>'s acquaintances
become suspicious of his gender, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> become hostile toward him.
(In real life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> had been involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> may have been briefly,
too, but the film avoids this history.) The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> pull down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>'s pants,
exposing his genitalia, then later beat and rape him. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> is warned
to keep quiet, he reports the rape. In the movie, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> sounds like a
blame-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim monster</ENAMEX> when he questions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> about the attack, but this
account jibes with what happened in real life. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff Charles Laux</ENAMEX>, who is
not named in the film, wanted to know why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> was masquerading as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and
asked him if he'd helped one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX> get an erection.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days</TIMEX> after
the rape, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lotter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nissen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX> and kill him.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> seduces <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with his good looks and his great
kissing in the film, but he charms them by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just</TIMEX> listening. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">girlfriends</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> was their best boyfriend
ever. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was engaged to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> said he was a "good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>." Did they know that their perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandon</ENAMEX> passed
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> by securing his breasts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ace bandages</ENAMEX>, keeping his clothes on
while snuggling with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, and occasionally using a fake penis during
intercourse, all of which is covered in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry . But he also told
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that he was going to get a sex-change operation and others that he
was a hermaphrodite, a fact that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> denies.

            When did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX> discover
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>'s true gender? Both the film and the record oscillate on this question.
In a telephone interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peirce</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana</ENAMEX> told her that "she knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
she met him." But in subsequent conversations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX> claimed that she didn't
find out until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> was jailed or until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> had taken his pants
down or until he'd been raped.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana</ENAMEX> knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a month</TIMEX> before his
murder, the filmmakers make their relationship seem longer and more serious,
perhaps to give their affair epic status. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celluloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana</ENAMEX> (played by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chloë Sevigny</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary Swank</ENAMEX>) almost escape the obstacles posed by
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and the hatred of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> by running away together.

            And at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> improbable
moment, they almost discover themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX>. In a lovemaking scene that
occurs after the rape, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> finally takes off his shirt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana</ENAMEX> says, "I don't
know if I'm going to know how to do it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> responds, "I'm sure you'll
figure it out." As best we know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> did not identify as a lesbian, saying
he was disgusted by the idea of loving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that way.

            One also supposes that the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana</ENAMEX> was a bit more
confused and angered by the public revelation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>'s gender than the
movie suggests. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn Brandon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> (not depicted in the movie),
asserted on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldo</ENAMEX> that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teena</ENAMEX>" told her that "she thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana</ENAMEX> had set
her up for the rape." This accusation, however, seems very much at odds with
the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana</ENAMEX> spent time together after the attack.

            In the film, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lana</ENAMEX> tries
to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> from finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> by asking them to go get a drink.
Instead, they drive her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX>, where she then tries to stop them
from killing both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candace</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candace</ENAMEX> is fictional.
There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had been involved with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was visiting the area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> takes aim at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX>, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bullet</ENAMEX> misses because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> shoves him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> leave and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana</ENAMEX> lies next to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, and the movie ends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> later with a music video-ish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequence of Lana</ENAMEX> driving out of town. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry 's postscript
explains that she eventually returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falls City</ENAMEX>, where is she currently
raising a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.

            Nobody actually knows if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana</ENAMEX> accompanied the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> did swing by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> before heading to the
scene of the murder, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> reportedly said to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> (who does
not figure in the movie), "I feel like killing somebody." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gutierres</ENAMEX> (not her name in the film), told them where they could find
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> have
been criticized for not warning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> that trouble was on the way. It's
possible that one of the reasons they didn't phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX> went
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aphrodite Jones</ENAMEX> recounts in her book about the incident,
All She Wanted (for which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX> has bought the movie rights), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
told a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX> "was in the car" but didn't go into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">farmhouse</ENAMEX>. "She stayed in the car the whole time." Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> testified against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX> so as to avoid the electric chair. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> maintains his innocence from
death row. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> is serving a life sentence.) On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> stand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> said that
he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> were the only ones in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. And as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gregory Dunne</ENAMEX>
reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>'s initial allegation "was not vigorously
pursued in testimony."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Muska</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greta Olafsdottir</ENAMEX>, who made the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
documentary <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Brandon Teena Story</ENAMEX> , say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX> "was adamant that she
wasn't there." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peirce</ENAMEX> struggled over whether or not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">place Lana</ENAMEX> at the murder scene. "Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX> actually going to sit in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and
let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> be murdered<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peirce</ENAMEX> asks. As to whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX> would have sat in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peirce</ENAMEX> admits that it's possible, but that it wouldn't have been as
dramatic.

            Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> feel as though they had to kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>? They had to be worried about the rape allegation, although as Dunne
points out in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX>, it doesn't make sense to try to escape a
rape charge, which is difficult to prosecute, by committing murder. But these
were not especially bright ex-convicts. They tossed the murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> into a
river, which was frozen at the time. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> would later describe the murders
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> before his trial (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> was called as a
witness).

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> were troubled. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys Town</ENAMEX> rejected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> for admission when he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> had been abused and liked to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mutilate</ENAMEX> himself. They were no doubt enraged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>'s deception and angered
by his identity, as the film implies. Perhaps they were also disturbed by the
meaning of the rape. In the documentary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> says someone told her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> was a "faggot," and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>: "After this sexual assault ...
didn't [your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>] tell you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were calling you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pervert</ENAMEX>? .... You
had just had sex--forcible sex--with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was dressing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. How did
you feel about that?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> replies, "I didn't feel very good about it at
all."

         
      
   
