
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Do Bleed

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fight Club</ENAMEX> is silly
stuff, sensationalism that mistakes itself for satire, but it's also a brash
and transporting piece of moviemaking, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bull</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>. The
film opens with--literally--a surge of adrenalin, which travels through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bloodstream</ENAMEX> and into the brain of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward Norton</ENAMEX>), who's
viewed, as the camera pulls out of his insides, with a gun stuck in his mouth.
How'd he get into this pickle? He's going to tell you, breezily, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Fincher</ENAMEX>, is going to illustrate his narrative--violently.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fincher</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Game</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>) is out to bombard you with
so much feverish imagery that you have no choice but to succumb to the movie's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reeling</ENAMEX>, punch-drunk worldview. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, you might feel as if you, too, have
a mouthful of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>.

            Not to mention a hole in your head. Fight
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> careers from one resonant satirical idea to the next without quite
deciding whether its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are full of crap or are <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gen X</ENAMEX> prophets. It
always gives you a rush, though. At first, it goofs on the absurd feminization
of an absurdly macho culture. An increasingly desperate insomniac, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> finds
relief (and release) only at meetings for the terminally ill. At a testicular
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, he's enfolded in the ample arms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meat Loaf</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aday</ENAMEX>), a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodybuilder</ENAMEX> who ruined his health with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> and now has
"bitch tits." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and Bob subscribe to a new form of male bonding: They cling
to each other and sob. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>'s idyll is rudely disrupted by--wouldn't you
know it?--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. A dark-eyed, sepulchral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> case named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marla Singer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helena</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonham Carter</ENAMEX>) begins showing up at all the same disparate meetings for
essentially the same voyeuristic ends, and the presence of this "tourist" makes
it impossible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> to emote.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> finds another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outlet</ENAMEX>, though. On a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, he meets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Durden</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX>), a cryptic
hipster with a penchant for subversive acts both large (he makes high-priced
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soaps</ENAMEX> from liposuctioned human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX>) and small (he splices frames from porn
flicks into kiddie movies). When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> mysteriously explodes--along
with his carefully chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IKEA</ENAMEX> furniture--he moves into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyler</ENAMEX>'s squalid
warehouse and helps to found a new religion: Fight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>, in which young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>
gather after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX> to pound one another (and be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pounded</ENAMEX>) to a bloody <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pulp</ENAMEX>. That last parenthesis isn't so parenthetical. In
some ways, it's the longing to be beaten into oblivion that's the strongest.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>-improvement," explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX>, "is masturbation"; self-destruction is the
new way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX>'s manifesto calls for an end to consumerism ("Things you own end
up owning you"), and since society is going down ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> is polishing
brass on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> "), the only creative outlet left is annihilation.
"It's only after we've lost everything that we're free to do anything," he
says.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fincher</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Uhls</ENAMEX>, seem to think
they've broken new ground in Fight 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> , that their metaphor for
our discontents hits harder than anyone else's. Certainly it produces more
bloody splatter. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, the same impulse was called punk and, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greil Marcus</ENAMEX> documents in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lipstick Traces</ENAMEX> , it was other things before
that. Yes, the mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Rotten</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake La Motta</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is unique;
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Faludi</ENAMEX>-esque emasculation themes are more explicit. But there's
something deeply movie-ish about the whole conceit, as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> were weaned on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX> pictures and never stopped dreaming of
recapturing that first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masochistic</ENAMEX> rush.

            The novel, the first by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Palahniuk</ENAMEX> (the surname sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eskimo</ENAMEX> for "palooka"--which somehow
fits), walks a line between the straight and ironic--it isn't always clear if
its glib sociological pronouncements are meant to be taken straight or as the
ravings of a delusional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. But onscreen, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> announces to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">assembled</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> that they are the "middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of history" with "no
purpose and no place"--emasculated on one hand by the lack of a unifying crisis
(a world war or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>) and on the other by lack of material wealth as
promised by television--he seems meant to be intoning gospel. "We are a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tyler announces</ENAMEX>, and adds, "If our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>
bail, what does that tell you about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God?</ENAMEX>" (I give up: What?)

            F ight 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> could use a few different
perspectives: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s, obviously, but also an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>'s--someone
who'd have a different take on the "healing" properties of violence. It's also
unclear just what has emasculated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>: Is it that he's a materialist or that
the materials themselves (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IKEA</ENAMEX>'s lacquered particle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>) don't measure
up to his fantasies of opulence? Is he motivated by spiritual hunger or envy?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX>'s subsequent idea of confining his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s mayhem to franchise coffee
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX> and corporate-subsidized art is a witty one--it's like a parody of
neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nazism</ENAMEX> as re-enacted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX>. It might have been a howl if performed by,
say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troupe</ENAMEX> of artsy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> nihilists in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Coen</ENAMEX>'s The Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebowski</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Somehow Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> doesn't have the same piquancy.

            Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> isn't as terrible as usual: He's
playing not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> but a conceit, and he can bask in his movie-idol
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrogance</ENAMEX>, which seems to be the most authentic emotion he has. But the film
belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX>. As a ferocious skinhead in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American History</ENAMEX>
X , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX> was taut and ropy, his long torso curled into a sneer; here, he's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skinny</ENAMEX> and wilting, a quivering pansy. Even when he fights he doesn't
transform--he's a raging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp</ENAMEX>. The performance is marvelous, and it makes
poetic sense in light of the movie's climactic twist. But that twist will annoy
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than it will delight, if only because it shifts the drama from the
realm of the sociological to that of the psychoanalytic. The finale, scored
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pixies</ENAMEX>' great "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where Is My Mind?</ENAMEX>" comes off facetiously--as if Fincher
is throwing the movie away.

            Until then, however, he
has done a fabulous job of keeping it spinning. The most thrilling thing about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fight Club</ENAMEX> isn't what it says but how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uhls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fincher</ENAMEX> pull you into its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrator</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and simulate his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">adrenalin</ENAMEX> rushes. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of rock videos,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fincher</ENAMEX> is one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> who helps make the case that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>--along with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital</ENAMEX> editing--has transformed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> for better as well as worse. The syntax
has become more intricate. Voice-over narration, once considered uncinematic,
is back in style, along with novelistic asides, digressions, fantasies, and
flashbacks. To make a point, you can jazzily interject anything--even, as in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> , a shot of a bullet slicing through internal organs. Films
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fight Club</ENAMEX> might not gel, but they have a breathless,
free-associational quality that points to new possibilities in storytelling. Or
maybe old possibilities: The language of movies hasn't seemed this unfettered
since the pre-sound days of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sergei Eisenstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abel Gance</ENAMEX>.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary Swank</ENAMEX> gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rapturous</ENAMEX> performances I've ever seen as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cross-dressing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Teena</ENAMEX> (a k
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teena Brandon</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly Peirce</ENAMEX>'s stark and astonishingly beautiful debut
feature, 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry
               . The movie opens with Teena
being shorn of her hated female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tresses</ENAMEX> and becoming "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>," who swaggers
around in tight jeans and leather jackets. The joy is in watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
transform, and I don't just mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swank</ENAMEX>: I mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teena Brandon</ENAMEX> playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teena</ENAMEX>--the role she has been longing for her whole life. In a redneck <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>
bar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> throws back a shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX> and the gesture--a macho
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cliché</ENAMEX>--becomes an act of self-discovery. Every gesture does. "You're gonna
have a shiner in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>," someone tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> after a barroom brawl, and
he takes the news with a glee that's almost mystical: "I am????? Oh, shit!!!"
he cries, grinning. That might be my favorite moment in the picture, because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swank</ENAMEX>'s ecstatic expression carries us through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next hour</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> acts
out his urban-cowboy fantasies--"surfing" from the bumper of a pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>,
rolling in the mud, and straddling a barstool with one hand on a brewski and
the other on the shoulder of a gorgeous babe.

            That the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> feels most at home
would kill him if they knew his true gender is the movie's most tragic
irony--and the one that lifts it out of the realm of gay-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr hagiography</ENAMEX> and
into something more complex and irreducible: a meditation on the irrelevance of
gender. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peirce</ENAMEX>'s triumph is to make these scenes at once exuberant
(occasionally hilarious) and foreboding, so that all the seeds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>'s
killing are right there on the screen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Sarsgaard</ENAMEX>), one of his
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>, calls him "little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>" and seems almost
attracted to him; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarsgaard</ENAMEX>'s performance is a finely chiseled study of how
unresolved emotion can suddenly resolve itself into violence.

            Though harrowing, the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry isn't as great as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. The early
scenes evoke elation and dread simultaneously, the later ones just dread; and
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last half-hour</TIMEX> is unrelieved torture. What keeps the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tantalizing</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chloë Sevigny's Lana</ENAMEX>, who might or might not know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> but
who's entranced by him anyway. With her lank <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>, hooded eyes, and air of
sleepy sensuality, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sevigny</ENAMEX>--maybe even more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swank</ENAMEX>--embodies the mystery of
sex that's at the core of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry . Everything she does is
deliberate, ironic, slightly unreadable--and unyielding. She's could be saying,
"I'm in this world but not of it. ... You'd never dream what's
underneath."

            I n 
               brief: If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> tells you
you'll love 
                  Happy Texas
               , rethink the friendship. This
clunky mistaken-identity comedy about escaped cons who impersonate gay pageant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX> doesn't even make sense on its own low farcical terms; it's mostly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame homo</ENAMEX> joke after another. The only bright spot is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Zahn</ENAMEX>, who could
be the offspring of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Fox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crispin Glover</ENAMEX> if they'd mated on the
set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>).

            It's hard to make a serious case for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasdan</ENAMEX>'s 
                  Mumford
               , which has apparently flopped but
which you can still catch at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>- and third-tier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>. It looks
peculiar--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Rockwell</ENAMEX> painting with noir shadows. And its tale of a small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> healed by a depressive (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loren Dean</ENAMEX>) posing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> is full of
doddering misconceptions about psychotherapy. I almost don't know why I loved
it, but the relaxed pacing and the witty turns by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Short</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Danson</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Paymer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary McDonnell</ENAMEX> surely helped. I can't decide if the weirdly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">affectless Dean</ENAMEX> is inspired or inept, but my indecision suggests why he works
in the role. There's no doubt, however, about his even more depressive love
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">object</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope Davis</ENAMEX>, who posseses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>'s most expressive honking-nasal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX> and who slumps through the movie like the world's most lyrical
anti-ballerina. Even her puffy cheeks are eloquent: They made me think of
Mumford as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of the psychological mumps.

         
      
   
