
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX>

            We were somewhere around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> when the drugs
began to take hold. Benadryl, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prednisone</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cimetidine</ENAMEX> make a potent little
combination. I was out for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>, during which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> violated our carefully
negotiated cassette agreement by playing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of his loud <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germanic</ENAMEX> rock tapes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">back-to-back</ENAMEX>. In the middle of my drugged-out stupor, I believe I heard
something on the radio about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Craig</ENAMEX> is paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky $10,000</ENAMEX>
for each pound she loses on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Craig</ENAMEX>'s weight-loss program. But wait a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>. Why would this convince an average overeater that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX> program
works? The average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> isn't going to be paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> for every pound she
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sheds</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McSalad Report</ENAMEX>: Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hagerstown</ENAMEX>, I've been unable to find a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> that sells the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McSalad Shaker</ENAMEX>. In fact, most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>
look at me like I'm an escaped lunatic when I ask for the product. (It doesn't
help that I'm still wearing my hospital identification bracelet.) Using the
power of the Internet, I calculated the chances that any given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> will
carry this major dietetic innovation. The news is grim. There are approximately
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. There are only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> that
carry the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McSalad Shaker</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX> of them are concentrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. That leaves <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only 350</NUMEX> for the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Even if those are
equally distributed, this means I only have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-in-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32.8</NUMEX> chance of walking into
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> that serves the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McSalad Shaker</ENAMEX>. Good grief. The odds that I'll
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">sleep with Bob</ENAMEX> are better than that!

            New thought: I've noticed that nobody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> says "You're welcome" anymore. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, where I'm from, "You're
welcome" is still the customary follow up to "Thank you." But here, when you
say "Thank you," the best response you can hope for is, "No--thank you ."
Sometimes you get total silence. And the most common response is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yup</ENAMEX>" or worse
yet, a low, honking "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uh Huhhh</ENAMEX>."

            Is there any deep social meaning to this shift? Is
it that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are becoming more sensitive and "You're welcome" sounds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immodest</ENAMEX>, even aggressive, as if a huge favor has been done and is owed?
(Indeed, the only accepted use of "You're welcome" seems to be as an actively
hostile reminder of ingratitude--"You're welcome," as in "You forgot to say
thank you, you asshole.") Or does it just sound too formal? My own theory
(which I admit may be a stretch--but remember, I'm on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>) is that it is part
of a large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>community trend: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> want to have as little to do with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as possible. Elaborate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> of respect imply a degree of
entanglement <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> wish to avoid.

            Another disturbing trend: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> has taken to removing
progressively more of his clothing in my presence. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, he was
walking around the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> without his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> on. Then, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX>, he
casually mooned me. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, I looked up into the large mirror on our
hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> only to see Bob emerge from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom en déshabillé</ENAMEX> . "It
was an accident," he claimed. "Who knew the mirror was there?" The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is so
transparent.

         
      
   
