
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999>Preparing for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Korea</ENAMEX></SPAN></SPAN>

            

               
                  
                     
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
                     , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10</TIMEX>
               
            

            The
cover story forecasts that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> is doomed to
imminent collapse. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Dae Jung</ENAMEX> must strengthen that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s democracy and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> more market reform to prepare for a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> urge a halt to the coddling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Jong Il</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s plan to test another long-range <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> is proof that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> can only be persuaded to back down by the threat of economic sanctions.
... An article worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are shakier than
they look. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> boast mounting profits, the credit quality of
their loan portfolios has declined precipitously. ... Another
piece <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> new measures to discourage the trend
toward recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> into armed conflict, including raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
Convention minimum age for soldiering from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 to 18</TIMEX> and pledging to withhold
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> from rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruit kid fighters</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story concludes, as previously predicted, that the abortifacient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU-486</ENAMEX>
will revolutionize the politics of abortion. The pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
plans to market the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> won't name its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, lest pro-lifers hound
them out of business. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU-486</ENAMEX> will make abortions less invasive and more
politically tenable, since it can be administered early in a pregnancy by a
wide range of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> in the privacy of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epinions</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, a new Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> offering an online
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zagats</ENAMEX>-for-everything," started up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 weeks</TIMEX>. Typical of "second-generation"
Web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who abandoned
fortunes in unvested stock options to pursue their entrepreneurial dreams. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> quickly coalesced based on professional connections and recruited capital
before writing any code. ... A photo essay, pinpointing where executions
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incinerations</ENAMEX> took place, documents the destruction <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> wreaked on one
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story assails the avarice of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for
developing lucrative lifestyle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to treat impotence, baldness, wrinkles,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toenail fungus</ENAMEX>, while ignoring unprofitable deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1 percent</NUMEX> of new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> were developed to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tropical diseases</ENAMEX>.
Meanwhile the pet drug market is exploding, producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> to alleviate
separation anxiety in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. ... A sidebar castigates the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> for championing the interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to the
detriment of public health by trying to prevent the sale of generic substitutes
in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. ... An editorial condemns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s spate of decisions
that have sacrificed individual rights to protect state rights.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX>
12
            

            The
cover story forecasts that within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> Latinos will
become the predominant minority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, due to booming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immigration</ENAMEX> and birth rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> will alter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, since they are
heavily <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, concentrated in important electoral <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and vote in
increasing numbers. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> Gen-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Xers</ENAMEX>--called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Generation Ñ</ENAMEX> --cling to their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> heritage and shape
popular culture through their artistic contributions. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> beat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> to this conclusion with its recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> pop cover story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">featuring Ricky Martin</ENAMEX>.) ... Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicappers</ENAMEX> claim <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anal-retentiveness</ENAMEX> will hinder her campaign, according to an analysis . Her attention to detail might be what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> needs
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> keeps confusing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovakia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovenia</ENAMEX>. ... An article counsels that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> must overcome the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbagger</ENAMEX> question and press-phobia to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> race. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> has his own problems: He will be weakened by a tough primary
challenge, and if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> challenger runs in the general election under the
Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> banner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> will cakewalk back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story assesses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX>. By protesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> cuts,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> signaled her distance from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, but she still needs to
establish a rationale for her candidacy. ... A piece maps the minefield of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
must energize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> without alienating white ethnic suburbanites
who favor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX> plans to consolidate his lead in the burbs by pushing
school vouchers, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> will tap into health-care frustrations and make
the election a national contest. ... An article argues that projected budget surpluses rest on the
shaky assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will maintain budget ceilings by slicing popular
domestic programs.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX>
12
            

            The
cover story condemns the culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s play. An
estimated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> participate in organized sports. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX>
send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to costly summer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> and hire professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultracompetition</ENAMEX> is spoiling the fun, squeezing family schedules, and
increasing sports-related injuries. ... A piece asks how best to topple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> to condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobo</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> might offer humanitarian
aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that oppose him. But the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of opposition
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> is too factious to stage a coup. ... An article condemns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for ingratitude toward his
loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> openly criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s political skills and
privately claims that he could do a better job campaigning than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has.

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smallpox</ENAMEX> poses a catastrophic threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. The highly contagious virus was declared eradicated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, and
routine vaccinations ended. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> suspects some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of stockpiling
the virus for use as a biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uncontrolled smallpox</ENAMEX> epidemic
could be more deadly than a hydrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> attack because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
maintains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 7 million</NUMEX> doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>. ... A piece echoes
speculation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> run might be motivated by her
ambition to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Its only evidence is a chorus of rumors,
none traceable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. An accompanying illustration pictures <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
taking the oath of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for the presidency while Bill watches in the
background.

         
      
   
