
   
   
      
         
            High Fidelity

            It has been heartening to
see some of my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'70s</TIMEX> adolescence (<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-Vietnam</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">post-Watergate</ENAMEX>, pre-punk, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pre-Reagan</ENAMEX>) finally clear their heads of all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and bad music and put those "lost" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> into perspective. But how can
any filmmaker nowadays convey the nihilistic embrace of dope and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> and do justice both to the way it felt at the time--blissfully gonzo,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberating</ENAMEX>--and the way it came to feel after everyone did too much--like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quicksand</ENAMEX>? The comedy Outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> treats those dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> got flushed away with just the right amount of gleeful nostalgia and
horrified incredulity. The film is so free of cant that it's positively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleansing</ENAMEX>: It leaves you both cleareyed and high.

            The movie is based on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terse</ENAMEX>, bleakly funny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Farrelly</ENAMEX>, who, with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>,
wrote and directed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dumb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumber</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>) and There's Something About
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>). It tells the story of a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Dunphy</ENAMEX> who
lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pawtucket</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>, "a rotting city bleeding off an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anemic</ENAMEX> river just
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north of Providence</ENAMEX>." That description is more bitter than anything in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>, but it does suggest how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrelly</ENAMEX> kept life among the urban unwashed from
crushing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>: He cultivated a caustic sense of humor. The movie, directed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Corrente</ENAMEX> from a script he wrote with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrellys</ENAMEX>, is not in the
whacking, gross-out school of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>' other projects, but it shares with
them a tender regard for the scruffy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>, the yearning misfit. (In the
novel, a headmaster actually refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumb</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumber</ENAMEX>.") More important, it has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrellys</ENAMEX>' characteristic mix of misery
and brightness: Whenever the view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX> threatens to become
oppressively self-pitying, the filmmakers pull something nutty out of their
hat--a scam, a bit of stoner dialogue, a jolt of rock 'n' roll--to prove that
this particular end only looks dead. OK, maybe it is dead, but
sometimes you can plow through a brick wall and come out the other side.

            The other side, in this case, is a fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> prep
school, where "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dunph</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn Hatosy</ENAMEX>) gets sent when he rear-ends a police
cruiser after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> and their bong. (It's thanks to the
murky intervention of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX>, a gangster, that he ends up
there and not in juvenile detention.) At <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cornwall</ENAMEX> (a k a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cornhole</ENAMEX>"), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunph</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stoner</ENAMEX> lifestyle proves more of a challenge to maintain. It's not that the rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't party as determinedly as the poor ones, it's that the dorms are
prowled by sadistic faculty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdogs</ENAMEX> such as Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Funderburk</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Crowe</ENAMEX>), as
well as by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> happy to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> out their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> if it means getting into an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivy League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. It's also that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunph</ENAMEX> falls for the blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">WASP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Weston</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Smart</ENAMEX>), who, if not a goody-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-shoes, is determined not to let drugs
overwhelm her course of self-improvement. As his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pawtucket</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> die in car
crashes or face the prospect of lives scrambling for a dwindling number of
factory jobs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunph</ENAMEX> has a vague inkling that his level of consumption is not a
design for living.

            
               Outside

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> is hardly an anti-drug picture. That would be hypocritical,
since its most meaningful (and hilarious) connections happen over (and with a
large assist from) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> and pot. Its impulses are divided--which is just, I
think, as they should be. The movie says that getting high all the time can rot
your brain and even kill you, but it's not above going for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheech</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chong</ENAMEX>-style laughs or blithely wallowing in the sense of community that drugs
can instill. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pawtucket</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get stoned and hang out at the water <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>.
Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">bong</NUMEX> hits, they talk of moving to a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> utopia where "they got
babes, they got <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weed</ENAMEX>, they got <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that don't rust." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunph</ENAMEX> tells them he
likes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> he's seeing so much he doesn't think about banging her, they say
she "sounds like a cool mule." I wish that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pawtucket</ENAMEX> scenes hadn't been
shot on a special film stock--they're bleached a toilet bowl blue--but they
still have a powerful comic hum. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Bone</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunph</ENAMEX>'s
wheelchair-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> ("He had a freak accident at touch <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and fell
off a roof," explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunph</ENAMEX>, in a voice-over), gets to be in on the jokes
instead of the object of them: In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> scene, he feigns extreme cerebral palsy
so that he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> can have great seats at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX>.

            The charm of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corrente</ENAMEX>'s direction comes as a shock. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native</ENAMEX> made his debut in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> with a mannered, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streets -style</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>-from-the-neighborhood picture called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and followed that with a strenuously boring adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>). In Outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> , he
stops trying to wow us with indie-auteur smarts. The details are right. Songs
that I hoped never to hear again--"Hold Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> Up," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Take It Easy</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Band</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Free Bird"</ENAMEX>--sound, in context, startlingly fresh, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunph</ENAMEX>'s brown
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corduroy</ENAMEX> jacket looks like the one I persisted in wearing into the late '80s
when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> finally took the initiative to drop it down a garbage chute.
Better, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corrente</ENAMEX> brings out the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">radiance</ENAMEX> in his young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snaggletoothed Hatosy</ENAMEX> has a soft, agreeable presence. Early on, he makes Dunph
seem a tad stupid, but when he's picked up hitchhiking by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> and her rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, you glimpse the sneaky undercurrents of his rube act. He passes her a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>, which turns out to be spiked with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have a magical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collusion</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Smart</ENAMEX> must be the nicest, most down-to-earth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> WASP
goddess in history--if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Scott Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> had met her, he'd have lived into
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">90s</NUMEX>.)

            Like its title,
Outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> hints at a godless universe--as well as a motherless
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunph</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> shot herself when he was much younger.) You learn from your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>--for better or worse--and not your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX>. The movie might have been
unbearably depressing if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Old Man Dunphy</ENAMEX> had been the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrelly</ENAMEX>'s novel.
(In one of the book's first scenes, he kills his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>' mutt by crushing it in a
door after it tears apart a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX> brings an outsize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic spirit</ENAMEX>--and outsize vulnerability--to the film. He drops his voice an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">octave</ENAMEX> and bellows lines like "Drag your pimply ass in here and say hello to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>--show some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> f'r chrissakes" in a way that transcends caricature.
He's so frightened of communicating with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that he has to caricature
himself . The source of his comedy is also what makes him tragic.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Very Thought of You</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> shallow,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates coincidentally</ENAMEX> meet and fall in love with the same pretty
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">blond American flake</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Potter</ENAMEX>), thus filling the one she likes best
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Fiennes</ENAMEX>) with guilt and shame. If watching the bug-eyed and irritable
Fiennes wrestle with this nonissue for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90 minutes</TIMEX> sounds like fun to you, then
don't hold back on my account. The movie isn't awful. It pulls a couple of
amusing tricks with its narrative (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> act doesn't come until after the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, whereupon everything starts to--sort of--make sense), but this kind of
flimsy romantic confection is either utterly charming or it collapses into a
heavy slab of obviousness. It doesn't help that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX> looks and sounds as if
she has just stepped out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> where someone was laboring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>. She has the same wide eyes, turned-up nose, and vaguely glassy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hysteria</ENAMEX>, but everything is smaller-scale: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, I shrunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>.

            
               The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astronaut</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wife</ENAMEX> is one of the
classiest terrible sci-fi movies you're likely to see. The tale of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX> with a drawl) who comes back from a space accident somehow
different is cut from the same paranoid cloth as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invasion of the Body</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snatchers</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Married a</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monster From Outer Space</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>)
and, midway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>). But someone forgot to tell the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rand Ravich</ENAMEX>, that a genre movie can't survive on fancy,
high-toned portent alone--especially when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> knows what's being
portended before they even buy their tickets. It's a testament to the lovely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlize Theron</ENAMEX> that she can hold our attention even when we're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> steps ahead
of her character and only waiting around to see the big slimy outer-space
monster--which never comes. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Beckett</ENAMEX> would be yelling, "Get to the
damn point!"

         
      
   
