
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">281</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Sign Here&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>, at
a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,200</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vicksburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, erected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> identical signs. Now one has
been spray-painted with the word "hypocrite," and the other has been smashed to
pieces. What do the signs say?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 280</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perturbed":</ENAMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, around the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>,
something will happen on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> believe has a small but
genuine chance of causing "perturbations of the universe" that could destroy
the world. What will happen?
            

            
( Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>.)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey</ENAMEX>!
Lay off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernadette Peters</ENAMEX>. She's settled down now."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX>
            

            
"According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Salinger</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX> will resume testing of the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> that brought down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thomas</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
Gimelsteins, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>, will order tastefully understated invitations to
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s bat mitzvah."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> Kroop
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> will list <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort Zuckerman</ENAMEX> as a 'confirmed arrival' even though he hasn't
RSVP'd."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hendrik Hertzberg</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trumpet</ENAMEX> will sound and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Fitzgerald Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> will rise out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sound</ENAMEX>,
clothed in pure white, shining like the sun, surrounded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> of
heaven."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard A. DeCamp</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> epitomizes boredom is
because of its ur-suburb, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Levittown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tedium</ENAMEX> expressed as architecture. For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
thing, it's relentless--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>, you could get a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-room <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape</ENAMEX>
Cod cottage for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">under $8,000</NUMEX>.) For another, you can't walk anywhere, and even
if you could, you wouldn't be any place once you got there--no civic center, no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parks</ENAMEX>, no shopping district. This was not an inevitable consequence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suburbia</ENAMEX>--in his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City Life</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Witold Rybczynski</ENAMEX> describes many
delightful suburbs built in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>--this was simply bad
design.

            One thing these postwar
tract-home developments did have in abundance was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and considered as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, they were wonderfully designed. There were generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> recreation
grounds, the unfenced backyards through which we swarmed. There were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> civic
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> where we met one another; they were called "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>." And you got to
them via the excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> transit system, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX>. There was even a mobile
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dessert van</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> truck, that came <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">around each evening</TIMEX>, offering kid
food. In my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennside</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popsicle Pete</ENAMEX>--not
C
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rème Brûlée Pete</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chocolate Mousse Pete</ENAMEX>. It was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s
world.

            
               End of the World
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven National Laboratories</ENAMEX> will crank up its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relativistic Heavy Ion Collider</ENAMEX>, a nuclear accelerator designed to replicate
the Big Bang.

            When they do, ions moving at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99.9 percent</NUMEX> of the
speed of light will smash into each other, generating minuscule fireballs of
superdense matter with temperatures of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a trillion degrees</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> times
hotter than the sun, creating quarks and gluons and--fingers crossed--strange
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quarks</ENAMEX>.

            Some physicists assert that there is a tiny but
real risk that the machine might create "strangelets," a new type of matter
made up of strange quarks, which might start an uncontrollable chain reaction,
converting anything they touch into more strange matter. An alternative, but no
cheerier, theory suggests that colliding particles could achieve sufficient
density to form a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">black hole</ENAMEX> whose gravitational field would suck in all
surrounding matter. "The creation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> points
out, "could be disastrous."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven</ENAMEX> has convened
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to investigate the danger. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Jaffe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Theoretical Physics</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>, who is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, told the
Times , "There have been fears that strange matter could alter the
structure of anything nearby. The risk is exceedingly small but the probability
of something unusual happening is not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>."

            
               Death and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This weekend</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> events
drew huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Woodstock '99</ENAMEX>. A
comparison:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capsule Description</ENAMEX>
Funeral: a moving tribute to a fallen leader
Festival: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> of peace, love, music, looting, arson, and riot 

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Description</ENAMEX> of Crowd
Funeral: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of mourners"
Festival: "marauding bands of shirtless bellowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Distinguished Guests</ENAMEX>
Funeral: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX>
Festival: a sun-addled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brown</ENAMEX>

               Most Moving Image
Funeral: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun carriage</ENAMEX> bearing a king's coffin
Festival: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metallica</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> pushing over a Portasan

               Frequently <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heard Cry</ENAMEX>
Funeral: "God is great!"
Festival: "Let's set fire to the pretzel truck!"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catalyst for Outburst of Emotion</ENAMEX>
Funeral: death of a longtime monarch
Festival: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX>? For a bag of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato chips</ENAMEX>?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heartfelt Remarks From Ordinary Person in Crowd</ENAMEX>
Funeral: "He was like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>."
Festival: "I'm going to steal some more stuff."

               Lesson Learned
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Funeral: Death</ENAMEX> comes to us all
Festival: "Should have spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the $60</NUMEX> for pay-per-view."

            

            

               Errata "charybdis.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> does exist; carybdis is a misspelling, so it
is no surprise that it does not. (I'm afraid I've taken too much <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> for any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sane person</ENAMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Newman</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
