
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East Peace</ENAMEX> Hopes

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on his way back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace hopes sprang afresh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sky</ENAMEX> brightens," declared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> over an editorial saying that "after the negativity of Binyamin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> is a confidence-building measure all by himself." It said
peace, if it comes, will be "a peace of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatists</ENAMEX>" with "no outright
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>--but, just possibly, a collective victory." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX>--patrol the new peace lines if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX> are returned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s "calm realism"--as shown in his admission that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> already have a de facto <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--is a good omen for the future.
Describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a hurry, under pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to
produce results, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> pointed out that "nothing would delight Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
more than a beautiful ending to his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX> with a diplomatic success in
this part of the world where he has invested so much." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> was
rather less cheerful. "The outlook is too complicated to permit of excessive
expectations," it said. For example, an entente with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> would make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s
life more difficult elsewhere. "The paradox of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab-Israeli</ENAMEX> dispute is that
it has often served as a distraction from several inter-Arab differences of
scarcely less intensity," it said.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s plan to speed up the peace
negotiations. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> are more than enough," it said in an
editorial. "The disputed points have been debated to death, the
conditions for compromise are known, and many of them have already been agreed
upon. ... Since the inception of the peace process, no peace-seeking prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> has had such a rare opportunity to end the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab-Israeli</ENAMEX> conflict. The
combination of a solid mandate at home with ripe regional conditions, and now
also the renewed and energetic support of senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and international
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, creates a diplomatic and security base that must not be wasted."
Elsewhere, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported mixed reactions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s
reported turnaround on terrorism. It said there was optimism among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>, who hadn't expected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez Assad</ENAMEX> to make such a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
gesture before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX> were returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, but skepticism among
others who saw it as a psychological tactic to soften up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> public opinion
into accepting territorial concessions.

            Two
themes preoccupying the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX>'s air raid on southern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> reportedly died, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s recent
airstrike on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> close to its border with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-'Arab</ENAMEX> deplored the lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> response to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> action, which it said was an indication of the utter subservience of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. "If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> air raids that killed and injured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Najaf</ENAMEX> cannot arouse the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> conscience from its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-year</TIMEX>
slumber, it would be best to consider that conscience dead," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Khaleej</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Arab Emirates</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> attack, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> claimed was within its territory, "underlines the increasingly aggressive
and militaristic attitude <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> has adopted toward its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> since it
forged its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-sponsored strategic alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurriyet</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> fabricated the incident to divert attention
from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> unrest.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> ran an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with Manouchehr
Mohammadi, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national students</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>, who said
that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' revolt was "bloodily repressed in the name of Islam
and of so-called national interests which were really only those of a corrupt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clergy</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamic Republic of Iran</ENAMEX> were numbered. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mohammadi</ENAMEX> also
disowned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatami</ENAMEX>, whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> originally
supported, saying he listened less and less to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who voted him in and
was now only concerned with hanging on to power. "He no longer represents his
electors of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> and therefore ought to resign," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammadi</ENAMEX> said.

            

               Corriere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera of Milan</ENAMEX> reported a hardening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
line toward illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, now that the war is over. It said
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> are mainly gypsies fleeing persecution by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>
Kosovars, who claim they collaborated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">541</NUMEX> gypsies
landed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Apulia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>). They will be expelled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said,
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s guarantees of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and lodging for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>
were conditional upon there being a war in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
is keeping up its pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, with the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX> reporting
condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s abandonment of the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>" policy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also had
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhang Qiyue</ENAMEX> vaguely hinting at the possibility of
military action by saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Liberation Army</ENAMEX> "shoulders the
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>-backed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wen Wei Po</ENAMEX> reported
troop movements in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">provinces</ENAMEX> facing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, but this was later denied
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Herald</ENAMEX> reported a little victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>--a decision by the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX> to withdraw diplomatic recognition from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
Party has decided to speed up privatization of the textile, electrical,
electronic, and construction industries by giving up majority control of them.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--through various holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--holds <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 to 70 per cent</NUMEX> of
shares in the bulk of mainland listed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, making it hard for minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> to ease out ineffective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and enforce strict corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">governance</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has announced plans
to cut spending on social welfare programs, which are largely notional anyway,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segodnya</ENAMEX> published an upbeat interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Khristenko</ENAMEX> predicting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will get its promised loans from
happens again."

            On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> front, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London's New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanna Coles</ENAMEX>,
wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are surprisingly dry-eyed about the tragedy.
"The real mystery of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy Jr</ENAMEX>'s death is why it hasn't unleashed the
national hysteria that greeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s fatal car crash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>.
Notwithstanding cable TV's frenetic electronic vigil, with station <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
clearly hoping for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>-like bounty of extra <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, the attempts by a series
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> to launch a national wave of emotion has failed. Not even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christiane Amanpour</ENAMEX> sobbing on air (she once roomed with him) was able to shake
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s uncharacteristic stoicism."

         
      
   
