
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>

            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX> floated the idea of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> presidential campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s ambitions have been
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>'s most delectable political story. The jokes abound: what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
would do on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> carpet, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President Beatty</ENAMEX> would hire as his
intern, etc. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> has stayed virtually silent, but his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are encouraging speculation: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> has been consulting with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>," they say. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> is taking this very
seriously." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Click for Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courting Beatty</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> nomination.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wife Annette Bening</ENAMEX>, they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, is enthusiastic.

            The right thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> is a ridiculous, preening
glory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hound</ENAMEX> who would preach limousine-liberal ideas. The left thinks he can
illuminate a grand populist vision with pure charisma. Both sides mistakenly
assume that because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, he, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, could flatter,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seduce</ENAMEX>, and inspire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. He charmed the panties off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Wood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faye Dunaway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Christie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabelle Adjani</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">et al. Surely</ENAMEX> he
could charm the pants off <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few million</NUMEX> disaffected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. (And even if the
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who slept with him, he could make a
strong showing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> primary.)

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> has always
been, in the words of film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Thomson</ENAMEX>, "a very uneasy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Beatty</ENAMEX>
is too cool and distant to be great on screen. He has made his mark on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> more as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, and it is this that explains his
political ambition. The media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">snicker</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor-politician</ENAMEX>, who presumes to
speak on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s great issues. But consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> as a self-made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Beatty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sympathizers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffington</ENAMEX> rightly ask why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, who inherited his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>, is a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> is a
joke. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> has shown a ruthless, brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> for manipulating the
politics of his industry. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, where no one gets his way all the time,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> has got his way forever.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Easy Riders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bulls</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Biskind</ENAMEX>
chronicles how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> parlayed the heartthrob status he'd won from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>'s
Splendor in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grass</ENAMEX> into a controlling position as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>. He
almost single-handedly brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX> to the screen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>
and made his fortune off it by negotiating a contract for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of the
gross. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, he bullied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> into making
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Shampoo</ENAMEX> and Heaven Can Wait his way. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, during the height
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, he persuaded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf & Western</ENAMEX> to pony up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reds</ENAMEX> , a movie sympathetic to communism. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years later</TIMEX>, he got
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> to spend the then-preposterous figure of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ishtar</ENAMEX> .
It flopped, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> walked away unscathed. Most recently, he compelled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX> to put up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> and to give him absolute creative control over the film, even
though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) it was a political movie and hence a lousy investment, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) it
propounded ideas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> detests. There are endless stories about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">charmed</ENAMEX> or threatened or kneecapped this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> into doing
what he wanted.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> brought those same
skills to his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> career as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brownstein</ENAMEX>, who chronicled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s politicking in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Power and the Glitter</ENAMEX> , notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> may
be the only star in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> history who preferred to participate in politics
from behind the scenes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> doesn't need the ego gratification of public
politics. He has been famous his entire adult life. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> gave
speeches on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McGovern</ENAMEX>'s behalf, but he disliked the high-profile role. He
was an awkward, embarrassed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. "He understood why the public is skeptical
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who makes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> talking about the class struggle,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownstein</ENAMEX> says.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> excels at the backroom nitty-gritty. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, he
aided <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGovern</ENAMEX> most by organizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX>, even persuading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX> and
Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Garfunkel</ENAMEX> to reunite for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGovern</ENAMEX> benefit. (If that isn't great politics,
nothing is.) When he advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984 and 1988</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> remained in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shadows</ENAMEX>, planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> and campaign strategies. "Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> in that
campaign thought he was a positive force," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownstein</ENAMEX> says. Of the few public
statements <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> has made about his potential campaign, the most revealing is
this: "There has to be someone better [than me]." This is not modesty--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>
has no modesty. It is his cool and honest pragmatism. He recognizes that he'd
be a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.

            Though he's supposed to
be a liberal icon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> lacks the crystallizing vision of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. His
politics are a muddle. It's not happenstance that he is backed by such an odd
assortment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huffington</ENAMEX> to earnest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liberal Bill Moyers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> is not cynical: He desperately believes the
political system is broken and needs fixing. He just seems unable to explain
how it's broken and how it should be fixed.

            In interviews, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> repeatedly chokes when asked for
specific political ideas. He seems vaguely to believe that there is too much
money in politics, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are too powerful, welfare reform was wrong, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX> is a big problem. He says he wants to conjure up the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. Bulworth , the closest thing to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> political
platform, is a mess as political science--an incoherent, condescending slop
about the evils of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and the innate decency of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> is
fabulous on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> campaign tactics. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>: His political
principles tell him to deplore gamesmanship, but gamesmanship may be what he
understands best. Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> spends a lot of time savaging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
corruption, yet he cultivates friendships with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> incarnate.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> is meticulous, even anal. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, he is famous
for demanding take after take till he's sure it's right. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to see how his
general caution contrasts with his brazen womanizing.) Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> can control
their images. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> can forbid interviews, decline to answer questions, and
refuse to appear in public. He didn't speak to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> from the late '70s
till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> must answer questions, take abuse,
and keep smiling. The first thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> would have to learn, says
Huffington, is "to get comfortable with ridicule." It's not clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>
is willing to do that. He's too cautious. After all, he twice declined
opportunities to run for office in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, when he was a much more credible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> than he is now. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownstein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> led the polls in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> race to succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> but refused to run. And in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1976 Beatty</ENAMEX> resisted pleas to make a late primary challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s flirtation with the presidential campaign
may be a canny political tactic. He doesn't really want to run, but perhaps he
can use the threat of a candidacy to make himself a behind-the-scenes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who delivers the left to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '60s</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> turned down the opportunity to play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> in a movie, then
became a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> may turn down the opportunity to play
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> in a campaign, then become a power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broker</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
