
   
   
      
         
            I'm Melting

            
               One
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred eighty-two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> heat wave. Health
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> worried about more deaths, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> worried about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meteorologist</ENAMEX> said that in some regions "there is a
drought that is comparable to the drought of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX>." (Chatterbox wonders it
can get.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> raised money for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> campaign in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> insisted that he went "to learn more about the things
that unite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> called it a "brazen
publicity stunt." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Huckabee</ENAMEX> jested, "He's never been here
before, he's never worked here, he's never lived here. ... <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> he will be
announcing his candidacy for some significant major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>."
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> prepares <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> will guard computer data essential to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and major
industries. It will monitor nonmilitary government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and track
banking, telecommunications, and transportation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX>
warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> that the monitoring could be misused for
spying on or hacking into private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eileen Collins</ENAMEX> became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">command</ENAMEX> and land a space
shuttle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX> called her landing "beautiful" and "textbook." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>
later acknowledged that the shuttle suffered a hydrogen leak and a
short-circuit as it took off.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> gathered support for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> tax-cut plan.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> appeased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> by agreeing to condition the cuts on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX>
reductions in the federal debt. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ways and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Means</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> of supporting
"big government 
                  on 
                  autopilot
               " and
argues that the cuts epitomize compassionate conservatism. But in the same
pages, deficit-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk ex-Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Nunn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Rudman</ENAMEX> assert that the surplus
should be used to pay down the deficit , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> a
"modest, effective" plan quietly being brokered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey Graham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>
The paper condemns the bill as "misshapen," "unaffordable," and
"a further mortgage on an already overburdened future." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
warned, "I will not allow a risky plan to become law."

                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> questions .

            
               A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motel handyman</ENAMEX> confessed to a spate of slayings in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yosemite National Park</ENAMEX>.
He killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> sightseers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> and decapitated a park-employed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">naturalist</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. After the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> killings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> had questioned the
killer but ruled him out as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> instructs
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> to review "its
every action " in the case.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Hassan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX> died. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> praised
his deft leadership, opposition to militant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, and brokerage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
peace deals. Everyone wondered why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez Assad</ENAMEX> didn't show up
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> (see "" for more). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               Post lauds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>'s "moderation and reason" but wishes he had done more to speed his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s progress.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> banned the religious sect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> and arrested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Among the detainees are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, who will be
forced to take "re-education" classes. According to "," the official paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX> accused the sect of spreading superstition, hoodwinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, provoking unrest, and jeopardizing stability. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
calls the sect harmless and warns <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> against "returning to the ideological
monitoring and indoctrination methods of the past." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journeyed</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing but
barely mentioned the crackdown.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fourteen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> were massacred in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation</ENAMEX>
Army denounced the killings, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> attributed the
murder to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">faction</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX> worried that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> will now
flee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the murders, which happened within earshot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>,
demonstrate the ineffectiveness of the peacekeeping mission; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) they
demonstrate the ineffectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s entire campaign, since ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> are still killing each other. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> editorial noted
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are not cops" but urged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Serbs</ENAMEX> .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> pledged to strike peace deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 months</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Syria</ENAMEX> responded by asking radical
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX> to end their attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. His meetings
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> were roundly applauded for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soured</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> explains in 
                  Slate
                why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>
are . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>
not to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> out of the peace
process, while an op-ed piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> cautioned
that congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, under the sway of the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud</ENAMEX>
Party, will "throw spikes into the newly energized peace train."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> will try to soothe tension between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> abandoned its "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>" policy, which implied
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s sovereignty over and eventual reunification with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. "Don't
underestimate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s firm determination to uphold national
sovereignty, dignity, and territorial integrity," warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> Foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry</ENAMEX> in response. An editorial from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xinhua</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> vilified
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Teng</ENAMEX>-hui for venturing down "a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>" and swimming
against the "historical tide" of unification. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX>
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> with words now and, if necessary, military
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> later, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoys</ENAMEX> will
pressure him to back down. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> predicted that the spat will blow over when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> steps down in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> was laid to rest. The ashes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> were scattered at sea. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> attributed
the crash to a piloting error by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, but a tidal wave of eulogies
(including this one from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ) blamed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>. Other explanations: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> cited
hazy flying conditions , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX> explained the of
the flight in 
                  Slate
               , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> reported
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> had been obliged to schedule the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX> landing by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> says that Wall Street is blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan Stanley</ENAMEX> for making JFK
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> pointed to a
"novelty-seeking and risk-taking gene discovered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>" (see "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" for ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> why "we lard
up the sorrow with this great and gross festival of national media blah-blah about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">royalty</ENAMEX> and The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Curse</ENAMEX>." In 
                  Slate
               ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Brinkley</ENAMEX> has cashed in on the death; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. William Medley</ENAMEX>
tells he was with the deceased; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi Kantor</ENAMEX> wonders how started.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of millions of dollars</NUMEX> on projects
unapproved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , a
congressional report accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> of funding a top-secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
program, an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX>, a high-tech missile defense system
previously rejected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">unapproved</ENAMEX> purchases. The report
expresses shock at the flagrant illegality of the expenditures. "Do we get it
right <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the time? Of course not," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> responded.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> agreed that a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> should supervise nuclear weapons
research. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> would report directly to the secretary of energy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Sponsors</ENAMEX> of the plan say it would institute accountability for security
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breaches</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> reportedly prefers an even stronger independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ</ENAMEX> market are going public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX>
say the switch will result in more robust and better-financed markets for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doubters</ENAMEX> ask how they will be regulated. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> doubts that they can continue to regulate themselves.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX> chose a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carleton S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiorina</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> among the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> biggest publicly held
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> among the Fortune 500. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
says the choice proves that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H-P</ENAMEX> "is serious about continuing to revamp its
stodgy image," while a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> editorial calls it evidence that
the glass ceiling "is at least cracking."

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Woodstock '99</TIMEX> ended in vandalism, looting, and arson. Concert-goers
threw bottles, set fire to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor-trailers</ENAMEX>, and recreational <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bonfires</ENAMEX> grew
into serious blazes. "These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> ," a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendee</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigars</ENAMEX> will carry warnings similar to those on cigarettes. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX> said the current
absence of labels implies "that cigars are a safe alternative to
cigarettes." Industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">honchos</ENAMEX> protested that "cigar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> are mature,
well-informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> who smoke on an occasional basis."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyclist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance Armstrong</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tour de France</ENAMEX>. He is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">testicular cancer</ENAMEX> that had spread to his brain and lungs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>,
like everyone else, expressed awe at his comeback . "I'm happy I finished <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. No one deserved to
beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armstrong</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," said the second-place <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyclist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Zuelle</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> implied that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armstrong</ENAMEX> must have used performance-enhancing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> implied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> were sore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
