
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">265</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Serfs Up&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, the
rule was well established that 'no lord could be sued by a vassal in his own
court, but each petty lord was subject to suit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> of a higher lord.'
" 
               This surprisingly relevant bit of medieval lore turns out to
be the philosophical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 264</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The $156K Problem":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     Overheard at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>: "My intention is to do
whatever he indicates to me he wants done with them. He may want them returned.
He may want me to destroy them. He may not care at all." You make the
prediction: Who will want whom to do what?
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> will want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> of his letters to return them to him. Then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> will send them back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>, and she'll auction them off
again, and once again, they'll split the take in one of the most elaborate
swindles ever devised."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> will want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Levine</ENAMEX> to destroy the entire print run of the first
issue of Talk . That'll stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from voting for her!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Gaffen</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Wolk</ENAMEX>
had similar answers.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> is still waiting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> to let him know about those test
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rabbits</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Bitterman</ENAMEX>
            

            "This
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s response to the question of what she should do with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'over</ENAMEX> budget' collection of clothes she tried to sneak by customs in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Geer</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Thomason</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond</ENAMEX> )

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> does not care what law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarians</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> do with
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1790 through 1998</TIMEX>. Apparently, for
all those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> were just kidding around."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX>
(similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Once "auction" invoked the incomprehensible
high-speed chatter of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> to the giddy crescendo, "Sold
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>!" Then some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> slipped a bag of cash to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, and
we all went out and drank <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bourbon</ENAMEX> until we puked all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>-bought
shoes of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>. Lordy me, I'm as nostalgic for the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>.

            Now "auction" invokes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX> and the sort of human
progress that means an unsociable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX> of original animation cells from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prewar Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> cartoons will now have even fewer occasions to socialize
awkwardly with others, in their pretty-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> footwear.

            And even nowier, it
means <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> auction, which has dismal connotations, but so does everything with
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netherlandish</ENAMEX> prefix--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> treat, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> courage, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>. This is, of
course, because a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> treat is no treat, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> courage is no courage, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dutch Schultz</ENAMEX> is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> at all. Or maybe he is, but undoubtedly a very
inferior sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>. However, as 
                  Slate
               's own James
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surowiecki</ENAMEX> explains with admirable clarity, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> auction is quite a fine
idea. You see, the way this thing works is if someone bids <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> and someone
else bids <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>, the low bid takes it--can that be right?--but in some
sophisticated way that makes it great for everyone except the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> . Although the fun of calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Talbot</ENAMEX> a sap must be diminished
by the fact that last week his assets were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> he's got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX>.
What a loser. In his fancy schmantzy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>-bought shoes.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beholdin</ENAMEX>' to You
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX> will want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Norton</ENAMEX> to return
those letters--that's my prediction--and on the way over, maybe pick up a pizza
and some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>--no, malt <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>--and some pornographic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, and some
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-weight motor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, and that cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 7-Eleven</TIMEX>. That's what I
forecast. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> will tell.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX> auction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>
of the popular software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton Utilities</ENAMEX>, paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$156,500</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> letters <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>
wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27 years ago</TIMEX>.

            In other
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80-year-old</TIMEX>-recluse news, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX> announced the impending
publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dream Catcher</ENAMEX> , the memoirs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>'s 43-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>.

            
               Fun With Fordice
Extra
            

            Caught in an adulterous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liaison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Fordice</ENAMEX>, a flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of family values,
resigned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> as co-chair of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>'s presidential campaign. ("I said,
'I'm going to do what's best for you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>.' ") No pesky blanks to fill in, no
messy matches to, erm, match. Simply join me in kicking a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> governor
when he's down.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fordice</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Principles</ENAMEX>
of Good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>" (for more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fordice</ENAMEX> twaddle, click here):

            
               

                  

                     Is it pleasing in the eyes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>?

                     Is it good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>?

                     How much does it cost?

                     How are we going to pay for it?

                  

               
            

            Fordice answers a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that vacation with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>:

            "Let me tell you
something, you invade my privacy this way, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months from now</TIMEX>, I'll whip your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ass</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fordice</ENAMEX> explains he's not
a hypocrite:

            "You say somehow I've
betrayed the idea of family values? To me, the idea of family values has to do
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nurturing</ENAMEX>."

            After pleading memory
lapses for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fordice</ENAMEX> admits that it was indeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Creson</ENAMEX> who was
with him at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>-heavy lunch that preceded his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> crash:

            "Of course it was. Did
you ever doubt it? I told you the absolute truth I had no clue what was going
on. I still don't, other than what I was filled in on. Later on, of course, I
found out that's who I was having lunch with."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fordice</ENAMEX> explains that when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has an affair, it's bad, but when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, it's OK:

            "I have never lied
before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. I have never lied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, wagging my finger on TV
and telling blatant lies about my conduct."

            
               Dance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            " 'Hockey,' performed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole Porter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Every Time We Say Goodbye</ENAMEX>' and to music by Alkistis
Protopsaltis, is a gliding in-line skating duet for the deliciously goofy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
Guglietti as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Player</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Lewis as the Elusive Puck</ENAMEX> who tames
him."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24, 1999</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lois Ambash</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headline Haiku</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Delegates</ENAMEX> vote to
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">unionize</ENAMEX>
approval of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' lies
as the world heals
at a nude beach.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24, 1999</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>'s
Ongoing Extra
            

            Last chance to mock the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greatest Legends List</ENAMEX> of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> by devising a brief plot summary of a
movie in which any equally ranked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>--for instance <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crawford</ENAMEX> are both rated No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>--should have co-starred. Replies due by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.

            Inspirational example:

            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> I Am
Spondylosis! --A brash young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Douglas</ENAMEX>) plots to marry a rich
heiress but finds himself smitten instead with her mute widowed grandmother
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lillian Gish</ENAMEX>).

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leftover Lewinskiana</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
