
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lessons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX>
after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> agreed to end the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> rose on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor to gloat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Biden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Del.</ENAMEX>, called it "a victory for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Reid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nev.</ENAMEX>, chided
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who had called it "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s war." More than a week
later, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> remain unrepentant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombing was unnecessary and
caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' ethnic cleansing, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> charged
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . "This is not a victory. I think that this
is going to continue to be a mess."

            
Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2000 election season</TIMEX> and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> to come, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will go on debating who was right and who was wrong in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. They
still don't get it. The point isn't who was wrong. The point is to understand
what was wrong and to learn the corresponding lessons.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Aggressors</ENAMEX> don't control the rules. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX> reasoned that
the war was futile because aggression is the way of the world, and indomitable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ferocity</ENAMEX> is the way of aggressors. They said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> enmities were too deeply
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ingrained</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> was too ruthless, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> were
too fiercely attached to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to back down. While assuming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was infallibly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> and weak, they assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> was
infallibly clever and resolute. But just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> proved capable of fighting
on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> proved capable of giving up.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. We can make the rules. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the war's outbreak,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and talking heads pronounced it a failure. Throughout the bombing,
they said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> lacked the ability or resolve to
prevail. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundits</ENAMEX> assessed the war's prospects with detached skepticism, as
though forecasting the weather. But war is more than an objective event.
Subjective factors--resolve, confidence, and patience--can prove decisive.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> simply refused to lose. Rather than accept the law of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jungle</ENAMEX>, they overrode it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wagered, as he put it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago</TIMEX>, "that we
could raise the price to a point where it would no longer make any sense for
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>] to go on, and where he could no longer maintain his position if he
did." By ending the war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> accepted the new rules.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. To impose limits on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, you must know your own.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of the war observed, rightly, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> was protecting itself rather
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> by refusing to risk its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> in low-flying missions or its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infantry</ENAMEX> in a ground invasion. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> thereby exposed a
"huge limit on its will," i.e., "it believes the defense of [its] values is
important enough to kill for, but not important enough to be killed for." But
by depriving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> of the ability to kill allied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">demoralized Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> who had counted on body bags to demoralize citizens
in the West. In essence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> held <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> at a safe distance with one arm
while pummeling them with the other. In such a hopeless situation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
gave up. By taking into account the limits of its own will--the will to endure
pain--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> broke <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. It's not about who wins. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deride</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for having
let squeamish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> curtail the early stages
of the war. They're indignant that we allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, our old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nemesis</ENAMEX> and new
deadbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">debtor</ENAMEX>, to water down our terms for ending the war and sneak its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> ahead of us. They argue that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX>, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, won the war by drawing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> out into the open, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>
could pound them. While complaining that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> shoulders too much
responsibility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and will end up paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconstruction</ENAMEX>, they fret about the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> control of the
peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. They don't understand that the point of the war was
international justice and peace, not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> power.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. It's not about who loses. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who argued
throughout the war that we shouldn't have got into it now say we didn't really
win it because we didn't invade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>, seize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, depose or kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, and force the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to agree explicitly to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> independence.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have left the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in power," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>.
The peace agreement includes "no mention of a referendum on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s
sovereignty," frets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX>. But the point of the war wasn't to
conquer or humiliate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. The point was to stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> cycle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conquest</ENAMEX> and humiliation.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Just because we're doing something bad doesn't mean the alternatives
are better. By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s own estimates, we killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. We destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, crippled power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, accidentally
bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, and wiped out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s economy. While <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> prevented
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> from ascertaining the fate of ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leftists</ENAMEX> held up images of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian casualties</ENAMEX> as proof
that the bombing was wrong and must be stopped. Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has persisted and
has broken the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>' lock on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have gone in and are
beginning to confirm the scale of the atrocities halted by the bombing. As bad
as the bombing was, permitting the atrocities to go on would have been
worse.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Just because we didn't do the right thing before doesn't mean we
shouldn't do it now. Predictably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> on the left denounced the
war, arguing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s motives were suspect because we have
often invaded small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> for selfish reasons and have failed to intervene
in conflicts when altruism required it. Unpredictably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> on the right
adopted the same argument, pointing out that we had failed to act in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>,
Chechnya, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eritrea</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>. While claiming to have judged the government
by its deeds, both camps judged the current war--wrongly--by who was waging
it.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. It's better to build a law enforcement system than to punish one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outlaw</ENAMEX>. During the war, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX> who prized human rights and vigilance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused Clinton</ENAMEX> of going easy on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. They faulted him for letting
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> veto bombing targets and rule out ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. Now that it's
over, they're criticizing him for letting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> broker the peace agreement and
participate in the peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, and they're still complaining that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> "were impeded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian leadership</ENAMEX> from effectively fighting
the war." They don't understand that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> compromised with each other and
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> because they sought long-term peace--not short-term
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gratification</ENAMEX>--and that such peace requires a level of deterrence that can be
achieved only by an international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Don't define yourself merely by your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> preached military strength in the face of foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expansionism</ENAMEX>. But now that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> whom they despise has led the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> into war, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have adopted the arguments of the counterculture.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX> claim that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> was open to peace all along, that the war and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> were our
fault, that we needlessly offended <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and that our "victory" is false. By
forsaking their intellectual heritage just to spite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, they have paid him
the ultimate homage. They have allowed him, through their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, to redefine
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. History defies laws. Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> pretend to explain
the past and predict the future with the same certainty as natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>.
They trotted out numerous theories to establish the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> mission's futility:
Air power alone had never won a war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> had proven their invincibility
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, and negotiation backed by gradual military escalation had
failed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas L. Friedman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> even had a
theory that no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> had ever gone to war against another
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>.) None of these theories panned out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. That's
because theories apply only in certain circumstances, and circumstances change.
Surveillance and air power are vastly more sophisticated than in previous wars,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has a far greater power monopoly in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> had, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>,
unlike in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, the isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in the war was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> but
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>.

            Who was wrong about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>? Those who were too cynical to challenge the ways of the world, too
preoccupied with the past to see the present, and too obsessed with who was
wrong to recognize what was right.

         
      
   
