
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proud Bear</ENAMEX>

            Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have been crowing about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> stealing a march over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> have queried the wisdom of the move. The daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segodnya</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masterminds</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
campaign clearly failed to consider the consequences of plonking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>
paratroopers at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> got there. The greatest
danger was not that they would be left without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and reinforcements
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulgaria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> having refused to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> with an air corridor
into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>) but that they could be subject to attacks by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation</ENAMEX>
Army, which had already brought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> suburbs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>
would target the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX>, which would have to rely on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> for
their protection, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neue Zürcher Zeitung of Switzerland</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
pressing for the immediate disarmament of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kommersant Daily</ENAMEX>
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> had been lured into a trap, because they would have
to hold out until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least the weekend</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> summit takes place in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cologne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. "It is only then that the paratroopers will become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trump</ENAMEX> card in a political game between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>," it said. "Otherwise,
the thrust to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> will have been a spectacular but ineffective
action."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestia</ENAMEX> , however, believes that this act of bravado has
already achieved a lot by showing the West that it cannot brush <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> aside.
"Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who have got into the habit of confronting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> with
faits accomplis will now know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>, too, is capable of
getting its coup in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s strategy of getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to win the peace for it and then, after dividing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zones</ENAMEX>, casting it out, has proven its futility." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Komsomolskaya Pravda</ENAMEX>
made the same point, saying this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has
managed to score a point off <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX>. Moskovskaya
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pravda</ENAMEX> said the coup means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> would not, after all, be able to
impose its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, but the paper criticized
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> for not going further. "When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> was under our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, we should have landed a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> contingent there immediately," it
said, even though this would have meant cooler relations with the West and
probably a suspension of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s negotiations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary</ENAMEX>
Fund.

            As to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s claim that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paratroopers</ENAMEX>' premature incursion had been "a mistake,"
this was ruled out in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestia</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relations Committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Lukin</ENAMEX>, who said in an interview that only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> could have given the order for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to go in.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> did not act at all in opposition to the political will of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukin</ENAMEX> said. He added that the move was in keeping
with the relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> resolution "because instead of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
operation, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> had got under way. ... The blitz march of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> was an attempt to make matters develop in full compliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukin</ENAMEX> added that the West should treat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lackey</ENAMEX>, but he ruled out any clashes between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
"because the allied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> realize perfectly well that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> was right,
legally and morally."

            
Coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western European</ENAMEX> papers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> focused mainly on
horrific new evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> massacres and on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX>,
which, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Süddeutsche Zeitung</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> reported, is occupying
strategic positions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and hampering the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> retreat. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> led on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian Orthodox</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> demanding the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> "in
the interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" and his replacement by a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">salvation</ENAMEX>." Describing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>'s influence as "enormous," Corriere
said this was "the first severe attack" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> returned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to one of its favorite themes: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Washington</ENAMEX>,
after dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, have another go at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toppling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>? The
most frequent answer was yes, though an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX>
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> was increasingly convinced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has no plans to
remove the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. The article said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, which borders
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, has seen no signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military preparations and believes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> may be deterred from fresh action by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s intensive
preparations over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past nine months</TIMEX> for a "final showdown."

            But in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arab al-Hayat</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> articles predicting that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will adopt a much more aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> policy after
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salameh Ne'matt</ENAMEX> wrote that the defeat of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> was "a resounding demonstration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s power and its ability
to foil attempts by radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> ... to defy the New World Order which it
leads." So, in a different way, was the defeat at the ballot box of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, who fell as a result of "sustained political
bombardment." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ne'matt</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> had given the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> greater
credibility in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> and broader room for maneuver, since a number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> classifies as "radical," such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, have
shown that "they fully understand the rules of the game" and have taken to
dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> much more intelligently and pragmatically than before. He
said, "This may be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>'s last chance to learn lessons from the developments
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX> and appreciate the futility of entering into a fresh
stand-off with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, irrespective of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> or injustice of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
policy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MidEast</ENAMEX>."

            
Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Hayat</ENAMEX> article said that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> "shamelessness is set to
make a major comeback" in the region, as, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, there is "no prospect
of persuading the policymakers in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that they are not always
right--just as it was impossible to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> that he did not win the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> that it was his savagery which led to the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> and provided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> with moral cover for its first dirty war.
... We cannot expect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to change the way they think about the
region, with all their arrogance, high-handedness, and ignorance of
realities."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> scare in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> led the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> , which said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is "fighting to
recover consumer confidence" after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belgians</ENAMEX> fell ill after drinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>. The FT said it evoked memories of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1990 Perrier</ENAMEX> scare, when
traces of benzene were found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mineral water</ENAMEX>. This is believed to have
cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX>, it said. A story reported in most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> concerned a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana skin</ENAMEX> found in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudor</ENAMEX> garbage
dump near the Tower of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. Giving this front-page treatment, the
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX>, dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1480s</TIMEX>, could have been
nibbled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry VIII</ENAMEX>--which is odd, since <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> were previously though
to have first arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 300 years later</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
