
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">274</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Chants Taking&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               
                  Over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few days</TIMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> shouted: "Down with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>," "Oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX>, shame on you!" and "Jerks!" Who was protesting
what?
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">273</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun With Ambiguity":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              Here's a headline from this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Swerve and Sharp Elbow Cost a Hotfoot the</ENAMEX>
Stage." What's the
lead?
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gretzky</ENAMEX> reverts to old ways in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ill-fated Cats cameo</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Olivier</ENAMEX> in a posthumous revival of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodman-Malamuth</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Things got ugly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> suddenly shouted, 'Off the
stage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">m*****f*****</ENAMEX>,' and sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> reeling, in a scene eerily
reminiscent of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> tumble."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nikonovich-Kahn</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> from both sides of the aisle opened Pecksniffian frippery
holus-bolus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> vowed to roughhew the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spittoon</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bruce</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Riverdance</ENAMEX> craze came to a bizarre ending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> as the show's star
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Flatley</ENAMEX> was pummeled to death by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience members</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sturgis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biker</ENAMEX> rally."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Markus Beeby</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Putting aside "stage" as
a horse-drawn conveyance, a popular delicatessen, a part of a rocket, and an
opportunity to mock <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Sheehy</ENAMEX> (who seems to get a free ride from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>), this question all but demanded the invention of a violent
theatrical event, and that's not easy. Violence may look magnificent on screen,
but on the theatrical stage it's phony baloney. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Violence</ENAMEX> among theatrical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, can be entertainingly savage, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">cf, All About</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> .) In all the hullabaloo about violence in popular entertainment, movies
and television were often chastised, the stage never. (Although a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who
toured as a showgirl in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sugar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Babies</ENAMEX> once saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Rooney</ENAMEX> naked, as
vicious a blow to the senses as one is likely to survive.) Nudity on stage can
be powerful, and is still protested, but not as powerful as the frightening
glimpse I had as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ethel Merman in Gypsy</ENAMEX> . Now, if you could get
the ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethel Merman</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">undead Mickey Rooney</ENAMEX> to strip to the waist
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> rounds of bare-knuckle action, that would be truly frightening stage
violence. And a shoo-in at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonys</ENAMEX>.

            
               Hell on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wheels</ENAMEX> but
Unrelated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Steels</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, who had already won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sprints</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tour de France</ENAMEX>, badly wanted to win the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> stage today
because it ended in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maubeuge</ENAMEX>, just across the border from
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>."

            A little later, we learn:

            "In a tumultuous finish, Steels crossed the line
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. ... But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> later the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> was disqualified and placed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX>
because of his aggressive and dangerous tactics. After swerving to cut off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan</ENAMEX>
Svorda, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lampre, Steels</ENAMEX> dug his right elbow into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cipollini</ENAMEX> a few
times just before the finish line.

            "The elbows could be pardoned as a common offense,
but the swerve was too blatant a piece of interference."

            "Another triumph for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>!" the story did not conclude.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Places</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connecticut Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mashantucket</ENAMEX> Pequot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribal Nation</ENAMEX> operates both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foxwoods Resort Casino</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mashantucket Pequot Museum</ENAMEX> and
Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, financing the latter with revenues from the former, an
arrangement that could easily be reversed if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, sated on gambling,
suddenly grew enthusiastic about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>. With that in mind, can you tell which
of the following are from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, and which from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>?

            
               Features
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bull-A-Rama</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wampum Club</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Meaningful change through the power of
training"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fast Track</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild Thing and Pequot Wampum</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">185-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Observation Tower</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12-foot</NUMEX> figure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainmaker</ENAMEX> kneels with
bow and arrow aimed at the heavens to bring down the rain"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the original teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idols</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Anka</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> bring home a dyed sample"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smash Factory</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>
words: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HANG</ENAMEX> ON!!!"

            
               Locale
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>. It's a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Schemitzun 99</ENAMEX>, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">intertribal</TIMEX> powwow, along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eighth Annual Feast of Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corn</ENAMEX> &
Dance, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Championship</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance & Song</ENAMEX>. If only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Anka</ENAMEX> could
somehow participate.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Casino. It seems to be the tasteful name for
some kind of high-roller area, "the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">club</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keno, Slot, Bingo</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table Game</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Casino. Part of the "mission" of the operation
is "to help advance the personal and professional growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mashantucket Pequot Tribal Nation</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>-driven
educational development." And for my money, nothing promotes "personal growth"
more than MBA jargon and a job as a pit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Casino, of course. These are various scratch
ticket games.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>. After a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessing</ENAMEX> by tribal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elder Laughing Woman</ENAMEX> and the ceremonial ribbon cutting, the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">185-foot</NUMEX>
glass-and-stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> opened to the public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past June 18</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Casino. "This is a must-see, high-tech show
presented with majesty and beauty in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town Square</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Casino. His height is not given, although he is
presumably shorter than both the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Observation Tower</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainmaker</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
shows only, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23, 24</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>. Tickets: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38.50 and $60.50</NUMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anka</ENAMEX> is not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mashantucket Pequot</ENAMEX>; he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>. Although at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60.50</NUMEX> a ticket, you'd think
they'd let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> bring home a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Anka</ENAMEX>'s toupee. Rather, it is
part of a demonstration of how natural dyes can be extracted from indigenous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> and used to decorate basketry, clothing.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Casino. Some kind of
ride in the amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> section. "This hilarious speed adventure is loaded
with whack-o-matic fun for everyone. Join escaped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> on a wild and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crazy VIP</ENAMEX> tour of a zany automobile smash <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> will lead you through
wild underground caverns, hilarious test <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX>, and dangerous derby-styled
action. Hold on tight ... this is not your average, run of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> tour or
ride!" Incidentally, tribal elder <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Laughing Woman</ENAMEX>, although laughing, is in no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> associated with whack-o-matic fun.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MyTwinnâ„</ENAMEX>¢
Follow-Up
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine wanted
to do a story on them--his plan was to order the doll, dress it exactly like
him, and then carry it everywhere, noting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>' reactions--so he ordered
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. It arrived and looked utterly unlike him. Not even close. What it looked
like was a standard, creepy doll. Which gave rise to speculation that maybe,
rather than actually tailoring dolls to look like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MyTwinn Co.</ENAMEX>
simply <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hires child models</ENAMEX> who look uncannily like their dolls.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            No business-like show business.

         
      
   
