
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">299</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;What Would Jesus Sue</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> independent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> plans to petition the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Court</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Rights</ENAMEX> to have the ban lifted. Ban on what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s
Question(No <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">298</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fair Play":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     "I'm so excited!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hairstylist Richard Ferris</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syracuse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Fair</ENAMEX>. "This is the most exciting thing that
has ever happened to me." What happened to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX>?
                  
               
            

            "He
invented a ride to sell to the fair that involved stationary painted horses
that revolve on a circular platform to calliope music. He called it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferris</ENAMEX>
Go <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Round</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrill Markoe</ENAMEX>
            

            "He
won a blue ribbon for best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairdresser</ENAMEX>. Nobody has the heart to tell him that
this simply means he'll fetch a higher price at auction, where he'll be sold
off to a rendering <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the news media asked him a question and wrote down his answer
and his name in a spiral notebook."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Considine</ENAMEX>
            

            "Doing
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wash</ENAMEX> and comb-out to a stick of spun <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX> had a similar answer referencing the bearded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s beard; as did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian O'Henley</ENAMEX> referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ape Woman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borneo</ENAMEX>)

            "He
was touched by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Angel</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX> (similar, but less
tender, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">And Jacob</ENAMEX> said to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebekah</ENAMEX>, his mother, 'Behold,
Esau my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is a hairy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and I am a smooth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, so maybe I should take
him to a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylist</ENAMEX> who would no doubt be, as so many of them are, gay. And
attending a state fair.'" (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Genesis 27:11</TIMEX>)

            All well and good, but what really intrigued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> was the coincidence of names between a certain hair stylist
(no doubt gay; they all are) and a giant amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> attraction. And
because, refreshed by my vacation, I want only to please you, here is the
uncharacteristically melancholy entry from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> edition of the World
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encyclopedia</ENAMEX> describing the invention of the popular ride:

            "The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Ferris</ENAMEX> wheel was the largest of all. It
was much larger than wheels seen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. It was built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. W. Gale Ferris</ENAMEX>, a
mechanical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galesburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World's Columbian Exposition</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX>. The wheel was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">250 feet</NUMEX> in diameter and had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. Each of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> could carry <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. After it was used at the exhibition in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX>, the wheel was sold for scrap metal. By heartless bastards
without an ounce of poetry in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>. You pour your guts into something,
trying to create a little beauty and wonder<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">--250 feet</NUMEX> tall!--and they just use
you up and throw you away. Why try? Why live?" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last few</TIMEX> sentences added by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autumnal News Quiz</ENAMEX>, if it matters, which hardly seems likely, so ephemeral are
the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, as transient as the mood-lifting effects of a vacation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, I'm back from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX>. Did you miss me?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>
               ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ferris</ENAMEX> kissed the right hand of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who was not an official exhibit at the fair but was, rather, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visitor</ENAMEX>, in the sense that someone working the crowd for money and votes is
visiting. "And I want to do her hair!" exclaimed the giddy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX>, "I've always
been mad about corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, especially when they're pro-death penalty,"
he did not add.

            Accompanied by her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> took in an exhibition of quilts but skipped the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freakathon</ENAMEX>.

            
               Augmented

               Quotations Extra
            

            (Final sentence added by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.)

            

               "There appears to be every reason to believe that the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> acted
in accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> procedure and acted in a responsible way to save
human life. And of course by 'save human life,' I mean 'shoot some idiot.'
"--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Unapologetic New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> responds to the fatal
shooting--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> cops--of a mentally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> armed with a hand
tool.

               "It is almost as if she never existed. If we are not very careful, there is
a real danger that she will disappear. Although, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> said, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> were right to shoot her; she might have had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amusingly</ENAMEX> named
British social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Mallory Wober</ENAMEX> assesses his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s reaction to
the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX> on her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> deathaversary.

               "The conclusion I've reached is that no one is doing what I believe needs
to be done. I refer, with my trademark belligerence, to gay-bashing and
encouraging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> down the mentally ill; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">well</NUMEX> actually, I suppose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> is doing one of those."--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pugnacious</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> explains why he enjoys being a losing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> primary
race.

               "It makes me nervous, because I've seen what these things can do. It is as
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> had sent over a boatload of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> to patrol
our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and shoot us."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Homeless Turkish carpenter Yusuf Okul</ENAMEX>, who often
wields a hammer, reacts to recent aftershocks.

               "These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have their heads in the sand. Thank goodness they don't have
to govern a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> because things would be really dangerous. There'd be cops
gunning down the mentally ill--you know, in accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> procedure
and in a responsible way to save human life; is that my phone?"--Puffed up New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> disagrees with a federal appeals court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s decision
that even those expressing unpopular views have the right to speak in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wheel</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
