
   
   
      
         
            Questioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cocaine Question</ENAMEX>

            
               Ask, but Don't
Tell
            

            Real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> don't write, "I asked" because it's
not important who asked the question. While framing questions in a way to draw
out interesting or informative answers is important, as your article "" points
out, it's still the answer that matters. And while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> (print and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electronic</ENAMEX>) talking on television often talk about themselves and how they
developed a story, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> itself it's the story that matters. There
really is enough self-promotion in the business, and your suggestion that we
advertise our authorship of questions would make it worse.

            Moreover, you misrepresent the article you
criticize. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> was not asked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, about
"long-ago <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> abuse," and my story did not say he had been. He had declined
to answer a question about what he had told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--on the
reasonable ground that he wanted to leave them out of the campaign. But as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bloom</ENAMEX> was trying to rephrase the question in a more general way,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did it for him, and said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomer parents</ENAMEX> should tell their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
not to use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and do so forthrightly.

            I then followed up with this question, for which I
make no apology because it corresponds with an obvious reality: "And if a child
asks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomer parent</ENAMEX>--'Well, did you?' "

            His reply, which I
quoted and characterized as "awkward," was: "I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomer</ENAMEX> parent
ought to say, 'I've learned from mistakes I may or may not have made. And I'd
like to share some wisdom with you.' "

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Clymer</ENAMEX>
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saletan</ENAMEX> replies:
                
               You're a fine and careful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. A
careful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> enough context to put each quote in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> and to understand how the events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> were shaped. Why
doesn't this rule apply to your questioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> evidently would have preferred to talk to
the press that day about tax cuts and religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>. Instead, reporters
asked him about issues arising from the controversy over his alleged drug abuse
and--in the case of your question--the implications of that controversy for
what boomer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> should say to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. In short, you, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>, and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> on hand chose the topic. That's a major reason
(albeit not the only reason--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> provided some justification in his speech)
why "questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use" ended up in your headline, and "faith-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>" ended up buried at the bottom. In that sense, you helped drive
the story. If you don't report this fact, aren't you omitting information that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> needs in order to understand the persistence of the drug
story?
            

            
               You say that "it's not important who asked the
question." But if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protester</ENAMEX> had shouted your question at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, would you have
reported who asked the question? If so, why not follow the same practice when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> posing the question is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               I share your distaste for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> talking
about themselves, and I don't propose that we print our names every time we ask
a question. Usually, as you know, the choice of topic is fairly obvious. But
isn't there some point at which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s choice of topic can become so
controversial and so determinative of the course of the campaign that the
principle of self-disclosure supersedes the principle of modesty?
            

            
               You're right that I oversimplified the exchange
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>. The questions were about what he had told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> should tell their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Of course, we both know
that the implicit background to these questions was the rumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s own
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> abuse, and in that sense, this larger topic was what your question and the
others were "about." Nobody was asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> such questions that day
(except perhaps for pointed contrast), because the obvious hook for these
questions is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s alleged hypocrisy.
            

            
               Still, I should have
characterized your question more carefully. I'll take responsibility for my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oversight</ENAMEX>. Will you take responsibility for yours?
            

            
               Lines of
Succession
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VI</ENAMEX> (see "," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg</ENAMEX>)? At times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> was mentally ill or at least clinically depressed.
So much so that it was unsafe to leave him alone with sharp objects. Doesn't
sound like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> to me.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward IV</ENAMEX> a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>? This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who spurned
an offer of marriage with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, a marriage that
would have created a valuable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>, in favor of a commoner. He married her
without notifying anyone in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. This shortsightedness caused his chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warwick</ENAMEX>, to defect to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lancaster</ENAMEX>, and they were able to oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> from
the throne for a time. It was only with the aid of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, the eventual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard III</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> was able to reclaim it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> turning to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Henry VII</ENAMEX>? That's the
biggest joke of all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> won one battle and, fortunately for him, killed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>, despite his having the aid
of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, because they were tired of civil war, not out of any love
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> killed off all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> and blamed some of
their murders on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> helped him keep the throne. And it let his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIII</ENAMEX>, become the most powerful and autocratic of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>.

            So, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg</ENAMEX> is
correct, it means that we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> (read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>) in our future.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brandon</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
