
   
   
      
         
            Nuclear Infusion 

            

               Massive radiation leaked from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> nuclear fuel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were hospitalized, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> were ordered to remain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indoors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> said the threat to widespread health appeared small. The
nuclear industry's spin: This was no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chernobyl</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Environmentalists</ENAMEX>' spin: Do we need another
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chernobyl</ENAMEX> to realize that nuclear power isn't safe ?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> shook up his campaign. He is moving his
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> and challenging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> to a
series of debates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said he'll assemble a "leaner, tougher" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to
respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, who has recently raised more money than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. The rosy
spin: The return to his roots will show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is independent from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville Tennessean</ENAMEX> ). The skeptical spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Put the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> where you will, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> is never an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum of Art</ENAMEX> filed suit to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> from
withdrawing its funding. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> has halted checks to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> because of its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" exhibit, which includes a dissected pig
suspended in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> and a painting of the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> that's adorned with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant dung</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists</ENAMEX> are guaranteed freedom, not taxpayer
support. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s spin: When you withdraw support for unpopular views, you
violate this freedom. The jaded spin: The debate is less about principles than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about self-promotion</TIMEX>. (
                  Slate
               's "" and "" debated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s move.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed a temporary spending bill. It will
fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> at current levels for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
negotiate the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> budget. Separately, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> study
concluded that current budget proposals would spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $18 billion</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> surplus. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> promise-breakers are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">raiding Social Security</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are the real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">raiders</ENAMEX> since they won't cut spending.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> quit the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> entered
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> said he had insufficient funds to remain competitive with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. Pundits variously said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>'s withdrawal revealed: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>' control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the influence of money over presidential
politics; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>'s lingering reputation "as a lightweight" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain framed</ENAMEX> himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of patriotism and integrity,
promising to reform campaign finance and strengthen national defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX>
debated whether his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> would: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) differentiate him from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>)
alienate him from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>.
(
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan McCain</ENAMEX>'s messages.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> opened its Web site to sales by other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>.
Anyone can list products through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> by paying a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> fee and a
percentage of each transaction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s zShops began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> new
products. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bezos</ENAMEX> asserted that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was becoming the
Internet's supermall. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> worried that poor products or service from
unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> could tarnish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s reputation (
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Post-Intelligencer</ENAMEX>
               ).

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> is withdrawing from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> now officially control the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> and are encouraging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exiled refugees</ENAMEX> to return <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> discovered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> charred
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bodies</ENAMEX>, the first physical evidence of human rights abuses. The hopeful spin:
It's safe to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> again. The gloomy spin: Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Timorese</ENAMEX> don't
have <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> to go back to.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> wrote himself into the story as a fictional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. The forthcoming book portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s contemporary. 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
                featured an excerpt of the book. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> called the book "pure fiction," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> dubbed it "dishonorable" for its distortions.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX> said the mixing of fact with fantasy was appropriate for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "whose life owed so little to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weems</ENAMEX> and so much to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirandello</ENAMEX>." (
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Culturebox</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX>' literary
device.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> will likely switch his presidential campaign to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX>
Party. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, who sparked controversy with a new book questioning
the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, has been increasingly vocal
about his frustration with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are
divided over whether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s views are too extreme to be included; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>)
his conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> is too valuable to be excluded. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are
unanimous: When the dust settles, we'll come out on top.
(
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" the debate.)

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> won <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder Cup</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>'
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-point victory over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was the biggest comeback in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tournament</ENAMEX>'s history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Justin Leonard</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">45-foot</NUMEX> birdie putt on the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> hole set off a celebration on the course before his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
opponent finished playing. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> called the win historic: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> said it was golf's "greatest moment" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>);
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> labeled the celebration "the most disgusting thing" the sport had
seen (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>).

         
      
   
