
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">315</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Cool, Calm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rejected&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "They're taking
something that's about as likely to happen as a meteorite falling on your head
and telling everybody that it could happen any time," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlin D.</ENAMEX>
Tuttle, about those worry <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">warts</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Health Department</ENAMEX>. Name
that exaggerated (or not) danger.
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">314</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Chaucer</ENAMEX>, Not an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mixner</ENAMEX>, a gay rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">praises</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at a black-tie fund-raising dinner in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>:
"Ever since The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Canterbury Tales</ENAMEX> --strange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> that was--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
been judged by their ____________. And we picked a good one in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>."
               
            

            "Grete
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses buttokes</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Floyd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott</ENAMEX> had similar answers, but in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.)

            
"Ability to accept specious <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pardoner's Tale s."</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX>
            

            "Sely
instrument. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, look, I made a dirty joke in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle English</ENAMEX>! My college
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> would be so proud of me, if they weren't all dead or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senile</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loving the Tavern Better Than the Shop</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pandering</ENAMEX>. No, wait, that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troilus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cressida</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, somebody call
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> and find out where the hell that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pizza</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Ability to say one thing while doing the exact opposite. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HELLO</ENAMEX>?? Gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>??
He signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Preservation of Marriage Act</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> on a crutch, what does he
have to do to lose your support, stab <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Geffen</ENAMEX> with a kitchen
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">knife?</ENAMEX>?)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Berlin</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thomas</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            It is astonishing to see a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> at a
political event refer to any work of literature written before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> or, in the
case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>, written. In her best column in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, in which she reverts
to actual reporting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> had a fascinating talk with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.W.</ENAMEX> about his
cultural tastes. It turns out he has none. He is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of unflappable ignorance
who, despite the round-the-clock presence of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian wife</ENAMEX>, remains all
but illiterate. " 'I've always liked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John La Care</ENAMEX>, Le Carrier, or however you
pronounce his name. I'm mainly a history <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.' He's just finished <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX>'s
Storm , a history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Galveston hurricane of 1900</ENAMEX>, and reads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX>-for-hire stories." It's one thing to be a deeply ignorant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a satin-skinned complacency, a cheek unwrinkled by self-doubt. But
when you declare that you'd like to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, shouldn't everyone just mock
you with a lot of snooty literary references that you don't get?

            "Classical quotation is
the parole of literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> all over the world," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, I
note, quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, who, while not actually classical, was not all over
the world either, although he once took a very nice tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hebrides</ENAMEX>. He
found it to be a lot like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galvoostoon</ENAMEX> or however you pronounce
it.

            

               Angwissous 
               Answer
            

            "Ever since The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canterbury Tales</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
been judged by their traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX> ."

            Mixner, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>, paid tribute
to the political gains the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has made for gay and lesbian <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and
encouraged their continued support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton-Gore</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> ticket received <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of their vote. Or,
to put it more weirdly, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> voted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>.

            While acknowledging his disappointments--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mixner</ENAMEX> was
jailed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> while protesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s position on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in the
military--he applauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s many victories.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Broder</ENAMEX> describes
it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> responded with appropriate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modesty</ENAMEX> and--if I can read between the lines or simply make things up,
important things, things that should have happened--brushed away a tear, " 'I
wish I could have done better,' Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said wistfully. 'But we've done
pretty well, and we're a long way from where we were.' "

            
               Joy

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun With Canterbury Tales Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "Ever since The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canterbury Tales</ENAMEX> , people
have been judged by their stunning ability to have their careers summed up
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX>, B, and C entries in the glossary for The Canterbury
Tales
               .

            Check this out--a "coverchief" is a head-dress.
(Think it over.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuck</ENAMEX>'s sake, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>, flyppe through these! It's like Chaucer
was in, like, pre-cahoots with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> or somethynge.

            Plus, you toss in a
little punctuation, and some consecutive entries read like excerpts from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ouija</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> :

            

               "Aleyes alkamystre, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speke</ENAMEX> he, 'Amor vincit omnia,' angwissous ape
aperteneth areste." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Translation: Garden</ENAMEX>-paths alchemist, although he may
speak, 'Love conquers all,' anxious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> befits stop.)
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asterted</ENAMEX>, astoned, aswowne avowtier, bauderye." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Translation: Escaped</ENAMEX>,
astonished, aswooned adulterer, pandering.)
               

               "Bigileres biknowe, bille bitook, biwreyed blent, bleynte, boghte."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Translation: Liars confess</ENAMEX>, formal charge, entrusted betrayed, turned pale,
redeemed.)
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clerk clippeth cokkow</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Translation</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> embraces
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cuckoo</ENAMEX>.)
               

            

            So anyway, here are
selected A, B, and C words from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CT</ENAMEX> glossary. I'm telling you,
though: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coverchief</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head-dress</ENAMEX> is the best. (Get it? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> dress? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coverchief</ENAMEX>?)
That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mixner</ENAMEX> clearly has his planchette on the pulse.

            aleyes: garden paths

            angwissous: anxious

            ape: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fool</ENAMEX>, dupe; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">monkey</ENAMEX>

            assoillyng: absolution

            asterte, asterted: escaped

            astoned: amazed, astonished

            aswowne: in a swoon, aswooned

            avowtier: adulterer

            bauderye, bawderye: pandering

            bigileres: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liars</ENAMEX>, deceivers

            biknowe: reveal, confess

            bille: petition, formal charge

            biwreyed: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>. revealed, exposed; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. betrayed

            blent: deceived, blinded

            bleynte: turned pale

            bord bigonne: sat in the place of honor

            bour: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>, private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for lord and lady

            briberyes: ways of stealing money

            brike: trap, plight

            brotelnesse, brotilnesse: insecurity, instability,
fickleness

            buxom: obedient

            capul: nag

            chaped: mounted

            chastitee: chastity, abstinence from sexual
intercourse

            chidyng: scolding

            clippeth: embraces

            cokewold: cuckold, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of an adulteress

            conseil kepe: keep secret

            contricioun: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of being contrite, affected
by guilt, feeling

            remorse or penitence

            coom: came

            corage: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>. heart, feeling; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. (sexual) desire,
ardor

            corrumpable: corruptible

            costlewe: very expensive

            countrefeted: imitated

            coveitise, coveityse: avarice, greed,
covetousness

            coverchiefs: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-dresses

            covyne: treachery

            crekes: tricks

            culpe: guilt

            cure: charge,
jurisdiction

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ongoing Amour-Propre Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "My novels ... explore the mysteries behind love
and hate, the darkly amusing, deeply disturbing and ultimately unanswerable
questions that they inspire."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Adler</ENAMEX> takes a long hard look at
his work, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random Hearts</ENAMEX> , and likes what he sees.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited
to submit similar authentic examples of rigorous self-assessment. Replies to
run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penises</ENAMEX> and noses, which, incidentally, scans
beautifully when substituted for the refrain in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lollipops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Roses</ENAMEX>," the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>
Grammy-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Jones</ENAMEX> hit written by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Velona</ENAMEX>. Let's sing it together
right now! Everybody!

         
      
   
