
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Elephants</ENAMEX> in Pinstripes 

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> page on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s campaign Web site
explains that "Running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is a lot like playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>. ... There
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> in professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX>. In politics there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, straw poll, the site advises, is like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, the primaries are the playoffs, and the general
election is the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX>, apparently, is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpire</ENAMEX>.) The implicit message of all this seems to be that because Dubya
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX>, he certainly can be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>.

            If politics is like <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> can be a lot
like politics. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>, for example, is a political contest:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bronx Bombers</ENAMEX> are, well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>--the original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. This begins
at the top with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steinbrenner</ENAMEX>, who is the very model of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>. Steinbrenner recoils at the socialistic demands of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poorer</ENAMEX>, small-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League Baseball</ENAMEX> that want rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> such
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> to give them a cut of their revenue. Steinbrenner loathes this
redistribution of wealth: He considers it a welfare program that rewards bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> for not trying and robs successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of their hard-earned riches.
Like all good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinbrenner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanks</ENAMEX> buck regulation: When other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> tried to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinbrenner</ENAMEX> from signing a separate endorsement deal with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adidas</ENAMEX>, arguing it would undercut the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>'s endorsement plan, he told
them to get lost. It is no accident that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanks</ENAMEX> wear pinstripes. The
business of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> is business. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinbrenner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Republicanism</ENAMEX> runs deep:
He funneled illegal campaign contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>,
winning himself a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> suspension from <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> in the process.)

            Steinbrenner may be a
righty, detesting all who might intervene in his business, but he's happy to
bat lefty when it comes to government aid: He has eagerly petitioned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
City to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> or more to build him a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX>, by contrast, are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dixiecrats</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>' most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous fan</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s No. 1
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> is left-wing icon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Fonda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinbrenner</ENAMEX>'s
charitable contributions go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestras</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turner</ENAMEX> is giving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX>' Web site devotes almost as much space to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Straight A</ENAMEX>" Program, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opportunity Through Baseball</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Revitalization Program</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend of Caring</ENAMEX>, etc.--as it does to triumphs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamond</ENAMEX>.) Steinbrenner
spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last years</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> bidding on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> contracts for his (now
defunct) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipyard</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX> organizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill Games</ENAMEX>, his
squishy plea for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet-American</ENAMEX> friendship.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> are democratic
in their recruiting efforts. They reintroduced the "open tryout" to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>,
an audition where any schlub has a chance to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX>. They endorse an
open-door immigration policy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> on their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roster</ENAMEX>, compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX>' foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> hail from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican Republic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, by contrast, have
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> refugee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Duque</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-communist</ENAMEX>, anti-Castro
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hideki Irabu</ENAMEX>, who comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthy</ENAMEX>, capitalist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, like all good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, favor an
extremely strong defense: They are among the best fielding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX>, who represent former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Nunn</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, are equally strong on
defense.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> mimic their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>' greed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, brazenly take enormous
"contributions" wherever they can be found (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, cable TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adidas</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> pull in close to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, more than any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>,
and own <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s highest payroll, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$87 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, they
exhibit no shyness about raising and spending record amounts of cash to ensure
victory. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> are as rapacious as their rivals, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subtler</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> collect <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions</NUMEX> from their nationally broadcast
games and strong ticket sales, and they pay lavishly for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. They raise
and spend more than all but a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> claims
to speak for the little guy while dunning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX>
hold themselves out as a modest, small-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> resemble the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more important way: In this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>, as in most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> elections, too little separates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX>. Elections match
corporatized, moneyed, and ideologically similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>
matches corporatized, moneyed, and athletically similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> play highly competent, professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>. They rely on
careful teamwork and role-playing, eschewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstars</ENAMEX> and flash. They are
impossible to dislike. (Here, again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> mirror the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX>-haters used to despise Bombers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Ruth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Mantle</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reggie Jackson</ENAMEX>, just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> left abominated hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Goldwater</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. Gradually, that conservatism has
been accepted and embraced by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. So too have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, who are no
longer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> have assuaged the
Yankeephobes with their skill and modesty.)

            This similarity of style and talent between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> flattens the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> as it flattens politics. The
regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and playoffs have eliminated more quixotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Orioles</ENAMEX>, willing to spend endless <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to prove their
incompetence; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan Keyesian Chicago Cubs</ENAMEX>, hopeless but mesmerizing; the
Reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partyesque Boston Red Sox</ENAMEX>, erratic, crazy, but with just enough
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brilliance</ENAMEX> to be dangerous. We are left with the wealthy, talented, mainstream,
likable achievers: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Yankee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albert Brave</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
