
   
   
      
         
            
<P>Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Sensation&quot; Art Worth the Fuss</ENAMEX>?</P>

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>,

            Since you're writing from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, I assume you
haven't seen the show in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, so the first thing I'm wondering is how you
can dismiss an exhibition that you haven't even seen. Consider yourself a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Art</ENAMEX> Criticism--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, too, has not
seen the show.

            I have been out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> several times to see
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sensation</ENAMEX>," and I think it's a wonderfully spirited show. Obviously, not every
piece in it is a masterwork, and there are more than a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. But, on the
whole, I felt moved by the level of energy and feel that the show provides a
welcome antidote to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> scene, which at the moment is suffering from a
severe case of theory-itis. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sensation</ENAMEX>," to its credit, isn't about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derrida</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baudrillard</ENAMEX> or gender-bending or the reified moment of perception. It isn't
about political correctness. Generally speaking, it takes art away from the
theory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> with their <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-pound</NUMEX> books and their
unbearable jargon, and allows real life to come shining through.

            Take, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Damien Hirst</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shark</ENAMEX> piece. It
occupies a giant glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> and so obviously harks back to the geometric forms
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minimalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>. Yet it's also a critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minimalism</ENAMEX>, which at a certain point became too elegant and mannered for its
own good. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minimalism</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, became an art of polished, quite exquisite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surfaces--and Hirst</ENAMEX> wants to get us below the surface, into a deep, muddy ocean
of feeling. Hence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX>, the perfect below-the-surface symbol. At any
rate, I love the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX> piece. Maybe I'm just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> for icons.

            By the way, I think it needs to be said that Damien
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirst</ENAMEX> isn't nearly as dangerous as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damien Hirst</ENAMEX> is not running
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>.

            As to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Ofili</ENAMEX> of
Holy Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> fame, I think he's a solid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofili</ENAMEX> is a black
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX>, and to my mind the picture represents an earnest attempt to
appropriate the Virgin for black culture. I have no problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> dung
(which is just chewed up <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> anyway), and I'd guess the reason the painting
set off such a furor is that it depicts a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Virgin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>
freaked out when he saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Virgin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> who wasn't white. I mean, it's probably
not a coincidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> decided to single out (and all but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lynch</ENAMEX>) the
most prominent black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>. That's a shame, especially since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum of Art</ENAMEX> is the only major art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> that serves
a racially diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.

            Yours
truly,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
