
   
   
      
         
            Finding Money on the Web

            The
Internet economy has already revolutionized the world of campaign fund raising,
even if only a tiny fraction of the total money raised so far for the
presidential contest was raised online. Evidence that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> worlds have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">collided</ENAMEX> does not show in the bottom line. Instead, there are subtler signs:
Online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> give more on average than offline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>; they are
repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>; and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have begun to clamor for
online contributions.

            The
news is so encouraging, in fact, that one firm supplying presidential wannabes
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> fund-raising tools may soon go public. Aristotle, previously Aristotle
Publishing, which has provided campaign-management software to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>, has already reserved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> stock ticker symbol VOTE. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, which has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, recently
received venture-capital financing from high-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.R. Hambrecht & Co.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s e-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, and the market
research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX>. Company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say they don't intend to file with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>.

            The
news of the possible public offering comes at a time when <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only about $1 million</NUMEX>
has been raised online in the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>--and that's by all the
candidates combined. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than half</NUMEX> of that amount has gone into the coffers of
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, who has e-raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $600,000</NUMEX>--including
contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> who print out the form on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s Web site and mail
it in with a check. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">That $1 million</NUMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1 percent</NUMEX> of the more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120 million</NUMEX> raised in the race so far. (The campaigns are expected to release
updated figures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>.) While some are quick to conclude that the Net hasn't
lived up to its hype as a cheap, efficient fund-raising tool, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at
Aristotle beg to differ.

            "We
expect that within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and a half years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the money raised from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> for political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> will be raised on the Internet," says
Aristotle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Aristotle Phillips</ENAMEX>. While <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $125,000</NUMEX> was raised
online in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, he expects <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> to be raised in all federal campaigns in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. "The presidential funds are just a fraction of the money that will be
raised," he says. "The overwhelming majority of the funds that will be raised
and spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> will be in races for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX>--and the dog
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">catcher</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Five</TIMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, and independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX>--have signed up for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle's CampaignContribution</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. The Internet fund-raising service
processes contributions, gathers demographic information, coordinates data for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> reports and, using a nationwide list of registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, checks that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in good standing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, like its competitors
Campaign
Solutions and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PoliticsOnline</ENAMEX>, charges campaigns a percentage of the
contributions they raise. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aristotle</ENAMEX>'s case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> charges an initial
setup fee plus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the contributions, a percentage that's also split
with credit-card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">issuers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middlemen</ENAMEX> who interact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CyberCash</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PoliticsOnline</ENAMEX>, a nonpartisan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, is
discouraged by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s showing, but he doesn't think the problem is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX>'s discomfort with using credit cards online. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who once said new
fund-raising tools were "going to do for campaign finance what the machine gun
did for bank robberies" blames the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for the tepid public
response. "I haven't seen them give anyone a reason to donate money," he
says.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> campaigns have raised little more than pocket change
through their Web contribution "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">storefronts</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> online
out of a pot of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52 million</NUMEX>. The last figure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign released was
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85,000</NUMEX> online out of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $25 million</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, who dips deep into
his own considerable pockets, has netted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $50,000</NUMEX> online, although he
has arranged with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> to develop a contribution site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>, whose
campaign won't reveal how much she has raised on the Internet, had her site
designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intershop Communications</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>-based commercial Web
design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, whose fund-raising figures are also unavailable,
uses tools supplied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign Solutions</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.

            
Despite the numbers, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> are impressed with the activity on the Web.
"The key to raising money online is trying to develop a relationship of
e-commerce with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. ... I almost said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornfield</ENAMEX>, an adjunct associate professor of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington University</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> of e-fund raising hope they will be
able to get more out of each individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> during the course of the entire
campaign."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> campaign's Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Segal</ENAMEX>, says campaigns are already
able to draw some conclusions about the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> donating via the
Internet. "I would say we have learned some fundamental things," he says. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
The political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX> is willing to make a contribution in a secure online
environment. That's been proven and validated in this election cycle. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) You
get the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> contribution and the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> contribution. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) you can get the
repeat contribution."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign has been raising <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $6,000</NUMEX> per day in credit-card
donations online since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, the campaign netted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13,000</NUMEX> over the Internet. "I
can tell you that our average contribution is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $130</NUMEX>, and that is much
higher than the average contribution for direct fund-raising mail in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Democratic</ENAMEX>
campaigns," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Reed</ENAMEX>.

            The
campaigns seem to reach a new pool of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. "We're seeing younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. The average age of direct-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 to 70</TIMEX>. That's not your
demographic profile on the Net," observes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Arena</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presage</ENAMEX>
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consulting</ENAMEX>, who coordinated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s Internet campaign in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. He
notes that contributions might jump if campaigns used innovative
approaches--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> model, for example, in which campaigns offer donors
incentives, such as a T-shirt or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> pad featuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s likeness
or slogan.

         
      
   
