
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">291</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Ocelots&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> tried ocelot scent and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> feces but neither worked as well as Calvin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein Obsession</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>. What were they trying to do?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 290</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fighting Crime ... With Science</ENAMEX>!":
            

            

               According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX>, the list includes
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistanis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cajuns</ENAMEX>. List of what?
            

            "Those
who are looking to 'whup <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Rickles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ass</ENAMEX>' after his last-minute substitution
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indigo Girls</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilith Fair</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little</ENAMEX> brown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who dance around naked in your face, while ranting like
imbeciles, just to get you to shoot a squirt of pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> at them. Because,
you know, they eat it for breakfast. Or is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Green</ENAMEX> I just
described?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer Gabel</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who cannot be subdued with pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> alone, but require repeated,
severe beatings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> is also on this list."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
Star
            

            "
'Native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> language. Some forget the large number of
Dravidian language <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. Grade: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-</ENAMEX>.' Signed, 'Prof. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chomsky</ENAMEX>.'
"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minorities</ENAMEX> to be cruelly caricatured in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Wars: Episode II</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Barlow</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>'
Wrap-Up
            

            It's hard to know where to draw the line when
you're making a joke about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>, especially when it comes to those shifty,
no-good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cajuns</ENAMEX>. I have nothing against them myself, but you know what happens
when they move in next door. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> they turn all the washboards and jugs into
musical instruments, and the next thing you know all the neighborhood crawfish
start to disappear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Cass</ENAMEX> was not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrant</ENAMEX> who suspected
he was being tricked into saying something he'd regret later. But that's not
why I'm here. That's not what I'm all about. What kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would write a
question about race and then get all shirty on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were just trying to
have a little fun? Not yrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trly</ENAMEX>.

            The trick is to think of
me less as the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and more as one of the nannies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">von Trapp</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> killed before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX>.

            
               Spicy
Answer
            

            Ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> with a natural resistance to pepper
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX>.

            As Training Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gutoski</ENAMEX> explained to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> , "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> [pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX>] doesn't
affect are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have consumed cayenne pepper from the time they are small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and this generally breaks into ethnic categories. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
tend to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pickers</ENAMEX>. So with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cajuns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> ...
[w]hat happens is that [pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX>] is effective for a much shorter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>."

            In an apology <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cambridge Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie Watson</ENAMEX> admitted, "There is no scientific
evidence to support these statements." "We're not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, we're police
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>," added <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Pasquarello</ENAMEX>.

            
               Parallax
Answer
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at 
                  Slate
                remind
me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX> never made anyone wait a whole day for the answers to the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX>." Fine.

            The question, if you recall, was about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s age as opposed to the age of some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who
you probably thought were older than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> because they weren't as well
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lit</ENAMEX>.

            The trick was to
rearrange the list by the age they were--or would be--when they became
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Here's the solution:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Harding</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX>

            Calvin Coolidge--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester Arthur</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Polk</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>

            Did I have a point? Not really. I just wanted to
take a cheap potshot by pointing out how old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> is, and how old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX> is. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liddy</ENAMEX> really is old, you know; she just looks young standing
next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>. Of course, so do the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adirondacks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Bruce</ENAMEX> said his problem
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> was that he wouldn't vote for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who couldn't get life
insurance.

            The other charming thing
about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> at the bottom of the list? Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garfield</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McKinley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>, by the time they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>'s
age, they were dead.

            
               Common
Denominators
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, doughnuts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
