
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty '99</ENAMEX> Tour

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> finished his poverty tour. He spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> visiting
poor areas such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Appalachia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi Delta</ENAMEX> to "shine the
spotlight on places still unlit by the sunshine of our present prosperity."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> on the right dismissed the tour as a simplistic photo op, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelman</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who quit to protest the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> welfare reform,
called it cosmetic, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "cannot admit the extent of the
problem because his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> has a vested interest in the notion that
welfare reform has been a success." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeParle</ENAMEX> chides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and the press for their "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skepticism and Indifference</ENAMEX>," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post interprets the tour as a plug for a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX>" strategy of using tax incentives for businesses
to help the poor.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s claim to an "indivisible" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>.
She said this in a letter to a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. This comes several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> after she antagonized some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> by endorsing the idea of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cynics</ENAMEX> suspect she's reversing course to curry favor with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post faults her not for reversing course but for endorsing what it deems an
unwise position . Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX>

               applauds her for "breaking the mold" by running for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> 
               complains that both her campaign travel and that of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>, "are being subsidized--by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> in
Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s case and by private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s
campaign will probably end up paying for the subsidized travel says a

                  Slate
                ".")

            

               Serb rallies against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> are
growing. Unpaid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reservists</ENAMEX> have reportedly
joined the rallies. A news article in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> played
up expectations "that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s survival in power might now be measured not
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>," but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorial throws
cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> on that hope.

            

               Tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> lost another big liability case. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> found
them liable for damages for conspiring to conceal how addictive and harmful
cigarettes are. This increases the chances that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will have to pay
for treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>' health problems. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> observes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>, too, are responsible for knowingly
endangering their health. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> argues that if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> don't pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>' medical care, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> will .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
Radio hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>. His weekly talk show, which has been running on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> radio station for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, will now be syndicated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s spin is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>'s show is part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> entertainment, not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> news. But according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Westin</ENAMEX> isn't buying that .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> 
               formed a 
                     a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> bid from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and
announced plans for a "summer-long listening tour" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. An
experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> sounded
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX> note in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed that star-struck local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> have chickened out of the race in deference to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbagger</ENAMEX>. Political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> noted that whatever her drawbacks, she appeals to soccer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moms</ENAMEX>.
               
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> was sworn in as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> after taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven weeks</TIMEX>
to assemble his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, which comprises <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli Arabs</ENAMEX> complained that they were not included in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ousted Likud Party</ENAMEX>, which tried to form a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> but was rebuked,
accused the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> of being autocratic. In his inaugural speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>
reached out to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> press, including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> editorial page, received <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> warmly. (For more on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s reception, see ".")

            
               The
suspect in the Chicago-area racist killing spree committed suicide.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Smith</ENAMEX> (who had changed his name to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> because he thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
sounded too <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>) allegedly killed a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korean-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and
wounded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX> before shooting himself
as the cops closed in. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> found plenty of racism and anti-Semitism in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s past but little history of violence. The shooting spree has made the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Church of the Creator</ENAMEX>, the hate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> was linked, the new
poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> racism.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s military record is under fire. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times reported that he got "favorable treatment and uncommon attention" when he was admitted
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air National Guard</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, thereby avoiding being drafted to
fight in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> found "no evidence of illegality or
regulations broken to accommodate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s entry." The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX>
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> nearly flunked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> pilot aptitude test but "scored high as
a future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says he "served my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>" and got no special
treatment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> are largely blowing off the
story.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Sampras</ENAMEX> won <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX>. He has now set the record for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX> singles titles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>) and tied the record for most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Slam</ENAMEX> victories (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12</NUMEX>). Sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> likened him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nicklaus</ENAMEX>. "In a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">His Own</ENAMEX>," gushed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . However, the
computer that ranks <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> by their recent
performance in tournaments elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Agassi</ENAMEX>, who lost the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Wimbledon</ENAMEX> final,
to the top rank, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sampras</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay Davenport</ENAMEX> won the women's title,
inspiring much chatter about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dominance on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>.

            
               The

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> women's <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> advanced to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> finals , beating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazil</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> now faces <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, which crushed defending champion <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-0</ENAMEX>. While soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> remain emotionally attached to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, some,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Trecker</ENAMEX>, fault their sloppy play and predict a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> victory.

         
      
   
