
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">316</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Don't Do It, Deacon Don</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deacon Don Thomas</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Church of God</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairbanks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, defends
what he does to reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>: "Yeah, we want to compel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to come to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, but at the same time we don't want to intrude on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. I think
there's a big difference." What does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deacon Don</ENAMEX> do?
            

            
               ( Question
courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Glassenberg</ENAMEX>. )
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">315</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cool, Calm, Rejected":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     "They're taking something that's about as likely to
happen as a meteorite falling on your head and telling everybody that it could
happen any time," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlin D. Tuttle</ENAMEX>, about those worrywarts at the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York State Health Department</ENAMEX>. Name that exaggerated (or not)
danger.
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
meteorite falling on your head."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Feige</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Berlin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Nikonovich-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kahn</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Gaffen</ENAMEX> had similar
answers.)

            
"Paintings containing elephant dung falling on your head."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>
Markoe
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlin D. Tuttle</ENAMEX> falling on your head."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Vance</ENAMEX>
            

            "Being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">christened 'Merlin D. Tuttle</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nikonovich-Kahn</ENAMEX> )

            "I'm
taking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">to-2</NUMEX> odds that he gave himself that name."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlin Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "You
wake up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> bright <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and you're halfway to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> when you
decide to walk to work instead. But you don't go to work. Instead, somehow, you
find yourself at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park Zoo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> just opened and there's no one
there and it's clear and bright and so quiet you can hear the seals break the
water as they circle their pool and the gulls fighting the kept <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> for their
seed. You close your eyes and think about other <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boats</ENAMEX>, back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nova Scotia</ENAMEX>. The wet wool smell of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eaton</ENAMEX>'s
sweaters and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> surplus peacoats and shredded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> for breakfast and thin
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> on the tide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> and diesel as the engines kick in. Then you hear another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noise</ENAMEX>, a cry for help! It's winsome and multitalented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese Witherspoon</ENAMEX>, and
she's accidentally dropped her new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in the polar bear cage! You don't
think, you just act, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless seconds</TIMEX> later the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> is back in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witherspoon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. But something else is bothering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese</ENAMEX>. She's crying, but
they're not just tears of relief because you saved her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">polar bear</ENAMEX>.
Something deeper is wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> just isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> she thought she married ...
he's not real ... like you ... and that's when you get hit by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meteorite</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            When is a threat real and when is it exaggerated
for political interest, like the missile gap, or the bomber gap, or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>
death threats against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, up from last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>? That danger is very, very real declared Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oates</ENAMEX>, testifying in federal court <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> as to why protests on the steps of
City <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> must be limited to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, a limitation set for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s history.

            "I have to take the position that anyone in that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> might have some evil intent," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>. "And that you are an evil
space robot. Taste lead, evil robot! Blam! Blam! Blam!" he did not add.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> stressed that
this beefed-up security is in no way intended to stifle dissent. Nor is it
evidence of a megalomaniac <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> with a puffed up sense of self-importance. Nor
is it simply a chance for any city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to indulge a personal taste for
martial law, surrounding himself with a hunky praetorian guard, manly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> whose
manliness glistens in the light of their boots, burnished to a fine sheen by
the sweaty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exertions</ENAMEX> of muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX> in arms who--I'm sorry. Could you
repeat the question?

            
               Caught

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unawares Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Health Department</ENAMEX> warns that you
might be bitten by a rabid bat and not even know it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlin D. Tuttle</ENAMEX> thinks
they're a bunch of hysterics. The health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. Not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bats</ENAMEX>, of whom only
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent to 4 percent</NUMEX> are rabid, and if they bit you, you'd know it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSHD</ENAMEX> recommends rabies shots if a bat is found
in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with a sleeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or unattended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, even if it is not
known if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has been bitten or if the bat has rabies or if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is
very nice.

            To help sound the alarm, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSHD</ENAMEX> distributes a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bat Rabies Alert</ENAMEX>" refrigerator magnet and a poster with a sinister bat
silhouette: "If you see me, tell an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>." Says the bat, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, who
probably doesn't have rabies either.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bat Conservation International</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merlin D. Tuttle</ENAMEX> made his comment, says that there has never
been a case of rabies from an unnoticed bite. But that doesn't impress the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSHD</ENAMEX>'s comically named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Pospisil</ENAMEX>. (A name even sillier than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlin D. Tuttle</ENAMEX>. Imagine the childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">teasing</ENAMEX>. There must be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when she
yearns for the sweet release of an unnoticed bite from a rabid bat.) "Let's say
you wake up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and there's a bat in there and the bat flies out the
window," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pospisil</ENAMEX>, hoping to be taken seriously. "The health department
would recommend you get treatment."

            The treatment comprises <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> injections over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 days</TIMEX>
and costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1,000</NUMEX>. If untreated, rabies is fatal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has
recorded only a single bat rabies fatality in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45 years</TIMEX>. It was not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>.

            

               Technologically 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blessed Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called
Tsu-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> is promoting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panasonic Inti-Mist Personal Hygiene System</ENAMEX>, a high-tech toilet seat.
Beneath a headline that makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indisputable</ENAMEX> claim "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comfort You Never</ENAMEX>
Expected," is this list of features:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bidet Shower</ENAMEX>

               Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slam Seat</ENAMEX>

               Heated Seat

               Dryer

               Family Shower (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anus Washing</ENAMEX>)

            

            Now, I don't know about
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, but ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Adler Is Only a Symptom Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "My novels explore the mysteries behind love and
hate, the darkly amusing, deeply disturbing" blah, blah, blah, I'm so
scrumptious, me, me, me, concludes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Adler</ENAMEX> about his own work.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited
to submit other actual examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> finding similar delight in their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wonderfulness</ENAMEX>. Replies to run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Encephalitis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant dung</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
