
   
   
      
         
            Big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Brother</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  Note: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's poetry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, will soon be answering your Fray posts!
To join in the discussion, just go to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" 
               
                  poetry
thread <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 29</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m. ET</TIMEX>. And in the meantime, click
here to read excerpts from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinsky</ENAMEX>'s Fray appearance last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
            

            
               Subject:
Beware the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics of "Common Sense</ENAMEX>"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Tanenhaus</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Sat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>

            Interesting, clever piece but it seems wedded to
the premise that liberalism = moral virtue. But mightn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> offer
sentiments wholly opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Q</ENAMEX>'s and seem to his/her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> the paragon
of homespun good sense? Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> think he's simply talking
"horse sense"?

            Others might object
[that] Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>'s warm sentimentality is really smugness. I'm reminded here of a
column she wrote on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX>, which (if I recall it correctly)
made the argument--never established, save on the grounds of emotional
identification with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX>--that his acquittal was proof of the flaws in
our legal system. At a time like this Big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> sounds like kissing kin to Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX>.

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Tanenhaus</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker Chambers</ENAMEX>: A Biography .]

            (To reply, click
here.)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX>, Cultural Mandarin

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Brynes</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>

            Far from being a voice of common sense, Q is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sophist</ENAMEX> who tries to make confused thinking look like common sense.

            In connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Ofili</ENAMEX>'s painting [in her
first 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
                column], she invokes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> but fails to mention that neither was publicly funded. She
mentions banning and burning, but the painting is not being subjected to
either. The funding issue isn't supposed to matter because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> don't have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of every item in the budget anyway. Oh? Maybe they don't directly
oversee every item, but they have every right to complain about items they
don't like and demand that they be deleted.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX> seems to think that the issue of what is or is
not offensive can be resolved by appealing to analogies in culture and history:
"medieval <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> art, for example, is chockablock with sexual and
scatological imagery." Do the medieval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> use the imagery in the way Ofili
did? Would she apply the same reasoning to her issue of hate speech and say for
example that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">n*****</ENAMEX> word shouldn't be offensive because it is widely found
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> literature and is sometimes used by blacks
in referring to each other?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> case isn't about free speech
but rather subsidized (i.e., privileged) speech. Most speech and artistic
expression are not subsidized by anyone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is subsidizing the Ofili
painting because it is supposedly of exceptional value. But do our cultural
mandarins, in the name of "free speech" have the right to frivolous (and likely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-seeking</ENAMEX>) judgments as to what speech is valuable and what is not?

            (To reply, click
here.)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Missed Moment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow Dog</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Tue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>

            Campaigns have defining moments. Remember the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moment Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> demanded that his microphone be turned on--after the media
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moderator</ENAMEX> ordered it turned off [in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> debate]--so that he could speak in
support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s whining disruptions to protest that he should be
included in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashua</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, debate? ("I paid for this microphone, Mr.
Breen!")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> missed such a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moment the other night</TIMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> brayed at him from the stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> had just relinquished.
"How about it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> taunted, looking straight at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>. "If the answer
is yes, stand up and wave your hand."

            What if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> had risen from his chair, walked
over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, and said, "Let me respond. As I just finished saying, let's
abandon the old politics of personal confrontation and have the kind of
reasonable discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want before deciding how to vote. Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>, I agree
to debate--not on your schedule, not on your terms, but at mutually acceptable
times and places and in a format that lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hear what we have to say. And
in the meantime, why don't you knock off the 'How about it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>?' stuff.
That's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> ball." Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX> have been ready to "Stay and Fight" under
those circumstances? We'll never know ...

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journalism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Metabolife</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
Theo Przybyszewski

            
               Date: Tue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> does a terrific job of pointing out the
essential lunacy of trying to control information in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this era</TIMEX>, where anyone
with a computer can read, watch, or hear something in the mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, then get
onto the Internet, find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> versions of the truth, and make up his own
mind.

            Access to all this data makes us all a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crazier</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, it helps guarantee that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of media moguls
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> controlling our thoughts and opinions ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Citizen Kane :</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> will think what I tell them to think!") are fading fast. Unlike my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, I won't buy a brand of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake flour</ENAMEX> or vote for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> just because
that lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Margaret McBride</ENAMEX> tells me to on her radio show. Not when I can
go to a cake <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">flour chat room</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> and get the real lowdown.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True Cost of Driving</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard K. Green</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moneybox</ENAMEX> is likely correct about taxi medallions
and rent control. But I am not convinced about parking on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> counts:

            The value of land in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midtown Manhattan</ENAMEX> is somewhere
in the neighborhood of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> per square foot. This high land cost, along with
the high cost of constructing underground parking, means that more parking
might not be economically feasible (i.e., land might be used more profitably
for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>, office space, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX>).

            Even if new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage space</ENAMEX> were feasible under
current conditions, there is a good chance that it should not be built. While I
tend not to worry about market failure unless it is large, in the case of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">automobiles</ENAMEX>, it is large. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Mills</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern University</ENAMEX> estimates that
the social costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> could be internalized with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> per gallon gas
tax in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX>, the tax would have to be higher than that. But there
seems to be little political will to impose rational gas taxes, so <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> best
solutions, such as regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage space</ENAMEX>, are likely better than allowing
unregulated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage space</ENAMEX> combined with subsidized auto travel.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary, My Marriage</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Marie Fenton</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Mon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>

            Today, I have been in a verbal communiqué with my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Robert E. Fenton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USCG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ret</ENAMEX>.) regarding his desire to travel
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>reunion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USCGA</ENAMEX> Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'63</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.
Having just returned from a week in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> convention, I feel less
than enthusiastic about these plans. After all, we still have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to care for! <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX>, I telephoned him (at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>) asking, "Why
do you want to go on this dumb trip?" After all, we have been married for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 33 years</TIMEX>, and we have seen some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> within the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            His reply was that it will be wonderful--we shared
so much together and went through so much, I want to see them. He then
forwarded this article written by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-sea <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>. Is this a
coincidence? My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> served as a commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CG</ENAMEX> cutter, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980-82</TIMEX>.
He claimed it was the best time of his life. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> does not allow him
to express emotion or sensitivity. After reading this article, I know why he
has always felt so close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guard</ENAMEX> (as I have), and why he wants to share a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> with his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX>. Thanks for the great article. We will
forward it to as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> as possible. No doubt I will be on that plane
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. I will send you a follow up as to how it went.

            (To reply, click here.)

         
      
   
