
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Ball</ENAMEX>

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, announcing his candidacy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> compared politics to
basketball, recalling his love of discipline, teamwork, and "the swish of the
net." Pundits ate up the speech . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> called it "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and ethics assault"
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> applauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> for "slam-dunking"
the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. "It's the best speech I've ever heard him give," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX>. A video replay of the speech, however, shows that the swish
was the sound of a jump shot missing the rim altogether. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> continues to
think up new ways of saying nothing while making it look like something.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leadership</ENAMEX>. A speech can set a direction, define an
agenda, and explain what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has done or would do. Instead of
fulfilling these responsibilities, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> simply asserts that he has fulfilled
or will fulfill them. He promises to act on his "convictions" but doesn't say
what they are. Rather than explain where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should go, he says he has "a
strong sense of where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is and where we need to go." Rather than define
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s role in the world, he pledges to "define more clearly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s role
in the world." Rather than challenge his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> or tell them where he plans
to lead them, he says they deserve "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that respects the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as well
as challenges them." Rather than say what he would do, he promises, "There are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>: those who talk and promise, and those who listen and
do. I know which one I am."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. 
               Depth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, says prosperity
isn't enough. "What we need in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is a deeper prosperity ... a prosperity
that makes us feel rich inside as well as out," he argues. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that
is called for at this moment goes beyond a presidency, and into every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and
heart. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that understands the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s fears as well as their
hopes." By exuding profundity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> shames those who wonder what it means to
"feel rich inside," and why this is more important than rising incomes and
declining unemployment. The problem isn't that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s message is empty. The
problem is that you're too shallow to understand it.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immeasurability</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX> is at record
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">heights</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> concedes, but "such numbers are not the measure of all
things. They do not measure what is in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> and our hearts. They do not
measure a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s smile or a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s first handshake or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s pride. They convey nothing about friendship or the
self-fulfillment of helping a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in need. They tell us little about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magic</ENAMEX> of a good marriage or the satisfaction of a life led true to its own
values." As 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> , these things have nothing to
do with the presidency. But never mind. The point is that they can't be
"measured," and therefore, no one can disprove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s suggestion that
they're lacking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and that his presidency would restore them.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wholeness</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> speaks constantly of elusive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wholes</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should be made whole," he says. He proposes to build "racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unity</ENAMEX>," "confidence in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">collective</ENAMEX> will," and "a prosperity that adds up to
more than the sum of all our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">possessions</ENAMEX>." "A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is not just about winning,"
he adds. "It's about shared sacrifice; it's about giving up something small for
yourself in order to gain something large for everyone. It's the same for our
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." What is the "something large"? What does "unity" entail? What does
our "collective will" call for? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> doesn't dwell on such coarse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>.
The point is wholeness itself.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. 
               Things. Lest anyone doubt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>, he
touts his record of doing "things." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, he "reached across party
lines to get things done. I attempted to do big things without ever losing
sight of the little things." If elected, he'll "do some of the big things that
need to be done. ... We will do fewer things, but they will be essential
things, and we will do them more thoroughly." And what exactly are these "large
and essential things"? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> cites <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> example: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Works Project</ENAMEX>
Administration. How he would apply a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX> public jobs program to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s roaring economy remains unclear.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. 
               Reality. To those who suspect him of empty idealism,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> asserts a firm grasp of "reality." "Isn't it just common sense that we
make sure every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is covered by health care?" he asks. "Isn't it
just common sense that we protect our natural world from destruction, and do
what it takes to achieve racial unity? Isn't it common sense that all our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> should perform well, and that more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> should do better
economically? What others may call idealism is a common sense reality I know we
can achieve." How will <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> realize these "realities"? He doesn't say. The
point is that he will "do what it takes." Really. It's just common sense.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. 
               Possibility. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dream</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> argues,
"is not just an ideal to wish on. It should be a possibility available to all.
... The renewal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dream</ENAMEX> has to shine so bright that we can dream
dreams we never thought possible before. ... I want that hope, that
encouragement, that sense of possibility to be a reality for everybody." Since
possibility can't be measured, no one can disprove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s claim that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dream</ENAMEX> is impossible for too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, and no one can disprove
him if he claims <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years from now</TIMEX> that he has made it possible again.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. 
               Poetry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> relies heavily on metaphors.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> should "be fixing our roof while the sun is shining," he says. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, he pledges to "set the table for future economic growth," "put every
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> of that deeper, broader prosperity," and "urge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
to bridge the divide of prejudice." What any of this means is left to the
imagination. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> recalls, he learned from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is where you find it." As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, "I tried to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> where
they lived their lives." As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, he will "invest in our common future."
So, if you want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who invests in the past, finds character where it
isn't, and helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> where they don't live, vote for someone else.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. 
               Skepticism. "Our campaigns often end up doing the
very opposite of what they intend," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> laments. "Instead of engendering
hope and optimism, they breed mistrust and cynicism. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just last week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>,
after I spoke about political involvement, once again making our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> better,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> came up to me and said, 'It all sounds so wonderful, if only it could
be true.' ... Yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a right to be skeptical. But I have
a right to try to change that skepticism. ... I am trying to run a different
kind of presidential campaign. I'm calling us to renew our faith in each
other."

            
Skepticism, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> defines it, is about whether a big-money political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> will let his vision come "true." This obscures a more sophisticated
skepticism about whether he has a substantive vision to begin with, much less a
serious plan to achieve it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> isn't asking us to overcome that
skepticism. He's asking us to overlook it. And by planting what looks like a
bold idea--that the purpose of campaigning is to "engender optimism" and "renew
our faith"--he erases his obligation to tell us how he would govern. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
campaign, it turns out, isn't about the presidency. It's about campaigning.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> can't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has nothing to say. Some surmise that he's
cleverly waiting to unveil his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>. Others infer that he's already
mounting a brilliantly oblique attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> read insight into his
every remark. If you don't recognize his wisdom, you must not get what the
election is about. Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> get it? Don't be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX>. Ask not whether your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is worthy of you, but whether you are worthy of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
