
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX>

            In the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early evening</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16, 1978</TIMEX>, the newly
elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> appeared on the balcony of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter's Basilica</ENAMEX> and
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> that he had accepted election even though "I was afraid in
receiving the nomination." If so, it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and last time that the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cardinal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karol Wojtyla</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Krakow</ENAMEX> had known fear. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six days later</TIMEX>, when he
was invested as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> was commending the Christianity of courage.
Echoing the assurances of the angel who told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazareth</ENAMEX> that she would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conceive</ENAMEX> and bring forth the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of God, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> told the throng
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter's Square</ENAMEX>: "Be not afraid."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> is not
afraid--of religion's cultured despisers, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geopoliticians</ENAMEX> who find his
near-pacifism naive, of liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> who accuse him of betraying the
spirit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Vatican Council</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Vatican II</ENAMEX>"), of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> who suspect
that he sees only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> acceptable roles for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--virgin and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. He is
unafraid of his own infirmity, caused by advancing age and by the residual
effects of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> assassination attempt. Finally, and perhaps most interesting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> has intimated that he might be unafraid even of a downsizing of
the papal authority his charisma has done so much to dramatize.

            Born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>, the future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pope</ENAMEX> was a precocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> who worked in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarry</ENAMEX> and
a chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imbued</ENAMEX> with the popular Catholicism of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>--marked by effusive devotion to the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> (an aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>'s spirituality that discomfits <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> and liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>)-- Wojtyla
began studies for the priesthood in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX> in an "underground" seminary made
necessary by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> occupation.

            After the war he studied
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, boarding an ecclesiastical fast track: auxiliary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Krakow</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archbishop</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
regarded him as more pliable than other churchmen, he proved unafraid to
confront them in the cause of freedom for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wojtyla</ENAMEX> was
elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33-day</TIMEX> reign of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul</ENAMEX> I, the
international press portrayed him as the darkest of dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>. In hindsight,
his ecclesiastical networking during and after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> made him a logical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> once it was clear no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX> could win election.

            The rest is history, from which liberal and conservative
Catholics draw strikingly contrary conclusions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> took the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospel</ENAMEX> and
his magnetic personality on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>--forsaking the throne, on which past popes
were carried through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter's Basilica</ENAMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popemobile</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The year</TIMEX> after
his election, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine days</TIMEX> and encountered a
rhapsodic reception that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> credits with helping to sow
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solidarity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>'s later challenge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
regime.

            Elsewhere on his world
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tour</ENAMEX>, which has passed through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, he kept faith with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predecessors John XXIII</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul VI</ENAMEX> in defending the dignity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and
anathematizing the arms race. He called for negotiations rather than the use of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. He has been critical of
international sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and he hopes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to visit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">birthplace</ENAMEX> of the biblical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> there. These and similar
initiatives pleased political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> inside and outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>; not so
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s use of its quasigovernmental status to oppose population-control
initiatives that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> feared would contribute to the "culture of
death."

            The style of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX>'s papacy has occasioned as much
comment as its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. Past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">popes</ENAMEX> were remote and magisterial figures, but
capitalizing on his relative youth, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s panache, and a mastery of mass
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> changed all that--unafraid of diluting the papal
mystique through overexposure.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s roadshow has
never had an exclusively <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> cast. He has met with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> and
has joined in worship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> and, in a historic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> ceremony in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canterbury Cathedral</ENAMEX>, with the spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of England</ENAMEX>, which
broke with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16 th century</TIMEX>.

            Some would dismiss this as photo-op ecumenism and note that
Anglicans are not invited to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Communion</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>,
despite agreements by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican-Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> theological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> on the
meaning of that sacrament. Anglicans were also dismayed when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardinal Joseph</ENAMEX>
Ratzinger, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s doctrinal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdog</ENAMEX>, signed a document that seemed to
rehabilitate a much-criticized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1896 papal</TIMEX> bull declaring the holy orders of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Anglican clergy</ENAMEX> "absolutely null and utterly void."

            It isn't only in his
policy toward other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> is accused of preaching reform
and practicing reaction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican II</ENAMEX> gave rise to a less hierarchical and more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outward-looking Catholicism</ENAMEX> and set the stage for once-unthinkable innovations
like plainclothes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nuns</ENAMEX> and the celebration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and other
modern languages. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Liberal Catholics</ENAMEX> concede that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> may follow the
letter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>'s decrees but, mindful that "the letter killeth, but the
spirit giveth life" (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 Corinthians 3:6</ENAMEX>), they see in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> II a trajectory of
further change that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> has frustrated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> is not oblivious to
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX>, just contemptuous of them. It is his duty, he writes in
Crossing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Threshold of Hope</ENAMEX> , to "interpret [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>] correctly and
defend it from tendentious interpretations." It seems the pope enjoys
confounding his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. He recalls that on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> he offended
local adherents of the "enlightened agenda" by emphasizing the Ten
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commandments</ENAMEX>. "For such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," he said, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX> becomes persona non
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grata</ENAMEX> when he tries to convince the world of human sin."

            Much of the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> case against the pope deals
with sexuality. It is even said that he has a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> problem," which supposedly
finds expression in his defense of church positions on an all-male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX>,
contraception, and abortion. Yes, abortion is anathema to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX>, who is
bemused by suggestions that he has an "obsession" with the subject, but he
condemns abortion because he sees it as not only anti-life but also
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> has endorsed sexual equality in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workplace</ENAMEX> and in society, but there is no doubt that he subscribes to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> version of difference feminism. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> apostolic letter on the
"dignity and vocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> warned that "in the name of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberation</ENAMEX> from male domination, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> must not appropriate to themselves male
characteristics contrary to their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">feminine 'originality</ENAMEX>.' "

            What is so "original" about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>? In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> retreat
for university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Krakow</ENAMEX>, the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, espousing what sounds like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gospel According to Carol Gilligan</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female participants</ENAMEX> that "women
are more feeling and intuitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and become involved in things in a more
sensitive and complete manner." In separate remarks to male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, Wojtyla
argued that "in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, the intellect has a certain supremacy over the heart, and
this is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> entrusted responsibility for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospel</ENAMEX> as idea to
them."

            This view of sexual
differences suggests that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX>, opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women priests</ENAMEX> is not
simply a tradition inherited from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> or even an emulation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>' decision to call only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as apostles. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX>, as for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul VI</ENAMEX>,
the male monopoly on priesthood is required by "theological anthropology." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pope</ENAMEX> has ratcheted up its importance by decreeing that the male monopoly on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">priesthood</ENAMEX> is an article of faith that must be "definitively held by all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX>."

            His obstinacy on the issue is cited as proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> is indifferent to one of the major themes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican II</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> reunion.
The picture is more complicated. While the pope has warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archbishop</ENAMEX> of
Canterbury that the ordination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> poses "an
increasingly serious obstacle" to reconciliation between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canterbury</ENAMEX>,
he has indicated a surprising willingness to compromise on a seemingly more
fundamental obstacle to reunion: the papacy itself. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> encyclical, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul II</ENAMEX> broached the possibility that, in the interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> unity, he
or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> might "find a way of exercising the [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">papal</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">primacy</ENAMEX> which,
while in no way renouncing what is essential to its mission, is nonetheless
open to a new situation." He went on to note that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 1,000 years</TIMEX> of
Christianity the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> "acted by common consent as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX>" when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX> disagreed about belief or discipline.

            This tantalizing suggestion of a scaled-down papal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was seized on by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican-Roman Catholic International Commission</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this May</TIMEX> in a report that suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anglicans</ENAMEX> should accept a circumscribed
papal primacy as a "gift to be shared." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s suggestion also dovetails
with a new interest among some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX> in a "universal primate"
who would serve as a focus of unity for world Christianity. (What it does not
comport with, ironically, is the papal role as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> has so effectively
enlarged it. Would a "tiebreaker" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> have any use for an airplane
or a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Popemobile</ENAMEX>?)

            Here is perhaps the ultimate example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>'s fearlessness: a willingness at least to consider some diminution in the
scope of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in exchange for an improvement on the current "imperfect
unity" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christendom</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> that ordain female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> might have their
own "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> problem" in accepting a scaled-back papacy that came with
theological strings attached. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> surely knows this, which suggests that
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> might not be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> and
other ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>. Although estranged from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, these tradition-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> long have fascinated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX>, who
comes from a part of the world where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> Christianity overlap.
And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more thing: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> do not, and likely never will, ordain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
