
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">302</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;It's Back&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               
                  "It's back, and
we used it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. But they don't want us to use it too much. It's not
going to be a big deal." Who said this about what?
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 301</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Army Men":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Stevenson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National War</ENAMEX> College assesses a new study of military
and civilian beliefs. It is "scary," he said, to have "an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer corps</ENAMEX> so
overwhelmingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">_____________</ENAMEX>."
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Made</ENAMEX>
up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> merely using the experience as a steppingstone for starting their
own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Unable to say the phrase 'humanitarian mission' without giggling."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
Heimer
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subscribing</ENAMEX> to the utilitarian beliefs of disturbing yet guilt-inducing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philosopher Peter Singer</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Oder</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indebted</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for loans to buy their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>
            

            "Prone
to sudden bleeding and speaking in scary voices!!! (Promotional fee paid by
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Stigmata © 1999</ENAMEX>)."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Banana <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> were half the trend-spotter it thinks it is, that's the
banner it would run to mark the triumph of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganism</ENAMEX>, transforming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> into the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> we used to deride. We now have
the essentials--a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> far to the right of the rest
of society, a vast chasm between a tiny rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> and everyone else, and
the proliferation of soap operas in prime time, despite the
counterrevolutionary snubbing of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emmy</ENAMEX>
Awards.

            
               Fun 
               Facts:
            

            

               The wealthiest <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much</NUMEX> after taxes as the poorest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

               That ratio has more than doubled since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>.

               The poorest <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> now earns a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">smaller percentage</NUMEX> of the
national income than they did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>.

               <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s economic growth has gone to the richest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name easily substitutes for the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evita</ENAMEX>," making
it possible to do a new version of the musical without cluttering up the
elegant rhythm of the songs.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky Martin</ENAMEX>.

            

            If anyone wants me, I'll
be in the mountains--probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catskills</ENAMEX>--growing my beard.

            
               Right

               Face Answer
            

            It's scary to have "an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer corps</ENAMEX> so
overwhelmingly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> was
commenting on a study conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangle Institute for Security Studies</ENAMEX>,
comparing the social and political views of the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> with those of
prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. The study concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are far to the right
of the general society.

            
               Scary 
               Facts:
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Sixty-four</NUMEX> percent of the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 30 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> surveyed are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Sixty-seven</NUMEX> percent of the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 32 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> call themselves "conservative."

               <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Forty-five percent</NUMEX> of the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 17 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> would bar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> from military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>.

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seventy</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 46 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>
favor school prayer.

               <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 10 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> think
capital punishment should be banned.

            

            "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> frequently
had political alignments," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> said, "but they did not favor a single party
consistently."

            Defense Secretary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> said it would be a major challenge for him "to somehow prevent a
chasm from developing between the military and civilian worlds." News Quiz host
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years</TIMEX>, said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too late</ENAMEX>. And, actually, no
relation."

            
               Other

               Quizzes, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other Rooms Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            So that none of you play
because of a lack of alternatives, here are actual questions found by looking
for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>" through various search engines, along with comments pointing
out how much better things are right in your own backyard.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacksonville</ENAMEX>
                        Times-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
                     
                  
               
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacksonville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> had to close
which <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> after it filled to capacity on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Westside Regional Park</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanna Park</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mandarin Park</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Park</ENAMEX>

            

               Comment : Questions may be overly local.

            
               KET
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
               
            

            True or false? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newport Aquarium</ENAMEX> is home to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> that live in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.

            

               Comment : Unless this is some kind of trick question, they're
talking to us like we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX>. Are we going to take that?

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> 
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Monitor</ENAMEX>
                     
                  
               
            

            What is nicknamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
branch?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>

            

               Comment : Admirable use of quiz form to slyly denigrate the
military-industrial complex, although the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> choice might have been "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Topeka</ENAMEX>

                        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital-Journal</ENAMEX>
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s CJ KidsZone News Quiz</ENAMEX> (in coordination with
the public school system of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Topeka</ENAMEX>)
               
            

            What is making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwinch</ENAMEX>'in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> lose their
ancient ways?

            Laws

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>

            Money

            Television

            

               Comment : I can't prove it, but I suspect that an early draft
included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> answer: "attacked by dinosaurs just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">800 years ago</TIMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">colorado</ENAMEX> .now
               
            

            Test your "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NQ</ENAMEX>" with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s array of questions,
dreamed up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">colorado</ENAMEX>.now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Division of Wildlife</ENAMEX> wants to spend as
much as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> to fight "whirling <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>," which afflicts what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>?

            Black bears

            Whooping cranes

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Deer mice</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trout</ENAMEX>

            

               Comment : There's no such thing as "whirling disease."
(Although little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whirling deer mice</ENAMEX> would look adorable.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>.now staff
should have "dreamed up" ways to smoke less pot.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old, Pre-Java CNN Quiz</ENAMEX>
               
            

            Travel through the world of current events with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s quiz!

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Product Safety</ENAMEX>
Commission, at least how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have choked to death on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
products since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>?

            17

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">259</NUMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">753</NUMEX>

            1,030

            

               Comment: If you read between the lines, it's pretty clear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
thinks the best answer is "not nearly enough." Heartless bastards.

            
               Philanthropy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
               
            

            This quiz is based on news articles abstracted in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philanthropy News Digest</ENAMEX> . To view the full
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abstracts</ENAMEX>, go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digest</ENAMEX> .

            Who narrates the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Learn & Live</ENAMEX>" film produced
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas Foundation</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Jones</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lucas</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX>

            

               Comment : Focus pretty narrow, but not narrow enough to exclude
reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX>.

            
               Test Your
Pesach IQ
               
            

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seder</ENAMEX> we drink <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cups of ...

            Hot chocolate

            Wine

            Olive oil

            

               Comment : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> of quiz too insecure about his place in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life to include possible answer "blood of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX> 
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Journal</ENAMEX>
                     
                  
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 27</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
               
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midtown Plaza B. Forman Co.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> closed for a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time. Name the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> named this executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice chairman</ENAMEX>; later in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, he announced his retirement. Name him.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> faced charges in a suit
filed under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act</ENAMEX>?

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester Business Journal</ENAMEX>
ceased to be a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>. Why?

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> says it lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTS</ENAMEX> funds?

            Which leading area realty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> filed for
bankruptcy?

            Name the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> who was
accused of stealing trade secrets.

            What local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was rocked by a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$225 million</NUMEX>
legal feud?

            

               Comment : Most depressing set of questions I've ever read. The
quiz format may not be the ideal way to chart a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s economic collapse. And
couldn't they at least get out of bed long enough to update the thing now and
then? And shave? And put on clean clothes?

            

               Clarification
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s gun
buy-back plan does not include a proposal to eliminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">middleman</ENAMEX> and funnel
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith & Wesson</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            Don't ask, don't tell, don't kvetch.

         
      
   
