
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangulation Strategy</ENAMEX>

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> tried to postpone a fiscal squeeze by deferring payment
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX> to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Their presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-runner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, shot them down. "I don't think they ought to
balance their budget on the backs of the poor," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, speaking in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> about education reform, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> spanked his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> again, this time for
projecting pessimism, indifference, and "disdain for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
broadsides have filled the talk shows and front pages with speculation that he
is "triangulating" against congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
"triangulated" against left-wing rap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souljah</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and against
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s one-dimensional understanding
of triangulation--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is trying to "distance himself from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s right
wing" and "stake out the middle ground" between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> extremes--oversimplifies
the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> isn't positioning himself on a straight line between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. He isn't even taking up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> position on their
two-dimensional battlefield. He is venturing into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> dimension, rejecting
the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> debate, and defining his contest with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> along a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">axis</ENAMEX>. He is trying to render <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-point campaign message obsolete.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. 
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is doing well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
constantly recite statistics that reflect well on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>: more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX>, lower deficits, lower interest rates, fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on welfare, less
crime. They credit their own policies, particularly the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> tax hike, for
achieving these results by establishing fiscal responsibility. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>,
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan would ruin the economy.
Then they defied credulity by reversing their message, claiming that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> was in great shape and that their own policies were responsible for
it.

            This
is the biggest obstacle facing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>: He is challenging the incumbent vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in a time of peace and prosperity, and the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has not
made a persuasive case either that the prosperity is false or that it is true
because of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> efforts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> have spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> telling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> the story of how their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> revived the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. Whether or not this story is true, it is now deeply ingrained in the
public consciousness, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> can't look to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> for an
effective rebuttal to it.

            
Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is attempting something far more bold and interesting: He is
weaving an alternative story. While focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s criticisms of his party
in his speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the media overlooked the more important passage that
preceded them. He said:

            
               In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> after state, we are seeing a profound shift of
[educational] priorities. An "age of accountability" is starting to replace an
era of low expectations. ... The principles of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> are similar from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>. ... At the beginning of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1990s</NUMEX>, so many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s problems, from education to crime to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX>, seemed intractable. ... But something unexpected happened on the way
to cultural decline. Problems that seemed inevitable proved to be reversible.
They gave way to an optimistic, governing conservatism. Here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, Mayor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> brought order and civility back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>--cutting crime rates by
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Thompson</ENAMEX> proved that welfare dependence
could be reversed--reducing his rolls by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91 percent</NUMEX>. Innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> followed their lead--cutting national welfare rolls by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX>
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> and reducing the murder rate to the lowest point since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>. Now
education reform is gaining a critical mass of results. In the process,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conservatism</ENAMEX> has become the creed of hope. The creed of aggressive, persistent
reform. The creed of social progress.
            

            What's
important about this narrative is not what it says but what it doesn't say. It
makes no mention of anything that happened in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> or in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has decided that he can't win the federal policy debate that has consumed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, and the national media for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>. So he has
simply erased it. Yes, crime is down, fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are on welfare, and school
reform is gaining momentum. And yes, the incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> deserves credit. But
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s story, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. It's the state
and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is petty and mean. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>--have spent their tenure in the majority denouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
bickering with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, impugning their integrity, and
blaming them for every problem. They have convinced many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> are blameworthy. But they have convinced many others that
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are more interested in impugning integrity and fixing
blame than in solving problems. The negative portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s game plan,
therefore, is to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">carping</ENAMEX> and destructiveness.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
game plan is to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s game plan on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. He's not going to argue with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> over which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is destructive or blameworthy. He's going to reject the
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> blame game--undercutting his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">portray</ENAMEX> himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who solves problems instead of complaining about them
or blaming them on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. "Too often, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has confused the need for
limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with a disdain for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> itself," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
"Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founders</ENAMEX> rejected cynicism and cultivated a noble love of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. That
love is undermined by sprawling, arrogant, aimless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It is restored
by focused and effective and energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. And that should be our goal:
a limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, respected for doing a few things and doing them
well."

            Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>, have fired back at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, accusing him of
betraying them, meddling in their business, and distorting their ideas. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counterattack</ENAMEX> has only helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> achieve the distance he sought in the first
place. Others, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX>, have tried to spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s comments, suggesting
that he's really siding with them against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> budget
fight. They don't understand that they've lost that fight and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is
willing to repudiate the fight and everyone in it--including them--in order to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ruin Gore</ENAMEX>'s strategy and beat him.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. 
               The religious right is scary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
has often used cultural issues such as abortion to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> look extreme.
The media and "moderate" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, convinced that these issues are the
party's weakness and that its libertarian economic ideas are its strength, have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interpreted Bush</ENAMEX>'s remarks as a rebuke to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puritanism</ENAMEX>." But a closer
look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s comments suggests the opposite: He is concerned that the party
looks mean because of its economic policies, and he is using cultural issues to
soften that image by projecting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "compassion."

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had felt a need to triangulate against the cultural right, he could have
joined others in repudiating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> for questioning the wisdom of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> intervention against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. He didn't. Alternatively, he could
have used his address to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> to criticize
religious intolerance. Instead, he gave a speech that bypassed traditional
moral issues such as school prayer and homosexuality and never mentioned the
word "abortion." The media inferred that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was ignoring moral issues because
the religious right has nowhere else to go. They missed the real story: The
reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> doesn't have to talk about old moral issues that might make him
look mean is that he's introducing new moral issues that make him look warm and
caring.

            In his
speech to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> used the word "compassion" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> times. He urged
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> to pursue a kinder, gentler mission: "What we need are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
live out their faith in every walk of life, in politics, but also working in
crisis pregnancy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, drug treatment programs, and homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who make God's work their own. ... Our compassion must extend to the
poor and to the fatherless. Our compassion must defend the disabled. ... I will
rally the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> of compassion to nurture, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>, to comfort, to perform
their commonplace miracles of renewal. ... I will involve them in after-school
programs, maternity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> homes, prison <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fellowships</ENAMEX>, and drug treatment
programs."

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> warned, "Too often, on social issues, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has painted an
image of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> slouching toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gomorrah</ENAMEX>. Of course there are challenges to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and compassion of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>--too many broken <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and broken
lives. But many of our problems--particularly education, crime, and welfare
dependence--are yielding to good sense and strength and idealism." He went on:
"Too often, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has focused on the national economy, to the exclusion of
all else--speaking a sterile language of rates and numbers, of CBO this and GNP
that. Of course we want growth and vigor in our economy. But there are human
problems that persist in the shadow of affluence." On this view, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
problem is libertarian indifference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, and the solution is to fix
"broken <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and broken lives" through "compassion" back home.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recognizes Bush</ENAMEX>'s strategy and is trying to drag him back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
fight. "He's now differed with [congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>] on one little
detail," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> . "If he really wants to try to
break with them, he ought to endorse our health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>.
He ought to endorse an increase in the minimum wage for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX>. And
he ought to come out against this huge, risky tax scheme." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> isn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biting</ENAMEX>, and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, more interested in beating their
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> than in beating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, have welcomed and exploited his
indictment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> doesn't mind. They can have the battle. He wants
the war.

         
      
   
