
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wing Man</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Aviation</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe</ENAMEX>,
Legal, and Not That Rare
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Chapman</ENAMEX>'s attack on general aviation (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>")
paints a distorted picture. To begin with, all transportation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is "subsidized" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> help pay for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s mass transit system, for example. A safe, well-regulated
transportation system benefits everyone.

            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Some 75 percent</NUMEX> of major airline flights operate to
just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> big-city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of all airline flights merely shuttle
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hub airports</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> aviation provides air
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX> for the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by serving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 13,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> aviation carries <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> per year.

            And it does it safely. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">361</NUMEX> fatal
accidents out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39 million</NUMEX> flights. The "risk" of a fatal accident is only
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.000009 percent</NUMEX>. On a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">per-mile</NUMEX> basis, you are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times more likely to be
involved in an automobile accident than a general aviation accident.

            The air traffic control system was created by and
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> aviation is only a marginal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATC</ENAMEX> services. The
vast majority of general aviation flights are flown under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visual Flight Rules</ENAMEX>,
which don't require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATC</ENAMEX>. And general aviation is often forced to use ATC
services that it doesn't want or need. Many small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> have control towers
simply because of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> airline flights a day.

costs of providing air traffic control services to each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> of aviation are
unknown because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> does not have an adequate
cost accounting system. But the costs imposed by general aviation aren't
anywhere close to the number cited in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRA</ENAMEX> study, which reached erroneous
conclusions based on mistaken assumptions.

            The bulk of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> grants go to commercial
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX>) service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1997</TIMEX>, commercial service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>
received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1.1 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reliever</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> (which give general aviation
aircraft an alternative to using commercial service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>) received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>, and general aviation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$139 million</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> aviation <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> don't cause delays for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">airliners</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> hub-and-spoke system (which has large numbers of flights
all trying to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> at the same time) and weather are the major
causes of delay for airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>.

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> considers search-and-rescue services
and accident investigation a "subsidy" for general aviation is absurd on the
face of it. It's an appropriate role for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to rescue its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>,
whether they be boaters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hikers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>, or airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. And that
rescue, more often than not, will be accomplished using general aviation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> aviation isn't a
"hobby"; it's serious transportation that fulfills many vital needs in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Morningstar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, media relations
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ditch Is</ENAMEX>
Back
            

            I would like to suggest that the research for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Brus</ENAMEX>' "" ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Event of a Water Landing"</ENAMEX>) was lacking. I spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in commercial aviation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> flag <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> and offer the
following comments based on that experience.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) There have been numerous ditchings of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> flag
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least three</NUMEX> incidents that immediately come to mind involved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>
Am and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX>), as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Airlines</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco Bay</ENAMEX>).
I believe that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> incidents involved fatalities; however, the vast
majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> survived.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> are routinely trained for water
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landings</ENAMEX> and must be certified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Authority</ENAMEX> to fly over
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Cabin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> receive specific passenger safety training with emphasis on
aircraft evacuation, since this is their primary area of responsibility. Flight
deck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> do not focus on passenger survival because they are responsible for
the overall aircraft systems <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> and are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew members</ENAMEX> least likely to
survive a traumatic event.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) While water landings are treacherous, they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">survivable</ENAMEX>, irrespective of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>'s comments.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Since most major
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> are located around large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, both air <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> and aircraft
are certified with airworthiness certificates based on evacuation procedures
that include <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> landings.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Azar Malibu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Brus</ENAMEX>
replies:
                
               I got my information on accident history from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>. Its
database does not go back to the beginning of commercial flight, obviously, so
it is possible there were ditchings before it began keeping records. It is also
conceivable that some accidental crashes into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> upon landing or takeoff
were not classified as deliberate ditchings.
            

            
               How do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> receive "overwater" training? There
are no test crashes done, either by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>, so "evacuation
procedures" are about the extent of the preparation--which could help if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fuselage</ENAMEX> remains intact, but that is a big "if." Only military helicopter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> get dropped in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> as part of their actual training.
            

            
               Are water landings survivable? Only in best-case
scenarios. There are too many variables involved to make a rule, but ditchings
of international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> have shown that keeping the fuselage intact and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> out of cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is hard indeed.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> does not
perform crash tests on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, nor does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> require them. Their planes
are subject to stress tests in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hangar</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Tax Talk
            

            In "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> did his usual admirable job
of delineating the competing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Greenspins</ENAMEX>" of congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. However, he failed to address a gaping hole in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>'
tax cut plans that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> had pointed out: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Namely</ENAMEX>,
that a tax cut of the size proposed might stimulate the economy to the point
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> would feel compelled to raise interest rates in a pre-emptive
strike against inflation.

            In his remarks to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> spoke of the benefits of "pre-emptive" action, i.e., moving
against inflation before it actually develops. I--and, I think, many
others--consider this remark an explicit warning to congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
that, however the debate about the projected budget surplus goes, a large tax
cut will endanger low interest rates and thus the prosperity that makes
surpluses--and thus the proposed tax cuts themselves--possible.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew B. Goodwin Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
