
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Place</ENAMEX>

            What a difference a plane ride makes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> I
left on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> queasy about peace talks and anxious about its new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> was already squabbling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">viciously</ENAMEX>, a party allied with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> had splintered and collapsed, the
opposition had called for a no-confidence vote, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Golan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>
were readying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> campaigns against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s peace schemes, and my in-laws were
shouting at the television every time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> came on the screen: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He</ENAMEX> wants to
give it all away!"

            But landing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, I touched down in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak Euphoria</ENAMEX>. During
his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> is traveling not by limousine but on a cushion
of perfumed air. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Policy Forum</ENAMEX>'s new poll of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX> finds
almost universal support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> and his peace proposals. His <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> visit
includes a triumphal march through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> talk shows, backslapping meetings
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, and glowing newspaper profiles.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has rarely seemed giddier about a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> papers
have suggested that "peace is just around the corner," that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is united
behind its new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, that final rapprochement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrians</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> is just a matter of proofreading the treaties and scheduling a few
ceremonial handshakes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Garden</ENAMEX>.

            This discontinuity between the thrill in the air here and
the "facts on the ground" there (to use a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israelism</ENAMEX>) is striking and
worrisome. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> seems to be mistaking the opportunity of peace talks for the
reality of a peace treaty. "The challenge facing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> in the face of this
euphoria is the danger of unrealistic expectations," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Smerling</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Policy Forum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            True, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s election is
a welcome event for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> was
widely mistrusted and despised by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>, and universally mistrusted and
despised by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>. A majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> (admittedly a narrow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>) favors
peace talks, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> is the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Israel</ENAMEX> could send to the table.
He has constructed a broad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of pro-peace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. He has assuaged
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> by presenting a hard vision of peace: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s peace with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> will be a divorce, not a marriage (as former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shimon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peres</ENAMEX> imagined). But while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> may be the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> to bring peace,
that does not mean peace will come. Enormous obstacles remain, obstacles that
an exultant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should stop and remember.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> The chasm between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> visions of
peace. Peace with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> is a (relatively) easy matter for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
will surrender the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golan</ENAMEX> (except for a surveillance base), the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> will
be demilitarized, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> will stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX> guerillas from operating in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Lebanon</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> problem is much more difficult.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> are willing to conduct final negotiations, but that
does not mean their positions can be reconciled. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> may have been elected
largely because he was not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s publicly stated peace
proposals are similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> demand: all the West
Bank, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> as their capital, the right of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1948 and 1967</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> to
return, full statehood, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> withdrawal from settlements. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> rejects
all these conditions, except perhaps statehood.

            Even the most optimistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> succumb to paralysis when they try to resolve these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disagreements</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> is likely to concede the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> a capital just
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> and to allow some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> to return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> (though
not to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> proper), but he certainly won't give up all the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> or even
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a square inch</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, who grabbed the moral high ground
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> sabotaged negotiations, have so far shown little willingness to
moderate their demands. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> (understandably)
delayed resolving these issues until final status talks because they were
intractable. Now final status talks have arrived and, lo and behold, the issues
are still intractable. Already some are predicting the "final" talks won't be
final at all: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> will again kick the questions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Heightened Arab</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tension. The
mutual loathing and mistrust that divides <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> is bad
enough already, but the peace process promises to exacerbate it. Serious peace
negotiations are expected to spark anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> terrorism by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
extremists bent on sabotaging a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-a-loaf agreement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> will
be no happier. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> withdrawals from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> may leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
settlements encircled by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> territory. Surrounding well-armed and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">enraged Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> is a recipe for disaster.
Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> terrorism during the peace talks of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'90s</TIMEX> contributed to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peres</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s defeat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s fragile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> is equally vulnerable if
terrorism or settler violence surges. Support for peace could dissolve.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Heightened Jewish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tension. The peace process
also endangers intra-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> relations, which are already fraught. Religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are feuding with secular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sephardic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are battering the Ashkenazi
establishment about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of discrimination. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> are fighting
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rabbis</ENAMEX>. Any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> agreement will probably require <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>
to remove or consolidate <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> settlements. Any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> agreement will
undoubtedly require <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> to remove all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX> settlements. There are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,000</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golan</ENAMEX>. Most of them strongly
oppose any plan to uproot them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> had a nervous
breakdown when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menachem Begin</ENAMEX> evicted just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> during
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '80s</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Bankers</ENAMEX>, are far more
militant than their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'80s</TIMEX> counterparts. Some religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> deny the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and believe it is their biblical duty to
populate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Judea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Samaria</ENAMEX>"). They will not leave quietly. It
is difficult to conceive how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> can remove <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golan</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> more from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> without fracturing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> The instability of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez Assad</ENAMEX> is old and ailing. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bashar</ENAMEX>, is inexperienced (he's an ophthalmologist by training). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assad</ENAMEX>'s
ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alawites</ENAMEX> are a tenuous minority, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 11 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, is dead. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s economy is totally
broken. As long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assad</ENAMEX> lives, he can manage these troubles and keep an
agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. But if he dies, it's not clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> can control
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> or that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Golan</ENAMEX> border will remain peaceful.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> situation is more perilous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>
is also ailing and has no clear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>. His authoritarian rule has prevented
the emergence of future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and the development of strong civic and
political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Extremists</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> are already
jockeying for power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> economy is a disaster, devastated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> limits on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. The return of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of destitute <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
will only compound the economic misery.

            So if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> gets his final deal with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> may find itself with a new kind of problem: an autonomous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, a stone's throw (literally) from sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> territory,
that is sinking into Third World poverty, anarchy, and civil war. This could be
a peace, even a good peace, but it won't be cause for euphoria.

         
      
   
