
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal History</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Republic</ENAMEX>, Not an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> , has drawn fire for its claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> posed no threat to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> national interests. Already, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have disavowed him, and
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX>
Goda, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard L. Weinberg</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert G. Kaufman</ENAMEX>, have rebutted him.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitlerophilia</ENAMEX> is just the start of his problems. The real news
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic</ENAMEX>, Not an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> is that it repeatedly warps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
history to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s nativist ideology. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would have voted to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>.)

            The aim of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s book is to revive the
doctrine of isolationism and restore legitimacy to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, the term "isolationist" (which he rejects) was coined in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> to
denigrate those who would keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> wars. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, what
others call isolationism has a noble history, dating to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>'s
admonition that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should "steer clear of permanent alliances." In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> argues, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> obeyed, and the nation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thrived</ENAMEX>. But with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX>, he says, the policy was junked, and
since then we've been rushing headlong into ruin.

            Errors, distorted
emphases, discredited theories, internal inconsistencies, and outright
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prejudice permeate Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s book right from the beginning. Early on, he
refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American West</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> arrived as "empty land."
For a screed against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> imperialism, his book is astonishingly uncritical
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s violent conquest of the West. In writing about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1811</TIMEX>
Battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tippecanoe</ENAMEX>--the showdown between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tecumseh</ENAMEX> and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Henry Harrison</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> treats the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minions</ENAMEX> who ran around scalping <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for sport,
rather than a threatened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> in a strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>.
He also describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> of the early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> as "a haven
for ... marauding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> who regularly crossed into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> to pillage,
burn and murder," and calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX>, who ruthlessly waged war against
them, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of "vision, unapologetic about the means [he] employed to realize
the destiny [he] foresaw for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." There's much to admire about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, , but his brutal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> campaign should elicit at least pause, if not
apologies.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s determination to see the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th century</ENAMEX>
as a success story (the better to underscore the failures of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -century</TIMEX> policy) also leads him to a rosy view of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX>. Dismissive of those who have questioned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
aggressive annexation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>, he argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of annexation
were dupes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. Actually, expansion aroused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> fears mainly
because it promised to create more states hospitable to slavery, but in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s telling, the central issue of antebellum <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> garners barely a
mention. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anglophobia</ENAMEX> returns when he buys into hoary theories that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foolishly</ENAMEX> accepted the "Open Door <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Policy</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conned</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hay</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> also resurrects <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75-year-old</TIMEX> claims
that the wily schemes of Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financiers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">munitions-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> plunged
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.</ENAMEX> (And as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> notes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> ,
recent scholarship suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser Wilhelm</ENAMEX> was more of a continental menace
than previously recognized and that the war wasn't necessarily the "mistake"
common wisdom once held it to be.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s theory of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -century</TIMEX> foreign policy is basically that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>
have been bad. His vituperation for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodrow Wilson</ENAMEX> extends beyond the familiar
argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>'s arrogance sabotaged his efforts to win <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> approval
for joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Nations</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> also faults <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> for impugning
the patriotism of so-called "hyphenates"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> who wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> policy
to favor their native lands. The criticism is plainly disingenuous: In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
his last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> bashes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for
speaking up on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, until now not
known as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, sheds crocodile tears for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese-Americans</ENAMEX> interned during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>--apparently so he can take
another swipe at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>.

            This brings us to the much-reported <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
controversy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> never should have pledged
to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>. Had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX> acquiesced in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s invasion there
(following, mind you, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s unchallenged invasions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhineland</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX>), then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> would have spared the West and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attacked Stalin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, leading the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> regimes to fight to the death.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan further</ENAMEX> argues that after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s loss in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was safe, and thus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, who inveigled the country
into war, is at fault for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lives lost.

            Counterfactuals----are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unprovable</ENAMEX>. They carry rhetorical power but no meaning. Besides, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goda</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberg</ENAMEX>  have both shown at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TomPaine</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> did plan for war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>, he commissioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> that could reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>
actively quested for the atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. And even if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> had ignored the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and achieved "only" its goal of becoming "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s words), no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> would agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> interests would have
remained unimperiled.

            As for the charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, they too are specious--the
residue of 1940s conspiracy theories by the ultra-rightists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> seeks to
redeem. Yes, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> ran for office promising
peace while contemplating war. But throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940 and 1941</TIMEX>, the overall
climate became increasingly belligerent, making neutrality untenable. For a
while, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> succeeded anyway in his balancing act: supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, as he knew he had to, while satisfying popular anti-war sentiment with
what he called, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fireside Chat</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 29, 1940</TIMEX>, "methods short of war."
Mainly, this policy meant "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lend-Lease</ENAMEX>," a congressional act that allowed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> to arm <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> under attack, most importantly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> theater, meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> pursued a diplomatic resolution with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan</ENAMEX>
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late November 1941</TIMEX>, when he learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> was continuing its
southward aggression despite the negotiations.

            Recently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, boxed
in by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX>, has insisted that he does agree the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should have
declared war on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>--because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> declared war on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. He has called it a "damnable lie" to claim that he doesn't consider the
war to have been a noble <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. But he doesn't realize how this admission leaves
him without an argument. If going to war against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was ultimately the
right policy, then in hindsight <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">isolationists</ENAMEX>, even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">well-intentioned</ENAMEX>, were wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> might reply with what he says in his
book: that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> "maneuvered us into one collision after another with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> so that war would be 'thrust upon us' "--in other words, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> effectively made the choice to wage war first. But if that's the case, a
consistent argument would have to stick by the claim that the war was a
mistake--a position even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> knows to be untenable in a presidential
election.

            To revive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isolationists</ENAMEX>' reputation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> also
distorts the views of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Lindbergh</ENAMEX>, who even his sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> A.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Berg</ENAMEX> admits was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> correctly notes that many
non-bigots opposed the war, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lindbergh</ENAMEX> isn't so easily exonerated. Lindbergh
openly admired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, cozied up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermann Goering</ENAMEX>, and branded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">un</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agitators</ENAMEX> who used their alleged power to attain their parochial
ends. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> pities the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lone Eagle</ENAMEX>," who he says suffered "for the rest of
his life--and beyond" for uttering "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> short paragraphs." Recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>
yelled at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bob Schieffer on Face the Nation</ENAMEX> for asking about a
passage in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Republic</ENAMEX>, Not an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> in which he bemoans the alleged
power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>. "That is one paragraph out of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>-point essay,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> retorted, suggesting an affinity with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lindbergh</ENAMEX>. In fact, just as
Lindbergh was guilty of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than three</NUMEX> offending paragraphs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bigotry</ENAMEX> is not confined to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> paragraph of this book, as .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> can't reconcile his lifelong
anti-communism with the anti-interventionist philosophy that supposedly unites
his book, so when it comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> he carves out an absurd exception:
The extreme evil of communism, he says, warranted military action in places as
far-flung as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> or as minuscule as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> wasn't a threat to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ho Chi Minh</ENAMEX> was. Nearly everyone agrees <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> was unwinnable and was needlessly prolonged so <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> could save
face. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> deems it "a legitimate war of containment that could have
been won in half the time ... if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had used full conventional
power." Incidentally, he also asserts wrongly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christmas</ENAMEX>
bombing" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> made peace possible. In fact, the peace treaty signed
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1973</TIMEX> differed little from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the table <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous October</TIMEX>. The
key to peace lay in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s decision to jettison his demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ho Chi Minh</ENAMEX>
withdraw from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX>--a demand that he could have renounced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
earlier, sparing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lives.

            One could go on. Buchanan throws in tenuous
assertions and crusty old theories willy-nilly, regardless of their provenance.
That's because he has set out to make an argument, and only then rounded up
whatever "evidence" he can find to support it. And the real argument that comes
through is less about foreign policy aims--his arguments on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
intervention make that clear--than about a nativist vision of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> aren't to be trusted, where the fates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
don't count. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> reject this vision. But even those who don't should
realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s method--forming his conclusions based on prejudice,
then rustling up the support for them--invariably produces bad history.

         
      
   
