
   
   
      
         
            To a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friend Who Keeps Telling Me He Has Lost His Memory</ENAMEX>

            And
yet you know that you remember me
whoever I am and it is to me
you speak as you used to and we are sure of it

            and
you remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> being saved
by some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> from whatever
she insists he will never be able
to do when he has done it easily
the light has not changed at all on that one
falling in front of you as you look through it

            and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of explaining
are a fan
that opens against the light here and there
proving something that then darkens again
they are at hand but closer than they are

            is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> who entrusted you
with her old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baedeker</ENAMEX> to take along
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Normandy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landing</ENAMEX> where it turned out
to have powers and a time of its own

            but
the names fade out leaving the faces
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weddings</ENAMEX> and processions anonymous
where is it the sudden tears well up from
as you see faces turning in silence
though if they were here now it would still be
hard for you to hear what they said to you

            but you lean forward and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confide</ENAMEX> in me
as when you arrived once at some finely
wrought conclusion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> that now
what interests you most of all is birdsong
you have a plan to take some <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> with you

         
      
   
