
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remnick</ENAMEX>'s Progress

            The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was much impressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s "dash and daring" in sneakily
moving into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. In an editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Who Dares</ENAMEX>
Wins" (the motto of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British SAS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commandos</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> have won "not only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> and the initiative, but the secret
admiration of scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> frustrated by an enforced wait on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> borders." Their "coup de théâtre" has served as a reminder "that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dithering</ENAMEX> loses to derring-do," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said: "This may have been a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>-dominated war; but to halt and advance to allow the cameras to catch up
is a grotesque irresponsibility."

            But
this was a minority view in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Left</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
military "seems ever closer to being out of control" and that its behavior in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is "proof that there is no longer one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in that vast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
but rather several, held in loose, often hostile connection to each other."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> should continue to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> its own sector in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, but should also
soothe its wounded pride by "admitting that the West has been cavalier in its
treatment of the former superpower and that it now has to be given a seat at
the commanding table."

            On the
Right, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for being too
accommodating to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. It is hardly surprising that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX> aim of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
policy is to counter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s influence in central <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, "and the role of
honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> between the West and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> gave them an ideal opportunity to
do so," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "Trusting them with that task prolonged the air
campaign and has now seriously queered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFOR</ENAMEX>'s pitch," it added. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> cannot
blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> for making difficulties. The fault lies in giving them such
an opportunity."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> ran an editorial saying that the message of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s race to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> was a "brutal" one: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> are not willing to submit to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s authority and that they want control of the northern sector of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> to carry out a de facto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partition</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> had good
reasons to be considerate toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> (by delaying preparations for a land
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invasion</ENAMEX> and seeking a solution to the crisis within the unusual context of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX>, only because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> was a part of it), it also has the right to expect
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> "to play the game," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> was right to involve
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, it concluded, "but not at any price, and especially not at that of a
partition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>."

            
Another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> , said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s dash into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
shouldn't be treated lightly because it's unclear "who pilots the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> might well ask this question of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> when they
meet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cologne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, but "it isn't certain
that his answer will be very convincing." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX>
called the move "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s coup" but added in a front-page comment that the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next few days</TIMEX> would show whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> has only been acting on whim or
whether there's a strategy behind it.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> papers were generally dominated, however, by the results of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter turnouts</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>, delivered heavy rebuffs to both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> trounced the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Left</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> as well, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of
TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvio Berlusconi</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, came in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. But in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Socialists</ENAMEX> triumphed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> said, however, that the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> of
the elections were the absentionists. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than one</NUMEX> elector in two
voted; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> did. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> said
the low turnouts threatened to undermine the effectiveness of the European
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, and most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> said the results might set back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>'s
plans to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> single currency, the euro.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
Remnick, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sera</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that his objective for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> was that it would be
said that "of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> best articles of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> were published in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> --ideally, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of those under my editorship." Confessing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interviewer Alessandra Farkas</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> was still in the red,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remnick</ENAMEX> said he is pleased that it has been rechristened "the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authoritative</ENAMEX> and prestigious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> on the planet" because "when you're the
best in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>, it's inevitable that sooner or later you become
profitable."

            He
rejected a suggestion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> was "elitist," saying that the
word applied better to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> --"a purely celebral,
if brilliant, undertaking." Asked if he agreed that the quality of the world's
press is in decline, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remnick</ENAMEX> replied: "We are the living proof of the opposite:
Investing in quality has and always will have a place in the market. Despite
our deficit, nobody tells me what to publish and what not to publish. And do
you know why? In a world of fast food, there will always be room for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">five-star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
