
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beanie Baby Panic</ENAMEX>

            

               The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> agreed to an independent inquiry
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waco</ENAMEX> incident. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of denials, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> confessed it
had fired incendiary tear gas devices at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Davidian</ENAMEX> compound. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
still says it's unlikely that these devices caused the fire. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> ordered federal marshals to seize videotapes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> headquarters
on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> reportedly can be heard discussing the use of these devices.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s actions would damage an already
strained relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> doubt her
get-tough attitude will redeem her reputation as "."

            

               Violence 
               broke out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX>
territory voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> on independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. Results are expected
to show that the referendum passed. Pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> and have threatened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
                criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, which is
still responsible for maintaining peace on the island, for failing to respond
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> warned that international intervention might become
necessary.

            

               One
               -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League Baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpires</ENAMEX> lost their
jobs. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umps</ENAMEX> had resigned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, hoping to win concessions from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> accepted their resignations, they sued to block their
removal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> accepted their removal in a settlement but claimed victory
because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> agreed to let an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arbitrator</ENAMEX> decide whether to reinstate
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpires</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) in any event, they'll be paid for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the season</TIMEX>.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpires</ENAMEX> disagreed, saying they'd rather be working .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Beanie</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Babies</ENAMEX> may be "retired" at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>.
The cryptic announcement by the toys' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> rushing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. The anxious take: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quirkiness</ENAMEX> lends
credibility to the announcement. The cynical take: It's a
marketing ploy to jump-start demand. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Collectors</ENAMEX> warned
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beanie</ENAMEX>-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> wouldn't take kindly to being
jerked around. (
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s James Surowiecki</ENAMEX> .)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> 
               improved memory in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> by implanting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> with the extra gene outperformed normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> at learning and
memory tasks, though the difference dissolved after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> called
the improved <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> "smarter" and "geniuses." The findings, published in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> , are
expected to boost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) biologically based theories of intelligence; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
development of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> for memory loss and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) worries about
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer babies</ENAMEX>" and a superhuman race; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) concerns that humanlike animals
will require humanlike rights.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> 
               scores may soon be adjusted for socioeconomic
background. Under a plan being considered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Testing</ENAMEX>
Service, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who score at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> points above the norm for their
socioeconomic cohort would be classified as "strivers." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detractors</ENAMEX> called the plan an end run around affirmative action bans at state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. Affirmative action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> warned that any consideration of
race in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formula</ENAMEX> would be unconstitutional. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETS</ENAMEX> did not comment on
whether wealthy, low-scoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> would be classified as
"underachievers."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX> still 
               hasn't come ashore . Having
disappointed the media hype, the storm lurked off the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> coast. The
old spin: It's a threat to life, limb, and property. The new spin: It's a
threat to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> beach weather.

            

               The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> bid on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westchester</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. The century-old
Georgian Colonial features <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>, a swimming pool, and an exercise
room. It is listed at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 million</NUMEX>.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC Entertainment</ENAMEX> resigned. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Tarses</ENAMEX>, who created hits such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad About You</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, left her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> job after being
demoted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> wondered if she was "too young, too
immature, too emotional and, yes, too female for the job she was assigned." The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarses</ENAMEX>' tenure at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> was marked by few
hits but a great deal of personal friction.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> may have laundered money for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> are examining whether mobsters diverted
funds--including foreign aid--out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> through an offshore network
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticizing Al Gore</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naively</ENAMEX> accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> pledges of economic
reform.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> 
               war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> caught a suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Momir Talic</ENAMEX>, the highest-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to be
arrested so far, was seized in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               Post
predicts that the arrest will remind other suspected war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> not to travel abroad .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were caught smuggling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. They stashed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and marijuana in food trays and used their
security clearances to transport the contraband.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will prosecute the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX>
               . A
government order excused most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> saying they had been brainwashed into
joining a subversive political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Sheinbein</ENAMEX> will serve a murder sentence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. The American
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> had fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> after allegedly committing murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> refused to let him be extradited back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.
Under a plea bargain, he will be sentenced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and will
probably serve less. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> from both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> decried the way he
manipulated the discrepancies between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legal systems.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">whistleblower</ENAMEX> resigned. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colleagues</ENAMEX> had called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notra Trulock</ENAMEX>'s allegations against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> racist and had said there was
not a "shred of evidence" against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> . Trulock
countered that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> initial suspects in the case were of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> background. He also called a recent report exonerating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration a "whitewash" and said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moler</ENAMEX> blocked him from briefing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> 
               blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayed</ENAMEX> commanded an intoxicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chauffeur</ENAMEX> to drive them and that
both could have survived had they been wearing seatbelts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Maj.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hewitt</ENAMEX> a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judas</ENAMEX>," a "heartless <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>," a
"rotter," a "love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>," and a "repulsive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah</ENAMEX>" for publishing a book
about his affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>; see "" for more on the outraged reaction.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> allegedly ignored positive drug-test results. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> tape of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Players Association</ENAMEX> meeting obtained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> boasts of having secretly convinced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> to overlook <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
positive drug tests.

         
      
   
