
   
   
      
         
             Flushed

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court to outlaw the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.8 billion</NUMEX> video poker industry is the most
remarkable defeat for gambling in memory. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have blocked
gambling--as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> did by defeating a lottery referendum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>--but this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has outlawed gambling and
uprooted a living industry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> decision is a triumph for
anti-gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, who have been hammering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palmetto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
Yet, weirdly, it is also a victory for gambling--at least the kind of gambling
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> want.

            To understand why, you
have to realize how ugly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina</ENAMEX> video poker industry is. Those who
have not visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> recently don't know what a favor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court has done the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Gambling everywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has produced its share
of social disarray and political sleaziness, but nothing remotely equals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>, whose poker industry was built on lies, legal chicanery, and just
plain crime.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't realize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> even has legal
gambling, yet it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX> places to gamble--more than any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and three
times as many as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>. It has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34,000</NUMEX> gambling machines, more than all but
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> is--and there is no other word for it--blighted by
gambling. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About one-quarter</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> retail businesses
offer gambling. Every place you can think of that might have gambling has
gambling: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convenience</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> stops,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>, are fogged with cigarette smoke and filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't have
much money playing games they can't win for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 hours</TIMEX> at a stretch.
(I'm not exaggerating. I have seen this.) Video poker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> grossed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, and their take has been growing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. And all
this has occurred in a state that never intended to legalize gambling.

            The video poker industry
finessed itself into existence. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> law clearly banned gambling. But
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, as a favor to a big local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>, a state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> stuck a tiny
amendment in the back of a gigantic budget bill. The amendment erased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
words--"or property"--from an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> law. It passed without any
debate--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> or private--and without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> knowing what they had done.
It legalized video gambling, allowing game <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to pay jackpots to video
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">poker winners</ENAMEX>. It wasn't until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> that the state even realized what had
happened.

            Having legalized itself through the backdoor, the industry
proceeded to duck, skirt, or break every law passed to control it. When the
state banned big jackpots by forbidding machines to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $125</NUMEX> to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> ignored the law. They continued to offer
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">multithousand</ENAMEX> dollar jackpots: If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gambler</ENAMEX> hit the jackpot, he was simply paid
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX> a day for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as many days</TIMEX> as it took to empty the pot.

            When the state banned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> by limiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> machines on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>
surmised that "premises" meant, essentially, anything with a wall and a door.
Then they jammed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 or 60 or 100</NUMEX> machines into a single <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and subdivided
it into endless <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-machine closets. (They call these places, with a sick
sense of euphemism, "video <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>." More dismal casinos you cannot imagine. At
one "video <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>" where I spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX>, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> on offer was Tootsie
Rolls.) Unlike virtually every other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> with gambling, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> does
not tax gambling revenues, does not forbid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to play the machines, and
does not ban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> from owning them. Gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> call it the "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild West</ENAMEX>"
of gambling.

            The video poker industry's latest trick was buying itself a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Beasley</ENAMEX> tried and failed to ban video
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, the industry went to war against him. It spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>--and almost certainly a lot more--to defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beasley</ENAMEX>'s re-election bid.
By <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> estimate, video poker supplied <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 70 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
gubernatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hodges</ENAMEX>' war chest, plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another million</NUMEX> from a
single poker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> on his own anti-Beasley <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another million</NUMEX>
or more in soft money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> is the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for the poker industry.) Beasley, a
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> in a thriving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, lost to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">little-known</ENAMEX>, uncharismatic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>. The poker money swamped him.

            But despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodges</ENAMEX>'
victory, the backlash against video poker grew. The overwhelming image of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> gambling is of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> glamour, but the new reality is "convenience
gambling." This is the industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">euphemism</ENAMEX> for the infiltration of gambling into
everyday life (which is indeed convenient for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that make millions
off it). Traditionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have separated gambling, exiling it to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">desert of Nevada</ENAMEX>, the horse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>, or the beach. But convenience gambling has
brought it next door, in the form of video gambling in places such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, and in the form of scratch-off lottery games all
over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> is by far the most extreme example of
convenience gambling.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> deplore convenience gambling. It is extremely
dangerous to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>: Every trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> becomes a temptation. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Video</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>, which is fast and requires skill, is known as "video crack" because it
is by far the most addictive form of gambling. According to the only study of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>, the state seems to have a problem-gambling rate twice
as high as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>'s.) Convenience gambling also addicts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> hooked previously independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gas stations</ENAMEX>, convenience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> on gambling dollars.

            Most alarmingly,
convenience gambling exacts huge social costs in the form of addiction and
financial hardship without providing any economic benefit. Unlike casino
gambling, convenience gambling does not bring with it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, or good jobs. "There is no pretense that this is about tourism or
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a nice night out or this is entertainment. This is hard-core,
grab-the-paycheck gambling," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Grey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Coalition</ENAMEX>
Against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gambling Expansion</ENAMEX>, when I interviewed him about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> this
spring for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s decision is the culmination of the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>
backlash. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> ordered a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX> referendum to decide
the status of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> once and for all. The law specified that if the referendum
were ruled unconstitutional, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> would be banned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>
has no referendum right, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> canceled the vote and upheld the
ban.

            It's unfortunate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> voided the
referendum, because it deprives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of the opportunity to throw out the
poker industry themselves. And there is little doubt they would have done so.
The anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> campaign has galvanized the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> like no issue ever has.
Virtually every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> from both parties, the
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber of commerce</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of grassroots <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> banded
together to defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>. The most recent poll suggested that the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX> would win in a rout: More than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> favored banning
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 16 percent</NUMEX> wanted to keep it.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Poker</ENAMEX> was a like a
houseguest that was unwelcome in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, that stayed too long, and was
really obnoxious. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> just want it gone," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Stanton</ENAMEX>, who runs the
anti-gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palmetto Family Council</ENAMEX>.

            Video <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> is not gone yet. The industry has a magnificent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">aptitude</ENAMEX> for escaping defeat. It has used suits and lobbying and more suits to
stymie previous efforts to restrict it. There is no doubt the industry will ask
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> usually "asks" with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> in campaign
contributions--to reconsider the ban.

            The irony of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina</ENAMEX> fight is that video
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>'s death may actually help the gambling industry. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX>,
rumors have been circulating in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> were
subsidizing the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Gaming Association</ENAMEX> has spoken
out against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s gambling anarchy, and for good reason. The gambling
industry wants to be the gaming industry. Casino <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> have carefully
cultivated a family-friendly, law-abiding image: They loathe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>,
where gambling is criminal, ugly, and unpopular.

            Kill video <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, and you erase the biggest stain on gambling's image. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that remain--perfumed slot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bingos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>--seem
virtuous, and are virtuous, by comparison.

         
      
   
