
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Comeback Tour</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>, like an aging rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> who keeps
squeezing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more year out of the same old hits, has embarked on yet another
comeback tour. The former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX> has just released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renewal</ENAMEX> , a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,079</NUMEX>-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">behemoth</ENAMEX> about his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX>.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert D. Kaplan</ENAMEX> has lionized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. This tribute--a bow from the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pessimist</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> to
the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pessimist</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>--revisits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> doctoral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dissertation</ENAMEX> and finds it "brave," a persuasive account of why realism keeps
the peace better than idealism. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> is popping up on TV screens with
alarming frequency, delivering his gloomy assessments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> bombing and
the frost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> relations.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>, of course, has never gone entirely out
of fashion. His press savvy, charm, and resolute courtship of the rich and
powerful have ensured that he always remains plenty visible. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>--to whom he is eternally yoked--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> out of
power spinning, endlessly spinning, his record (and revising it when
necessary). Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> has been trying to escape a black mark on his
career (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>). And as with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, this spinning
occasionally produces vindication, as it has for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kissinger</ENAMEX>
is back in vogue not because he is saying anything new. He's only saying what
he has been saying for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45 years</TIMEX>. He's back in vogue because his doleful realism
frames the debate for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s foreign policy,
especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> policies.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s vindication
isn't complete, because the current talk is silent on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
vindication could be just around the corner. Click for more.)

            Much of the current fascination with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> grows out of
the journalistic debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Years of Renewal</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renewal</ENAMEX> ,
it must be said, does not seem a promising start for any kind of debate. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and final (thank God) volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s memoirs, it drones on about
an entirely forgettable period in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. The Mayaguez
Incident. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quick</ENAMEX>, can you tell me what that was about? Or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basket III</ENAMEX>"? I didn't
think so.

            But beneath the welter of
details about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> makes a surprising claim, arguing
that his tough-but-accommodating policy toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'70s</TIMEX> led
directly to the confrontational <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> tactics that won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> in the
'80s. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>, the breathing space created by détente gave the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> time to recover from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> without retreating into
isolationism, thus setting the table for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>, have embraced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s interpretation. But others, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Kagan</ENAMEX> in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>, have savaged <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Years of Renewal</ENAMEX> for its self-serving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revisionism</ENAMEX>. Now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX> has collapsed, they say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> is
pretending that he was much tougher on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> than he ever was. In the
most telling example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kagan</ENAMEX> slams <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> for taking credit for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Helsinki</ENAMEX> human rights provisions. (That's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basket III</ENAMEX>.") These provisions
became a key weapon of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet-bloc</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kagan</ENAMEX> says,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> was skeptical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basket III</ENAMEX> and had virtually nothing to do with
it.

            The fight over whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">détente</ENAMEX> helped win the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> is not simply academic. It especially matters
for current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> relations. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kissingerian</ENAMEX> détente helped break the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>, then presumably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kissingerian</ENAMEX> détente could help tame <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> downplayed ideological conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet Communists</ENAMEX>
in favor of soothed relations, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sino-apologists</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authoritarianism</ENAMEX>, human rights violations, and
suppression of democracy. Idealistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> despised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s accommodationist policies during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX> was an evil
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">empire</ENAMEX>, not simply a dance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in the great geopolitical waltz. Likewise,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s idealistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> still despise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> and detect in Years
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renewal</ENAMEX> 's détente argument an excuse to coddle <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. It is no
coincidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kagan</ENAMEX>, the sharpest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Years of Renewal</ENAMEX> , is also
the strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> around, author of many anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> articles for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> comeback wouldn't be possible without the
spectacle of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> foreign policy confusion. Since the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has divided itself into Wilsonian idealists, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , who believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should be the global
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">crusader</ENAMEX> for justice, and the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, which isn't sure what it
believes but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loathes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealists</ENAMEX> favored intervention
and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> didn't, has deepened this divide.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> seems an unlikely guide for the lost
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. After all, he backed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> bombing on the grounds that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>,
having started fighting, must win to preserve its credibility. But beneath
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s reluctant support was a larger principle: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has no
vital interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> never should have involved
itself there at all. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ideals, should ultimately
determine our foreign policy.

            It is this gloomy but coherent vision that has made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> a favorite of floundering anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. (It is this same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX> so admires.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> offers them a stiff foreign policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">framework</ENAMEX>, a set of principles sharply contrasted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hocism</ENAMEX>. He
gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> intellectual window dressing to what would otherwise be
just more incoherent anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clintonism</ENAMEX>. This is not as glorious as another stint
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>, but the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> will happily accept the
assignment.

         
      
   
