
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Horrors</ENAMEX>

            Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with the discovery of a "medieval torture
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX>" beneath a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> and on an official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
estimate that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10,000</NUMEX> ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> died in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> atrocities. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
carried front-page photographs of some of the instruments of torture found
inside the police interrogation center--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">knuckle-dusters</ENAMEX>, knives, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hangman</ENAMEX>'s
noose, and a chainsaw. Although, according to local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> spent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> burning documents before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> arrived, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
quoted an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX> war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> as saying that scraps of
paper left behind might be useful in establishing a "paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>" between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> and the massacres carried out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. "There is
correspondence going between here and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> about numbers of 'terrorist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>' picked up," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said. "It tells us a lot about how much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belgrade</ENAMEX> knew was going on." The discovery prompted a hard-line editorial in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> calling on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to stand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> against any deviations
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peace deal. It asked in particular for rejection of a request
by some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> to be allowed to discard their uniforms and
return to civilian life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. "To backpedal in any way would result
in more demands from all sides for more renegotiation, put the deal as a whole
in jeopardy, and must not be countenanced," it said.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> strongly attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Interior Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Pierre</ENAMEX>
Chevènement for his apparent indifference to the sufferings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>. It described as "shocking" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>'s public declaration of
concern about what might now happen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> "without a word
about the violence and deportations endured for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long weeks</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX>,
without a thought for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the massacres carried out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> 's editorial also deplored the timing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>'s
statement, coming just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is discovering that its worst fears about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
atrocities were justified and that the accounts by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> were not
exaggerated.

            The
Independent
reported the reappearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veton Surroi</ENAMEX>, the publisher of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koha Ditore</ENAMEX> , which had its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and printing
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> destroyed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> during the war but which started publishing again
in exile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> , which described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surroi</ENAMEX> as a
possible future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>, said it reached him by telephone and
was told that he is fine and will soon be coming out of hiding. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> ran an article by former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX> about
the environmental consequences of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> air campaign. Writing in his
capacity as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Cross International</ENAMEX>, a nongovernmental
environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> called for a ban on weapons containing
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">depleted uranium</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. Although their external
radiation levels are quite low, he said, "the internal radiation source damages
various types of cells in the human body, destroys chromosomes and affects the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reproductive</ENAMEX> system." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> also wants the bombing of nuclear power
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX> and of some chemical and petrochemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> to be prohibited by
international law. "The human drama and the drama of nature should be of equal
concern to us," he wrote.

            In an
editorial on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cologne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said world leaders
"should stick to the hard stuff," such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> and Third World debt
relief, rather than introduce a new topic, education--"an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interloper</ENAMEX> that risks
distracting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> from urgent matters and perverts the purpose of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">summits</ENAMEX>"--to their discussions. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G8</ENAMEX> should concentrate on issues that only
they can solve," it said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> and his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> may hope that by
endorsing this charter [for lifelong learning] they will make the summit seem
more relevant to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives. Yet few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are likely to be impressed by a
wedge of motherhood and apple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>, served with a topping of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jargon</ENAMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> highlighted anticipated summit differences
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and the West over the postwar reconstruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. It
said that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Chirac</ENAMEX> had agreed to deny all but humanitarian aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> remains in power, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> opposes such a condition and has already
pledged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> toward reconstruction.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welt</ENAMEX> and Frankfurter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> on a clash over abortion between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX>. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> get
free abortions within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three months</TIMEX> of pregnancy, provided they have
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> discussed their situations with a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> comprising social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>. Of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,700</NUMEX> such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270</NUMEX> are organized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX>. But in an
"outspoken" letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">German Bishops' Conference</ENAMEX>, the gist of which was
leaked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankfurter Allgemeine</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> ordered the German
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> to stop participating in the state consultancy system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said he
had thus put himself in opposition to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 70 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.

            The
scandal, originating in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, of contaminated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> continued to make
front pages around <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> said this was an "annus horribilis " for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>,
that "the sun is setting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>," and that "the gods have
turned against the fizzy drink." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is suffering from "a credibility
crisis which could prove devastating," it said.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> 's front
page included an exposé of the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">underwater explorer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques-Yves Cousteau</ENAMEX>, as a rabid anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Semite</ENAMEX>. It quoted a letter written by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cousteau</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>, when he was working for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> naval intelligence in
Marseilles, complaining about the lack of decent accommodation. "There won't be
a suitable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> until they have thrown out those vile 'youtres ' [an
abusive term for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>] who encumber us," he wrote to a fellow naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cousteau</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago this month</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
