
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">261</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;The Rules&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
pages of rules are these: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> must smile and wear makeup at all times, any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> caught chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> gets an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80</NUMEX> fine, and then there's the draconian Rule
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>--"if any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> complaints, she must immediately resign." Rules
governing what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 260</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Touching (and Smelling) Tale":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  "You're telling me I have to touch anyone who comes in here,
even if I don't want to? I have to get up really close to them and smell their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perfume</ENAMEX>, smell their breath<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" asked an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incredulous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Damico</ENAMEX>. As it turns
out, yes, he does. And what does he have to do after
that?
               
            

            "Shake
their hands and announce his candidacy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cole</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Cloutier</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Gibson</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "Give
them a prescription for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> and bill their insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for another
successful round of outpatient diagnosis and treatment."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
(similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Rogers</ENAMEX> )

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hump</ENAMEX>
their legs."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Cloutier</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Devine</ENAMEX> )

            
"Whatever happened to 'Hello, welcome to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>?' "--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Terns</ENAMEX>
            

            "Stop
telling me he wants a divorce."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Most responses could be
divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of contempt: some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">target snobs</ENAMEX> who disdain the rabble
(the reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>, the smarmy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>), others target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slobs</ENAMEX> who
are the rabble (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX>). The former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POV</ENAMEX>
might be thought of as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>, the latter <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. The Ds' motto is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rs</ENAMEX>' motto is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ew</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>." Ds want good seats at the game;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rs</ENAMEX> want a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> near the game (equipped with a good television). Ds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proclaim</ENAMEX>, "We're in it together"; Rs assert, "I'm in it to get you." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ds</ENAMEX> knock
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree trunks</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rs</ENAMEX> hold a leaf in their mouth and clip bits off in a noisy way.
No, wait, sorry, that last thing refers to different ways chimpanzee males
attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, evidence of true cultural variation among the apes, not one of
whom formally announced his candidacy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.

            
               Take a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hike</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granny</ENAMEX>, Answer
            

            He must cut their hair.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Damico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> and operator of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Giovan</ENAMEX> hair <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">salon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, refuses to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>. He was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">astonished</ENAMEX> to learn about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> access laws, but both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Affairs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission on Human Rights</ENAMEX> have been filling him in.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX>, I suppose you'll be saying I can't turn away <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>," he didn't add.

            And on a personal note
from admired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>: "This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> cut my hair <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. Couldn't have been creepier."

            
               Either/Or
Extra
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> deserve refuge from a culture of violence and mayhem."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is either treating us all to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck E. Cheese</ENAMEX>'s or
launching his run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

               "That's pretty much an accomplishment that won't happen, unfortunately for
basketball and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Jackson</ENAMEX> , the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> Lakers
coach, refers either to the stoning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">halftime</TIMEX> during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> finals or to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> coming out of retirement yet again.

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Customer</ENAMEX> expectations will drive changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> if that's what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> want."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Berquist</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>, explains why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance of Automobile Manufacturers</ENAMEX> is either willing to produce a new
gasoline-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">soaked</NUMEX>-paper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or is unwilling to accept any more damn safety
regulations.

               "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One hundred</NUMEX> thirteen years of our success has been based on the trust
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> have in that quality."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Ivester</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> chief
executive, reassures <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belgians</ENAMEX> that they either will be able to rely on steady
supplies of new <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fever-, Nausea-</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Headache-Inducing Coke</ENAMEX> or they won't.

               "There's a protest here. There's a protest there. There's a protest
everywhere ."--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> is either reading from his
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s book or displaying his trademark dismissiveness and contempt for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> who disagree with him, in this case street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> he's throwing out
of work.

               "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> teach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that they are nothing but glorified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apes</ENAMEX> who are evolutionized out of some primordial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Either Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> 's surprisingly tasty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud soup</ENAMEX> now contains zesty chunks of real ape,
or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX> is blaming gun violence on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Darwin</ENAMEX>.

               "This is cultural behavior."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Whiten</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> Primate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Group</ENAMEX> is either mustering a rather limp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> or
reporting surprising findings about chimpanzee life.

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Sex, death, and dentistry.

         
      
   
