
   
   
      
         
            A Cooling off in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> claimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that an ecological catastrophe "far worse"
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon Valdez</ENAMEX> accident <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX> could happen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> "at
any moment." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six</TIMEX> "senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Trans-Alaska Pipeline System</ENAMEX> wrote
to Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Browne</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP Amoco</ENAMEX>, and to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX>, warning of an imminent threat to human life and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX>
environment from irresponsible oil operations there, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in its main
front-page story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP Amoco</ENAMEX> owns <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alyeska</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
operates both the pipeline and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Valdez oil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> near where the huge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tanker Exxon Valdez</ENAMEX> crashed on a reef in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, spewing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gallons</ENAMEX> of heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prince William Sound</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alyeska</ENAMEX>'s other biggest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arco</ENAMEX>.) The unnamed whistle-blowers included evidence
in their letter of compliance failures, falsified safety and inspection
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>, intimidation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and persistent violations of procedures and
government regulations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> reported. Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alyeska</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
allegedly instructed middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to "disregard and/or circumvent"
compliance manuals and codes of conduct and to "tone down, alter or delete
negative reports, including internal audits and surveillance reports."

            While
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>-backed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> have
started pulling out of the disputed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Himalayan</ENAMEX> region of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>--a development
described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> as
"a dramatic victory" for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and a "total military rout" for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>
led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on planned protests by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> militants against the
withdrawal. As <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz Sharif</ENAMEX> prepared to defend the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">withdrawl</ENAMEX> in a national broadcast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said several mujahideen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and
the opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaat-i-Islami Party</ENAMEX> announced that anti-government
demonstrations would be held in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Punjabi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lahore</ENAMEX> and in the port city
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX> is planning to argue that the withdrawal is justified by his
winning unprecedented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> backing for new Indo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> talks to end the
52-year-old deadlock over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn</ENAMEX> said
that "persistent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> rejection of anything it sees as third-party mediation
might undermine his assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s pledge to take a
personal interest in the row might yield progress."

            
Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> reiterated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in an editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> must resist
third-party intervention. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> must move to put bilateral relations
back on the rails--and obviate the need for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>," it said. "There is
no alternative but to seriously engage in bilateral discussions with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX>." In another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> editorial,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> said that while "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> attempt at aggression against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>" has ended, like all previous ones, "in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ignominious</TIMEX> defeat," its leaders
are "in the process of trying to proclaim victory once again." To counter this,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> should compile a detailed list of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> killed in the
fighting and publish it in the media and on the Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> must realize the extent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> in the conflict, it
said. To sustain the myth that only unsupported mujahideen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> were
involved, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> killed in combat have been disowned
by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX>, their services unacknowledged; even a decent burial has been
denied them," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> which repudiates its war dead will have
little credibility among its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn</ENAMEX> 's editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was devoted not to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> crisis but to the
safer subject of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab-Israeli</ENAMEX> peace process. It expressed misgivings about
a statement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> by new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> that he wanted to
modify parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> has done
"incalculable damage to the peace process" by throwing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s commitment to
international treaties into doubt, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "Now it is Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s duty
to correct that image and prove to the world that agreements signed by a
previous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are not considered mere scraps of paper by a
succeeding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> and that every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has the
duty and international obligation to honor treaties signed by its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predecessors</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> press, by contrast, was generally upbeat about peace prospects
following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s meeting between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>,
who referred to him afterward as his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported
that discussions on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement would begin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 10 days</TIMEX>' time, after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> has visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Quoting diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> would present <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with a detailed negotiating plan
that includes a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> tour by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>. The plan would culminate at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak-Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> summit to declare an "agreed framework for the permanent
settlement" or, failing that, a declaration of principles outlining the steps
toward a settlement. In an editorial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> to help to
create a new atmosphere of trust by unilaterally dismantling the outposts
illegally established by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> on hilltops outside existing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>
settlements in "a wild, catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-catch-can land grab" during the run-up to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, the Frankfurter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the wave of student
demonstrations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, which were also prominently reported in many
other leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. An analysis in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> said
that the protests reflect mounting frustration among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and many
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> at the lack of progress in implementing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>'s reforms because of opposition by the conservative clerical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. It noted the disproportionate influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX>
university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 62 million</NUMEX> where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 60 percent</NUMEX>
are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 25 years old</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claimed that while popular indignation with
the conservative clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> was running high, support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>
remained solid.

            Both
the Straits
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinapore</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> ran editorials
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to be more sensitive toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> or risk
another <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> means to be taken seriously, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> owes it that
respect," the Straits Times said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cockiness over its display of military technology
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, and smugness over its longest post-war prosperity
streak, can blind it to a need to cultivate its relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> beyond
promoting democratisation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russians</ENAMEX> cannot eat democracy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> should snap
out of its hubris over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>--or the world could become very dark indeed if
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> hurt turns to mischief-making." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
anger over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s recent actions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> is in many ways justified and
since it is not understood, is the more likely to have broad, negative
consequences for the West's dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and, more particularly,
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
