
   
   
      
         
            Brits as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corny</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>

            In the
run up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>'s confirmation as the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> continued to speculate about the reasons for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>'s
removal. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times of London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Aron</ENAMEX> declared
that "the sole rational explanation [for the dismissal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sergei Stepashin</ENAMEX>]
appears to be a sudden deterioration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s health and his expectation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incapacitation</ENAMEX> or even death. ... It is reasonable to assume the president
wanted to see in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> someone he could trust in the interregnum to keep
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> hand on the wheel."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX>
said
that Stepashin "proved to be nicer and more honorable than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entourage</ENAMEX> hoped or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> feared. ... In contrast, it is widely assumed
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> would be prepared to do whatever it takes to assure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
family remains a commanding presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> politics." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s attempts to "subvert or cancel" elections could backfire,
and added, "Even more ominous is the possibility that political infighting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> could shift the real power to regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>, many of whom are even
less democratic and more self-serving than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> himself. The fragmentation
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> could have terrible
repercussions far beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s borders."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Observer</ENAMEX> speculated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> might try to hold on
to power by causing the cancellation of elections. "This could be done," the
paper said, "either by declaring a state of emergency or a hasty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belarus</ENAMEX>, so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, who cannot by law have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two</NUMEX> terms, could
become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> when his term
as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> finally ran out."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> fronted remarkably similar
photographs of impassioned gatherings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX> were
taken in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omagh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> marked the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-year</TIMEX>
anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> and injured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX>
crowds protested the assassination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humorist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Garzón</ENAMEX>,
probably by right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramilitarists</ENAMEX>.

            
Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omagh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday People</ENAMEX> said that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s bombing by the splinter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group Real</ENAMEX> IRA could easily have derailed the peace process, but "the desire
for peace was too strong for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> breakaway IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to torpedo it. All sides
now owe it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Omagh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> to make sure that, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next August</TIMEX>, they are
signed up to a fair and lasting peace." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> took a less
positive view, saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> away all the talk about peace and progress and
look at what has actually happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Friday</ENAMEX>
deal. The brutal reality is that the only concrete changes are the weakening of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of law and order and the simultaneous strengthening of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramilitaries</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranks</ENAMEX> are now swollen by a number of former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiempo</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garzón</ENAMEX> was killed because of his attempts to bring an end
to the political fighting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>, especially his negotiations with leftist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, and also because of his efforts to secure the release of many kidnap
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. An article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombians</ENAMEX> have long
ago become desensitised to violence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apathy</ENAMEX> is deeply ingrained and it is
unlikely things will change, despite the widespread repugnance and anger shown
by most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>," but an editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Tiempo</ENAMEX>
suggested otherwise. Echoing the cries of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombians</ENAMEX> who lined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garzón</ENAMEX>'s funeral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parade</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "NO MORE. NO MORE. NO MORE. ... Let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FARC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELN</ENAMEX> [the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> largest leftist rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>], the paramilitaries,
and the extreme right end their deafness and understand that we are not
afraid."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers took a field trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for the straw poll and
came back with stories that made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> seem more like a distant planet than a
Midwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> puzzlingly described <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX> as "a cross between 1930s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> and
Calcutta," and speaking of the poll's disproportionate influence on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
electoral process said, "It is as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnshire</ENAMEX> village
were pivotal in deciding the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>."

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said that even if media inquiries into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s private life were to "uncover damaging
details" it might not put him out of the running, since " 'character issues'
have less power than they did to wreck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> era has
rewritten the rulebook. Unless Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has committed some major sin very
recently, he is likely to survive any new revelations." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> added that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> may have helped his chances by staying out of the
straw poll: "He has thus placed himself to emerge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> as a new voice that
could win over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who found beauty in none of those parading their
credentials at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>."

            If
electoral politics are indeed a beauty contest, and if a history of sinning is
no longer an impediment to electability, perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> could
become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. A story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> put a positive spin on
his possible run. Despite his lack of electoral experience, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> had "several key qualifications": "He fosters instant name recognition.
He is good-looking. He is smart, charismatic and a good talker. True, he has an
infamous past as a skirt-chaser, but unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, with his taste in
big-haired <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX>-park <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX>, he can honestly say he has slept with some
of the most beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the world."

         
      
   
