
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">287</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;First-Class Male&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fournier</ENAMEX>, a health insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Novato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> gather round: "They say, 'Boy, that's neat!' " What do the postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> admire?*
            

            
               (*a gun-free
question)
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 286</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Supplies Party":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Vinyl rope, magnets, large nails--what's the connection?
            

            "One
can only have so many face lifts."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Glassenberg</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Things used to prop up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Mum</ENAMEX> for her birthday photo-ops?"-- Trey
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Adams</ENAMEX>
            

            "Items
not on display at the check-out counter of my local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVS</ENAMEX> drugstore (except for
the magnets and vinyl rope)."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Kurtz</ENAMEX>
            

            "These
things are in such short supply in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> that they have to be smuggled in
in the stomachs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Myers</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            The rope, the magnet, and the nail comprise a fine
set of fasteners. Indeed, we live in the golden age of attaching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing to
another thing--bolts, rivets, screws, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX>, tape, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Velcro</ENAMEX>, staples, giant rubber
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bands</ENAMEX>, various forms of welding, some of which are practiced by cool robots,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suction</ENAMEX> cups, funtac--I could go on. But I'll tell you this: There is no
fastener--however great the tensile strength of its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon fibers</ENAMEX>, however
powerful the chemical bonds of its space-age <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polymers</ENAMEX>--that can hold together a
marriage without love, without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>, and without communication.

            (This has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quiz/Lifetime Television</ENAMEX> Romantic Moment. Promotional fee paid.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Beans</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autopsies</ENAMEX> turned up
all these items in the stomachs of dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>, part of a charity herd trucked
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyundai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung Ju Yung</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyundai</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>, donated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of cattle to the famine-stricken <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>. Now about
half the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> are dead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> of sabotage; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
denied it, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vets</ENAMEX> still searched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> carcasses for
suspicious viruses and electronic devices. "It was absolutely untrue that we
planted any type of surveillance device on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>," says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>'s intelligence service.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung</ENAMEX> donated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>
to honor a family debt. As a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, he stole his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>, sold it, and
used the money to head south to make his fortune. He has since donated an
additional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>; their fate is unknown.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Object of My</ENAMEX>
Reflection Extra
            

            Match each subject with
its object to complete the sentence and determine what is being reflected.

            
               Subjects
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s note, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk : "New</ENAMEX>
voices are everywhere. We would have a chance to bring some of them together to
reflect ..."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>, same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, same piece, same lame
figure of speech: "Of course, we needed a new format, one that would reflect
..."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xinhua</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Daily</ENAMEX>
Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Hongzhi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fallacies Reflect ...</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> press release, announcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
Faludi piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Recent Shootings Were Acts of Individual Madness</ENAMEX>, but
Also Reflect ..."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press Release</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaunchPad Technologies</ENAMEX>,
an idealab! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that recently acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PointCast</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> announced it has
changed its name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EntryPoint</ENAMEX> to reflect ..."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press Release</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuron Data 'Blazes</ENAMEX>' Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way Into</ENAMEX> the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Service Market</ENAMEX>. Changes Name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blaze Software</ENAMEX> to
Reflect ..."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Company Press
Release: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxnet, Inc.</ENAMEX>'s name has been changed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MaxPlanet, Corp. MXNT</ENAMEX> has
changed its name to reflect ..."

            
               Objects
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "... a point of view, a marriage of emotion and
ideas."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. "</ENAMEX>...the accelerated boom and flack of modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">... Dangerous Political Aims</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">... Pressures of Changed Society on American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX> "... its powerful new desktop 'EntryPoint' to
the Internet."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">... Runaway Success of Its</ENAMEX> WebPersonalization
Engine."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. "</ENAMEX>... its diversified
Internet development and marketing business."

            
               Answers
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-A, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-B, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3-C, 4-D,</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6-F</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Extra Credit
            

            Compare and contrast the
accelerated boom and flack of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life with the pressures of
changed society on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Illustrate. With photographs. Of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cocaine-snorting</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
