
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Decline and Fall&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               
                  "That was a
miserable year, when I watched a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I love more than life--you
know, one of the really fundamentally solid, decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--go from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">92 to 38</TIMEX> in
a very quick period of time." Who watched whom go from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92 to 38</NUMEX>
what?
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">302</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's Back":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 
                                    "It's back, and we
used it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. But they don't want us to use it too much. It's not going
to be a big deal." Who said this about
what?
                                 
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Permanente</ENAMEX> talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>'s heart-lung
machine."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Greenberg</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military on ethnic cleansing."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenton A. Hoover</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>; speaking about use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Force</ENAMEX> to combat oddball religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissenters</ENAMEX> who have it coming."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thomas</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
promotion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>'s music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>; about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Lopez</ENAMEX>'s
butt."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            "It
was the caption for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Circus</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolly</ENAMEX> is showing
Jeffy the family crack <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Meyerson</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            The most popular response (the one all the cool
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are writing) plays with the "malathion" (yeah, right) the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is spraying
throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to kill "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">mosquitoes"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wink</ENAMEX>, wink) that transmit
"encephalitis" (go on: pull the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>). It makes one nostalgic for the fear
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSD</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and saltpeter in the cafeteria
food, presumably to create a docile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of human slaves with excellent
teeth who keep hallucinating that they're uninterested in sex.

            There is a difference between canny skepticism and
dumbbell skepticism. The latter is unearned and knee-jerk: "They're all a bunch
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooks</ENAMEX>." It's a form of self-aggrandizement whose effect is to make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptic</ENAMEX> feel knowing. The former is informed and terrifying: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was
willing to let <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get slaughtered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>." Its
effect is to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptic</ENAMEX> want to throw himself out of a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> -floor window.

            Of course, there really
is <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> really did test hallucinogens on
unknowing human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, and sexual vitality can be diminished by watching
television. At least in prime time.

            
               Help

               Me off the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field and Into the Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Jets</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Parcells</ENAMEX> said this about
the use of instant replay to challenge an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>'s call, a rule change
instituted for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Football League</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season that began Sunday</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>' preseason pick to make it to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>, lost their season opener and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> starters
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vinny Testaverde</ENAMEX>, out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> with a ruptured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Achilles</ENAMEX>' tendon.

            This concludes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Quiz coverage of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>. Next up: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASCAR</ENAMEX> reaches out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yet More News Quizzes Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Adding reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> (as suggested by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite</ENAMEX>) leads to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brisbane Airport</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>
quiz.

            Sample: What is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> busiest domestic air
route in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> currently?

            (Probably not the one
into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dili</ENAMEX>. Because that wouldn't be domestic. Right?-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> .)

            
               Sick

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> Follow-Up
            

            "We trout fisherman consider this an extremely
threatening situation that you make light of, especially since it is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado DFG</ENAMEX> that is largely responsible for the proliferation of the disease.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado DFG</ENAMEX> decided to go ahead and stock thousands
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> that it knew had been exposed to the disease; wouldn't you know it,
the disease soon showed up in wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Now
they're gonna spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 million</NUMEX> to study it. Go figure."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
Hellerman
            

            "Oh, fine, it's OK to slander the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> in the name
of a quick laugh, but there is a whirling disease in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX>. The poor little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> just swim around and around in a circle until they die. And it's all our
fault for genetically engineering them and raising them by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hatcheries</ENAMEX>."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Kate Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            (My apologies to any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">afflicted fish</ENAMEX> I may have offended, and to those who love to kill
them.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> .)

            

               Clarification
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> will
disclose all campaign contributions on his Web site; he will not let major
contributors post saucy photographs of themselves on a page called the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bare-Ass Eagle Club</ENAMEX>."

            
               Common

               Denominator
            

            Skepticism about just what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> is
spraying for, praying for, howling at the moon and baying for. (Look for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz Music</ENAMEX> , a hot new CD in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Christmas</TIMEX>, if the man
doesn't stop us.)

         
      
   
