
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=120490521-01071999><SPAN class=630250921-01071999>Don't Ask, Don't Tell, Don't Continue</SPAN></SPAN>

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> ,
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s
less-than-overwhelming straw poll victory makes the primaries competitive.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s third-place finish demonstrates she can compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> as the moderate alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. (For 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Ames</ENAMEX>
debriefing, click here .) ... A book review calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s "don't
ask, don't tell" policy an abysmal failure. In practice, commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> do
ask and vigorously root out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> have been put under oath
and forced to describe their sexual propensities; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 5,000</NUMEX> have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discharged</ENAMEX>. ... "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRB</ENAMEX> " <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extrapolates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>'s presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> from
his political manifesto, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulworth</ENAMEX> . That "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">108-minute-long</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">affront</ENAMEX> to
black dignity" portends a demagogic campaign that blames corporate interests
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s real and imagined ills. (
                  Slate
               's "" bets against a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> candidacy.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21</TIMEX>
            

            A
piece predicts that brick-and-mortar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will
beat pure Web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> in the battle for e-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Although Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have lower start-up costs, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>-space <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>,
established distribution systems, and the ability to cross-market through their
retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. ... The cover editorial warns that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> economic
recovery is precarious. Real recovery depends on regional political stability,
the continued strength of the export-absorbing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
ability to bounce back from its slump. ... An article cautions against underestimating the
possibility of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is
reluctant to anger the West, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s rejection of a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>" policy makes
any diplomatic settlement difficult.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and Fall Fashion Supplement</ENAMEX>
            

            The
cover package worries about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> story says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, bombarded with
images of unattainable male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, have more body image problems than ever.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I. Joe</ENAMEX> has got buffer, so have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvin Klein</ENAMEX> models.) The "culture of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cruelty</ENAMEX>" in junior high can make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> "pathologically preoccupied" with
body image. More adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are getting liposuction. ... The other cover
story describes the survival strategies of high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outcasts</ENAMEX>, who seek
solace in computer games, camaraderie, and the occasional joint.. ... A
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. Smith</ENAMEX> touts her as the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>. The former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX> has
parlayed her restaurant successes into a lifestyle TV show and a forthcoming
magazine. She has a much more relaxed style than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mistress Martha</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> is an
icon of the new black upper-middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of her audience
is white. ... The surprisingly delightful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fall Fashion Supplement</ENAMEX> is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of blithe self-parody and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> games. There is a fashion-centric
crossword puzzle, a color-by-numbers dress, a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad Libs</ENAMEX> column, and a cutout
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Paltrow</ENAMEX> doll, among other amusements.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1999</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story argues that stocks are massively undervalued. Bullish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are
not irrationally exuberant; they recognize that stock prices have been
depressed by an excessive aversion to risk. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' valuation
theory, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> should be heading toward <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,000</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Glassman</ENAMEX>
expounded this theory <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in . disputed it.) ... A piece
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lavishes</ENAMEX> praise on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waldorf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Established by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> place imagination at the center of the learning process and emphasize
art projects, oral presentations, poetry recitations, and discussion. Graduates
are capable and inquisitive. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waldorf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX> worldwide.
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23</TIMEX>
            

            A
special issue on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> includes a rare editorial declaring war on "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> common link in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of
violence: firearms." All assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> should be banned, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>
licensed, and all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> registered. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's crusade follows a
Time essay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> calling for a handgun ban.) ... A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               poll finds that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> support registering
all handgun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">93 percent</NUMEX> favor a mandatory waiting period for gun
purchases. ... A piece explores the backroom battle between the gun industry
and the gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>. The industry wants to make concessions, but the NRA
threatens the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> with boycotts if they give <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23, 1999</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story reports on new discoveries about human evolution.
We started walking on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between 6 million and 4 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>,
tool-making began <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, and our brains grew dramatically
between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 million and 1 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. Abstract thought began only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. Our technological improvements have dramatically slowed
natural selection. ... A piece surveys new school safety precautions,
including mass-shooting drills, locker searches, and security cameras.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23 and 30</TIMEX>
            

            The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adventure</ENAMEX>" issue meditates on human limitations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>, and courage. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent camps</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>, braving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>, ducking cops, and
talking to raccoons. ... An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> recounts how he abandoned a plan to
sail solo to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> in order to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> his dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s gracious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX> of death is a braver act than any macho journey could be. ...
A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne Cox</ENAMEX> describes how the solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swimmer conquered</ENAMEX> fear by braving
icy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX>-infested waters. She traversed seemingly unconquerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bering Strait</ENAMEX>, to demonstrate the potential for harmony
between hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover
story calls for censorship of movies, television, and music. The mass
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>'s "moral pollution" is "actual and malignant." Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forefathers</ENAMEX> didn't
have sex and violence in mind when they crafted <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> freedoms. The
choice is censorship or barbarism. ... A series of commentaries rejects the censorship proposal, arguing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do not want to be regulated by institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>. Government
should discourage images of sex and violence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> by holding
congressional hearings that demonize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. ... An article argues
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should provide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> with new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and military
advice in order to deter <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> expansionism.

         
      
   
