
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnival of Carnage</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are we shooting?</ENAMEX>" calls a boyish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Wahlberg</ENAMEX>) to distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> at the start of Three 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kings</ENAMEX> .
He stands in a flat, whitish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> desert dotted with mounds. On top of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,
far away, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> waves a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> and some kind of cloth. Is he taunting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>? Appealing to him? Is he surrendering or on the verge of opening fire?
Hard to tell: The light is too glaring; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s frantic gestures too alien. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> has informed us that it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, that the cease-fire with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has just
become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. "Are we still shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or what?" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> calls
again. In the absence of a clear answer--of a clear anything--he raises his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rifle</ENAMEX> and shoots. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> as he's hemorrhaging, a look of
wonder in his dying eyes. "You shot yourself a raghead!" whoops <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who fired--identified by an on-screen title as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army Sgt. Troy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barlow</ENAMEX>--recoils from his handiwork. The war is over and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barlow</ENAMEX> has just killed
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            That scene is like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mini Beckett</ENAMEX> farce with a cruel jet of gore for a punch line. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barlow</ENAMEX> is
shooting at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he doesn't know and can barely see for reasons that are
never apparent in a place that's as foreign as the surface of the moon. All
that's finally real is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. From this brilliant overture, it's obvious
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David O. Russell</ENAMEX>, wants to break down your defenses
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>'s violent imagery: He's juxtaposing farce and atrocity in ways
that few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> have dared. And he's not stinting on the carnage,
either. The movie's most talked-about close-up shows the track of a bullet as
it enters a body, plowing its way through tissue and into a liver, which
releases blackish bile. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reportedly, Russell</ENAMEX> had bullets fired into a cadaver.)
No wound, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> is saying (screaming, in effect), should ever be taken
for granted.

            It helps that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> is fueled by genuine outrage at that
most jumbled and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>'s length of wars: the one that pretended to be about the
"liberation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>"; the one that ended up (once the oil wells
were recaptured) rebounding on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqis</ENAMEX> who'd been convinced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to
take up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. As the protagonist, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Forces</ENAMEX> Capt.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie Gates</ENAMEX> (a hard, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brooding</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX>) declares in his first scene, "I
don't even know what we did here." Cynical and disgusted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> gets
wind (so to speak) of a wild discovery: a map lodged in the rear end of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> that shows what appear to be bunkers holding loot plundered from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>. Announcing that he has no moral problem stealing from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> has stolen from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheiks</ENAMEX>, he joins with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barlow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barlow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> Vig
(skinny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Jonze</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the upcoming Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX> ), a game but witless redneck, and the resourceful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cube</ENAMEX>) in search of the motherlode. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> worth of gold bullion,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> says, can be loaded into their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humvee</ENAMEX> without firing a shot, and they'll
be back at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> before lunch.

            At this juncture,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> seems poised to turn into a relatively straightforward genre
piece--a perverse "caper" movie with a touch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gunga Din</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>). But
the surreal setting hints at dissonances, disturbing incongruities. The white
light scorches every surface--it seems to be eating into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Details of the
natural world are bleached out, but artificial colors--such as the pink and
green footballs the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> pack with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> and lob from their speeding
vehicle for sport--leap out of the screen like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">radioactive Christmas baubles</TIMEX>.
The action comes in jarring spasms. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> is blown up during an exercise, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are showered with bloody chunks of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>--a harbinger of the
insane slaughter to come. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> is supposed to be stashed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think they're being liberated
and rejoice, pushing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX>." They can't
understand why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> aren't chasing away <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX>, in light of the cease-fire, has shifted from fighting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-led
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX> to ruthlessly suppressing all signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> rebellion.

            The weird juxtapositions in these scenes are the movie's
soul. Inside a bunker, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> uses a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NordicTrack</ENAMEX> in front of a television
just down the corridor from a torture chamber. Piles of cell phones,
Cuisinarts, blue jeans, and gold watches sit side by side with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass
destruction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX> on a truck that's heading for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, riddling its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> with bullets. When it skids into a building
and overturns it doesn't explode: Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> are full of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> for the starving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have gone beyond the computer simulations and the TV
cameras. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> has said, they've "fallen down a rabbit hole" into a place
where nothing makes sense. It's the same twilight <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zone</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>
attempted to capture in Saving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> , set
in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, ultimately lacked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> ' sense of moral
chaos.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Kings</ENAMEX> lacks
something, too, but only because its imagery is so ferociously original that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> can't quite find a structure worthy of it. All at once, the movie
becomes a "conversion" melodrama--the kind in which an amoral, Bogartish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protagonist</ENAMEX> is unable to ignore injustice and so throws in his lot with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oppressed</ENAMEX>. It's a winning formula, but a formula all the same. Whereas the
opening manages to be shocking and ironic at once, the picture's turning point
is crudely manipulative. (Don't read this if you want to be surprised--but I do
recommend you read this, because it's not a good surprise.) A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
leaves her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and howls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to free her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>; a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soldier</ENAMEX> pulls her away, holds a gun to her head and then, in full view of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, blows her brains out; and the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> throws herself on
top of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> shrieking, "Yuma! Yuma!" while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s blood gushes into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>. This shocking act recalls the climax of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Peckinpah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wild</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunch</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>), in which a prisoner is executed with similar defiance, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> builds to the same wordless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> among the protagonists: Those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manly</ENAMEX> looks that say, "We're outnumbered and outgunned. We could leave now with
our money. But if we do, we'll never be able to live as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> again." But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wild Bunch</ENAMEX> was morally compromised: He'd shot people
himself for no good reason. And he didn't have a wide-eyed little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> bearing
witness to his murder.

            No doubt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> would justify the starkness of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>'s killing by saying you can't make a movie about the obscenity of
violence without showing something so obscene that it scalds us. I don't
quarrel with his intentions. But after that sequence, a part of me shut down.
Where do you go from something like that? To more horrible killings? To more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">absurdist</ENAMEX> comedy? The climax--in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and the others decide to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horde</ENAMEX> of noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iraqis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the elderly) to the border and are
predictably converged upon by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, unfriendly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Dunn</ENAMEX>)--isn't bad; it just feels cheap compared to what has
preceded it. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX> calls the genre structure a
pretext for a "surreal essay" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, and he might be right. And it's
also true that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> would never have spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX>
on a film that didn't have a conventionally rabble-rousing outline and an
upbeat finish. But I think those conventions diminish the movie. If I'm holding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> to the highest standards imaginable, it's only because his vision is
that powerful.

            It's also possible that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> is too sadistic by temperament to make a fully convincing anti-war
film. He's out to blast us. He wants to punish the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>--for their ignorance. At the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, a study showed that
a majority of heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who watched <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven hours a day</TIMEX>) who
supported the action believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> was a democracy, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
here are portrayed in a similar state of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gung-ho naiveté</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the film's
most outlandish (and effective) scenes is the torture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barlow</ENAMEX> by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saïd Taghmaoui</ENAMEX>) who wants to "educate" him. The session begins with a
bizarre dialogue about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>--an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> who in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>'s view was driven by bigotry to whiten his face and
straighten his hair--and winds up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> pouring oil down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barlow</ENAMEX>'s
throat in a brutal effort to drive home the war's real aim.

            We hate and fear the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>, but when he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barlow</ENAMEX> that
he lost his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> cuts to a shot of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in its crib as the ceiling caves in. When he asks how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barlow</ENAMEX> would feel
if his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> were similarly killed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> cuts to a shot of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> as the walls explode around them. The connections among enemy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> have rarely been made so palpable--or jocular. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> trying
to escape from the smoke-filled bunker with a huge pile of blue jeans isn't so
different from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> lugging bullion in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Vuitton</ENAMEX> bags. And both
sides share a reverence for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infiniti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convertibles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolexes</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kings</ENAMEX> is not the first anti-war movie in which opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> have
recognized themselves in one another before pulling the trigger, but it might
be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to make the point in a way that has nothing to do with liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">humanism</ENAMEX>. The movie takes the view of a mordant social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who recognizes
that consumerism has become the true world religion.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> films, Spanking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monkey</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flirting With Disaster</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), were much smaller
in scale, but both were products of the same angry sensibility. In the latter,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> used farce not to lighten the drama but to darken it, so that the
slapstick debacles seemed to spring from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>'s roiling unconscious. In
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> , those debacles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> from the blind desires of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX>--from the collective unconscious. A war movie that opens the
instant the war has ended, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> is among the most pitiless
autopsies ever filmed.

         
      
   
