
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Word</ENAMEX>

            The book is done.

            How long I've waited to write these words. It was a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade ago this summer</TIMEX> that I began my biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>--or rather,
signed a contract with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> declaring my intent to write it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> I
turned in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX> pages of manuscript to my beleaguered copy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avery</ENAMEX>, a kindly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">white-haired woman</ENAMEX> with a handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> face and
reserves of patience that run deep.

            From the beginning, the issue of duration loomed.
When my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> asked me how long I thought it would take to write the book--he
was negotiating the delivery date--I answered cheerfully, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten years</TIMEX>."

            "You can't say that," he informed me. "No one will
sign up a book that's going to take that long."

            "Why not?" I trotted out
the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographies</ENAMEX> known to every practitioner of the trade--biography
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lore</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Edel</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> labor on his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX> ("How long,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon</ENAMEX>, how long?" a reviewer in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Literary Supplement</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">importuned</ENAMEX> after the appearance of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> volume); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ellmann</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-year</TIMEX>
labor on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX>. And to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Milford</ENAMEX>'s biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edna St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Millay</ENAMEX> is long-awaited would be--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> himself might have
said--putting too fine a point on it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milford</ENAMEX> is already well into her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> on the project, with no end in sight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> has been at work
on a biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flannery O'Connor</ENAMEX> since I was in college, and I graduated in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Dabney</ENAMEX> signed up to write the biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Wilson</ENAMEX> that I
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jettisoned</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX>, and there's no trace of it. Some of my best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX>, and they've been in no hurry to deliver: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Strouse</ENAMEX>
devoted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P. Morgan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Thurman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colette</ENAMEX> is
forthcoming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>, finishing his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, is considered a model of punctiliousness. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decade</ENAMEX>'s nothing.

            Still, the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> may be permitted to wonder: Why
is biography such a protracted affair? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novelists</ENAMEX> seem able to turn out a book
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year or two</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historians</ENAMEX>, as burdened by footnotes and data as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographers</ENAMEX>, seldom devote more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> to a book. What's our problem?
Is it some congenital defect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX>? A laziness or dilatory habit of
mind? My guess is that our failure of promptitude has to do with the unique
relationship we establish with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, dead or living. Unlike the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelist</ENAMEX>, who invents (supposedly) his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, who
grapples with a populous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, the biographer enters into a curious intimacy
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> being written about, a relationship charged with ambivalence,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resentment</ENAMEX>, love, dependency, and all the myriad other emotions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in
whenever we allow ourselves to become intimate with another. That the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographer</ENAMEX> doesn't actually live with, or in many instances even know, his
subject; that the relationship may be involuntary (an unauthorized biography);
that it's by its very nature unequal, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> focusing attention on another
with no hope of reciprocity, in no way diminishes the intensity of the
experience. As any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> will tell you, the act of writing a biography is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">all-consuming</ENAMEX>. The abject acknowledgments pages tell the tale: "To my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, who
endured my obsession with grace ..." "To my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, who grew up hearing about
X at the dinner table ..." It's a wonder we don't all end up living alone in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boardinghouses</ENAMEX>.

            In my case, the equation
was infinitely more complicated than I could have fathomed when I embarked on
my biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellow</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1989</TIMEX>. It was in many ways an almost
inevitable project for me: I am from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX>'s turf; my first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biography</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delmore Schwartz</ENAMEX>, had closely paralleled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humboldt's Gift</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX>'s novel about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>; I was steeped in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> world he
wrote about. My subject, wary by nature, had, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of elaborate
equivocation, arrived at the point where he would grant me access to his
papers--subject to his approval--and consent to be interviewed from time to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. I didn't want him to authorize the book; I wanted my freedom. And for his
part, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX> maintained that he "wasn't finished yet, wasn't ready to be summed
up"--a reasonable stand for a robust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 74 th year</TIMEX>. In the
end, the book was, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX> took to describing it, "neither authorized nor
unauthorized."

            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>, I made my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>'s rounds, like
the postman deterred neither by sleet nor snow--nor by occasional emanations of
reticence or frostiness from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX>--from the routine (often a fascinating
routine) of poring over his unpublished manuscripts in the rare book and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manuscript</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago Library</ENAMEX>; lugging my laptop all
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in quest of high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>
of my famously peripatetic subject; driving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> rental <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> into the remotest
suburbs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and flying into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, in pursuit of letters in
private hands. Biography is no vocation for old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>; it requires physical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stamina</ENAMEX>. By the time I'd filled up my cupboard with the building materials for
my book, I was, to borrow one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellow</ENAMEX>'s favorite words, bushed.

            Then there was the labor
of composition, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX> of struggling to assemble these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> into
a coherent narrative form without getting bogged down by the facts--the
downfall of so many of the bloated biographies that now weigh down the shelves
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> for their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-week window</TIMEX> before being shipped back to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of nine years</TIMEX>, I'd "written through" to the end,
amassing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX> pages of typescript. Even my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who might as well have been
reading the story of his own life, so closely did he identify with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellow</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> origins, complained that the book was too long.

            The trouble is that you've gone through so much pain to
collect the damned junior-high-school transcript or the quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellow</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> that you feel you have to put it in--just to get
credit. Only after you have a completed manuscript does your confidence build
to the point where you can go through the top-heavy pile of pages and,
encountering the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX>'s occasional book reviews for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , decide: Who cares? and slash it with the red
pen. On my second go-round I cut <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> pages, dipping below the laminated Page
1,000 I'd presented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katy Medina</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>, as
evidence of my progress. (Did she smile, or was that a wince?) On the third
pass, recalling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proust</ENAMEX>'s admonition to one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> that if he'd
only had time he would have written a shorter letter, I managed to cut another
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> pages.

            At last it was clear that
I had to give up my decadal work-in-progress. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient publisher</ENAMEX> was weary of
waiting; my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were beginning to taunt me with the prospect that I'd never
finish; I was ready, as the self-help literature counsels, to "move on." The
cover had been designed, the catalog copy written. I was still revising the
copy-edited manuscript, tearing the whole thing up, finding, at the last
possible moment, my voice. And how to end it? At last I found a way (since,
happily and thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX>'s physical vigor, I wouldn't have to write a
deathbed scene): a conversation he'd had with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> documentary
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellow</ENAMEX>'s life. He was ruminating about death, and about possibly meeting up
again with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> in the next world. I thought of ending
the book with his quote, but then some other stuff happened in his life (you'll
have to buy the book--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24.95</NUMEX> at your local bookstore, arriving in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>--or at
least read the reviews to find out what). And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX>, too, is putting the
finishing touches on a novel titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ravelstein</ENAMEX> , about his late friend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Bloom</ENAMEX>, so I had to mention that.

            After turning in the manuscript <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, I spent the
weekend revising the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> I wrote the last
sentence on the last page: "His reunion with the dead would have to wait." Then
I dropped off the last pages at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> and rushed off to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn Station</ENAMEX> to
catch the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>, an hour from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            Depleted and drained, I stared out at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>
River in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer dusk</TIMEX>, drank <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> miniature bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zinfandel</ENAMEX>, and fell
asleep. My reunion with the living would have to wait.

         
      
   
