
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Weddings</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama Senate</ENAMEX> voted to repeal the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s constitutional prohibition against interracial marriage, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32 years</TIMEX> after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> struck down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s similar ban. Hadn't these archaic laws
gone out with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull Connor</ENAMEX>? I asked myself as I read the news account. And
haven't we been hearing that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has rediscovered the melting pot, that in
another generation or two we'll all be "cablinasian," like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX>?

            I talked to the
measure's main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>, state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin Holmes</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year</TIMEX> statehouse veteran
who has been trying to overturn the ban for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. "The last time I tried was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX>. "It didn't get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX>
credits his success to the last election, in which a bevy of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> were
swept into office.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX> wasn't just tidying up the legal code. In parts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural Alabama</ENAMEX>, he said, probate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> still refuse to issue marriage licenses
to interracial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX> explained that some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>
opposed his measure because they willfully refused to accept that the federal
government had the power to override state law--an ideology of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' rights
that goes way beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Calhoun</ENAMEX>.

            When you think about it,
it makes sense that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabamians</ENAMEX> found it hard to jettison overnight a
300-year-old custom. Laws against interracial marriage--and the taboos against
black-white sex that they codify--have been the central <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> in the
oppression of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> since the dawn of slavery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> charged him in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1864</TIMEX> presidential campaign with
promoting the mongrelization of the races (that's where the coinage
"miscegenation," which now sounds racist, comes from). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Enemies</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -century</TIMEX> civil rights movement predicted that the repeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
Crow laws would, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> put it, "open the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> doors
of our white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>." Fears of black sexuality have been
responsible for some of the most notorious incidents of anti-black violence and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persecution</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scottsboro Boys to Emmett Till</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Intermarriage</ENAMEX> bans arose in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1600s</TIMEX>, when tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> needed to shore up their new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of slavery. In
previous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, before slavery took hold, interracial sex was more prevalent
than at any other time in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> and black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX> lived and
worked side by side and naturally became intimate. Even interracial marriage,
though uncommon, was allowed. But as race slavery replaced servitude as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>'s labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, interracial sex threatened to blur the distinctions
between white and black--and thus between free and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> began
categorizing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> as free or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> according to the mother's status (which
was easier to determine than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s), and so in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1691</TIMEX> the assembly passed
a law to make sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> didn't bear mixed-race <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The law banned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, [and] their unlawfull accompanying with one another." Since the society
was heavily male, the prohibition on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> between white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and nonwhite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> also lessened the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s competition for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>. (In contrast, sex
between male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave owners</ENAMEX> and their female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">slaves</ENAMEX>--which often meant rape--was
common. It typically met with light punishment, if any at all.)

            If fears of interracial
sex underlay bans on interracial marriage, it was marriage that became the
greater threat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> might rape black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or keep them as concubines, but to
marry them would confer legal equality. Thus, over the course of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th century</TIMEX> all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--and many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern</ENAMEX> ones--outlawed
all marriages between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. Up through the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1780</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1843</TIMEX>--hotbeds of abolitionist
activity--repealed their bans.

            The end of slavery should have made things better. It
didn't. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> initially forced the removal of
the bans in several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. But when federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> pulled out, the bans
returned, along with a whole complex of new discriminatory laws known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Crow</ENAMEX>. In the West, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> passed new laws against interracial marriage, many
of them targeting white-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> along with white-black ones. Only in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> did laws against intermarriage draw real fire, coming off the books in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>.

            Still, even in the most
enlightened areas, mixed-race <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> faced enormous social stigma. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Clerks</ENAMEX>
refused to issue marriage licenses to mixed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> often
wouldn't marry them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Couples</ENAMEX> that did marry faced harassment from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gunnar Myrdal</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An American Dilemma</ENAMEX> , noted that
"even a liberal-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Northerner</ENAMEX> of cosmopolitan culture will, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> cases
out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>, express a definite feeling against" interracial marriage. It was,
he said, a "consecrated taboo" that "fixed" the boundary between the races.

            That changed slowly with the civil right movement, which
reshaped the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s consciousness. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, an interracial married couple
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mildred Loving</ENAMEX> brought to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> a suit against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, claiming the right to live there. The court sided with them
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unanimously</ENAMEX>, decreeing the ban unconstitutional under the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
Amendment. The fortuitously named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loving</ENAMEX> decision took its place in law
books, but not necessarily in practice. Where no one had the wherewithal to
stand up for it--say, in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loving</ENAMEX> was flouted.

            Precisely as white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">racists</ENAMEX> feared, desegregation
encouraged interracial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> began to meet and date,
especially on college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>, which started admitting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> in
larger numbers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>. The next generation saw a surge in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intermarriage</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.7 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> married someone of another race.
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> had reached <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.1 percent</NUMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> census recorded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51,000</NUMEX>
black-white marriages. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 300,000</NUMEX>. Attitudes changed
too. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> of white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> approved of interracial marriages.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, it was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX>. And younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> are vastly more tolerant
than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX>, suggesting these numbers will climb.

            Of course, it's hard not to also see the glass as
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>--or, more precisely, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent</NUMEX>--empty. All these numbers may be climbing,
but they remain low. What's more, the white-black marriage rate lags
significantly behind rates of white intermarriage with other, nonblack races.
Among <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25- to 34-year-olds</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> married outside their race, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 6 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> did so. The
racism that kept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>'s constitution unchanged has hardly been eradicated.
Whether these habits will change on their own, with the maturation of a more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tolerant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, or whether full social acceptance of black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will
require a concerted governmental effort, is unknowable. In the meantime, we can
take only meager pride in achieving a society in which interracial marriage is
safe, legal and, alas, rare.

         
      
   
