
   
   
      
         
            Greenspin

            From
time to time, a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> arises among us, teaching wisdom and virtue. Awed by
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>, the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of his day embrace his legacy, distort his
words, and persecute their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> in his name. Such is the fate of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prophet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, he testified before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in the midst of a partisan fight over a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan to cut <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 billion</NUMEX> in taxes over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
solicited his denunciation of the plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> sought his condemnation of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alternative</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> tried to preach higher principles, but
both sides twisted his answers to suit their purposes. Their fight for his
favor revolves around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> questions.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. What's the comparison? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> testified that debt
payment is the best use of the surplus, tax cuts are the next best, and
spending hikes are the worst. While opposing a big tax cut, he stipulated, "If
I became concerned that the surplus is going to be employed for increased
spending programs, [then] I would be strongly in favor of tax cuts now. I think
it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> best alternative." In short, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> supports a tax
cut depends on which alternative it's compared to.

            To
make the tax cut look bad, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> compare it to debt payment. At the
hearing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John LaFalce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> whether he opposed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan. "My first priority, if I were given such a priority, is to let
the surpluses run," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> replied. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFalce</ENAMEX> tried to quit while he was
ahead, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> insisted on adding, "My <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> priority is, if you find
that as a consequence of those surpluses, they tend to be spent, then I would
be far more in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> of cutting taxes, because the least desirable [outcome]
is using those surpluses for expanding outlays." In their post-hearing spin,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> ignored this caveat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Sherman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, asserted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> had "attacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Durbin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>,
suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s analysis made clear that a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 billion</NUMEX> tax cut was
just as "dangerous" as an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 billion</NUMEX> tax cut.

            
Conversely, to make the tax cut look good, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> compare it to spending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hikes</ENAMEX>. "My understanding from all you've said here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Castle</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Del.</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> at the hearing, "is that you believe that debt
retirement is probably the best thing we could do. And if not that, perhaps
some sort of a tax cut. But probably the thing that could really get us in
trouble in an economic sense from your perspective is to spend it all." In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-hearing TV</ENAMEX> appearances, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Budget Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Domenici</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.M.</ENAMEX>, argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s
essential message was to "be sure you do not increase government spending."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan debt payment or spending? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alternative plan would reserve <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 45 percent</NUMEX> of future surpluses
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> while setting aside <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 20 percent</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, defense, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, agriculture, medical research, and other
programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domenici</ENAMEX> call this "spending." "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is going to
spend every nickel" of the surplus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domenici</ENAMEX> protested, "so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>
would agree with us" that taxes should be cut instead. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is
buying down less debt, and increasing spending, and increasing taxes," added
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX>. "I'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> will applaud our effort relative to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s effort to buy down less debt and increase government programs."
Conversely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> spun <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan as debt payment. He claimed that when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> was asked whether he supported the tax cut, he said no. "The best
thing to do is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> plan: spend down [the] national debt, invest the
money in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Which excess would be harder to reverse? Since tax cuts and
spending erode the surplus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> is wary of both. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, seeking to
direct his ire against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan, emphasize the difficulty of reining
in tax cuts once they've been promised. At the hearing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Bentsen</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> about the "risks" of "having locked in a tax cut that
we then have to borrow more to pay for." Afterward, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> suggested that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> didn't want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to "get committed" to tax cuts. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, on
the other hand, emphasize the difficulty of reining in spending. "If you create
all those new programs, you'll never get that money back," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, argued, whereas if the money goes to tax cuts, "[y]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ou</ENAMEX> could get it
back by raising taxes."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Whose promise is less trustworthy? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> promise to
preserve the surplus for debt reduction by not spending it. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> promise
to preserve the surplus for debt reduction by cutting spending to keep pace
with their tax cuts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s remarks--that
taxes should be cut because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> can't be trusted to refrain from
spending the surplus--obscures the contrary possibility, i.e., that the tax cut
should be avoided because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> can't be trusted to make the necessary
spending cuts. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> neglected to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> about this possibility at
the hearing, but on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> put the
argument to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domenici</ENAMEX>: "Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would come back at you and say, 'Look, for
this surplus to be this large, you have to have a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> reduction in
programs, [which is] totally unrealistic.' "

            So
far, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' spin has prevailed, mostly because, as the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have ignored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s caveat that tax
cuts are preferable to more spending. Most reports say only that he opposed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan. None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' political stories or
editorials about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s testimony mentioned his qualified endorsement of
the tax cut. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> fed its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>'
comparison, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> said, "it is more important to pay down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> debt than cut taxes." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' only mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caveat</ENAMEX> was in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 th</NUMEX> paragraph of a story in the business section,
which dismissed the caveat and concluded that "effectively, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> was
siding with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>" and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan. A
Times editorial chided <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for "seeking Greenspanian ambiguity
where it did not exist."

            This
shallow reporting doesn't just bury the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> spin. It conceals a deeper
question about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> worship. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> made clear that
his recommendation against cutting taxes depends on a calculation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
won't spend the surplus. If that calculation is wrong, he would favor the tax
cut. And on what basis did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> make this calculation? His only answer was
that he "hoped" he wasn't mistaken.

            Not
only is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s answer scientifically baseless; his characterization of the
problem (whether the surpluses will "be spent") is superficial. The salient
questions, outlined above, are more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> and dynamic: whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
promises to refrain from spending the surplus are less trustworthy than
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> promises to match tax cuts with spending cuts, and which
hypothetical error--excessive spending or excessive tax cuts--would be harder
to reverse. How could an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s sophistication fumble such
important questions in such an unsophisticated manner? Because, like most
questions about how much money the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will raise and spend, they're not
economic. They're political. And instead of throwing these questions at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should be answering them itself.

            
               Photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slate Table of Contents</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamarque/Reuters</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
