
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">327</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Haider Go Seek</ENAMEX>"

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jörg Haider</ENAMEX> led his far-right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Party</ENAMEX> to a stunning second-place finish
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>'s national elections; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks from now</TIMEX>, he's coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. To
do what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 326</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scents and Sensibility":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  "This is a dream for me--to find the soft parts and touch them
and even smell them. It's very exciting." Who said this about what?

                  
                     (Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>.)
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
recently fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Authority</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Crawford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Akawie</ENAMEX> had
similar answers.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torre; Don Zimmer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Scheft</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Billionaire</ENAMEX> or no, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> loves mulch."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Mannella</ENAMEX>
            

            "My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandmother</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldbaum</ENAMEX>'s produce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>; about honeydew <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">melons</ENAMEX>, 'good
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>
            

            "All
my answers have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lorre</ENAMEX> accents."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            With so much news and so little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>, many
stories get neglected. However, it seemed important to provide the full text of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s speech on bolting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, for
reasons of space, I had to condense his remarks, adding nothing, just making a
few cuts and altering the punctuation to bring it into line with standard
usage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> speaks:

            "The junk <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">yards</NUMEX> of history are strewn with
wreckage. Dust!

            "Our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmer Gantry</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, whose
desecration of the temples of our civilization and personal misconduct are good
and generous, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> at the scene of natural disasters: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sir</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle</ENAMEX> is in
jeopardy.

            "To those who prattle I'm not running: I'm running.
All of us must learn our <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language. We can get pot doing its magic
again. We need a timeout.

            "This land is our land.
Pick up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX>. Insult a free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX>, the good manners are gone.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swagger</ENAMEX>! Homage to the great god mammon! This is our cause. And so it is, that
in the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Fathers</ENAMEX> we go forward to rescue our <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady America</ENAMEX>,
and will not quit this fight as long as there is breath within us."

            
               Huge, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hairy</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paleontologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Mol</ENAMEX> said it about a
nearly intact woolly mammoth recovered from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siberian</ENAMEX> permafrost last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> was directed to the site by
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> who found a tusk sticking up from the ground, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> wire service. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> dug up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, which had
partially thawed and decayed, then halted digging for fear of destroying their
find. Using ground-penetrating radar to locate the carcass, they broke up the
frozen soil with jackhammers. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> lifted the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">22-ton</NUMEX> block of frozen
dirt and flew it <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150 miles</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatanga</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexei Tikhonov</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zoological Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Petersburg</ENAMEX> denies that the mammoth can be cloned, because during its
"preservation in permafrost, dehydration destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. Now we
only have very small parts of the DNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>."

            The mammoth, dubbed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zharkov</ENAMEX> after the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who discovered its tusk, was a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9-foot-tall</NUMEX> adult
male, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 47 years old</TIMEX> at the time of death; it would have looked like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hairy elephant</ENAMEX> to the modern eye, much like ... oh, make up your own damn
joke.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. M. Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s new Early
Show <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">debuts</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, taking on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning America</ENAMEX> in the battle for moral suprema--sorry, for bigger profits
in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> television, much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Fathers</ENAMEX> anticipated when they
devised the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-network system. Competition, as we know, stimulates
creativity, so these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> shows no doubt offer diverse pleasures. Which of
these shows possesses the following qualities?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Studio with view of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Determinedly shallow news coverage.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Near-psychotic obsession with the weather.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Male and female co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> with eerie
resemblance to flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Inane celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> promoting current
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>, quack nostrums.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Tedious cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> include recipes for
human flesh.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Guests strip to waist and fight with bowie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knives</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Audience participation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Which Clam Is</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tainted?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Subliminal</ENAMEX> messages urge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> to pelt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX> with bottles.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Formerly hosted by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>.

            
               Answers
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 to 4</TIMEX> are true of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> programs.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 and 6</NUMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-truths, of which the true portion
applies to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> programs.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 to 9</TIMEX> are segment ideas none of the shows will
even consider, or even bother to return my calls to discuss. Uptight
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bastards</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> is true only of
Today , but it would be a big improvement on nearly any show or
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>.

            
               It Pays To Increase
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Word Power Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "We recognize the
importance of making the narrow-band end of the funnel as robust as possible
explicitly for the purpose of converting those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to broadband
eventually."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bell</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Excite@Home</ENAMEX>, explains why he's spending
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion dollars</NUMEX> to buy a greeting-card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, marketing prepackaged
sentiments for those unable to express themselves, until they can watch
television on their computers. Or something.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            As requested by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>, the tally is

            Sex Jokes: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>

            Death Jokes: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>

            Conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>--it's life-affirming. (In a
furtive sort of way.)

         
      
   
