
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lazy Man's Guide to Political Obsession</ENAMEX>

            As
recently as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, being a political obsessive was hard work: all those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">out-of-town</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and pricey newsletters to read, the gossipy
long-distance phone calls to other obsessives, the endless <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> spent combing
campaign finance filings at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C.</ENAMEX>

            But
thanks to the Web, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obsessive</ENAMEX> can gather more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX> poop in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour</TIMEX> than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX> could in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> not only give
their best stuff away, they collate their campaign archives for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, good-government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> feed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> data into
Web-friendly databases, making it a snap to track contributions. And political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> continue to fill the void with links to the sort of high-quality
information that was beyond the reach of even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nexis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jockeys</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>.

            
Because political information goes stale faster than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, the first
destination for obsessives should be a news site. I prefer the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaigns</ENAMEX> " portal page for its timeliness and simplicity. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>'s top stories are front and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, as they should be, and logical links
carry you to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Key Stories</ENAMEX> " archive. From here you
can connect to smartly done backgrounders on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and pieces on the
campaign's key races .

            
Finishing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> in the political news Web-stakes are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> '
"Campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> " portal page lets you submit quickie searches
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> by clicking their names. The site offers a helpful link to
the primary schedule , and multimedia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> will enjoy the
audio analysis by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s ace political obsessive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Brownstein</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> " portal links to overviews of the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> from a
map of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. It also hosts the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Points</ENAMEX> " page, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> links to the Web
sites of various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government branches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX>, political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. A most valuable page!

            See
Yahoo!'s "Presidential <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election 2000</TIMEX> " page for another superb
round-up of campaign news. Keeping with its strategy of being the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s great
aggregator, Yahoo! gathers breaking political news stories from a variety of
mainstream print <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as well as streaming audio/video from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>,
and other outlets. All self-promotion aside, you should get to know ","

                  Slate
               's campaign portal page, complete with a weekly political
cartoon by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Alan Stamaty</ENAMEX>. And, don't miss 
                  Slate
               's "," which
watches television's weekend political talk shows so you don't have to.

            
Perhaps more useful for their sociological content than their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> Web sites, which 
                  Slate
                (as well as other
sites) has collected and evaluated . The most annoying thing about the official
sites is they tell you only what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> want you to know. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skeleton Closet --"All the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dirt About All the Candidates"</ENAMEX>--shatters this reality distortion field. As
wicked as any opposition research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> page, this site collects the unsavory
and annotates it with links to relevant stories in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Prospect</ENAMEX> , and other reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>.
(Conducting a similar civics lesson on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is bushwatch.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            If
being there live is your idea of political obsession, visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>'s campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">portal</ENAMEX> . If being there on tape will do, see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> video archives
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> appearances, which can be searched by keyword here and
summoned to the screen. Still under construction is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>'s searchable
calendar of campaign events.

            The
biggest meta-issue of the campaign--money--receives ample attention on the Web.
The gargantuan databases at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Responsive Politics</ENAMEX> , and FECInfo
await your query about who gave what to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. Contributors to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> defense fund are also searchable.

            If you
want to put your money where your political mouth is, open an account at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Markets</ENAMEX> with real cash. 
                  Slate
                in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the
site's markets (the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX>, the battle
for control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> race in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>) several times a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. ( primer explains how the market works.)

            No
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obsessive</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> is complete without a visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Junkie</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> roundup of politics, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and political journalism links.
Want to register to vote? Looking for census/polling data? Need the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conason</ENAMEX>'s columns? The addresses of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>? Curious about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PACs</ENAMEX> or
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>? The state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>? Then roll up your sleeve,
tie your arm off with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> cord, slap your vein into view, and shoot this
site up. You're sure to overdose, but that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obsessive</ENAMEX>/compulsive thrill
you're looking for, right?

         
      
   
