
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX>'s Shootings

            

               
                  
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> approved the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> tax-cut
plan.
                  
                "It's a happy day for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beamed House Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rangel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are preparing to call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scrooge</ENAMEX> for vetoing this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>-in-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> package of tax cuts." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 
               condemns the bill as "misshapen," "unaffordable," and
"a further mortgage on an already overburdened future." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
comparing the negotiations to those over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> welfare bill, signaled that
he will accept a compromise plan.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died in an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> shooting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Eugene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> opened fire at his current and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workplaces</ENAMEX>. In "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>
says the killings were underplayed because they came too soon after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
massacre, which was bloodier and involved wealthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX> hit his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> home run. Before hitting
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">499</NUMEX>, he announced that he had quit the performance-enhancing drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">androstenedione</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX> prior. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX> lauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX>'s
decision. But a steroid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>, "I would have
preferred he said it at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the season</TIMEX>. ... That's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who took andro because of him ."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> was confirmed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>. His nomination had been held up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 months</TIMEX>, first on
ethics questions and then because of spats between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> gained little for their stonewalling, and the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> relays that the holdup made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> feel even more
snubbed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of Pediatrics</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to restrict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
television-watching. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> said to keep television away from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 2</TIMEX> and out of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shulevitz</ENAMEX> explains why television is an .

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX> was cleared of improperly helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. A
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> acted within the boundaries of election law when
it handed out <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-boosting voter guides. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
spun it as a setback for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Elections Commission</ENAMEX> and a possible boon
to special-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. An election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> asked, "If they can't get these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, how the heck are they going to go after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> or the business coalitions?" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> is faltering and was never as powerful as it
appeared.

            

               Arbitrators priced the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zapruder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s assassination at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 million</NUMEX>. The arbitration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> split over how much the federal
government should fork over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zapruder</ENAMEX> estate. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> compared it to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s desk and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da Vinci</ENAMEX>'s notebook. But the third
pointed out that the film is valuable mostly for its licensing rights, which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zapruders</ENAMEX> already own.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> discussed her marital problems. In Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>,
she attributed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s philandering to childhood abuse. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Daily News</ENAMEX> calls the revelations "remarkable ," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> says it's
psychological bunk . (
                  Slate
                decries the
excessive coverage in "," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>," and ".")

            
               A
disgruntled day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Barton</ENAMEX> bludgeoned
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to death, shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day</TIMEX> trading investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, and then committed suicide. He had previously been suspected in the
murder of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. This was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> shooting
spree in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>. "Pray for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>," urged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>. Explanations: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> tallies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s trading
losses; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Journal</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> points to the trend of
workplace violence ; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
blames loose gun laws .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was fined <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> for his false testimony in the Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Webber Wright</ENAMEX> called his perjury "a willful refusal
to obey this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s discovery orders." "We accept the judgment of the court
and will comply with it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> was indicted for illegally taping telephone conversations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> law prohibits recording phone calls without the
consent of both parties. Tripp protests that she made the tapes to protect
herself because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was pressuring her to lie in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> approves of the indictment in principle but says that
constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> should protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> from "a full-dress felony prosecution ."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is going after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX>. It introduced its own
version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s instant-messenger software and said it will offer similar
dial-up service for less or no money. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> noted that
similar tactics helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AOL</ENAMEX> countered that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> had already tried and failed to launch a proprietary online
service.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Chemical</ENAMEX> will buy rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Carbide</ENAMEX>. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> predicts the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX>, the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wrestling Federation</ENAMEX> is going public. "It's a collision of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the biggest pop cultural phenomena of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> ,
stock market mania and wrestlemania!" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> effused to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
