



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Approach - Building</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Energy Plan</ENAMEX> includes a number of conservation,
advanced research and development, and other efforts that will
reduce electricity usage. Reducing the amount of electricity we use
and the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> needed to produce it are part of the answers
to the challenge of providing energy in an environmentally
responsible way.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Energy Plan</ENAMEX> goes even further. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> me to develop proposed legislation that would
significantly reduce and cap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury emissions</ENAMEX> from
power generation. Such a program (with appropriate measures to
address local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>) would provide significant health benefits
even as we increase electricity supplies. The proposed legislation
will:


-
establish reduction targets for emissions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercury</ENAMEX>,


-
phase in reductions over a reasonable time period,
similar to the successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> Program established by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
amendments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> and to state programs,


-
provide regulatory certainty to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> to make
modifications to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> without fear of new litigation,
and


-
provide market-based incentives, such as emissions
trading, to help achieve the required reductions.


Nationwide reductions of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercury</ENAMEX>, in an integrated approach would result in key benefits
including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of avoided premature deaths and aggravation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">respiratory</ENAMEX> and cardiovascular <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> due to fine particles,
reduced hospitalization and emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> visits due to fine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">particles</ENAMEX> and continued exposure to ground-level ozone. It would
also address interstate transport issues as they relate to meeting
the new particulate matter and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> air quality standards.
Visibility improvement would be anticipated over large areas
including national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and wilderness areas and recovery of many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freshwater</ENAMEX> and coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ecosystems would be likely</ENAMEX>. Public health
risks associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX>, particularly those posed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> bearing age, may be reduced. This includes risks
of neurotoxic effects such as mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX>, cerebral palsy,
difficulty speaking and hearing others, and other learning
disabilities. Currently, current <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> plus <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have fish
advisories; that number would be reduced.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s approach builds on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Acid Rain Program</ENAMEX>, which
provides a wonderful model for future programs. It has not only met
expectations, but exceeded them. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Administering the Acid Rain</ENAMEX>
Program has been a cost-effective experience. The program will
achieve <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40%</NUMEX> of the total emission reductions required under
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1990 Clean Air Act Amendments</ENAMEX> at a low cost to industry and to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The program is administered with a relatively small
staff relying on strong and state-of-the-art data tracking and
reporting capabilities.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George H.W. Bush</ENAMEX> signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>
Amendments of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, it revolutionized clean air policy regarding
regional and national air pollution issues and drove environmental
protection in new directions. First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
designed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> Program to focus on reducing the SO2
emissions that cause acid deposition and translated the emission
reduction goal into a nationwide cap on emissions from electric
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">generating</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> provided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> with a tool to
achieve this reduction - - an innovative market-based allowance
trading program. This "cap and trade" approach provided greater
certainty that the emissions reductions would be achieved and
sustained while at the same time allowing industry unprecedented
flexibility in how to achieve the needed emission reductions. In
return for this flexibility, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> were to provide a full
accounting of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> through continuous monitoring and
reporting, and there would be consequences for failing to comply.
The objective was for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to find the most cost-effective means
for limiting SO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> and to be responsible for achieving
those emission reductions. There would be no government second
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guessing</ENAMEX> and lengthy permit reviews.
Compliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> Program began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and is now
in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> year. It has been a resounding success, with SO2
emissions from power generation dropping <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4.5 million tons</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
levels and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions down <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 million tons</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> levels
(<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 3 million tons</NUMEX> lower than projected growth). In addition,
during the first Phase of the program (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-1999</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions
were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 20 to 30 percent</NUMEX> below their allowable levels.
Furthermore, environmental monitoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> tracked important
environmental improvements - - acid deposition was reduced by up to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> in certain areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
And, these environmental improvements cost less than predicted
because of the built-in market based incentives. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
projected the cost of full implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions
reduction with trading at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.7 billion</NUMEX> per year (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1997 dollars</NUMEX>). In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> projected the cost at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.3 billion</NUMEX> per year (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
dollars). Recent estimates of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annualized</TIMEX> cost of compliance are in
the range of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 to $1.5 billion</NUMEX> per year at full
implementation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has not only promised to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the SO2</TIMEX> trading
program to the next level but he has experience to lend to the
matter. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> signed legislation that
permanently caps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2 emissions</ENAMEX> from older power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> and requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> to install a certain
quantity of renewable and clean energy capacity by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2009</TIMEX>.
Environmental Defense hailed this legislation as a model for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Emission Banking and Trading</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allowances Program</ENAMEX> is
expected to achieve substantial reductions when it is fully phased
in by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. It is estimated that this program will reduce NOx by
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">75,000 tons</NUMEX> per year and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35,000 tons</NUMEX> per year. It is
designed to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> flexibility in determining how and
where to achieve the reductions. Allowances are allocated to each
power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> emissions using a formula that does not
penalize the "clean" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that already have a low <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> or SO2
emission rate. Permitted power generating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> may opt into the
trading program.


II. Regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Emissions</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Generation</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s legislative approach stands in sharp contrast to
the complex web of existing regulations which currently confront
the industry. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> have
responded to specific environmental and public health problems by
developing separate regulatory programs for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> to address
the specific problems. Each individual program uses its own
approach to serve its own purpose. As I describe the different
regulatory programs, I think you will understand why we believe it
is time to simplify. If we have a new legislation that
significantly reduces emissions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX>, we can
eliminate many of the individual programs that apply to the power
generation sector and replace them with a system that will reduce
the administrative burden on industry and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, use
market-based incentives to keep compliance costs low, and provide
the industry with more certainty about its future regulatory
obligations.
There are many regulatory initiatives in place that will lead to
reductions in air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from electric power generation. These
regulations include both federal and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> requirements that
address a variety of emissions including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PM10</TIMEX>, and a
number of hazardous air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX>. The requirements also vary
depending on the characteristics of the generating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>,
including its boiler type, size, age and location. These programs
include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Ambient Air Quality Standards</ENAMEX> for particulate
matter and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 126</ENAMEX> and the NOx SIP Call rules, new
source review and new source performance standards, the regional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">haze</ENAMEX> rule and mercury regulation as a hazardous air pollutant,
among others.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has set national ambient air quality standards (NAAQS) for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon monoxide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>); particulate matter
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">NO2</TIMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pb</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> calls upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States</ENAMEX>
to adopt emissions control requirements in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Implementation Plans</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SIPs</ENAMEX>") to bring nonattainment areas into
compliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAAQS</ENAMEX>. Historically, most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' strategies to
attain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the SO2</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM NAAQS</ENAMEX> included power plant controls.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has taken two actions to address the contribution of
interstate transport of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions to downwind ozone
nonattainment problems, and both of these actions affect the power
sector. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> finalized the NOx SIP call, which now requires
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> (whose emissions
significantly contribute to downwind <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> nonattainment problems)
to revise their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIPs</ENAMEX> to control summertime <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions. In
response, all of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> are choosing control strategies that
focus on reducing power plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>. In a separate action aimed
at the same interstate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> transport problem, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
finalized a rule which was issued in response to petitions from
several northeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 126 of the CAA</ENAMEX>. In this
rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> found that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from large electric generating units
and large industrial boilers and turbines in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX> and the
District of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> are significantly contributing to downwind
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> nonattainment problems. The rule requires these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to control their summertime <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx Budget Trading Program</ENAMEX> beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1, 2003</TIMEX>.
The electric power generation sector is also regulated through a
variety of traditional and innovative programs. Consistent with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> have adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> reasonably available
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> technology requirements for combustion <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. In
addition, several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> have adopted market-based approaches. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Coast Air Quality Management District</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>,
for example, adopted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions trading program
(called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RECLAIM</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> and mid-Atlantic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> that
comprise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ozone Transport Region</ENAMEX> have developed a region-wide
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ozone Transport Commission</ENAMEX> NOx
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget Program</ENAMEX>). The revised <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone NAAQS</ENAMEX> and new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PM2.5 NAAQS</ENAMEX> could
lead to further regulation of power plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2 emissions</ENAMEX> (a
precursor to ambient <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PM2.5</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions (both for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PM2.5</ENAMEX> and
ozone attainment strategies).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> also requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Implementation Plans</ENAMEX> to include a
preconstruction permit program for new or modified major stationary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, referred to as new source review ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NSR</ENAMEX>"). This program
ensures that when large, new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are built -- or major
modifications to existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are made that result in a net
emissions increase -- they include state-of-the-art air pollution
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> equipment. It also assures <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> who live near new major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of air pollution that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> will be as clean as
possible. The requirements are different for (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the part of the
program called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention of Significant Deterioration</ENAMEX> program
that applies to construction projects in areas where the air is
already clean, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the part of the program called the
non-attainment NSR program that applies to construction projects in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> where the air is unhealthy to breathe. For attainment areas,
to prevent significant deterioration of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s air quality,
new major sources and major modifications to existing sources must
apply the best available control technology and ensure that the new
pollution introduced into the environment does not adversely impact
the air quality, such as in pristine areas like national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>. For
nonattainment areas, in addition to applying control technology
that represents the lowest achievable emission rates, new major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> and major modifications must offset their emissions
increases. This can be done by getting reductions from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in the general area to compensate for the increases
resulting from the new air pollution <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> also requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to establish new source performance
standards ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NSPS</ENAMEX>") that all new or modified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> must meet
regardless of their location. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSPS</ENAMEX> are technology-based
numerical performance standards that apply to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in a
particular source category, such as electric utility steam
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">generating</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> or stationary gas turbines. These standards are
intended to "level the playing field" so that all new facilities
install a minimum amount of air pollution control equipment.
The recently finalized regional haze rule will also require
power generators to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions either through the
implementation of best available retrofit technology (BART) or a
trading program yet to be developed. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> must show "reasonable
progress" in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> implementation plans toward the
congressionally mandated goal of returning to natural conditions in
national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and wilderness areas.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> is developing a rule to limit mercury <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">utilities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1990 CAA Amendments</ENAMEX> required <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to study and
prepare a report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on the hazards to human health that
can reasonably be expected to occur as a result of emissions of
hazardous air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> (air toxics or HAPs) from fossil
fuel-fired electric power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. Based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
and on other available information, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX> that
air toxics control is appropriate for coal-fired and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>-fired
utility boilers. As a result of that regulatory determination, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
is scheduled to propose "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Maximum Achievable Control Technology</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MACT</ENAMEX>) standards for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> categories by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. Given the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conclusions of the Report</ENAMEX>, the regulation is likely to focus on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions.
The utility industry is also required to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Acid Rain Trading</ENAMEX> Program described above. In addition,
to address <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> to
reduce their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> through emissions limits, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
established based on unit type.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>. Health and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Benefits</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s
Energy Plan
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Energy Plan</ENAMEX> recognizes that by conserving energy
and limiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury emissions</ENAMEX>, we can provide the
The problems we would address include: fine particle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX>,
visibility degradation, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone pollution</ENAMEX>, mercury deposition, acid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rain</ENAMEX>, nitrate deposition and climate change. In turn, this will
avoid incidences of premature mortality, aggravation of respiratory
and cardiopulmonary illnesses, and diminished lung function which
results in lost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">work days</TIMEX>, school absences and increased
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hospitalizations</ENAMEX> and emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> visits, and will also avoid
damage to eco-systems, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife</ENAMEX>. To understand the
tremendous benefits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s plan, we need to understand
the public health and environmental issues.


Emissions from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Generation</ENAMEX>
Power generators are a significant source of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> key
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SO2</NUMEX>), nitrogen oxide (NOx), and mercury
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> has been, and will continue to be, a
successful tool in reducing these emissions. However, while we are
observing significant environmental improvement, power generation
still contributes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37%</NUMEX> of man-made
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercury</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> has other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, such as carbon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monoxide</ENAMEX> and coarse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">particles</ENAMEX>, but the level of these emissions
poses smaller risks for public health and the environment.)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the reasons power generation accounts for such a large
share of these key <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> is that significant emissions
reductions have already been required from other sources. For
example, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> today is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 90%</NUMEX> cleaner than it was
before federal laws limiting emissions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and volatile
organic compounds - and they are subject to further reductions
starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, as are heavy duty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>. In contrast,
some older power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, built before certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> performance
standards were put into place, are still operating without modern
pollution control equipment for some emissions.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Quality Effects</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FINE PARTICLE POLLUTION</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Energy Plan</ENAMEX> will reduce fine particle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX>.
SO2 and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions from power generation react in the atmosphere
to form nitrates and sulfates, which are a substantial fraction of
fine particle (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PM2.5</NUMEX>) pollution. (Some PM2.5 comes from direct
emissions from a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.) A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> emitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and SO2
can cause <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">PM2.5 many miles</NUMEX> away. A substantial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of published
scientific literature recognizes a correlation between elevated
fine particulate matter and increased incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> and
premature mortality. The health impacts include aggravation of
chronic bronchitis, hospitalizations due to cardio-respiratory
symptoms, emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> visits due to aggravated asthma symptoms,
and acute respiratory symptoms. Based on these findings, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and
others estimate that attaining the fine particle standards would
avoid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to tens of thousands</NUMEX>, of premature deaths
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
The significant expansion in scientific research in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>
has enhanced our understanding of the effects of particles on
health. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> is summarizing all new information in the ongoing
review of the particulate matter standard in a "criteria document"
that will undergo extensive peer and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> review.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• VISIBILITY AND REGIONAL HAZE IMPACTS</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Energy Plan</ENAMEX> will improve visibility by reducing
SO2 and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sulfates</ENAMEX> and nitrates that form in the
atmosphere from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions are significant contributors
to visibility impairment in many national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and wilderness
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, as well as urban areas across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Sulfates are a
key factor in all areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, particularly in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>, where high humidity increases the light extinction efficiency
of sulfates. Sulfates are responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6080%</NUMEX> of total light
extinction in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>, based on data collected during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990</TIMEX>'s
in eastern national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acadia</ENAMEX>, Everglades, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Smoky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mountains</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shenandoah</ENAMEX>, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>.
In the West, sulfates account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 25-50%</NUMEX> of
visibility impairment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nitrates</ENAMEX> can play a larger role in
visibility problems in some portions of the West than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>.
For example, nitrates account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20-40%</NUMEX> of visibility impairment
in national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and wilderness areas in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>. In
many urban areas, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, and power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>
contribute to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> time "brown cloud" situations.

C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">OZONE</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Energy Plan</ENAMEX> will reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> by reducing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, a
key contributor to the formation of ground-level ozone. In the
presence of sunlight, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and volatile organic compounds react
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photochemically</ENAMEX> to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> can be transported long
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distances</ENAMEX> and contribute to ozone many <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of miles</NUMEX> from its
source. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 97 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live in areas that do not yet
meet the health-based <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-hour</TIMEX> ozone standard (based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997-1999</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>). The number would be even higher for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the new 8-hour</TIMEX> ozone
standard. Reducing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> levels will result in fewer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hospitalizations</ENAMEX>, emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> visits for asthmatics,
significantly fewer incidents of lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">inflamation</ENAMEX> for atrisk
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX>, and significantly fewer incidents of moderate to
severe respiratory symptoms in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
Not only will reducing ozone provide public health benefits, but
it will avoid damage to ecosystems and vegetation. Ozone causes
decreased agricultural and commercial forest yields, increased
mortality and reduced growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree seedlings</ENAMEX>, and increased plant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">susceptibility</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, pests, and environmental stresses (e.g.,
harsh weather). Since <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions result in formation of
ground-level ozone, reducing NOx <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> will reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> levels
and thus reduce the deleterious effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> on human health
and ecosystems.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Deposition Effects</ENAMEX>


C <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MERCURY</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Energy Plan</ENAMEX> will benefit public health by
reducing mercury air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> is highly toxic in small
quantities and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with diets with high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> are
at risk for adverse health effects. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> is a naturally
occurring element, but human activity mobilizes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> in the
environment, making it more bioavailable. After mercury is emitted
to the air, it can be transported through the atmosphere for days
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before being deposited into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> bodies.
Once <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> is deposited in lakes, rivers, and oceans, it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bioaccumulates</ENAMEX> in the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, resulting in high concentrations
in predatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, most human exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> is
the result of consumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> contaminated with methylmercury.
A recent report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Academy of Sciences</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAS</ENAMEX>) concluded
that while most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> face a very low risk from methylmercury,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who consume large amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> during
pregnancy face a much higher risk. Fetuses are particularly
vulnerable to methylmercury because of their rapidly developing
nervous systems. These effects include cognitive, sensory, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motor</ENAMEX> deficits. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAS</ENAMEX> study estimates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 60,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
annually may develop neurological problems because of low-level
methylmercury exposure through their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> prior to birth.
Forty-one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have advisories warning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to restrict
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eating fish</ENAMEX> from local waters due to methylmercury. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> estimates
that <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5.6 million acres</NUMEX> of lakes, estuaries and wetlands and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43,500</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX> of streams, rivers and coasts are impaired by mercury
emissions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACID RAIN</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Energy Plan</ENAMEX> will reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> by reducing
SO2 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>. Acidic deposition or "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>" occurs when <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> in the atmosphere react with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX>, and oxidants to
form acidic compounds. These compounds fall to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> in either
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry form</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and particles) or wet form (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>, and fog).
Some are carried by the wind, sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of miles</NUMEX>, across
state and national borders. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 67 percent</NUMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2 emissions</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions are
produced by electric utility <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that burn fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX>.
Although we have made progress as a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1990 Acid Rain</ENAMEX>
Program, we have not fully addressed the problem. Indicators of
recovery of lakes and streams do not show consistent change in
response to reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions. In sensitive areas such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adirondacks</ENAMEX>, for example, the majority of lakes have remained
fairly constant in terms of acidification levels, while the most
sensitive lakes continue to acidify. Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> deposition
continues to impair the water quality of lakes and streams in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41 percent</NUMEX> of lakes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adirondack</ENAMEX> region of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of lakes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> exhibit signs of chronic
and/or episodic acidification. Although sulfur deposition has
declined, nitrogen emissions have not changed substantially
region-wide. Moreover, recent findings also suggest that nitrogen
is quantitatively as important or, in some areas, possibly more
important than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur</ENAMEX> as a cause of episodic acidification because
of short-term acidic pulses occurring during the most biologically
sensitive time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish reproduce</ENAMEX>. Reductions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>,
particularly during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>, are critical for addressing
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">� NITROGEN DEPOSITION</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Energy Plan</ENAMEX> will improve eco-systems and water
bodies by reducing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions. Some air emissions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> from
power generation result in deposition of nitrogen in soils and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. While nitrogen is an essential nutrient, its availability is
naturally limited, making it an important factor in regulating the
structure and functioning of both terrestrial and aquatic
ecological systems. Human activity has greatly altered the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrestrial</ENAMEX> and atmospheric nitrogen cycle, doubling the annual
amount of nitrogen available in forms that are useful to living
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>. Nitrogen saturation of watersheds contributes to
environmental problems such as reduced drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> quality,
nitrateinduced toxic effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">freshwater organisms</ENAMEX>, increased
soil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acidification</ENAMEX> and aluminum mobility, increased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from
soil of nitrogenous greenhouse trace <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX>, reduction of methane
consumption in soil, and forest decline and reduced
productivity.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coastal</ENAMEX> water and marine environment are also impacted by
atmospheric deposition of nitrogen. Depending upon the location,
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 40 percent</NUMEX> of new nitrogen inputs to coastal
waters along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf Coast</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
come from air pollution. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best documented and understood
impacts of increased nitrogen is the eutrophication of estuaries
and coastal waters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Eutrophication</ENAMEX> refers to the increase in the
rate of supply of organic matter to an ecosystem and its many
undesirable consequences. Symptoms of eutrophication are found in
many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ecosystems</ENAMEX>. They include algal blooms
that are potentially hazardous to human health, low dissolved
oxygen concentrations, declines in the health of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and shellfish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX>, loss of seagrass beds and coral reefs, and ecological
changes in food webs.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summary of Health and Environmental Effects</ENAMEX>
Adopting a unified approach to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> is
better than looking at each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pollutant</ENAMEX> separately because of
synergistic effects. Beyond their impacts as separate emissions,
SO2, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> together contribute to many air
pollution-related problems affecting human health and the
environment. In certain cases, synergies exist between emissions
and among the various reduction approaches available, making it
imperative that efforts to reduce risk address <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> emissions
accommodate these synergies. In the case of fine particles,
atmospheric chemical relationships suggest that when only reducing
sulfate for example, it is replaced in the atmosphere by nitrate.
Thus, simultaneous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> emission reductions are critical. In
the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>, significant reductions in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX>
have not corresponded to ecological changes due to continuing high
levels of nitrogen. Continuing levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur</ENAMEX> deposition, albeit
smaller than before, also work to prevent recovery due to extremely
large sulfur loadings over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> count in
achieving the goal of recovery. Additionally, some synergies have
been observed between methylmercury and lake acidity - the more
acidic, the greater the mercury concentration.
As more environmental data become available and science
improves, we are observing some environmental improvement
accompanying the downward trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>. However, there are
persistent and growing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> regarding recovery of ecosystems
and the risks that air pollution pose to human health. For
instance, nitrate levels in surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> are not significantly
improving, and at best are constant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logically</ENAMEX>, if emissions
continue at the same level, or increase, pollution problems will
mirror that trend. Visibility impairment in national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>,
wilderness areas and urban areas also continues to be a problem.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> continue to be exposed to unacceptable levels of smog.
Of particular significance --the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> has become acutely
aware of the hazards to their health, including the risk of
mortality, posed by inhalation of fine particles and exposure to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercury</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> consumption.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> Climate Change
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Energy Plan</ENAMEX>, and the climate change strategy
that is under development, will provide benefits by addressing
climate change. Energy-related activities are the primary source of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> man-made greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> emissions. Power generators, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CO2</ENAMEX>, contribute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">abut 29%</NUMEX> of the total emissions of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
man-made greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> continue to learn more about
global climate change, its causes, potential impacts, and possible
solution. We recently held <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet-level</ENAMEX> working <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> meetings to
review the most recent, most accurate and most comprehensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX>. During those meetings, we heard from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> offering a
wide spectrum of views. We have reviewed the facts and listened to
many theories and suppositions. The working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> asked the highly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">respected National Academy of Sciences</ENAMEX> to provide us the most
up-to-date information about what is known and about what is not
known on the science of climate change.
We know the surface temperature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> is warming. It has
risen by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">.6 degrees Celsius</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 100 years</TIMEX>. There was a
warming trend from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>, cooling from the 1940s
to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1970s</NUMEX>, and then sharply rising temperatures from the 1970s
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. There is a natural greenhouse effect that contributes to
warming. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Greenhouse gases</ENAMEX> trap heat and thus warm the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> because
they prevent a significant portion of infrared radiation from
escaping into space. Concentration of greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX>, especially
CO2, have increased substantially since the beginning of the
industrial revolution. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Academy of Sciences</ENAMEX>
indicates that the increase is due in large part to human activity.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>'s report also tells us that there are many unanswered
questions about climate change, which makes it difficult to
determine what levels of greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> emissions need to be
avoided.
To address global climate change and greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> emissions,
we are pursuing a broad array of conservation and energy efficiency
goals under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Energy Policy</ENAMEX> as well as
the development of a comprehensive policy under the ongoing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cabinet-level</ENAMEX> review for this issue. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
announced the establishment of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major initiatives to address the
major scientific and technological challenges presented by this
serious, long-term issue: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Climate Research Initiative</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Climate Change Technology Initiative</ENAMEX>. In addition, he
committed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to increasing cooperative efforts in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Hemisphere</ENAMEX>, and with our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> globally, to
aggressively pursue joint research and actions. These efforts have
recently borne fruit, particularly recent agreements with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> to collaborate on climate modeling efforts and with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador</ENAMEX> in a "forest for debt" swap that will preserve tropical
forests there that sequester <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX>. The complex challenge of
global climate change requires a global response that will draw on
the power of global markets and the promise of technology to
achieve emissions reductions most flexibly and costeffectively in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming century</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> intends to address this
challenge in that context, and will leverage our national resources
to enhance our scientific understanding of global climate change,
and develop the advanced energy technologies that the world will
need in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming decades</TIMEX> to meet its energy and environmental
needs.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V. Conclusion</ENAMEX>
Our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has made great progress in reducing air pollution
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several decades</TIMEX>, but pollution from power generation
needs to be further controlled. We can draw no other conclusion
given the significant contribution that power generation makes to
the emissions that cause such serious public health and
environmental problems.
But our current regulatory programs are not the most efficient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to achieve the goal of ensuring a reliable energy supply in an
environmentally responsible manner. Rather than take a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">pollutant-by-pollutant</NUMEX>, problem-by-problem approach, we have the
opportunity to examine the sector as a whole. Doing so provides us
with the opportunity for cost-effective reductions and significant
public health and environmental gains. That is why this
Administration supports the development of new legislation that
builds on the success of the market-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> Program to
reduce significantly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury emissions</ENAMEX> from power
generation. Mandatory controls are not the only way to solve public
health and environmental problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Energy</ENAMEX>
Plan also includes measures to increase conservation of energy,
increase energy efficiency, and encourage technological advances
such as clean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> technology, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel cells</ENAMEX>, and combined heat and
power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> -- all of which will contribute to addressing the
energy and environmental challenges of
11
this industry.
I have already spent time with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the power
generation sector and have heard from a number of them who are
interested in legislation that will provide the public health and
environmental benefits we discussed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. I applaud their concern
and their willingness to help craft a workable solution. I have
also heard from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> who are interested in these same
issues. I know that many of you are interested in addressing these
issues through legislation. I hope that our common interests will
lead us to a consensus - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that will provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with
significant benefits. I look forward to working with you on these
issues.
12



