



Economic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Analysis of a Multi-Emissions Strategy</ENAMEX>
Prepared for: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James M. Jeffords</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph I. Lieberman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Office of Air</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Radiation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atmospheric Programs</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 31, 2001</TIMEX>



Executive Summary
In response to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17, 2001</TIMEX> request from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VT</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph I. Lieberman</ENAMEX> (CT), this report describes
the results of a modeling study done to evaluate the potential
impacts of reducing nitrogen oxides (NOx), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SO2</NUMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercury</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CO2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electric</ENAMEX> power sector. In their request, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords</ENAMEX> and
economic assessment of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> technology-based scenarios designed to
achieve the following emissions caps in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> electric power
sector by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2007</TIMEX>:


•
Reduce nitrogen oxides (NOx) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX>
below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> levels;


•
Reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SO2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> below
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Phase II</ENAMEX> requirements under title
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>;


•
Reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
levels; and


•
Reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CO2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
levels.


The request also specified that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> should evaluate the cost of
achieving these reductions using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> alternative technology
scenarios:


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Information Agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Technology</ENAMEX>
Scenario.


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Information Agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Technology</ENAMEX> Scenario,
including technology assumptions with earlier introduction, lower
costs, higher maximum market potential, or higher efficiencies than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> Scenario.


•
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> scenarios from Scenarios for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Energy Future</ENAMEX>
published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Ridge National Laboratory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Renewable</ENAMEX>
include assumptions about changes in consumer behavior, additional
research and development, and voluntary and information
programs.


Under each scenario, the costs of meeting the emission
constraints are included in the price of electricity. Such costs
include the purchase and installation of emissions control
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX> and the purchase of emissions permits. Factors that
mitigate projected cost increases include the availability of more
cost-effective, energy efficient technologies for both consumers
and electricity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s analysis indicates that, under the
conditions described above:


•
Electricity prices in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> would increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 32%</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>, depending on the technology scenario.


•
Coal-fired electric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> would decline by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2015</TIMEX>.


•
Overall costs, measured by the decline in household
consumption of goods and services, would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $13 and $30</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1% to 0.3%</NUMEX> of total consumption. Under all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the policy scenarios evaluated in this assessment, gross
domestic product (GDP) would remain relatively unchanged as
sacrificed consumption permits higher investment and government
spending to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>.


•
Oil and gas-fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> would be expected increase
by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 8%</NUMEX> under more restrictive technology assumptions, but
decrease by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 20%</NUMEX> under scenarios that


embody more optimistic assumptions about energy-efficiency
demand and supply technologies.
The combination of increased prices and the availability of more
energy-efficient equipment and appliances are projected to reduce
electricity demand by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10%</NUMEX>. With the combination of higher
prices and improved efficiency, total expenditures for electricity
consumption in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> are projected to increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 17% to 39%</NUMEX>,
depending on the scenario.
The increase in electricity prices and cost of the program, as
well as the impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel mix</ENAMEX>, varies considerably based the
technology future that is assumed. For example, the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> electricity
price increase, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 billion</NUMEX> reduction in personal consumption,
and the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> use are all associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean</ENAMEX>
Energy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future Advanced Scenario</ENAMEX>, which includes the most optimistic
technology assumptions. Likewise, the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> electricity price
increase, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> reduction in personal consumption, and
the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> usage are all associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Technology</ENAMEX> Scenario.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> was not asked to evaluate the merits of the alternative
technology scenarios. We note, however, that they are the subject
of considerable controversy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Energy</ENAMEX> Future scenarios have
been criticized on several grounds: assumed changes in consumer
behavior that are not consistent with historic behavior patterns,
results from research and development funding increases that have
not occurred, and voluntary and information programs for which
there is no analytic basis for evaluating the impacts. On the other
hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of those scenarios point to economic analyses
showing that the assumed investments can pay for themselves over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. The range of estimates associated with the different
technology scenarios highlights the importance of the technology
assumptions.
In conducting the modeling requested by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has assumed that the reductions would be achieved
through a nationwide "cap-and-trade" system similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acid</ENAMEX>
Rain program established under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1990 Amendments</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air</ENAMEX>
Act, together with increasing penetration and performance of energy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>. In accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>' request, the
analysis also assumes the use of banked allowances made possible by
early emissions reductions achieved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 2002 through 2006</TIMEX>.
(In practice, significant reductions beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> would be
difficult to achieve.) Because of the contribution of those banked
allowances to overall emissions reductions, the analysis shows
emissions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> above the caps. Regardless, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> emissions are
substantially reduced from current levels. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2015</TIMEX> a
small pool of banked allowances continues to be available for use
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>. The analysis contained in the report covers the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 2002 through 2015</TIMEX>.
The results provided in this analysis should not be construed as
forecasts of actual scenario outcomes. Rather, they are assessments
of how the future might unfold compared to a previously defined
reference case - given the mix of technology and policy assumptions
embodied in each of the scenarios. The results also imply a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> commitment that is successful in achieving the level of
emission reductions described within the report.
The economic impacts of the emissions reduction scenarios are
evaluated using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argonne National Laboratory</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> model, a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>-sector computer general equilibrium model of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy.
The modular design and economy-wide coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> model
makes it a logical choice to analyze alternative technology
scenarios. Although it does employ the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plant</ENAMEX>-level coverage of
the electricity sector as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEMS</ENAMEX> models used in other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">analyses</ENAMEX>, the pollution control technology assumptions are not
included at the same level of detail as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. This may be
particularly relevant for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> controls, where the effectiveness
varies by coal type, and may be difficult to model correctly
without additional detail. In addition, we note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMIGA</ENAMEX>
model is relatively new and has not been subject to the same degree
of peer-review and scrutiny as the older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEMS</ENAMEX> models. It
would be desirable in future work to establish the comparability of
results across these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Introduction

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>. Background
Responding to an earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> request, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Administration</ENAMEX> (EIA) released a detailed study
reviewing the effects of a so-called "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pollutant" strategy in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Information Administration</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>). The three
emissions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX> assessment included nitrogen oxides (NOx),
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SO2</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CO2</NUMEX>). Although a
coordinated climate and air quality policy appeared to lower costs
compared to a series of separate policy initiatives, the EIA
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX> indicated significant costs associated with capping
emissions.
At about the same time, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s national energy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laboratories</ENAMEX> released an extensive review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 50</NUMEX> different
policy options that might achieve cost-effective reductions of both
air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CO2</NUMEX>) emissions. The study,
Scenarios for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Energy Future</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interlaboratory Working Group</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), indicated that domestic investments in energyefficient and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> energy supply technologies could achieve substantial
reductions in both sets of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> at a small but net positive
benefit for the economy.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James M. Jeffords</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VT</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX> (CT) sent a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> seeking further clarity
in the scenarios examined by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> EIA analysis, stating
that "the analysis appears to unnecessarily limit the market and
technology opportunities that might significantly affect the costs
and benefits of emission reductions. In particular, the potential
contributions of demand-side efficiency, gas-fired cogeneration and
of renewable energy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> appear to be inadequately
represented."
In responding to this request, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> modeled the combined impacts
of both the emissions caps and the advanced technology scenarios
specified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>. We are aware that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX> has modeled the
combined impacts but has also modeled the effects of the emission
caps and the advanced technology scenarios separately. This
approach provides perhaps a better technique for isolating the
actual costs of the emissions caps. We have reviewed the EIA
analysis of these separate effects and we believe that they offer
interesting and important insights and that if we had performed the
same kind of analysis we would have seen similar results.
This report responds to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>' request. The results
provided in this analysis should not be construed as forecasts of
actual scenario outcomes. Rather they are assessments of how the
future might unfold compared to a previously defined reference case
- given a national commitment to achieve the emission reductions,
and given the mix of technology and policy assumptions embodied in
each of the scenarios.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>. Technology Scenarios
In the letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX> asked for an analysis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different scenarios,
requesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> "analyze the cost and benefits, including all
sectors of the economy and impacts on both the supply and demand
side of the equation, of the following multi-pollutant emission
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> scenarios for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s electricity generators. Where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feasible</ENAMEX>, this should include power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> both within the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conventionally</ENAMEX> defined electric utility <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> as well as
electricity generated by industrial cogenerators and other
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power producers</ENAMEX>."
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> scenarios are identified as follows:


•
Scenario <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A: Standard Technology Scenario</ENAMEX>. Assume standard
technology characteristics as defined in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AEO2001</TIMEX>. Further assume a
start date of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> below
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> levels, reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> below full
implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Phase II</ENAMEX> requirements under title <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>, reduce
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> levels, and reduce CO2
emissions to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> levels.


•
Scenario B: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Technology</ENAMEX> Scenario. Continue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2002</TIMEX>
start date, but assume the advanced technology assumptions of both
the supply and demand-side perspectives that are referenced in
AEO2001. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> levels,
reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> below full implementation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Phase II</ENAMEX> requirements under title <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>, reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
percent below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> levels, and reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CO2</ENAMEX> emissions to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
levels.


•
Scenario <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">C: Moderate Clean Energy Future Scenario</ENAMEX>.
Continue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2002 start date</TIMEX>, but assume the moderate supply and
demand-side policy scenario of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Energy Future</ENAMEX> (CEF) study.
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> levels, reduce
SO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> below full implementation of the Phase
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">II</ENAMEX> requirements under title <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>, reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>
below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> levels, and reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CO2</ENAMEX> emissions to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
levels.


•
Scenario <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">D: Advanced Clean Energy Future Scenario</ENAMEX>.
Continue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2002 start date</TIMEX>, but assume the advanced supply and
demand-side policy scenario of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Energy Future</ENAMEX> study. By
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> levels, reduce SO2
emissions to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> below full implementation of the Phase II
requirements under title <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>, reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>
below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> levels, and reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CO2</ENAMEX> emissions to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
levels.


In requesting an analysis of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> scenarios, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
request asked for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">"…results</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX>, in periods of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
or less, using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Energy Outlook</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">AEO2001</NUMEX>) as the
baseline."


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Multi-Emission Targets</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> identifies the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> emission caps used for each of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> scenarios. The emission cap is defined by a benchmark emission
level that is modified by the desired level (percentage) of
reduction. For example, the benchmark for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions cap is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Phase II</ENAMEX> requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act Amendments</ENAMEX>. That
total, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8.95 million short tons</NUMEX>, is reduced by a specific percentage
(<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX>) to reach the emissions cap of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.24 million tons</NUMEX>.
Following a similar pattern, the remaining emission caps are set as
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.51 million tons</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4.8 tons</NUMEX> for mercury
emissions, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">475 million metric tons</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MtC</ENAMEX>) of carbon
emissions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. Benchmark <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emission Levels and Assumed Emission Caps</ENAMEX>



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analytical Assumptions</ENAMEX>
As previously noted, the letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords</ENAMEX> requested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different sets of technology
and policy assumptions to meet the specified emission caps shown in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. The full set of technology and policy assumptions are
described more fully in section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of this report. All scenarios
are implemented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. At the same time, there are other key
assumptions that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> adopted to facilitate the evaluation of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> scenarios.
In addition to the different technology scenarios, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> was asked
to include the assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> would begin to make
cost-effective emission reductions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the five years</TIMEX> that precede
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> compliance date. These early reductions would be "banked"
for use in the post-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> period of analysis. For purposes of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simulation</ENAMEX>, the amount of allowances banked from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002 through 2006</TIMEX>
was calculated as the simple difference between the reference case
projections and the actual emission trajectory of each scenario.
The decision to earn and hold early allowances is based on the
assumption that allowances are viewed as an asset that must earn at
least an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8% real</NUMEX> return<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>
Following the assumption used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> study, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> of the
policy scenarios assume nationwide restructuring of the electric
utility industry. This implies that prices are based on the
marginal rather than the regulated, cost-of-service pricing now
used throughout much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> employed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argonne National Laboratory</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> modeling
system to evaluate the impact of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">capping emissions</ENAMEX> under the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
different technology scenarios. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200</NUMEX> plus sector model of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy that captures a wide variety of technology
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">characteristics</ENAMEX> and their resulting impact on key indicators such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, employment and income<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
In practice, it is more likely that significant reductions that
contribute to any kind of allowance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> would be difficult to
achieve before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. Assuming a delay in implementation to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>
would raise the economic impact of any of the scenarios.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> is especially suited to the t ask identifying and
evaluating a different mix of technologies in the production of
goods and services within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. It is not only a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
plus sector model of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy, but it also includes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argonne Unit Planning and Compliance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and database that
captures a wide variety of technology characteristics within the
electric generating sector, including industrial combined heat and
power systems and the typically available emission control
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>. When the electricity module is integrated with
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argonne</ENAMEX> to benchmark <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> to the reference case
projections of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AEO2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> was then modified to approximate the
assumptions behind each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> scenarios.
An economic analysis of a policy compares the world with the
policy (the policy scenario) to the world absent the policy (the
reference case or baseline scenario). The impacts of policies or
regulations are measured by the resulting differences between these
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> scenarios. In effect, any meaningful analysis should compare
the full set of benefits and costs to the extent possible.
For purposes of this exercise, there are at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
categories of costs and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> benefits that might be reviewed. The
costs include: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) direct investment costs, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) operating and
maintenance costs, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) research and development and other
government program costs, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) transaction, search, and compliance
costs, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) adjustment costs associated with large changes in
specific capital stocks, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) lost economic flexibility created by
additional emission requirements, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) potential interactions
with the existing tax system. At the same time, there are at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> categories of benefits. These include: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) direct savings from
lower compliance costs, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) process efficiency and other
productivity gains, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) environmental and health benefits not
captured within normal market transactions, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) spillovers
and/or learning induced by either the technology investment, or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D</ENAMEX> efforts.
The costs associated with the emission limits in each scenario
are computed as the increased expenditures on pollution control,
investment in more efficient equipment and appliances, research and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, tax incentives, and additional government programs -
all relative to the reference case. The increased costs are coupled
with credits for reductions in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> use and productivity gains from
technology. The economic impact of each scenario is reported in two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is as a change in household personal consumption,
measuring the goods and services available for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to enjoy
after subtracting these net expenditures. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is as a change
in economic output measured as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross Domestic Product</ENAMEX> (GDP).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> model reasonably captures those costs and benefits
noted above that arise in market transactions. Some, such as loss
of flexibility and adjustment costs on the cost side, and health
benefits and spillovers on the benefit side, remain beyond the
scope of this analysis.



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Multi-Emissions Analysis</ENAMEX>
This section provides additional details about the technology
assumptions that underpin the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> emission scenarios. It also
describes the results of the scenario analysis, both in terms of
the various marginal costs associated with emission control
strategies and the economy-wide impact of each scenario. Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> made every effort to calibrate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">AEO2001</NUMEX> reference
case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> is a different modeling system than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Modeling System</ENAMEX> (NEMS). Hence, it was not possible to
reproduce the exact AEO2001 reference case
the larger macroeconomic system, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> can then generate key
outputs including projected electricity sales and net generation,
resulting emissions for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> under
consideration, and the set of energy and permit prices associated
with the resulting production levels. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> can provide an
estimate of the consequent impact on the economy including key
indicators as consumption, investment, government spending, GDP,
and employment (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). For more background on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMIGA</ENAMEX>
model, see Appendix <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.1</NUMEX>.
projections. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argonne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> recently upgraded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> to incorporate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions. For this and
other reasons, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMIGA</ENAMEX> currently reports results only through the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2015</TIMEX>. Nonetheless, the differences in the resulting baseline
projections are minor for the purposes of this analysis.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modeling Technology Assumptions</ENAMEX>
Scenarios A and B are based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the AEO2001</TIMEX> standard and advanced
technology characteristics, respectively. The standard technology
assumptions of scenario A were used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX> in the development of
the AEO2001 "reference case" projections. The advanced technology
assumptions of scenario B were used as a sensitivity analysis in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the AEO2001</TIMEX>. They demonstrated the effects of earlier availability,
lower costs, and/or higher efficiencies for more advanced equipment
than the reference case<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>
Scenarios C and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> are based on the recently published
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>-sponsored report, Scenarios for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Energy Future</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interlaboratory Working Group</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>; see also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). Both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> scenarios assumed nationwide restructuring
of the electric utility industry. From an analytical perspective,
this means that prices are based on the marginal costs of
generation, transmission and distribution of electricity rather
than the regulated, cost-of-service pricing now used throughout
much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Moreover, both scenarios reflected increased
spending for research and development and other programs designed
to accelerate the development and deployment of low-carbon, energy
efficient technologies. Each of the scenario assumptions are
described more fully in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> that follow.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1.1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reference Case Scenario</ENAMEX>
The scenario A reference case assumes a "business-as-usual"
characterization of technology development and deployment. As
projected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the AEO2001</TIMEX> assessment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s economy is
projected to grow at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.9%</NUMEX> per year in the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000 through 2020</TIMEX>.
Given anticipated energy prices and the availability of standard
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s primary energy use is expected to grow
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.3%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> while electricity consumption is projected to
increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.8%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. Further details are provided in Appendix
5.2.1.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1.2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Technology</ENAMEX> Scenario
Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> advanced technology characterization,
scenario B assumes that a large number of technologies have earlier
availability, lower costs, and/or higher efficiencies. For example,
the high efficiency air conditioners in the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> are
assumed to cost less than in scenario A. This encourages a greater
rate of market penetration as electricity prices rise in response
to the emissions caps. Building shell efficiencies in scenario B
are assumed to improve by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50 percent</NUMEX> faster than in scenario
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX>
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">AEO2001</NUMEX> was published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Information</ENAMEX>
Administration, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>).
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>'s side of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX>, the heat rates for new
combined cycle power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> are assumed to be less compared to the
standard case assumptions. This means that more kilowatthours of
electricity are generated for every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of energy consumed by the
power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> supply increases by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10%</NUMEX> and the
capacity factor of wind energy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> increases by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 15-20%</NUMEX>
compared to the reference case assumptions. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the AEO2001</TIMEX> report,
the combination of higher efficiencies and earlier availability of
the technologies lowers the growth in electricity use from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.8%</NUMEX> in
the reference case to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.6%</NUMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1.3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CEF Moderate Case Scenario</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Energy Future</ENAMEX> (CEF) report describe
their analysis as an attempt to "assess how energy-efficient and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> energy technologies can address key energy and environmental
challenges facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). In that regard,
they evaluated a set of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 50</NUMEX> policies to improve the technology
performance and characterization of the residential, commercial,
industrial, transportation, and electricity generation sectors. The
policies include increased research and development funding,
equipment standards, financial incentives, voluntary programs, and
other regulatory initiatives. These policies were assumed to change
business and consumer behavior, result in new technological
improvements, and expand the success of voluntary and information
programs.
The selection of policies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> study began with a
sector-by-sector assessment of market failures and institutional
barriers to the market penetration of clean energy technologies in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, the policies and programs include additional
appliance efficiency standards; expansion of technical assistance
and technology deployment programs; and an increased number of
building codes and efficiency standards for equipment and
appliances. They also include tax incentives to accelerate the
market penetration of new technologies and the strengthening of
market transformation programs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rebuild America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX>
Star labeling. They further include so-called public benefits
programs enhanced by electricity line charges.
For industry, the policies include voluntary agreements with
industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to achieve defined energy efficiency and emissions
goals, combined with a variety of government programs that strongly
support such agreements. These programs include expansion and
strengthening of existing information programs, financial
incentives, and energy efficiency standards on motors systems.
Policies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> analysis were assumed to encourage the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diffusion</ENAMEX> and improve the implementation of combined heat and power
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHP</ENAMEX>) in the industrial sector. For electricity, the policies
include extending the production tax credit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.5 cents</NUMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kWh</NUMEX> over
more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and extending it to additional renewable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>.
Broadly speaking, the CEF Moderate scenario can be thought of as
a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> increase in funding for programs that promote a variety of
both demand-side and supply-side technologies. For example, the
moderate scenario assumes a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 billion</NUMEX> increase in
cost-shared research, development, and demonstration of efficient
and clean-energy technologies (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> dollars with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as federal
appropriations and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as private-sector cost share). It further
assumes a careful targeting of funds to critical research areas and
a gradual, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year</TIMEX> ramp-up of funds to allow for careful planning,
assembly of research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, and expansion of existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>. In addition, the CEF moderate scenario anticipates
increased program spending of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.0 and $6.6 billion</NUMEX> for the years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010 and 2020</TIMEX>, respectively. These expenditures include production
incentives and investment tax credits for renewable energy, energy
efficiency and transportation technologies. They further include
increased spending for programs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Assessment</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Star</ENAMEX> programs.
The combined effect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D</ENAMEX> and program expenditures,
together with other policies described in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> report, implies a
steady reduction in total energy requirements over the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2020</TIMEX>, for example, primary energy
consumption and electricity sales were projected to decrease by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>, respectively, compared to the CEF reference case.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1.4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CEF Advanced Technology Scenario</ENAMEX>
Building on the policies of the moderate scenario, the CEF
advanced scenario assumes a doubling of cost-shared R&D
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">investments</ENAMEX>, resulting in an increased spending of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.9 billion</NUMEX> per
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> (again, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> dollars with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as federal appropriations
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as private-sector cost share). In addition, the advanced
scenario anticipates increased program spending of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.0 and $13.2</NUMEX>
billion for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 2010 and 2020</TIMEX>, respectively. The added
spending covers all sectors including <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, industry,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>, and electric generation.
The combined effect of the program and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D</ENAMEX> expenditures,
together with other policies described in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> report (including
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> carbon charge applied in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CEF Advanced Scenario</ENAMEX>), drove a
steady reduction in the need for energy compared to the CEF
reference case. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX> total energy use fell by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX> compared to
the reference case. At the same time, electricity sales in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX>
were projected to decrease by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24%</NUMEX> compared to the CEF reference
case.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1.5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Implementation of the Technology Assumptions</ENAMEX>
The assumptions embedded in each of these scenarios have the
effect of progressively increasing market penetration of higher
performance energy efficiency and energy supply technologies. As
shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, the net effect of these assumptions is to lower
the expected level of electricity consumption while continuing to
meet the same level of service demanded by utility <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. The
technology assumptions also have the effect of increasing the
availability of cleaner energy supply technologies that reduce the
level of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> per <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">kilowatt-hour</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>. The critical
assumption used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> analysis is that program spending
affects both supply and demand technologies in a way that interacts
with the emission caps that are to be imposed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benchmarked</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2010</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> shows the percentage
change of key indicators for each scenario with respect to its
respective reference case. These changes provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> with
approximate targets so that each of the scenarios can be mapped
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> model. As such, the figures in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> should be
seen as inputs into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> model, not outputs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. Influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Technology Assumptions on Key Scenario</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Indicators - 2010</ENAMEX>

By definition, scenario A assumes the standard technology
assumptions of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">AEO2001</NUMEX> reference case. Hence, there are no
additional programs or policies that generate changes in the
reference case technologies when the emission caps are imposed by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2007</TIMEX>. The level of technology responsiveness grows for
scenarios B, C, and D as a result of greater program spending.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> advanced scenario, for example, assumes a significant
increase in program funds to promote a variety of both demand-side
and supply-side technologies. As a result of this greater level of
program activity, there is an accelerated penetration of
energy-efficient technologies that drives electricity sales down by
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.8 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX> (compared to the CEF reference case for that
same year). At the same time, the combination of a lower demand for
electricity and an increased investment in cleaner energy supply
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> reduces both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.7</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.1</NUMEX>
percent, respectively (again, compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX> reference
case). As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> modeled this scenario, the bundle of policies in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> advanced scenario became, in effect, a complement to the
emission caps imposed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>.
To avoid overestimating the impact of the policy scenarios in
this analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> made a number of adjustments before implementing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> assumptions in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> scenarios reported here. First, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> analysis was benchmarked to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> reference case. In the
AEO2001 reference case, however, the demand for electricity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX>
is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10%</NUMEX> higher compared to the CEF reference case. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> request asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to assume a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002 start date</TIMEX> in running the
technology and policy scenarios. In effect, there are fewer years
in which programs can achieve the desired level of technology
improvement compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> scenarios. In addition, the CEF
analysis includes a significant review of transportation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> and policies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> chose to exclude all assumptions
related to transportation, focusing only on the supply and
demand-side technologies associated with electricity and natural
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> consumption.
With the adjustments described above <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> reflected in the
current analytical framework, and using the program cost
information documented in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX> summarizes the
incremental program costs that were assumed as necessary to drive
the kind of changes in electricity consumption and emissions
described in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. Since transportation programs drove a
significant part of the CEF expenditures, and since there are fewer
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to implement policies, the estimated program expenditures are
also smaller compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> assumptions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Incremental Policy Costs of the Technology Scenarios</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion 1999 dollars</NUMEX>)

Because scenario A characterizes existing program and technology
performance, no additional funds are required to drive that
scenario. Scenario B, on the other hand, anticipates some changes
in the technology characterization that will affect the electricity
sector as shown in Table
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. While <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the AEO2001</TIMEX> analysis anticipated no program spending to
drive these changes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> assumed that additional spending would be
required for scenario <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. Calibrating</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> policy scenarios,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> estimated that program and policy spending would increase by
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.8 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, rising steadily to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.9 billion</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>. For
scenario C, program spending increased by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> starting in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, rising to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.8 billion</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>. Finally, program spending in
scenario <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> started at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.1 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> and increased to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.5</NUMEX>
billion by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> of this analysis<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>
The net effect of mapping increased program spending together
with adjustments needed to update the assumptions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> policy
scenarios can be highlighted by reviewing the change in electricity
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">generation for scenario D. In the CEF Advanced Scenario</ENAMEX> (based on a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> reference case), for example, the level of electricity
generation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX> was lowered by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> from the reference case
requirements of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,920 billion kilowatt-hours</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kWh</NUMEX>). As the CEF
technology assumptions were applied in scenario D within this
analysis (updated to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">AEO2001</NUMEX> reference case), electricity
generation was reduced by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4,253 billion</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kWh</NUMEX>). The trend
was more pronounced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>. Rather than a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 16%</NUMEX> reduction
from a generation level of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,200 billion kWh</NUMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> CEF
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Case</ENAMEX>, the scenario D equivalent in this analysis achieved
only a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> reduction from a generation of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,580 billion kWh</NUMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1.6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reasonableness of the Scenario Assumptions</ENAMEX>
The results of the technology-driven scenarios should not be
interpreted as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> endorsement of any of the policies or
technology assumptions behind each of scenarios described in this
report. On the one hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has not conducted any significant
review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX> assumptions that underpin the AEO2001
projections. On the other hand, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> do not necessarily
agree with the assumptions and projected level of impacts in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CEF</ENAMEX> assessment despite the fact that it was peer-reviewed and its
findings published this fall in an academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>. The EIA
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>), for example, notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> policies assume changes in
consumer behavior that are not consistent with historically
observed behavior patterns. Moreover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX> suggests that there
is little documentation to support the assumed technological
improvements generated by the research and development (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D</ENAMEX>)
initiatives described in the report. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX> notes that
The program spending assumptions developed in this analysis are
used only to approximate the impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> scenario s. They do
not reflect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> endorsement of these spending levels.
the effectiveness of voluntary or information programs may be
less than assumed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> scenarios. At the same time, the lead
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> have responded to the EIA assertions by citing
relevant economic literature and noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF</ENAMEX> study is one
of "the most carefully documented and complete analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
energy futures that has ever been funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koomey, et al</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>).
Notwithstanding these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> attempted to respond to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>' request by mapping in the critical assumptions of the CEF
as a range of policies that provide a set of alternative
assumptions about the future. In this regard, the scenarios are
more like descriptions of alternative future outcomes rather than
predictions or recommendations about how the future should
unfold.
To provide a more complete context for understanding the
magnitude of the changes in electricity generation that are
suggested by the different scenarios, the figure below illustrates
both the historical and projected trends in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
electricity generation. The information is shown as the number of
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kWh</NUMEX> per dollar of GDP (measured in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">constant 1999 dollars</NUMEX>). The
historical data covers the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970 through 2000</TIMEX> while the
projected trends are through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2015</TIMEX>. The historical period
shows a moderate level of volatility. The reference case
projections suggest an annual rate of declining intensity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.6%</NUMEX>
per year through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> with a final value <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.33 kWh</NUMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$</NUMEX>.
Historical and Projected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Electricity Trends</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kWh</NUMEX> per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> $
GDP)

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>

In comparison to the reference case, Scenario D (adapting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEF Advanced Case</ENAMEX> assumptions) reflects a national commitment to
improve both electricity supply and the efficiency of demandside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>. The presumption is that such a commitment would be
supported by a significant increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R&D</ENAMEX> and program spending
as described above. Under these assumptions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
electricity intensity is projected to decline at an annual rate of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5%</NUMEX>,
dropping to a final intensity of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.28 kWh</NUMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$</NUMEX>. This level of
decline is greater than previously seen in the recent past. In the
period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980 through 1986</TIMEX>, for example, and again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993 through 2000</TIMEX>,
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> rate of decline was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1.7 percent</NUMEX>. Hence, it appears
that the assumptions driving the advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX> are aggressive.
At the same time, however, the research undertaken by the CEF
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> indicates that the technology is available to achieve such
a reduction should a national commitment be successful in driving
similar policies.



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>. Results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scenario Analysis</ENAMEX>
With the model benchmarked to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AEO2001</TIMEX>, and given the different
mix of scenario assumptions previously described, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMIGA</ENAMEX> reports the
results in the figures and tables that follow. More complete data,
including reference case assumptions, are available in Appendix
5.2.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2.1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emission Projections</ENAMEX>
All program and policy assumptions have a start date of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>.
Moreover, the analysis anticipates the use of banked allowances
made possible by early emissions reductions achieved in the years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002 through 2006</TIMEX> (as requested in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> letter). Figures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> on the following page illustrate both the emissions
projections and the impact of banking the early reductions on all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> emissions caps implemented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>.
Although all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> categories of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> are down
substantially, they only achieve <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50-75%</NUMEX> of the proposed cap by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>
(shown as the dotted horizontal line in each of the above figures).
This is because of the availability of the banked allowances that
can be used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to meet emissions caps in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> and beyond.
Note that costs would be noticeably higher if power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> were
required to actually hit the target in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions continue to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> or more above the target.
The reductions that generate the banked allowances are shown as
the area to the left of each vertical dotted line as the
differences between the reference case and scenario emission
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trajectories</ENAMEX>. The emissions above the cap are shown to the right of
each vertical dotted line and between the scenario emissions and
the dotted horizontal line. Subtracting these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas on each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">graph</ENAMEX> reveals the level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>. Using Scenario D as an
example, the remaining allowances in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 million metric</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.3 million tons</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.2 million tons</NUMEX> for NOx
and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 tons</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX>. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> would last
another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> at the rate of drawdown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>, or longer if the
drawdown declined.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Carbon Emissions</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million metric tons</NUMEX>) Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. SO2
Emissions (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million tons</NUMEX>)

Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NOx Emissions</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million tons</NUMEX>) Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX>
Emissions (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX>)



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2.2</NUMEX>. Changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Generation Expenditures</ENAMEX>
Given the assumptions and economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> in each of the
scenarios, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> model calculates the capital investment,
operation and maintenance, and fuel costs necessary to meet
consumer demand for electricity. The incremental expenditures
required to generate electricity under each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> scenarios
as compared to the reference case are summarized in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> (in
billions of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1999 dollars</NUMEX>). In effect, the incremental expenditures
reflect the range of decisions made by the electricity sector to
comply with each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> scenario constraints-but do not
reflect efforts made outside the electricity sector. Because these
expenditures ignore spending on energy efficiency, research and
development outside the electricity sector-spending that can be
substantial-they are not measures of program costs. Note that
incremental expenditures are incurred as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as 2002</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX>
scenarios to generate early reductions that can be banked for use
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> and beyond.
The generation expenditures vary in each of the scenarios change
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> reasons: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the size of the allowance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> made
possible by early reductions driven, in part, by program spending
prior to the introduction of the caps; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the varying levels of
demand for electricity over time, resulting in changes in the
overall mix of generation resources; and, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the gradual reduction
in the banked allowances available for withdrawal necessitating
additional actions to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>.
As expected, scenario A has the largest increase with
expenditures rising by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $17 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> compared to the
reference case. The higher level of expenditures is driven by a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX>
increase in unit generation costs caused primarily by the emissions
caps and offset only slightly by a small decrease in electricity
demand. With less energy efficiency technology penetrating the
market, a greater level of control equipment must be installed and
operated which, in turn, drives up the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>. Scenario
B follows a similar pattern with expenditure increases being offset
by further reductions in electricity demand as more efficient
technology penetrates the market. The expenditures for scenario C
decline even further as reduced demand continues to lower both the
level generation and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> compared to
scenario <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Scenario D</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, actually shows a decline
in total expenditures by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>. The combination of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.5%</NUMEX> reduction
on generation load together with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only an 11.9%</NUMEX> increase in the unit
cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> (both with respect to the reference case)
results in a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.11 billion</NUMEX> reduction in total electric generation
expenditures.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incremental Expenditures on Electric Generation</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Billions of 1999$</NUMEX>)



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2.3</NUMEX>. Marginal Costs
The marginal costs of emission reductions over the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> are shown in Figures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX> for all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
scenarios.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Projected Marginal Cost</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carbon Reductions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">$/Metric</ENAMEX>
Ton)

Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Projected Marginal Cost of SO2 Reductions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">$/Ton</ENAMEX>)

Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Projected Marginal Cost of NOx Reductions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">$/Ton</ENAMEX>)
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Projected Marginal Cost of Hg Reductions</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$Million</NUMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ton</ENAMEX>)


The marginal cost of carbon reductions range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$46</NUMEX> to
$138/metric ton through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> with each scenario showing
successively smaller costs as technology characteristics improve
and more energy-efficient and/or low carbon technologies penetrate
the market. The marginal cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> reductions through
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> are less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450/ and $2,300/ton</NUMEX>, respectively, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX>
multi-emissions reduction scenarios. The marginal cost of mercury
reductions by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> ranges from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350 million</NUMEX>/ton to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$432</NUMEX>
million/ton, again depending on the scenario.
It is important to note that marginal cost reflects the
additional cost of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more ton of reductions, and not the total
cost associated with each pollutant. One can make a very rough
estimation of this overall cost for each pollutant, on top of the
costs associated with the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, by multiplying half the
marginal cost (to approximate average cost) by the volume of
reductions. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>, as an example, scenario A returns cost
estimates of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15.2 billion</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 billion</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.7</NUMEX>
billion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.4 billion</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX>. In Scenario D, the
cost estimates are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.6 billion</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6 billion</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.3 billion</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.8 billion</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX>. Note that these
figures cannot be added together for an overall estimate because
they (a) double count the benefits of controlling multiple
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pollutants</ENAMEX> simultaneously, and
(b) ignore the consequences of the underlying technology policy.
We discuss overall costs below.
Surprisingly, the marginal cost of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX> reductions
increases as the marginal cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon decreases</ENAMEX>. The reason
appears to be that as efficiency technology penetrates the market
and reduces <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX> prices, more of a price signal is required to
generate further reductions in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX>.
In the advanced scenarios, for example, both demand reductions and
the increased use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> tends to reduce carbon <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>. But gas
prices begin to rise which allows <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> to make a modest comeback
with respect to scenario A. This is especially true as cleaner and
more efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> technologies begin to penetrate the market as
assumed in scenarios B through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> In order to offset the tendency
for coal-generated emissions to increase, permit prices need to
adjust upward.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2.4</NUMEX>. Fuel Use Impacts
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> shows both total electricity consumption and the
fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> consumption used in the generation of electricity for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2010</TIMEX>. The results are in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">quadrillion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Btu</ENAMEX> in both the
reference case and each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> policy scenarios. As each
successive scenario generates a greater reduction in electricity
demand, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> use is reduced significantly (by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 30 percent</NUMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gas</ENAMEX> consumption increases slightly in scenarios A and B, and
decreases by a small amount in scenarios C and D as lower
electricity consumption reduces the need for new capacity.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Electricity Consumption and Fossil Fuel</ENAMEX>
Generation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quadrillion Btu</ENAMEX>)



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2.5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Price Impacts</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> suggests that under the conditions described above,
electricity prices are expected to increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 30%</NUMEX> (under
scenario <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> (under scenario A) by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2015</TIMEX>. This is the
logical result of increased control costs and permit prices. The
combination of increased prices and the availability of more
energy-efficient equipment and appliances reduce electricity demand
by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10%</NUMEX>. Total electricity expenditures increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 15%</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> depending on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and the scenario (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>, below,
and the tables in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Appendix 5.2</NUMEX> for more detail on the changing
pattern of expenditures).


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2.6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy</ENAMEX>-wide Impacts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX> provides a summary of key macroeconomic data for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2010</TIMEX> to compare the impact of emissions reductions on both
personal consumption and other components of gross domestic product
(GDP). The effects on personal consumption show a decline of
between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 billion and $31</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1% to 0.3%</NUMEX>, depending on the
scenario. This reflects the cost of the program in terms of the
decreased well being of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> who must forego a fraction of
their consumption of goods and services in order to pay for both
research and development programs, energy efficiency improvements,
and more expensive electricity production. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX> shows little
change in GDP under any of the policy scenarios, reflecting the
fact that this foregone consumption turns up as expenditures in
other categories of GDP, namely, investment and government
spending.5
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summary of Economic Impacts</ENAMEX> by Scenario - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2010</NUMEX>

The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA</ENAMEX> modeling system reports the costs and benefits of each
scenario with several major exceptions. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> omitted benefit
is spillover and productivity gains beyond energy bill savings. A
number of studies suggest that energy efficiency technology
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">investments</ENAMEX> also tend to increase overall productivity of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, especially in the industrial sector. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laitner</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laitner, et al</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). To date,
however, no systematic effort has been undertaken to incorporate
such benefits into the current generation of policy models. Hence,
this potential benefit is not reported at this time. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
missing benefit includes gains in environmental quality, especially
improved health benefits.
On the cost side, the model ignores costs associated with rapid
changes in capital stocks, as well as potential loss of flexibility
and interactions with the existing tax system. For example, the
model forecasts significant changes in the level and composition of
electricity generation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, ignoring the difficulty of rapidly
changing the capital stock by then end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. Losses in
flexibility occur when pollution control activities potentially
interfere with efficiency and other operational programs at a
regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. Finally, there are interactions with the tax
system when, in response to a rise in the relative cost of
purchased goods, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> decide to enjoy more
A more complete assessment of each policy scenario can be made
by reviewing the more detailed data contained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appendix</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leisure</ENAMEX> (which is now relatively less expensive), work less, and
lower taxable income (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oates</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>).



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX>. The Results in Context
Recent studies suggest significant economic consequences as a
result of substantial emission reduction strategies (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPRI</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>;
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>). On the other hand, the presumption of a trade-off
between environmental and economic benefits may not provide an
entirely appropriate framework for analysis of such policies
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeCanio</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>). Indeed, there are a number of studies that show
net economic benefits may be possible when a full accounting of
both benefits and costs are included within an appropriate analysis
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krause, et al</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailie, et al</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>).
At the same time, understanding the proper characterization and
role of technology improvements (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edmonds, et al</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), and then
capturing that characterization within an appropriate model
structure (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>), is a critical aspect of all such
economic assessments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> and the potential for positive net benefits does not
assure that these technologies will be commercialized and adopted,
nor that the net benefits will be realized (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaffe, et al</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). An
unanswered question is whether and how policies might encourage
these activities.
This current study, while drawing on credible data sources and
applying a state-of-the-art modeling system, cannot adequately
capture all such nuances associated with emission reduction
scenarios. The results of this analysis should be viewed within
this larger context.



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Conclusions
The analysis suggests that under the conditions described above,
emissions through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> will be significantly reduced although they
won't meet the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> target. This is largely because of assumptions
about the banking of allowances earned prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>. At the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, coal-fired electric generation is expected to decline by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2015</TIMEX>. On the other hand, oil and gas-fired
generation is projected to increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 8%</NUMEX> under more
restrictive technology assumptions, but decrease by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 20%</NUMEX>
under scenarios that embody more optimistic assumptions about
energy-efficiency demand and supply technologies. Electricity
prices are expected to increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32% to 50%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>, depending on
the scenario.
The combination of increased prices and the availability of more
energy-efficient equipment and appliances are projected to reduce
electricity demand by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10%</NUMEX> compared to the reference case.
With the combination of higher prices and improved efficiency,
total expenditures for electricity consumption in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX> are
projected to increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 17% to 39%</NUMEX> depending on the
scenario. Interacting with other changes in consumer and business
spending that is driven by each of the scenario assumptions, the
personal consumption reduced by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 0.1% to 0.3%</NUMEX>. This again
depends on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and the scenario.
The results provided in this analysis should not be construed as
forecasts of actual scenario outcomes. Rather they are assessments
of how the future might unfold compared to a previously defined
reference case - given the mix of technology and policy assumptions
embodied in each of the scenarios. The results from these scenarios
imply a strong national commitment, one that is successful in
developing the programs and policies necessary to achieve the level
of emission reductions described within the report.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. References
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bailie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Bernow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Dougherty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazarus</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sivan Kartha</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto</ENAMEX>
Protocol: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Analysis</ENAMEX> to Reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Carbon Pollution</ENAMEX>, Tellus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stockholm Environment Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn A.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark D. Levine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Short</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan G.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Koomey, 2001</TIMEX>. "Scenarios for a clean energy future," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Policy</ENAMEX>
Vol. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>): <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1179-1196, 2001</TIMEX>.
DeCanio, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen J.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. "Economic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Modeling and the False</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tradeoff Between Environmental Protection and Economic Growth</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary Economic Policy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vol.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>): <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-27, 1997</TIMEX>.
Edmonds, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jae</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph M. Roop</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Scott</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
Technology and the economics of climate change policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pew Center</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Global Climate Change</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2000</TIMEX>.
E-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRID</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emissions & Generation Resource Integrated</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">epa.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/airmarkets/egrid/factsheet.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Power Research Institute</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Energy-Environment
Policy <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Integration and Coordination Study</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TR-1000097</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>,
CA, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Information Administration</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. Impacts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto</ENAMEX>
Protocol on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Energy Markets</ENAMEX> and Economic Activity,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SR/OIAF/98-03</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1998</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Information Administration</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategies</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Reducing Multiple Emissions</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Power Plants: Sulfur Dioxide</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nitrogen Oxides</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Carbon Dioxide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SR/OIAF/2000-05</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Information Administration</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. Analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategies</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Reducing Multiple Emissions</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Power Plants</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Technology Scenarios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SR/OIAF/2001-05</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2001</TIMEX>).
Finman, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hodayah</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John A. "Skip" Laitner</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. "Industry,
Energy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Efficiency and Productivity Improvements</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proceedings</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">ACEEE Industrial Summer Study</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Council</ENAMEX> for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy-Efficient Economy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald A</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Framework</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Impact Analysis</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry Growth Assessment</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Description</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMIGA System</ENAMEX>,
Decision and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Sciences Division</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argonne National</ENAMEX>
Laboratory, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argonne, IL</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April, 1999</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interlaboratory Working Group</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Scenarios for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean</ENAMEX>
Energy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ORNL/CON-476</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBNL-44029 Oak Ridge</ENAMEX>, TN: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Ridge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Laboratory</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, CA: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence Berkeley National</ENAMEX>
Laboratory, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaffe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RN Newell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RN Stavins</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. "Energy-efficient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> and climate change policies: Issues and evidence." In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Climate Change Economics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFF Anthology</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. "Letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Administrator Christine Todd Whitman</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17, 2001</TIMEX>.
Koomey, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sanstad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernst Worrell</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Price</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. "Assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX>'s statements in their
multi-pollutant analysis about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Energy Futures Report</ENAMEX>'s
scenario assumptions," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Memo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skip Laitner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Laboratory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, CA, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 18, 2001</TIMEX>.
Krause, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florentin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul Baer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen DeCanio</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
Cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Carbon Emissions</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profit</ENAMEX>: Opportunities for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Project For Sustainable Energy Paths</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Cerrito</ENAMEX>, CA,
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
Laitner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John A. "Skip"</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernst Worrell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ruth</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Incorporating the Productivity Benefits</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX> of
Cost-effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Savings Potential Using Conservation Supply</ENAMEX>
Curves," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proceedings</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">ACEEE Industrial Summer Study</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Council for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy-Efficient Economy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.W.H. and W.E. Oates</ENAMEX>. "Policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> in the Presence
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distorting</ENAMEX> Taxes" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Policy Analysis and Management</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>), pp <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603-613</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Bernow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Cleetus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John A.</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skip"</ENAMEX>)
Laitner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aleksandr Rudkevich</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ruth</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. "A Pragmatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CGE Model</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Assessing the Influence of Model Structure and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Assumptions in Climate Change Policy Analysis</ENAMEX> ," Presented at the
2nd <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Global Conference</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Taxation Issues</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tellus Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2001</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory P.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph M. Roop</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert W. Schultz</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. "Quantifying the Benefits: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX>, Cost, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employment</ENAMEX>
Impacts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Industrial Technologies</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">ACEEE Summer</ENAMEX>
Study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proceedings on Energy Efficiency</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Industry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Council for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy-Efficient Economy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000b</TIMEX>. Guidelines for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preparing Economic Analysis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-003</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Administrator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2000</TIMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Appendices
