



Introduction 

As recognized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Energy Plan</ENAMEX> (NEP), one
of the principal energy challenges facing us is increasing our
energy supplies in ways that protect and improve the environment.
Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> directed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to propose legislation that would
significantly reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury emissions</ENAMEX> from power
generation through a cap and trade program. Such a program, coupled
with appropriate measures to address local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, would provide
significant health benefits even as we increase energy supplies and
maintain reasonable electricity rates.
Our work on this issue has given us insight that I believe will
be helpful to you. The more I learn about the cost and
inefficiencies of the current and future regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> to which
power generators will be subjected if we do not have new
legislation, the more I am convinced that we can --and must --
develop a smarter approach that protects the environment and public
health while reducing the cost to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and industry and
optimizing the size of both the state and federal government
machinery necessary to achieve that protection. It is possible to
achieve better results at lower costs,
but not if we simply add yet another program on top of all of
the existing regulations.
The current <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> has been enormously successful, but we
can do better. Significant cost savings can be achieved for power
generators and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> through a comprehensive legislative
package. I look forward to working with you to develop such an
approach to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from power generation. We applaud
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords</ENAMEX> for tackling this important issue and for
recognizing that a cap and trade program is the best way to achieve
these reductions. However, we have significant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> with S. 556
as drafted. Our analysis to date suggests that it could increase
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>' electricity rates by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 50%</NUMEX>, which we believe is
unacceptable. In addition, the combination of emission reductions
and timing is not feasible and could threaten the reliability of
electricity supply. We are concerned that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S. 556</ENAMEX>'s short timeframes
for installation of controls could lead power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> to be taken
off-line at important times, which could lead to electricity
shortages.
In addition, there are a number of issues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should
consider that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S. 556</ENAMEX> does not address. As drafted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S. 556</ENAMEX> would
make some existing requirements unnecessary, but would not
eliminate them. Rather than add yet another layer of environmental
regulations on top of the existing ones, we believe that S. 556
should eliminate those unnecessary existing requirements. S. 556
also does not have an allocation scheme. One lesson we should learn
from the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> cap and trade program is that
when certain key issues can be resolved through clear legislation,
we can avoid years of litigation, business uncertainty and costs,
and delayed environmental protection.
Finally, and most importantly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> strongly
opposes including CO2 reductions in any multi-pollutant bill. The
CO2 provisions in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S. 556</ENAMEX> will cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> too much and endanger
our energy security by causing too much electricity generation to
switch from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> to natural gas. Greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> emissions should be
addressed in the context of climate change, which is being
undertaken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> level working <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. For all
of these reasons, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> must oppose S. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">556</NUMEX>. In my
testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> I will elaborate further on these key points.


Background 

Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 30 years</TIMEX>, we have made substantial progress
towards improved environmental quality under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>.
During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>, gross domestic product has increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 160%</NUMEX>.
At the same time, we have reduced emissions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> key air
pollutants by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> consumption has increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77%</NUMEX> and
energy consumption has increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George H. W. Bush</ENAMEX> signed into law the most far reaching amendments
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> since its enactment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. Included in those
amendments was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> cap and trade program, the first
program tailored specifically to the utility sector, which is
achieving significant environmental and public health benefits at a
fraction of the initial cost estimates and with relatively little
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>. It is time to revisit and update the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean</ENAMEX>
Air Act once again in order to achieve the additional reductions
needed to address public health and environmental problems in the
most cost effective manner.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> Program is achieving its emission reduction goal
at a fraction of the estimated costs because it allows and
encourages innovative thinking and long range planning<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">.1</TIMEX> The
existing program establishes a cap on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions to ensure that
the environmental goal is met, and employs an innovative
market-based allowance trading program to achieve the goal at
lowest cost. Allowances are the currency with which compliance with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions requirements is achieved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX>, rather than
government, decide the most cost-effective way to use available
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to comply. Units that reduce their emissions below the
number of allowances they hold may trade allowances with other
units in the system, sell them to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> or save them for
future use. There are neither restrictions on trading nor
government second-guessing.
Allowance trading provides incentives for energy conservation
and technology innovation that can both lower the cost of
compliance and yield pollution prevention benefits. Simply, the
allowance market puts a price or value on each ton of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> not 
emitted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of a monetary value
with reduced emissions encourages innovation: in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>'s,
scrubber costs decreased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 40%</NUMEX> and scrubber sulfur
removal efficiencies improved from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90% to 95%</NUMEX>, and experimentation
led to the blending of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> to lower emissions. To ensure that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX> is met and to provide credibility, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> also are required to
install systems that continuously monitor and report emissions.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> Program has proven to be an excellent model for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX> and trade programs. Compliance with the program has been nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> emissions of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">SO2</NUMEX> from power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> have
already been reduced <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 6 million tons</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 35 percent</NUMEX>) from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> levels. Greater reductions earlier than expected have lowered
risks to human health and provided benefits to the environment
sooner. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Acid rain</ENAMEX> levels were dramatically reduced over large areas
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and trading did not result in geographic shifting of
emissions, or "hot spots", as some feared.
Despite the significant progress we have made under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean</ENAMEX>
Air Act, air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from power generators are still contributing
to serious public health and environmental problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Administrator</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> addressed these concerns extensively in her testimony
before you on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26, 2001</TIMEX>. Rather than reiterate her testimony, I
will emphasize just a few of her key points. Problems associated
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SO2</NUMEX>), nitrogen oxides (NOx), and mercury
emissions are of national and international significance, and the
interstate and long range transport of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> continue to play
significant roles in the nature and magnitude of the problems.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emission</ENAMEX> and deposition of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> and their
transformation byproducts are known to have a wide range of adverse
effects on human health and the environment, including:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• SO2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions contribute to fine particles, which are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with premature mortality, aggravated chronic bronchitis,
hospitalizations due to cardio-respiratory symptoms, emergency room
visits due to aggravated asthma symptoms, and acute respiratory
symptoms.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26, 2001</TIMEX>, testimony before this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> contains a detailed discussion of the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acid</ENAMEX>
Rain cap and trade program.
Fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">particles</ENAMEX> formed from power plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> as well as
mobile source <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> are of
concern. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">• NOx</ENAMEX> emissions contribute to ground-level ozone,
which aggravates respiratory illnesses and causes lung
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inflammation</ENAMEX>, particularly for at-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the elderly and those afflicted with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>, emphysema,
and other respiratory ailments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• Mercury</ENAMEX> emissions contribute to mercury deposition in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> born to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who consume large amounts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercury</ENAMEX>-contaminated fish while pregnant may be at risk for
neurodevelopmental defects.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• SO2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions contribute to atmospheric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sulfate</ENAMEX> and
nitrate concentrations that cause visibility impairment, including
impairment in many national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and wilderness areas.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• SO2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">NOx</ENAMEX> contribute to acid deposition, which damages
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">lakes</ENAMEX> and streams, adversely affecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and other species
that live in them, and leaches nutrients from the soil.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">• NOx</ENAMEX> emissions contribute to nitrogen deposition that may lead
to eutrophication of estuaries and near-coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> and can
damage forested watersheds.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and industry, working together, have made important
strides in addressing the adverse impacts of fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> combustion
by the electric power industry since the passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air</ENAMEX>
Act in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. Despite significant improvements in air quality
throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> however, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from power generation
continue to result in serious health, environmental and economic
impacts. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the electric power industry was responsible for
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX> emissions, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of nitrogen oxide emissions,
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury emissions</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.


Business as Usual 

The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s flexible, market-based approach to reducing
emissions from power generators stands in sharp contrast to the
complex web of existing regulations which currently confront the
industry. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> have
responded to specific environmental and public health problems by
developing separate regulatory programs to address the specific
problems. Each individual program uses its own approach on its own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">timeline</ENAMEX> to serve its own purpose. Absent changes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> will be forced to follow the same approach in future
regulations. It is time to consolidate and simplify to achieve our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> air goals. A comprehensive legislative approach with
mandatory caps could replace a good portion of the current
regulatory requirements with a system that will reduce the
administrative burden on industry and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, use market-based
approaches to lower compliance costs, reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>' costs, and
increase national energy security by providing the industry with
more certainty about its future regulatory obligations. By enacting
such an approach, we can achieve environmental and public health
protection more effectively and at less cost. If we do it the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s way, it will be a win-win.
There are many regulations in place that will reduce air
emissions from electric power generation. These regulations include
both federal and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> requirements that address a variety of
emissions including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PM10</TIMEX>, and a number of hazardous
air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX>. These programs
include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Ambient Air Quality Standards</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>,
particulate matter and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 126</ENAMEX> and the NOx SIP Call
rules, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Acid Rain Program</ENAMEX>, new source review, new source
performance standards, and the regional haze rule.
But the regulation of power generators does not end with
existing regulations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> is obligated by a settlement agreement to
issue by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2004</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Maximum Achievable Control Technology</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MACT</ENAMEX>) standard to require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>-specific controls of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> and
other hazardous air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> from electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX>. Emissions
reductions are required by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2007</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> will also be
requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> to comply with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Available Retrofit</ENAMEX>
Technology (BART) programs (either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">source</ENAMEX>-specific standards or a
trading program) to meet requirements to reduce regional haze.
It is expected that the existing fine particle and ozone
standards now in place will also result in further regulation of
power generators. Modeling shows that when full implementation of
existing regulations such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> program, the NOx SIP
Call, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tier II</ENAMEX> standards for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, the heavy duty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diesel</ENAMEX> engine standards, and the low <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur gasoline</ENAMEX> and diesel
fuel rules are taken into account, additional reductions will be
needed to bring areas into attainment. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> will be required to
develop plans for these areas. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> reductions
are also needed to reduce continuing damage from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> and
nitrogen deposition.
Because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> will have to find some way to
significantly reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions, it is probable that
power generators will be required to reduce their emissions
significantly. Power generation accounts for a significant
percentage of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, and our analysis shows that there
are significant reductions available at lower cost than from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Additionally, states know that if they do not get the
reductions from power generators, they will have to impose
significant reduction requirements on other local industrial and
commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> or impose local transportation control
measures.
Under current law, the necessary reductions would be achieved
through the development of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> plans. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> will not
just control their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, however. They will be reaching out
to control power generators and large industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> because transport from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> contributes to
both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> and fine particle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> in many areas. This is what
has happened in the eastern part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> when states
realized that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> were
significantly contributing to their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-hour</TIMEX> ozone non-attainment
problems. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 126 of the Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> can
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">petition EPA</ENAMEX> and request that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> require reductions from sources
outside the petitioning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s borders. The petitioning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is
entitled to relief if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> finds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are significantly
contributing to the petitioning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s nonattainment problem.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s requirement, adopted in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 126</ENAMEX> petitions,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in a number of eastern states reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions was
recently upheld by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals for the District of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Circuit</ENAMEX>. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has authority to
address transport pollution through responses to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">126</NUMEX> petitions or
by issuing a rule like the NOx SIP Call, we anticipate that states
will be turning to these types of control approaches early in the
SIP process. Although those of us who are
traveling that path with the current <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">126</NUMEX> petitions and NOx SIP
Call believe it will eventually take us to our environmental goal,
it has been -- and still is -- a very rocky <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> for industry,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>.
This <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-a-time, uncoordinated series of regulatory
requirements for the power industry is not the optimal approach for
the environment, the power generation sector, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. With most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> needing to install control equipment to
meet these requirements, it is likely that this approach would lead
to installation of controls that become obsolete and stranded
capital investments as additional requirements are promulgated.
Further, the attainment efforts of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and localities
not only impose costs on these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, but also can increase
complexity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> which face differing requirements when
operations cross state lines. These factors are exacerbated by
limited timeframes that may constrain available compliance options
and thwart long range planning. These and other inefficiencies
point to the need for a nationally coordinated approach that could
reduce cost while improving environmental progress and
accountability.


Changing the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Way We Do Business: Certainty, Flexibility</ENAMEX>,
Accountability and Innovation 

We believe there is a better way, one that could cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and industry far less than under current law and ensure
protection of the air we breathe in a far more certain,
straightforward manner. I know that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>
share that belief and are also working to develop such an approach.
It would provide power generators with more certainty about their
regulatory future and thus allow them to make wiser decisions about
investments in new technology, which would improve energy security.
This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> is developing such a proposal. It will build on
the successes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> cap and trade program. It would
establish national cap-and-trade programs for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> and mercury
emissions from power generators (with appropriate measures to
address local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>). Such an approach will benefit the power
generation industry, the economy, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, while improving
public health and the environment.
Up-front knowledge of future requirements for multiple
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> would lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to follow significantly different and
less expensive compliance strategies at individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, compared
with compliance choices which must be made as requirements are
addressed in a sequential manner under the current law. The savings
come from the opportunity to make cost-effective <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> investment
and retirement decisions with full knowledge of upcoming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, NOx
and mercury requirements, rather than investing in "add-on" control
equipment to meet the requirements of each regulation. Integration,
advance knowledge, and certainty regarding environmental
requirements will have even greater value over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming decade</TIMEX> as
the electric power industry undergoes further structural changes.
An integrated package of measures that addresses both the existing
regulatory requirements as well as many future environmental needs
would provide the greatest degree of certainty and flexibility for
the industry, while achieving the necessary emission reductions at
lower cost than under current law.
In exchange for flexibility in methods to control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> accounting of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> through
continuous monitoring and reporting is essential, as well as
significant consequences for failing to comply. Such provisions
have been critical to the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Acid Rain Program</ENAMEX>,
encouraging individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to find the most cost-effective
means of compliance with the collective emission reduction
goal.
Flexibility stimulates technological innovation, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> economic
activity and reduces cost to industry and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. Strategies and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> for the control of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions
exist now, and improved methods are expected to become available
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next several years</TIMEX>. The air pollution control and
monitoring technology industry is expected to continue to respond
with cost-effective compliance solutions just as they have done for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 years</TIMEX>. A predictable demand for such jobs over the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> is preferable to the boom and bust cycle created by the
current regulatory approach.
This approach also would reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' administrative burdens
and obligations. A national cap and trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> with appropriate
caps for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> could provide the emission reductions
necessary to bring a significant number of areas into attainment
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> and fine particle standards. Even those areas that
would not be brought into attainment by these caps would need
significantly fewer emission reductions to come into attainment.
Our approach would significantly reduce the state resources needed
to conduct modeling, planning and regulatory activities to attain
the standards. Additionally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> cap and trade program is
administered with a relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> relying on strong,
state-of-the-art data tracking and reporting capabilities. Thus,
well-designed national cap and trade programs can help use
government resources and taxpayer dollars more efficiently at both
the state and federal level.
Caps ensure that environmental goals are met. A cap that
represents significant reductions of emissions protects the
environment by reducing overall loadings. Consideration of local
concerns is important in conjunction with trading provisions.
Therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Energy Plan</ENAMEX> recommended that the
Administration's approach include appropriate measures to address
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, such as the unlikely occurrence of an SO2 "hot
spot" or area of concentrated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>. Significant reductions
will go a long way towards addressing local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. In addition,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> will be conducting modeling that will predict where emissions
reductions will occur. Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> cap and trade program,
we have not seen local hot spots because the highest emitters are
often the most cost-effective to control and therefore, the most
likely to control.
As I mentioned, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> are still in the
process of developing our proposal. Several guidelines are shaping
our efforts. These guidelines may provide a valuable basis as you
weigh the proposals before you. They will also guide our assessment
of other proposals, including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. 556</NUMEX>. These principles are
structured to ensure consistency with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEP</ENAMEX> objectives. The NEP
goals of increasing energy supplies, accelerating the protection
and improvement of the environment, and increasing our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
energy supply must be advanced. Towards that end, energy diversity,
the preservation of electricity generation and transmission
reliability, and improvement of energy
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> efficiency/energy intensity of the electric power industry
should be a key consideration. In particular, to prevent the
reoccurrence of energy shortages and price volatility, a diverse
mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">fuel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> should be maintained.


Specific Comments on S. 556 

We share the desire expressed in S. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">556</NUMEX> to significantly reduce
and cap emissions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> from power generation. We
applaud your acknowledgment of market-based incentives,
particularly cap and trade systems, as a powerful tool in
environmental protection. In this way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S. 556</ENAMEX> builds on successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>.
We do, however, oppose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. 556</NUMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> with the bill
-- both with some provisions that are in the bill and with some
that are missing. We believe the emission reductions and timing in
the bill will be too costly for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and will endanger
national energy security. We believe the bill is missing some
provisions -- it should address the allocation scheme and
integration with existing programs. Finally, we oppose inclusion of
CO2 in this bill.
First, let me explain some of our specific concerns about the
SO2, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, and mercury provisions in the bill. We are concerned that
the significant emissions reductions are required too quickly. We
do not believe it is reasonable to expect all the control
technology installations to be completed in that time frame without
very high costs and electricity reliability problems. To meet these
deadlines, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> may need to be taken off-line during critical
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods</TIMEX>. Reliability problems could arise as large amounts of
capacity are taken out of service for extended periods of time to
install the control <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">equipment</ENAMEX> necessary to meet the emissions
reduction requirements. The abbreviated time frame would force many
generators to make these retrofits simultaneously. This would
significantly reduce the amount of generating capacity available to
meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>' electrical needs.
We have not modeled the specific provisions in S. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">556</NUMEX>, but
useful information is provided by comparing the analyses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX> conducted to respond to a request from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voinovich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownback</ENAMEX> with the analyses responding to a request
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX>. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>/Voinovich/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brownback</ENAMEX> analysis, when we analyzed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> and NOx
reduction levels similar to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. 556</NUMEX>, mercury reduction levels more
modest than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. 556</NUMEX> and no CO2 reductions, we did not find
significant impacts on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> production or electricity prices.
However, in the analysis responding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords/Lieberman</ENAMEX>
request that had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CO2</TIMEX> reduction levels similar
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. 556</NUMEX>, we found significant ramifications: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately</NUMEX> a
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20-30%</NUMEX> decline of coal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30-50%</NUMEX> increase in
electricity prices compared to the reference case (depending on
assumptions of energy technology penetration).
The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> source-specific control for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> is also problematic.
We have not seen anything that demonstrates that every coal-fired
power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> would be able to achieve <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> source-specific controls
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>, without considerable fuel switching, which
would be very disruptive to our economy and undermine energy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>. In addition, requiring the same level of reduction at
a
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that emits <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.1 pounds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that emits
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2000 pounds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> - regardless of cost - is neither efficient
nor necessary.
We are also very concerned about the "outdated power plant"
provision. Requiring every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 30 years old</TIMEX> to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
Source <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Performance Standards</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Source Review</ENAMEX> modification
requirements seems unnecessary and could undermine the benefits of
the cap and trade approach. Allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to make reductions
where it is most economical to do so is one of the reasons cap and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> programs should be less costly than command-and-control
programs that achieve the same or even fewer reductions. When you
have a hard cap, as you would under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. 556</NUMEX>, requiring emission
reductions at a specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> does not reduce the overall level
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX>, it just limits industry's flexibility about where to
make the reductions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Layering</ENAMEX> additional requirements, such as the
"outdated power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>" provision, on top of a cap and trade
program is very likely to increase costs without providing
significant environmental benefits.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, we have concerns about what is not in S. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">556</NUMEX>. Comparing
our experience on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Rain</ENAMEX> Program with the NOx SIP Call and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 126</ENAMEX> petitions demonstrates the benefit of having
certain key issues decided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> rather than left to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemakings</ENAMEX>. Congressional resolution of key issues simplifies
whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> rulemaking is needed and decreases the
opportunities for the program to get tied up in protracted
litigation.
Perhaps the most important program element not addressed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> is integration of this new program with the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air</ENAMEX>
Act provisions. An effective market-based approach would make some
existing provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> unnecessary. For example,
depending on the ultimate cap levels chosen by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, this type
of legislation would obviate the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Available Retrofit</ENAMEX>
Technology requirements, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury MACT</ENAMEX>, and new source review
case-by-case technology requirements for power generators.
Also missing from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. 556</NUMEX> is the scheme for allocating
allowances. Developing an allocation scheme requires answering
numerous questions. Should the allowances be auctioned off or be
handed out for free? If they are not auctioned, should they be
allocated based on heat input or electrical and steam output?
Should power generators that do not emit air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> (e.g.,
hydropower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>) be given allowances? Should allowance
allocations be updated, and if so, how frequently? Should
allocations be fuel neutral? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imbedded</ENAMEX> in these and other questions
are important environmental and energy policy choices with
significant equity consequences. It may not be efficient for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to
make these choices in rulemaking.
There are other issues as well that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> should
consider, such as coordination with existing state and regional
programs like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Regional Air Partnership</ENAMEX> and the NOx
reduction programs in the east. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> may also wish to
consider provisions to track environmental progress to evaluate the
efficacy of the program this bill would establish.
Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> strongly opposes including
reductions for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CO2</TIMEX> in S. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">556</NUMEX> or any multi-pollutant bill. Pursuing
sharp reductions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CO2</TIMEX> from the electricity generating sector
alone would cause a dramatic shift from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> to natural gas and
thus would run the risk of endangering national energy security,
substantially increasing energy prices and harming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> will not support any legislation that would
cause a significant decline in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s ability to use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> as
a major source of current and future electricity. At the same time,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> will not support any legislation that does not
enhance the cleanliness of coal-fired electricity generation and
promote a future for clean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> technologies. In short, the
Administration supports a clean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> policy as a critical component
of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s energy and environmental policies, recognizing that
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of energy also have a critical role to play.
Additionally, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> said when she testified before
you in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CO2</ENAMEX> in this bill will slow down, if not
prevent, the consensus necessary for passage of legislation to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> and
I both believe consensus on the appropriate levels and timing for
reductions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> is achievable relatively soon.
We should not delay the public health and environmental benefits
from reduction of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> while we wait for consensus to
develop on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CO2</TIMEX>.
We agree that climate change is a serious issue we need to
address. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CO2</ENAMEX> has never been regulated as a pollutant under
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> and does not pose any direct threat to human
health unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SO2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX>. The current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of scientific
knowledge does not provide information regarding atmospheric
concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CO2</ENAMEX> or reduction levels necessary to prevent
dangerous interference with the climate system.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> convened a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cabinet-level</ENAMEX> policy review
of this issue and was provided with initial recommendations that he
accepted and announced on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 11</TIMEX>. In that regard, the
Administration is implementing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major initiatives on climate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> and advanced energy and sequestration technologies. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> now spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> on climate science
to reduce uncertainties - a commitment unmatched by any other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Climate Change Technology Initiative</ENAMEX>" will
accelerate priority research and the application of advanced energy
and sequestration technologies, recognizing that the real answer to
addressing climate change in the long term lies in the development
and global introduction of such technologies in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. And
the cabinet-level policy review is ongoing. Finally, as greenhouse
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas emissions</ENAMEX> are projected to grow exponentially in the developing
world in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two decades</TIMEX>, we must evaluate the costs of
imposing domestic reductions as a very high cost against
potentially low-cost opportunities for mitigating and sequestering
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon emissions</ENAMEX> in the developing world.
We appreciate the role of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. 556</NUMEX> in generating important
discussions and emphasizing the importance of a new approach to
controlling emissions in the power sector. I look forward to the
additional hearings you will need to address these important issues
and to working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>
to develop an approach that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> can support.
The history of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act legislation</ENAMEX> is one of great
accomplishments made possible by bipartisan efforts. I thank you
for the opportunity to work with you to continue that great
tradition.



