



<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EXECUTIVE SUMMARY - THE CLEAR SKIES INITIATIVE</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 14, 2002</TIMEX>
Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> proposed the most significant step America
has ever taken to cut power plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, the Clear Skies
Initiative. This new proposal will aggressively reduce air
pollution from electricity generators and improve air quality
throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clear Skies Initiative</ENAMEX> will cut air
pollution <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX>, using a proven, market-based approach that
will save <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> needs a clean, secure, affordable, reliable energy
supply in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> ahead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has often said that
environmental protection and energy production are not competing
priorities. This progressive plan shows how that objective can be
reached. We can meet our environmental goals while providing
affordable electricity for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has made great progress in reducing air pollution. Over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three decades</TIMEX>, air pollution has declined by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29 percent</NUMEX>,
while our economy has grown <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 160 percent</NUMEX>. These gains have
provided cleaner air for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Our understanding of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX>, technology, and markets has improved since the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air</ENAMEX>
Act was passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. We know more about the best way to reduce
pollution, and how to do it cost effectively. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> cap and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> program created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> reduced more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last decade</TIMEX> than all other <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> command-and-control
programs combined, and achieved significant reductions at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the cost to accomplish those reductions using a
"command-and-control" system. It's time to take the best of what we
have learned and modernize the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>. That's why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is proposing a new <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clear Skies Initiative</ENAMEX> will:

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dramatically Cut Power Plants' Emissions of Three of the Worst</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Pollutants</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ï¿½ Cut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SO2</NUMEX>) emissions by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX>, from current
emissions of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11 million tons</NUMEX> to a cap of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4.5 million tons</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>,
and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 million tons</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2018</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ï¿½ Cut</ENAMEX> emissions of nitrogen oxides (NOx) by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67 percent</NUMEX>, from
current emissions of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 million tons</NUMEX> to a cap of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.1 million tons</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX>, and to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.7 million tons</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2018</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ï¿½ Cutting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69 percent</NUMEX>, -the first-ever
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> cap on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions. Emissions will be cut from
current emissions of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">48 tons</NUMEX> to a cap of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">26 tons</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2018</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ï¿½ Emission</ENAMEX> caps will be set to account for different air quality
needs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> and the West.


Use A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">New, Market-Based Approach To Clean Air</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ï¿½ Protect Americans</ENAMEX> from respiratory and cardiovascular diseases
by dramatically reducing smog, fine particulate matter, regional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">haze</ENAMEX>; and protect wildlife habitat and ecosystem health from acid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rain</ENAMEX>, nitrogen and mercury deposition. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2</ENAMEX> emissions both
contribute to fine particulate matter emissions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> also
contributes to ground-level ozone or smog.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ï¿½ Save Americans</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $1 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> in compliance
costs that are passed along to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, while improving
air quality and protecting the reliability and affordability of
electricity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ï¿½ Cut</ENAMEX> pollution further, faster, cheaper - and with more
certainty - eliminating the need for expensive and uncertain
litigation as a means of achieving clean air.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ï¿½ Build</ENAMEX> upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1990 Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> program,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most successful clean air law in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>, and
encourage the use of new pollution control technologies.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has a strong track record on enacting
far-reaching clean air initiatives. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
signed legislation that permanently caps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SO2 emissions</ENAMEX> from
older power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. The legislation was
widely hailed as a model for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> program is
designed to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">75,000 tons</NUMEX> per year, and SO2
emissions by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35,000 tons</NUMEX> per year, while giving utilities
flexibility in determining how and where to achieve the
reductions.


This approach enjoys strong, bipartisan support throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should pass legislation to establish a flexible,
market-based program to significantly reduce and cap emissions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX>, nitrogen oxides, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> and voluntary reductions
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> from electric power generators. The legislation
should provide regulatory certainty by establishing reduction
targets for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, phasing in reductions over a reasonable
period of time and providing market-based incentives such as
emissions-trading credits to help achieve the required
reductions."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August, 2001</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Council of the States</ENAMEX> approved a resolution in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February, 2001</TIMEX>, supporting a cost-effective, efficient and
environmentally protective multi-pollutant proposal.



<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BACKGROUND ï¿½</ENAMEX> THE SUCCESS OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CLEAN AIR ACT</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">POLLUTION HAS DECLINED BY 29 PERCENT WHILE OUR ECONOMY</ENAMEX> HAS GROWN
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">NEARLY 160 PERCENT</ENAMEX>
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> emit significant amounts of air
pollution: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SO2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury emissions</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of all nitrogen oxide
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX>) emissions. These pollutants contribute to a variety of health
and environmental problems, such as smog, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>, nitrogen
deposition and visibility impairment.
Current law addresses each of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> independently, on
different timetables, through several different programs. These
laws are uncoordinated and often inconsistent. Power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> might
install equipment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> that is rendered obsolete the next.
Implementation and enforcement usually requires years of
litigation, leaving the fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s air to the uncertainties
of the courtroom.
After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> of experience in regulating air pollution,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has proved that there is a better way to accomplish our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> air goals.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1990 Clean Air Act Amendments</ENAMEX>, proposed and signed into law
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George H.W. Bush</ENAMEX>, have significantly reduced air
pollution, especially through the innovative "cap-and trade" acid
rain control program. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> program has been a resounding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>, cutting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX> emissions in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phase
by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> below allowed levels. Emissions were reduced faster
than required, and at far less cost. Industry compliance has been
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 100 percent</NUMEX>, and the program only requires a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to operate. This approach is vastly more effective, and
cheaper - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> cheaper - than the traditional
"command-and-control" approach.
This program is clearly a model for success. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
wants to expand this program to include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> -
nitrogen oxides and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> - while also dramatically reducing the
SO2 emissions allowed by current law.


THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CLEAR SKIES INITIATIVE ï¿</ENAMEX>½ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BUILDING</ENAMEX> ON THE <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CLEAN AIR ACT</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clear Skies Initiative</ENAMEX> is designed to help us
meet our national air quality goals. A new <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st century</TIMEX> must build on this founding principle -modernization
and better technology will mean a progressive new way to accomplish
these long-standing environmental goals. The Clear Skies Initiative
will continue to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ï¿½ Improved Air Quality</ENAMEX>: Reducing air pollution will bring clean
air to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, saving them from smog
(ground-level ozone) and fine particulate matter (dust) that cause
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">respiratory</ENAMEX> and cardiovascular distress.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ï¿½ Improved Health</ENAMEX>: Reducing emissions of fine particulate matter
will prolong <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of lives and prevent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of new cases
of chronic bronchitis, hospitalizations and emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> visits.
Reducing the formation of ground-level ozone, or smog, will bring
healthier air to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and reduce the number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX>-related health problems such as respiratory infection,
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma attacks</ENAMEX>, and chronic lung damage. Reducing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> emissions
will reduce the risk of toxic effects from mercury exposure to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> exposed during their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s pregnancy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ï¿½ Better Environmental Protection</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Acid Rain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smog, Haze</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nitrogen Deposition: Reducing SO2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions
will save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of northeastern lakes and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">acres</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>, particularly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adirondacks</ENAMEX>
and other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Appalachian Mountains</ENAMEX>. It will also improve
visibility over much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, particularly the scenic vistas
in national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> such the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX>. Reducing emissions of
nitrogen oxides will also reduce nitrogen deposition in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
improving coastal ecosystem health along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> coasts.
Reducing mercury <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> will reduce mercury deposition in lakes
and streams.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ï¿½ Secure, Affordable Power: The Clear Skies Initiative</ENAMEX> will keep
electricity costs low for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> by saving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $1 billion</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> in compliance costs. Power generators will have the
flexibility to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> in the most cost-effective way. It
will also encourage the continual improvement in technology to
reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from coal-fired power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in concert with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Coal Technology</ENAMEX> program and incentives
for power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that install "scrubbers" early in the program.
Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clear Skies Initiative</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> will continue to have a
diverse fuel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mix</ENAMEX> that ensures a reliable, affordable energy
supply.


HOW THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLEAR SKIES INITIATIVE WORKS</ENAMEX>
To improve air quality for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, the Clear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Skies Initiative</ENAMEX> will adopt the lessons learned from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> of
environmental regulation by:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Establishing <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Emission Reduction Targets</ENAMEX>, Based on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sound</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Science, That Will Significantly Improve Air Quality, Protecting</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Health</ENAMEX>: By reducing air pollution, and
conducting constant monitoring of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, the Clear Skies
Initiative guarantees that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> will meet
ambitious air quality goals, even as they bring new power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> on
line to meet growing demand. During the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phase, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Administrator</ENAMEX> will review new scientific, technology and cost
information and, if necessary, adjust the phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. This
will include a vigorous research program to further understand the
fate and transport of pollutants in the atmosphere.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Adopting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Multi</ENAMEX>-Pollutant
Approach: By reducing emissions of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of air
pollution at the same time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clear Skies Initiative</ENAMEX> will produce
environmental results more effectively and efficiently than the
current labyrinth of overlapping and uncoordinated single-pollutant
requirements. The current approach is inefficient and ineffective,
imposing unnecessarily high costs due to: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) stranded capital
investments from the installation of controls that later become
obsolete when additional requirements are promulgated; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) reduced
lead time for complying with those requirements; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) limited or
non-existent flexibility for emissions trading to allow
cost-efficient control options; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) a reliance upon lengthy,
expensive, and uncertain litigation to sort out regulatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambiguity</ENAMEX> and compliance with the law.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Improving Environmental Performance at Lower Cost Using</ENAMEX>
Market-Based <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mechanisms That Create Incentives for Innovation:</ENAMEX>
Using the market-based mechanism of a cap-and-trade program, the
Clear Skies Initiative will establish national, federally
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">enforceable</ENAMEX> emissions limits for each pollutant. Allowances are
distributed to electricity generators, and the cap declines at
specific intervals, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>, and then again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2018</TIMEX>. Generators
respond by gradually reducing their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> - reducing more than
the cap requires early in the program in order to save allowances
for use later in the program when the caps decline. That is,
generators respond to declining allowance caps just like people
respond to declining income when they're planning for retirement:
they do more now, investing and saving for the future. Individual
generators can choose when to reduce their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> in response to
their particular circumstances and the price of allowances they see
in the market. This encourages the least expensive reductions over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> as well as across <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>.
At this point, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> only has to enforce the emission
limits, distribute allowances and verify that each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> has
sufficient allowances for their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> emissions. There's no need
for lengthy, costly, uncertain litigation to enforce the law.
Creative, innovative strategies to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> are immediately
rewarded: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> save money by finding innovative ways to
reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> more than a command-and-control law would require.
This creates an incentive for continual improvement in
environmental performance.
The flexibility in the process of allocating emission credits or
allowances will also accommodate the different air quality needs in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> and the West while preserving fair competition. Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have already made significant headway in identifying future
SO2 reductions necessary to meet air quality goals in the Western
Regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Partnership</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"WRAP"</ENAMEX>) agreement between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>, industry and environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. SO2 allocations
will track this agreement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> reduction caps for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> and West
will also be set to accommodate these different needs, and separate
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> trading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> will be created.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Ensuring a secure, affordable energy supply: By setting firm
caps while offering flexibility in how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> can meet those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caps</ENAMEX>, the Clear Skies Initiative preserves a diverse fuel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mix</ENAMEX> that
supports economic growth with reasonably priced energy. The firm
caps and the adequate lead time create a predictable climate for
long-term planning and capital investment in power generation,
which will ensure an adequate energy supply. This will also create
substantial cost savings to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>.


THE <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CAP AND TRADE SYSTEM</ENAMEX> IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CLEAR SKIES INITIATIVE</ENAMEX>

HOW DOES IT WORK?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clear Skies Initiative</ENAMEX> will deliver substantial health and
environmental benefits through a market-based approach that rewards
innovation, reduces costs, and ensures results. Instead of the
government telling electricity generators precisely where and how
to reduce their emissions
- the old command-and-control approach - this market-based
program tells them when and how much to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> by
establishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, maximum "cap" on emissions. The trading
program creates incentives for electricity generators to reduce
their emissions even more than the law requires, and more quickly
than required. Electricity generators must hold an "allowance" for
each <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ton</NUMEX> of pollution they emit - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ton, one allowance. The
government controls the number of allowances that are distributed
and reduces them over time. Electricity generators must continually
monitor and report their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>.
Most importantly, these allowances can be traded freely. That
means that if you're smart and creative, and you figure out a
better way to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, you get rewarded by making those
reductions and selling unneeded allowances in the market. And, if
you unexpectedly can't reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> as much as planned, you
have the flexibility to go out and buy more allowances in the
market - all without any government interference, and without
undermining air quality. This flexibility lets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> figure
out the cheapest way to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> sticks to
setting the overall emission cap at a level that guarantees that
industry meets ambitious air quality goals.


WHY DOES IT WORK?
The cap ensures that the reductions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOx</ENAMEX> and mercury
required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clear Skies Initiative</ENAMEX> are achieved and maintained
over time even as new power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> are built. The open trading
program gives power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> the flexibility to choose how they meet
their target emission reductions, which minimizes compliance costs
and lowers consumer electricity prices.


WHAT ARE THE RESULTS?
Cost savings 
- The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> cap and trade program passed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> achieved reductions at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> the cost of
achieving the same reductions under a command-and-control system.
This program reduced more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX> than all
other <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> command-and-control programs combined during
the same period.
Innovation 
- Trading under the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> program created
financial incentives for electricity generators to look for new and
low-cost ways to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> and to do so early.
Integrity 
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-The acid rain</ENAMEX> cap and trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> has high
accountability and transparency. Electricity generators must
install monitors to prove that they have sufficient allowances to
match their actual emissions.
Regional Effect 
- The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> program resulted in emission
reductions well below the cap in the areas that contribute most of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Comparing emissions</ENAMEX> from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">263</NUMEX> power
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> regulated in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phase of the program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> with
those in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Central</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX> and Mid-Atlantic
regions achieved <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent and 43 percent</NUMEX> reductions
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SO2</TIMEX> respectively. Several analyses of trading under the acid
rain program have concluded that the program did not result in
local areas with higher emission levels ("hot spots").
Guaranteed Results 
- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Acid Rain</ENAMEX> program enjoys <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 100</NUMEX>
percent compliance and only takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to run - a track
record no command-and-control program can meet. Reductions in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX> averaged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> below the required cap. Emission
cuts resulted in air quality improvements over a broad area of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and significant reductions in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>.


Emissions <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Power Plants in the First Phase of the Acid Rain</ENAMEX>
Program
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 9 8 7 6 5 4 3 2 1 0</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sulfur dioxide emissions</ENAMEX> were far below allowable levels during
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phase I.</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1980 1985 1990 1995 1996 1997 1998 1999</ENAMEX>

WHAT THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">EXPERTS</ENAMEX> SAY ABOUT THE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACID RAIN CAP</ENAMEX> AND TRADE
PROGRAM
"The data confirm a general prediction about cap-and-trade
programs, that they will tend to create incentives for the dirtiest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> to clean up the most, as the per-ton cost of emissions
reductions may be expected to be the least. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">â€¦The</ENAMEX> data show that, if
anything, trading may be expected to cool hot spots and not create
them."
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron Swift</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Law Institute</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Allowance Trading</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Potential Hot Spots - Good News from the Acid Rain Program</ENAMEX>" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environment Reporter</ENAMEX>, pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">954-959</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12, 2000</TIMEX>.
"The superior environmental and economic results of ...the
Program are precisely what should have been expected of a program
that matched an explicit emissions limit with a market that turned
pollution reductions into marketable assets."
--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From "Obstacle to Opportunity: How Acid Rain Emissions Trading</ENAMEX>
is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Delivering Cleaner Air</ENAMEX>", <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Defense</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2000</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 2</ENAMEX>.
"The flexibility of the trading program has encouraged utilities
to capitalize on advantageous trends, such as changing fuel prices
and technological innovation that might have been delayed or
discouraged by traditional regulatory approaches."
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curtis Carlson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burtraw, et al.</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sulfur Dioxide</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control By Electric Utilities</ENAMEX>: What are the Gains from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX>?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1998</TIMEX>, Revised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2000</TIMEX>.
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">The</ENAMEX>] simplicity [of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program</ENAMEX>] has kept transaction costs
low and helped to create efficiencies that might otherwise not
exist."
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Chartier</ENAMEX>, Former <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Emission Trading</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Testimony</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1997</TIMEX>.
"This grand experiment [emissions trading under the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Acid Rain</ENAMEX>
Program] has demonstrated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can be effective and
non-intrusive."
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Ellerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts Institute of</ENAMEX>
Technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Energy and Environmental Policy Research</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Economics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1998</TIMEX>.




