



<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section G</ENAMEX>:
Summary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Models</ENAMEX> used for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX>



Description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated Planning</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model</ENAMEX> (IPM)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Analytical Framework</ENAMEX> of IPM
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• EPA</ENAMEX> uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated Planning</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model</ENAMEX> (IPM) to analyze the
projected impact of environmental policies on the electric power
sector in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> contiguous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>.
Developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICF Resources Incorporated</ENAMEX> and used to support public
and private sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPM</ENAMEX> is a multi-regional, dynamic,
deterministic linear programming model of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> electric power
sector.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• The</ENAMEX> model provides forecasts of least-cost capacity
expansion, electricity dispatch, and emission control strategies
for meeting energy demand and environmental, transmission,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dispatch</ENAMEX>, and reliability constraints. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPM</ENAMEX> can be used to evaluate
the cost and emissions impacts of proposed policies to limit
emissions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SO2</NUMEX>), nitrogen oxides (NOx), carbon
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dioxide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CO2</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX>) from the electric power
sector.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• IPM</ENAMEX> was a key analytical tool in developing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s
Clear Skies proposal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">IPM Is Well Suited to Model Multi-Emission Control Programs</ENAMEX>
• Among the factors that make IPM particularly well suited to
model multi-emissions control programs are (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) its ability to
capture complex interactions among the electric power, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>, and
environmental markets, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) its detail-rich representation of
emission control options encompassing a broad array of retrofit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> along with emission reductions through fuel switching,
changes in capacity mix, and electricity dispatch strategies, and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) its capability to model a variety of environmental market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mechanisms</ENAMEX>, such as emissions caps, allowances, trading, and
banking.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• IPM</ENAMEX> is particularly well suited for modeling Clear Skies
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> relies on the operation of an allowance market,
the availability of a broad range of emissions reduction options,
and empowerment of economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> to achieve emission limits.
Extensive documentation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPM</ENAMEX> is available at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">epa.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/airmarkets/epa-ipm/</ENAMEX>index.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Description of Air Quality Modeling</ENAMEX>
• The results for fine particle concentrations, visibility,
sulfur deposition, and nitrogen deposition are based on the
Regional <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Modeling System for Aerosols and Deposition</ENAMEX> (REMSAD).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">• REMSAD is an Eulerian</ENAMEX> air quality model developed to simulate
regional-scale distributions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, formation, transport, and
removal processes for fine particles and other airborne <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX>.
This analysis used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REMSAD</ENAMEX> version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.4</NUMEX> with meteorological inputs
previously developed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mesoscale Meteorological</ENAMEX>
Model (MM-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>).
• The results for ozone concentrations are based on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive Air Quality</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model with Extensions</ENAMEX> (CAMx).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">• CAMx is an Eulerian</ENAMEX> air quality model developed to simulate
local and regional-scale distributions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, formation
transport, and removal processes for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> and other photochemical
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX>. This analysis used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAMx</ENAMEX> version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.1</NUMEX> with meteorological
inputs previously developed using the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Regional Atmospheric Modeling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">System</ENAMEX> (RAMS) for episodes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1995</TIMEX>.
• The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated Planning</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model</ENAMEX> (IPM) was used to derive all
future projections of electricity generation source emissions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">• Emissions</ENAMEX> inputs for non-electric generating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REMSAD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAMx</ENAMEX> were derived from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Emissions</ENAMEX>
Inventory (NEI). In addition, inventories prepared for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heavy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duty Diesel Engine</ENAMEX> rulemaking were the basis for future year
emissions projections.
• For the most part, the modeling results are analyzed in terms
of the change in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">future year</TIMEX> air quality relative to predictions
under baseline conditions. In this way, effects of any
uncertainties in emissions forecasts and air quality modeling are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">minimized</ENAMEX>.
• Results for projected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> PM2.5 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8-hour</TIMEX> ozone
nonattainment were determined by "rolling back" current air quality
levels. This was based on the change in air quality between the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> Base <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each future year</TIMEX> scenario. Since no ozone
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">modeling</ENAMEX> was performed for the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, future ozone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonattainment</ENAMEX> in the West was determined through an emissions
scaling analysis that used forecast changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NOx</ENAMEX> emissions in the
West coupled with the response of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> to emissions changes, as
modeled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">• Maps</ENAMEX> which display the impacts on PM2.5 concentrations and
deposition are reported as a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> reduction. A positive percent
reduction (e.g. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX>) is a decrease in concentration or deposition
compared to current conditions (an improvement); a negative percent
reduction (e.g. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-30%</NUMEX>) is an increase in concentration or deposition
compared to current conditions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">• Visibility</ENAMEX> results are reported as a change in deciviews.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect</ENAMEX>" visibility is represented by a deciview of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, so a
decrease in deciview is an increase or improvement in visibility.
An increase in deciview is a decrease in visibility.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Description of Benefits Modeling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">• The Criteria Air Pollutant Modeling System</ENAMEX> (CAPMS) is used to
quantify human health benefits due to the changes in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>'s
exposure to fine particulate matter and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX>.
• Using the air quality modeling results, the change in
pollutant concentration based on modeling for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPMS</ENAMEX> grid cell
is determined. This is the level at which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> living in
that grid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> is assumed to be exposed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">• Concentration</ENAMEX>-response functions from epidemiological studies
are applied to each grid cell to predict the changes in incidences
of health outcomes (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">e.g. asthma attacks</ENAMEX>) that would occur with the
projected changes in air quality.
• The grid cells are aggregated to estimate the health impact
of the change in air quality across the study region.
• The estimated economic value of an avoided health outcome
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">e.g. $41</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma attack</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>) is multiplied by total change in
events to determine the health benefits of air quality improvements
for the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>.
• For visibility, benefits were calculated based on changes in
fine particle concentrations, presented as deciviews, which are
provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REMSAD</ENAMEX> air quality model.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">• Individuals</ENAMEX> place a value on visibility improvements in
recreational areas, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Parks</ENAMEX> and wilderness
areas
• The economic value that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> place on improved visibility
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> that they visit a Class I area is applied to the predicted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deciview</ENAMEX> changes and projected number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> affected to
attain recreational visibility monetary benefits.


Description of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freshwater Modeling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• The Model of Acidification</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groundwater</ENAMEX> in Catchments
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MAGIC</ENAMEX>) is used to examine changes in surface freshwater chemistry
as indicated by changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> neutralizing capacity (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANC</ENAMEX>) in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waterbody</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• ANC</ENAMEX> represents the ability of a lake or stream to neutralize,
or buffer, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>. The condition of a lake or stream improves as the
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANC</ENAMEX> increases, moving from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chronically acidic �</ENAMEX> episodically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acidic �</ENAMEX> not acidic.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">• Episodically</ENAMEX> acidic lakes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANC</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0-50 µeq/l</ENAMEX>) have a greater
capacity to neutralize acid deposition than chronically acidic
ones. However, these lakes remain susceptible to becoming
chronically acidic if acid deposition increases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">• Watershed characteristics</ENAMEX> (e.g., soils, bedrock type,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geologic</ENAMEX> history) affect the rate of water chemistry response to
acid deposition.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">•</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> response" lakes or streams manifest changes more
quickly, whereas "delayed response" lakes or streams manifest
changes over a longer period of time.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• MAGIC</ENAMEX> results show the distribution of lakes and streams (by
percentage) over the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANC</ENAMEX> classes
• <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> regions were modeled (the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adirondacks</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>
(including the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adirondacks</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX>).
• Results are reported for current conditions (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>) and in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2030</TIMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Base Case</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clear Skies Act</ENAMEX>.
Results are based on a model called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Model</ENAMEX> of Acidification
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groundwater</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Catchments</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MAGIC</ENAMEX>) used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Acid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Precipitation Assessment Program</ENAMEX> (NAPAP) to estimate the long-term
effects of acidic deposition (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur</ENAMEX>) on lakes and streams. The
model simulates the size of the pool of exchangeable base cations
in the soil. As the fluxes to and from the pool change over time
due to changes in atmospheric deposition, the chemical equilibria
between soil and soil solution shift to give changes in surface
water chemistry. Changes in surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> chemistry are
characterized by changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acid Neutralizing Capacity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANC</ENAMEX>) - the
ability of a waterbody to neutralize strong <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> added from
atmospheric deposition.


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Description of the Technology Retrofit and Updating Model</ENAMEX>

Uses of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Technology Retrofit and Updating Model</ENAMEX>
• At this time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPM</ENAMEX> does not model price elasticity of demand
and the effect of multiple allowance allocation mechanisms. To
study the effect of these variables on electricity prices and
markets, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICF</ENAMEX> developed a macro-driven spreadsheet program termed
the "technology retrofit and updating model."
• The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is used to discern trends in marginal costs and
retrofits, the approximate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnitudes</ENAMEX> of those trends, and the
reasons for those trends.
Modeling Approach
• The technology retrofit and updating model consists of a set
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately six hundred</NUMEX> "sample" generating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> with varying
characteristics. The mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation types</ENAMEX> and sizes was chosen
to mirror, in general terms, the nationwide mix of capacities. Each
unit is assumed to choose emission control retrofit options, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> levels so as to maximize its own net profit in
response to fuel prices, emission allowance prices, and prices of
electricity for various demand segments. Prices of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> can be
adjusted in the model in response to demand; prices of electricity
by demand segment is set in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> so as to meet demand; and
allowance prices can be adjusted to cause the industry to meet
given caps.
• To simulate the effects of demand elasticity, the quantity of
electricity demanded in each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> can be set as a function of
electricity prices using an elasticity value that is entered as an
input to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. Finally, to simulate the effects of allowance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">updating</ENAMEX>, the value of reallocated allowances can be calculated and
subtracted from each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>'s cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> - thereby inducing
each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> to change its profit-maximizing level of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> in
response to a given set of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>, allowance, and electricity prices.
Readjusting the allowance prices to meet the same emission caps
then generates results showing the costs of meeting given caps with
and without updating.
• An important limitation of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is that it does not
simulate changes over time in the demand for electricity, prices,
technology, or other factors considered within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPM</ENAMEX>. Instead, it is
run as though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> is the same as every other year and is
therefore static in its outlook. In addition, it does not recognize
the distinctions among electricity demand regions and the
transmission constraints that can keep them separate. Thus, only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> price of electricity is determined for each demand segment for
the entire set of sample <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>.


Description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retail Electricity Price Model</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primary Attributes</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• The Model</ENAMEX> provides a forecast of average retail electricity
prices from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005 to 2020</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> regions and the contiguous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>,
and considers areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) will have competitive
pricing of power generation and, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) are likely to price retail
power based on a cost-of-service basis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• Combines IPM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX> information with data from the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Research Institute</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Advanced Energy</ENAMEX>
Markets regarding the restructuring of the power industry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">• "Main Case</ENAMEX>" is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s forecast of "likely deregulation"
considering areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that should price generation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for retail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> competitively and those that most
likely to use cost-of-service pricing principles.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• The Model</ENAMEX> readily analyzes alternative multi-pollutant and
base case scenarios modeled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPM</ENAMEX>, alternative assumptions on
deregulation and future savings/costs, and the implications of
different allowance allocation approaches. The strongest
application of the Calculator occurs from examining the relative
price differences between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or more</NUMEX> scenarios.
The Limitations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model Include</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• The Model</ENAMEX> combines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIA</ENAMEX> cost elements that use similar
-- but not identical -- assumptions on capital recovery and
aggregate cost data in a similar -- but not identical -- regional
manner that needs adjustment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• The Model</ENAMEX> assumes public and private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> seek the same
return and have the same tax treatment, which overstates prices in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> where there are large amounts of public power.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• The Model</ENAMEX> focuses on major costs. It assumes for
cost-of-service areas (where most of power sales are likely to
occur) that allowance allocations will not alter pricing of
electricity.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• Uses EIA</ENAMEX>'s limited (but best available) data in some areas
(e.g. rate base with stranded assets).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• The Model</ENAMEX> cannot address the uncertainty of deregulation
created by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s experience -- where competition may
increase or decrease in the future. With the phasing in of
competition and limited experience, the full benefits and costs of
deregulation still remain unknown.



