
   
   
      
         
            More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffee and Less</ENAMEX> Coffey

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
both lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s admission <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that she was "mad" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> because she wasn't told in a timely manner about the coffee videos. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the destruction wrought in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Acapulco</ENAMEX> by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">hurricane</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s interest rate increase.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s remarks were "an extraordinary public
critique" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> admitted that the video controversy has
strained relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in its front page <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>
piece, says she has just completed "one of the most humiliating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> in her
tenure." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> is
considering holding hearings on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s conduct of the fund-raising inquiry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes further, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> "would hold a hearing." Just what we
need now: not just another investigation, but an investigation of an
investigation.

            The top-front-page picture used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> to illustrate its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>
story is also an illustration of how in general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> use photos with news
stories. It's a shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> sitting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>
has her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> turned completely away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, which is natural enough,
since they are listening to a speech, but the posture looks chilly. And that's
why it's there--after all, certainly there were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> immediately before and
after this one in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> shook hands and spoke to each
other.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's lead says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s decision to raise its basic
interest rate "sent shivers around the world." But none of the other majors
felt a thing: none of them led with the story nor even gave it any front-page
space.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> decision to lead with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> deaths caused in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort city</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurricane Pauline</ENAMEX> was not quite as lonely--the storm is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lead and tops the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's world-wide news digest--but was no
doubt influenced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> demographic. Incidentally, for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> running, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is running a complete page (about the soccer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Cup</ENAMEX> qualifying round) in the sports section in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>. This is
apparently a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> for a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, and for good or ill, probably
the start of a trend.

            The LAT front covers what it calls the unexpected departure of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby Coffey</ENAMEX>, who is described in the piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Willes</ENAMEX>, the
recently named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> of the paper, as "a truly remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> presents a little different picture in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> piece on the
situation. "'Shelby told me he's been through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> and doesn't want
to do this anymore,' said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro Editor Leo Wolinsky</ENAMEX>. 'He's used to running the
newsroom his way, and generally speaking he's been allowed to do that. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
intends to get involved with everything. . . . He's thrown a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hand grenade</ENAMEX> into
the middle of the system. He's blowing up what we have.'" Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> veteran
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tells Kurtz</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> is "convinced the newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> is filled with a
lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dopes</ENAMEX> who have let the business deteriorate."

            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyn Nofziger</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, bristles at
the suggestion made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> raised
money in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> too. Writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nofziger</ENAMEX>: "I have talked to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who served as his personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> during his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> in office, and each one is adamant that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> never phoned for
or personally solicited money. That coincides with my own knowledge of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ooops</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a transcription of a
solicitation made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Room</ENAMEX> at a gathering of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, who in response contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
