
   
   
      
         
            Jung for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Time</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the victory of long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Dae Jung</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> presidential election. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s official announcement of the long-rumored
decision to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> indefinitely.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> vote the most remarkable in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
history, pointing out that upon his inauguration, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">73</TIMEX>, will take over a
government that kidnapped and jailed him and repeatedly tried to kill him, once
by planning to toss him off a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> at sea. The LAT observes that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> has often been compared to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrei Sakharov</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lech Walesa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that
the victory celebrations were particularly joyous in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwangju</ENAMEX>, where
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> suppressed pro-democracy demonstrations, killing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>, and blamed the episode on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>, who was sentenced to death (he was
eventually given a medical release to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>). And now, points out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> will have the power to pardon the imprisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ex-president</ENAMEX> convicted of ordering that massacre.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stresses more than the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> that a big factor
in the election outcome was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> enraged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s financial
crisis and furious at economic mismanagement by the ruling party. The
Times adds to the picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> as the ultimate outcast by relating
how, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as the mid-80s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> viewed him as too radical to
invite to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual 4th of July</TIMEX> party.

            The papers all note that upon his victory, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> pledged to implement the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>-crafted economic bailout that was already agreed to by the current
government.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Bosnia</ENAMEX> announcement is also front-page news at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . The coverage emphasizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frank</ENAMEX> admission that he was wrong to have set a definite timetable for getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> out. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> stated that the military mission had enforced a fragile
peace but that it was still fragile and so, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s exit
thinking, deadlines are out and "benchmarks" gauging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>'s progress are in.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s off-the-cuff examples of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">benchmarks</ENAMEX> did not include the return of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> or the arrest of those
indicted as war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT front reports that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> national security
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Heslin</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> to provide intelligence
on several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> despite a presidential order banning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> from
doing so. The paper bases its story on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> documents.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's lead feature focuses on a group of
single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> housing project who have been thrust by welfare
reform into the workplace for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very first time</TIMEX>. The piece shows how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have become rather harsh in
their attitudes towards welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>. "It makes me mad," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, "Taking
money out of my check and giving it to those ho's." The story also shows that
even a steady job doesn't automatically translate into financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the story has only been able to save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> of
employment, but she did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Karan</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four-foot</NUMEX> TV/VCR <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>,
wall-to-wall carpet, and a stocked fish <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX>.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snapshot</ENAMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13.7 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> ended
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> with a total household income below the federal poverty level of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,036</NUMEX>
for a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>.

            In a rarity for a front-section story, not to mention for the front page,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> comes right out and says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Chase-Riboud</ENAMEX>, the woman
who accused "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dreamworks</ENAMEX>, (hey, what do Katzenberg
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geffen</ENAMEX> have to do to get their names in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>?) of stealing from her
work in making the movie "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amistad</ENAMEX>," is herself a plagiarist. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says that a novel she
wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> contains entire passages from a scholarly book that preceded it
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX>.

            Remember "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.B. King</ENAMEX>'s guitar? Well, guess who has it now?
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>. King handed it over during a papal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            
               No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Freeh pizza</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that the most common fake name
given to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza deliverers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> is...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
