
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>: Done

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> recall of apparently dangerous diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
Times , and is the top item in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business and Finance</ENAMEX>" news
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digest</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX>'s decision to abandon his quest for the ambassadorship to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and is the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> story at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . (The LAT
plays it on the front too, but below the fold.)

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s request, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyeth-Ayerst Laboratories</ENAMEX> withdrew fenfluramine, half
of the wildly popular "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">fen-phen</ENAMEX>," and also dexfenfluramine, which is marketed
as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redux</ENAMEX>." The request came because of new findings from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that
indicated use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> was correlated with serious abnormalities in
heart valves, a suspicion <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> revealed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> and in the press last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">291</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> evaluated exhibited
the valve problems. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> also recommended that dieters stop using any of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they have and contact their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that the drugs
were prescribed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20 million</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> makes the
extent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>' use a little clearer, stating that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 300,000</NUMEX> people
are taking each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes an obesity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> expressing the
worry that these developments will hinder the general development and marketing
of weight control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> makes the same point, but by quoting fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expressing it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' consensus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> pull-out is that he never had much of a
chance, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s support for him once the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> problem
presented itself was lukewarm at best, and that the source of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>'s enmity
was never completely clear. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> views the whole quixotic episode as
indicative of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s ulterior pursuit of some other greater political
goal--either a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> or presidential bid down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>--a claim the paper
makes both in its news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> and in an editorial. The paper quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>
as saying that he thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> had successfully used the attempt to become the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> floats the view that the dispute was on balance a plus for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, saying that several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> were delighted at the
fissures inside <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ranks it opened up.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a front-page piece about an emerging national
trend--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">close</NUMEX>-in parking spaces at retail locations for expectant and new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, known as "stork parking." And it's not just a voluntary trend. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dade County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, passed an ordinance last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of its kind in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> with more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> parking spaces to provide <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> spots for "stroller parking."

            There's also an emerging national backlash. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that some reject
the suggestion that pregnancy is a disability, while others wonder why parents
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should receive a special benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> do not. "How about
special parking zones for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers</ENAMEX> who need to lug heavy golf bags to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">clubhouse?</ENAMEX>" is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> irate response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dade</ENAMEX> measure the paper quotes. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also comments that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> don't think pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> need special
access, and in fact, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> advise them to park far away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, for
the extra exercise.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week</ENAMEX>" reports that flag and touch football have
become very big at many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Maybe a little too big. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> wrote an
entire playbook and spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> on a practice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEC Corp.</ENAMEX> pulled
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>, citing too many injuries.

         
      
   
