
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> and Out at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> tax cut. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>'s approval of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>'s reforms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the adverse affect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
downturn is expected to have on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> economy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
hears a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> and leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s warning to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> that no option for dealing with him is off the table.

            The main news of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
announced a surprise tax cut as part of its self-bailout package. The temporary
tax cut, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> explains, is an about-face for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX>,
who had recently staked his political reputation on reducing his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
budget deficit. The initial reaction was favorable, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> stock
prices went up, as did the yen against the dollar.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front page also covers this development, in a piece that points out that many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has prolonged the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> downturn
and that of the region by dithering. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also notes that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> situation is braking growth well beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>: as the largest creditor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>, for instance, it is expected to be able to provide, for example, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lion</ENAMEX>'s share of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the billion dollars</NUMEX> a day that is borrowed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> markets.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> hailed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>'s decision to allow the won to trade freely
against the dollar, a move that has, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, resulted in a marked
bounce-back in the currency in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>. On the other hand, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> expressed disappointment that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> bailout wasn't
bigger, "more stimulative."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis will cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65,000</NUMEX> new jobs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> and will cause export growth to
slow.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> warning came out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s press conference, which
garnered a lot of front-page space, during which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said he thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>
still has not met his international obligations regarding weapons inspection.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was asked if he thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> is crazy, he replied, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, if he is, he's clever crazy.." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says the press
conference seemed "designed to counter a spate of recent news stories that have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">portrayed Clinton</ENAMEX> as more engaged in his golf game than his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>," and
goes on to say it was "the longest presidential news conference in the
television age." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says it was the longest one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
presidency. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says it was the "longest ever of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes into much more detail about the conference's
actual questions and answers than say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which summarizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> more and puts the space
saved thus to use making meta-comments about the goings-on. For instance, the
Times dwells quite a bit on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>' various unsuccessful attempts to get
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> to bring the event to a close. And it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> or USAT , that notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several minutes</TIMEX>
describing how he came up with the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy</ENAMEX>" for his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Labrador puppy</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" notes that a bill passing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> recently would grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> and other tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> the privilege
of client confidentiality that is currently only enjoyed in tax matters by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. The change would give new privacy to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> who can afford to pay a
tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preparer</ENAMEX> but not hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> also notes that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> see the new provision as a powerful marketing tool.

            As suspected, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> couldn't resist the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Story</ENAMEX>" non-story.
But since the obvious political angles had already been (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over</NUMEX>)-reported, she
opts for doing an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who claims to be the real model for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenny</ENAMEX>. Continuing the theme of getting to the bottom of books published in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s next column will be the unmasking of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J</ENAMEX>," who, you won't
recall, wrote "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sensuous Woman</ENAMEX>." Maybe it'll be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tipper</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
