
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> Gone Conclusion

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the rebuke to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> likely to come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>, which
is also the top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX>'s decision to cut <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> jobs, the biggest layoff at any
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has been hurt by continued unimpressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital</ENAMEX> camera sales. A late-breaking story, which likely will dominate
everybody's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> editions, the gunning down of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> this morning, leads at the early edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> available to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" prior to the
column deadline.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> believe the shootings may have been
carried out by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist group</ENAMEX> in retaliation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s conviction in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> murders case. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>,
reports the paper, worked as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Texas Petroleum Co.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> appears to have accepted a milder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> than it originally hoped for, largely because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> wouldn't go for stronger language. Instead of threatening "serious
consequences" if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> doesn't cease its interference with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, it merely refers to possible "further measures."
The resolution, which could come up for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
also imposes a foreign travel ban on culpable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
in its front-page piece, has this too but adds the detail that, at the
insistence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has also accepted language in the resolution
affirming the territorial integrity and independence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes
these indicators of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military preparations: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of the aircraft
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">carrier Nimitz</ENAMEX>, stationed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>, is on "high alert," and both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> canceled overseas
trips. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also gives <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> front-page play. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> puts
it on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p. A18</ENAMEX>.

            In its front-page business and financial news box, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> flags a story describing how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
is now mounting a broad campaign to counter its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, both in real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of public opinion. The piece claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has hired a
politically well-plugged-in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and held a conference call
recently with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX>, all towards
playing catch-up in an area that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says, has historically not
been a company strong suit--inside-the-Beltway influence.

            The USAT front section cover story limns a low-profile but active
fault line in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> workplace--that between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
those without. With all the emphasis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> have been putting on meeting the
extra-vocational needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, it seems that many childless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> have had to pick up the slack. The working assumption at many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, is "if you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, you don't have a
life and are available to stay late and take the business trips from hell."
There's a suggestion in the piece for how a childless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> can create a
little more equity: put a photograph of a pretend <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX> on your desk, and
take a day off once in a while because they have a cold.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a piece inside reporting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> pediatricians
specializing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse have signed a letter criticizing the use of medical
evidence by the defense in the au pair trial. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> state that the
prosecution's evidence "overwhelmingly supported" a finding that there was a
violent shaking episode involving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> when he was in the sole custody of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Woodward</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> opines that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> has had a face lift and she thinks she
knows why: "Because he really, really wants to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
