
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triskaidekaphobia Times</ENAMEX> Three

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the threatened resignation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Levy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with possible complications in
the economic bailout plan for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the nationwide push for tougher drunk driving laws. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the fatal shooting of a local police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have shot and killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in the case.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levy</ENAMEX> may quit over a budget
dispute with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> is
keeping his fragile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> together by doling out funds to conservative
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, rather than fixing the economy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> buries this
crucial detail after the jump. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page story announces it up
top, in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph, and adds an item the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> misses: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levy</ENAMEX> has
threatened to quit several times before, without doing so. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levy</ENAMEX> does quit,
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> agree, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could fall. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts the story in its World-Wide
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newsbox</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead fingers small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> as possible spoilers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> financial bailout. Most large international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
plan, have extended their loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>, letting it fix its economy
before repaying debts. But several small foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, with less to gain from
a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>, will not extend loans, possibly jeopardizing the entire
bailout. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> issued a
televised request to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> for donations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> jewelry. A WP
front-page story on the crisis says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> are seeking
western-style training. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> plan will require stricter and more open
accounting measures from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, which traditionally cooks its books and
keeps its ledgers hidden.

            The USAT <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> covers the coming fight for lower blood-alcohol limits
in drunk driving cases. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> will try to move from a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.10%</NUMEX>
blood-alcohol limit to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.08%</NUMEX> limit. (To reach a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.08%</NUMEX> blood-alcohol level, a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">170-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> needs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> on an empty stomach.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> prints its predictions for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. The
forecast: Continued expansion, but slower growth (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.4%</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.1%</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>) due to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis and rising wages. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> sees interest rates and unemployment rates remaining unchanged over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. The story says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was the economy's best since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>.

            A story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> will see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three Friday</TIMEX> the
13ths in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a single year</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>). This
trifecta occurs only once every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> once saw three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday the 13th</TIMEX> s in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a single day</TIMEX>, but will not rent these movies again
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, if ever.

         
      
   
