
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ceding</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Censoring, Consuming</ENAMEX>

Times lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>'s approval of plans to withdraw
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>' moves to filter
pornography on the Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> lead - "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoppers</ENAMEX> hit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, look for
bargains" - bespeaks a slow news day.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX> agreed in principle to cede more land to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>.
The decision, however, appeased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backers</ENAMEX>:
It remained vague on how much territory to cede, and when to cede it. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece frames this as do-nothing action, designed to temporarily
quiet demands coming simultaneously from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> right-wing, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> (which is pressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> to cede land quickly). The LAT
quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> terming this a "public relations trick." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a front-page "reefer" to a page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A18</NUMEX> story, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts it in their World-Wide news box.
The USAT front ignores it.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> has
agreed to bail out the ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> economy. Details were not yet
available, but some reports put the amount at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55 billion</NUMEX>, to come from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>. This would make it the largest-ever
rescue, eclipsing the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48 billion</NUMEX> bailout of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> all run front-page reefers to
the story.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead says several Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> today will announce actions
designed to preempt regulation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America Online</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> will
fund education and filtering devices to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> safe from Web
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smut</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> say filtering devices won't go far enough; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free-speech</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> say they'll go too far.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead describes the early returns on holiday shopping as
"uncertain." Sales figures are not overwhelming, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>
now hold off on buying until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right before Christmas</TIMEX>.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story reports on newly released tapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> conversations. The tapes show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> hoped to sway
coverage on the television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> by threatening them with anti-trust
legislation. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> re-aired the broadcast of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tricia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wedding</ENAMEX>, after repeated demands from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. (This column assures you
it will not be swayed by threats of anti-trust legislation against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.
Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX> continues to thrive at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
