
   
   
      
         
            Up in Smoke

            The unveiling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stance on the proposed national tobacco
deal leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and is the top national story at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> (and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lead at the New York
Times ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision to shake up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> investigating campaign-finance irregularities leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (and
is on the front page at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">bull-market evergreen</TIMEX>: "Good inflation news boosts stocks,
bonds."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tobacco stand is: yes to a national
agreement, no to this one because it doesn't include steep enough penalties on
cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> for failing to meet targets for reducing teen smoking, and
because he wants guarantees that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> will have broad authority to regulate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nicotine</ENAMEX>. But (perhaps applying Lesson No. 1 from his stab at health care
reform--he who takes the initiative has the most to lose) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will not
propose a bill with these features. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> say, he will wait for bills
to emerge from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and try to influence them.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lead states that, according to brand-new research,
highly drug-resistant strains of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> that cause middle ear infections,
sinusitis, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX> are twice as common as they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. And the
paper points to the most likely cause of the trend with its citation of a new
often prescribe antibiotics for colds and bronchitis caused by viruses even
though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antibiotics</ENAMEX> are ineffective against viruses. The story is also on the
LAT front and inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . "We were surprised," the lead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , "that one in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antibiotics</ENAMEX> [was] prescribed for conditions that they don't even help." Could
it be that this story, together with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fen-phen</ENAMEX> debacle, will focus national
attention on promiscuous prescribing?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's inside-the-Beltway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX> brings news of a
seminar being put on by a top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C. PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burson-Marsteller</ENAMEX>. The purpose? To
teach government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> how to avoid, override, and even take advantage of
line-item-veto threats to their budgets. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> says in its promotional copy
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> should strongly consider spending "taxpayer money" to
attend.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past summer</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> sounded a front-page alarm over the
new-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tax-law</NUMEX>-driven expenses incurred by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> selling luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's turn to report on a
nonpressing economic problem: "Confusion abounds," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>," "as many financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> apparently aren't aware that the new tax
law killed an excise tax that forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> or more in
retirement savings to carefully time withdrawals."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has an op-ed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by a medical school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> that lasers
right into his profession's kuh-ching! mentality. It features multiple-choice
questions with answers from a recent medical ethics exam given to interns and
residents. A sample: "You receive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">regular</NUMEX> surgical referrals from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>
who is fellowship trained in nonsurgical sports medicine. He suggests that he
should receive some reimbursement for these procedures. Which of the following
payment arrangements is most acceptable? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Pay him an agreed amount per
referral. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Pay him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> on a contractual basis. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Have him scrub
[prepare for surgery] and bill an assistant's fee. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Share an office and you
pay overhead. Or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5</NUMEX>) Establish a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>, with both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> on
salary." The "correct" answer is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). "The idea," observes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, "that
you might tell a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> has a right to expect that a doctor
will send him to the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s decision will not be
based on whether he has a financial stake in the referral, is not even an
option."

         
      
   
