
   
   
      
         
            Studio: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dewey Care</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with a poll indicating that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
has too much power and frequently abuses it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-led investment deal, supported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
government, to develop a giant natural gas field in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> in direct
defiance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economic sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with just-released reports about the incomes of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead notes in passing that not all segments of society enjoyed
significant economic gains <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>--more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lacked health insurance and
the ranks of the "very poor" increased--but this isn't emphasized in the piece
nor in its headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Household Incomes Rise Again</ENAMEX>." A finding that is
emphasized in the story is also stated in the subhead: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disparity Between</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, Men's Pay Continues to Narrow</ENAMEX>."

            The increasingly sad straits of those at or near the bottom of the economy
is not the only report topic that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> chooses to downplay. The
paper doesn't broach the findings about ethnic income disparities until the
bottom of the piece. But they are bracing: median income for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37,171</NUMEX>,
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24,906</NUMEX>, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23,482</NUMEX>. And for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> it's
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$43,276</NUMEX>.

            Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> leaves to the very last paragraph of the story this
fact: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Family</ENAMEX> structure remains a critical predictor of who will live in
poverty, with rates among single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> dramatically higher, at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32.6 percent</NUMEX>,
than married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.6 percent</NUMEX>." Why does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> play up the
closing of the gender gap but downplay the widening of the marriage gap?

            The LAT income piece focuses on the worsening numbers for the poor,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> income lead emphasizes minority gains right from the
headline and claims the reports reveal "the lowest black poverty rate in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s history." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> delays until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> paragraph the
news about the diminishing gender gap. These variances show that no matter how
quantitative a story, it inevitably has subjective elements. The income story
headline could have easily been "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> Earn <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16%</NUMEX> more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whites</ENAMEX>" or "Single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mothers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nearly Six Times More Likely than Married Mothers</ENAMEX> to be Poor."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s newly created office managing his
initiative on race and reconciliation offhandedly mentions that it has a staff
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> and a budget of nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five million dollars</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front page presents a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chutzpah Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>. It seems that while working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> helping
to recover damages from junk-bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Milken</ENAMEX> and his investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drexel Burnham Lambert</ENAMEX>, a hot-shot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> got caught padding the bills
he submitted to the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an op-ed about the movie "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hoodlum</ENAMEX>" over the by-line of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas E.L. Dewey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> of the two-time <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, who first made a name for himself as a racket-busting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. The movie portrays the elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dewey</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX>, regularly taking
bribes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lucky Luciano</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. The op-ed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> makes the point
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s probity was legendary and that he in fact was the man
who put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano</ENAMEX> away. So he prevailed upon his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Dewey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>--to
write a letter of complaint to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Mancuso</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mancuso</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> wrote back, saying, "The film was a work of fiction and it was
presented as such to the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX> has not violated any legally cognizable
rights of either your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> position is quite
accurately summarized in the piece: "We in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> have no responsibilities
to society unless and until we might get sued."

         
      
   
