
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conoco Games</ENAMEX>

            With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX> saga receding ever so slightly, news diversity makes a small
comeback. So we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leading with the failure of an airline rate hike
attempt, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> on national educational testing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> with a startling development in the Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with a local political
story.

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> flying at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> capacity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and the Dow Jones
Transportation Index at record levels, it seemed like a good time for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
percent fare increase, which, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , most of the major domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> put into place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. But by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> still
had it in all markets. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that a computer system glitch
mistakenly rolled back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airline</ENAMEX>'s increase in all markets and when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> saw that, they, fearing the loss of business from
being underpriced, rolled their fares back too.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has decided to make national
educational standards testing a centerpiece of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-term agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
says his call for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade reading tests and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade math tests should
be beyond partisanship. Yet, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and many
other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> see it as a federal intrusion into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is focused on the wrong end," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> is quoted as
saying. "He's focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> regulations,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> red tape." To avoid this sort of opposition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has emphasized
that the tests would be voluntary and ultimately under the control of local
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. He has also said the tests could be designed by a
bipartisan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have said the problem is that the tests divert
money away from actual educational improvements. They are estimated to cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to develop. (To me, that's the only part that's hard to swallow. Why
should an elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> test cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who have handled Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'s lawsuit against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> thus far--including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> successful trip
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>--backed out of the case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. Close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> say that
the problem is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> rejected a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> settlement offer because it
didn't include a full apology from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> cites as a factor
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'s intransigence the influence of her new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and public relations
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Carpenter-McMillan</ENAMEX>. The piece also points out a strong reason
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> had for urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> to take the deal--they had recently switched
to a percentage contingency fee arrangement with her. (Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'s demurral
show that she's about more than money or does it show that she's about more
money?)

            The range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>-related front-page stories indicates a level of interest
that just won't wait for real news. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> has a story about how the royal
family offered to restore the title of Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Highness</ENAMEX> posthumously (and was
turned down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Press Pledges</ENAMEX>
Restraint" regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Princes William</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Helped Choose Ring</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front is graced by "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dollars Pouring</ENAMEX> in to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Favorite Charities</ENAMEX>."

            
               Correction : This column made a mistake last night in saying that AOL
was taking control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prodigy</ENAMEX>. The column meant, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compuserve</ENAMEX>. The
column is sorry.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reports, "In a
survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX> said they would move next door to their in-laws for
a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> pay raise."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> run front-page pieces reporting that on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> decided to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conoco</ENAMEX> to conduct oil
drilling on a federal property in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, during the election,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> established a national monument to protect the wilderness from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. This will be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that oil and gas drilling will be
allowed at any national monument. Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>: You might want to see
if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conoco</ENAMEX> was a soft money contributor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Just a
thought.

         
      
   
