
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Bite Too</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> firestorm leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the lead national story is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s appearance at ceremonies commemorating the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">40th</NUMEX> anniversary of the
forced integration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central High</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> used the occasion to issue a warning about the trend
toward the re-separation of the races, a trend both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> had no trouble observing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central High</ENAMEX>, where the dining areas and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">academic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> are largely de facto segregated. And both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> noted that the
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> voted not to support or participate in the
ceremonies. More heartening was the revelation in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that a white
woman famously captured in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX> photograph cursing the entering black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> was present to publicly apologize for her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long-ago</TIMEX> actions. (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Just</TIMEX>
wondering: Couldn't they also have found one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paratroopers</ENAMEX> who escorted
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> coverage includes a nice little survey of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> original black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and what they're doing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The list includes an
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, and an unemployed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> live overseas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has a nice photo on its
front top of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with some of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>, but runs the story inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> continue pressing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> story, with
leads describing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s testimony, in which a number of current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>,
speaking from behind a screen, their voices electronically altered, blew the
whistle on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s shady practices; and in which the acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dolan</ENAMEX>, continued to apologize and pledge reform. After ignoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> plays catch-up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Surprisingly, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sticks the story way inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> breaks the story that former senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickes</ENAMEX> has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> told federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> that he was in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> pitches
to several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> during the run-up to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> elections.
This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> corroboration of the claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> personally solicited
money from inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front page states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> has ruled out any chance
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> will pass the major campaign-reform bill banning all soft money that
has been advancing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> favors instead lifting all limits on
political contributions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that the
probe into the fund-raising behind the election of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> could, because some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> allegedly are involved, result
in the appointment of yet another independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>.

            At first, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> didn't even mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marv Albert</ENAMEX> trial, then
dealt with it deep inside and at arm's length. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> edit
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s testimony didn't mention, for example,
that she said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> was wearing women's clothes.) But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> of the case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gray Lady</ENAMEX> hikes her skirts, putting the story on
the front page and deigning to mention all the tawdry details. The story is
also on the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , alongside a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> that makes
him look downright scary, and is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lead at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which was much more aggressive from the git-go, simply raises
the ante <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, with not just a long front-page piece but also not one, but two
additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> pieces elsewhere in the paper, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a ramble</TIMEX> wondering if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> can rebound professionally, the other a thumb-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
stand by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> when he's in trouble. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albert</ENAMEX>
piece, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX> is never mentioned by name, a practice the paper explains
thus: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington Post</ENAMEX> does not identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of alleged sexual
attacks." But it turns out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> isn't able to stick to that policy
for more than a few paragraphs. A little further down, the paper identifies by
name the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who testified that she, too, was bitten and sexually
assaulted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>. So what's the actual policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ?

         
      
   
