
   
   
      
         
            Not Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s Guzzmobile

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Justice</ENAMEX>'s attempt to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> held
in contempt because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is allegedly flouting the recently issued court
order requiring it to market its Web browser Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> separately from
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 95</ENAMEX> operating system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> are ready
to roll out the cleanest-running-ever gasoline-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s decision to open the way
to full-scale trade between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Council</ENAMEX> has passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s toughest
restrictions on outdoor cigarette advertising.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> say they could put their new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of clean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> on the road soon provided they got
guarantees the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> would qualify as acceptable under the pollution standards
everywhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are said to eliminate
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99 percent</NUMEX> of smog-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> has adopted eventual
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>-admissions standards.) But much to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' chagrin, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> have adopted requirements similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s and their fear
is that other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> will follow suit. The story quotes unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automakers</ENAMEX>' proposals offer an acceptable compromise,
which will produce cleaner air.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead states that economic normalization between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> will result from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s decision, based on its view that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>'s emigration policies have improved considerably, to grant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> a
waiver from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Jackson-Vanik Amendment</ENAMEX>, which bars full economic relations
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that don't permit free emigration. This will unblock a
variety of government-backed financing programs for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> projects of
various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. It would have been helpful if the story had said
high up in what respects <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>'s emigration stance has improved, and had also
explained how it is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can alter a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s trade status like
this unilaterally, without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> approval.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front pages carry news of the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey</ENAMEX> to allow gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> to jointly adopt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on the same basis as
married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to do so. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs the story
inside.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story includes these factoids: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between eight</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thirteen million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> nationwide are being raised by gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, while two
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, bar the adoption of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> law
directly cracking down on unauthorized distribution in cyberspace of
copyrighted material even if there is no profit sought. The piece suggests that
the new law addresses the case of a large corporate interest being abused by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">lone-wolf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>. But does it also address cases where it's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX> that's doing the stealing? Like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s putting an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on its Web site for which one-time print rights only had been purchased
from a freelance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>? Or if its online archives contained plagiarized
material? The story doesn't say.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics"</ENAMEX> column reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch McConnell</ENAMEX> and Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Linder</ENAMEX> recently sent out a letter titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"In Praise of Soft Money</ENAMEX>" to the
Fortune <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>, which described soft money as "entirely legal, ethical,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beneficial</ENAMEX> and necessary to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s healthy two-party system."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> states that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> of a television
cartoon show were taken to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, many suffering from seizures and
unconsciousness, after viewing a sequence in the show containing strobe
effects. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Leno</ENAMEX> explained last night why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are so concerned:
TV isn't supposed to cause brain damage that fast.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>
plans to issue a philanthropy stamp <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> that will depict a bee
pollinating a flower and will bear the words: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Giving and Sharing: an American</ENAMEX>
Tradition." Guess the rights to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pamela</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Lee</ENAMEX> video weren't
available.

         
      
   
