
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>-Off

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton/Jiang</ENAMEX> summit is everybody's lead. A nuclear nonproliferation
deal was struck, as was a deal selling American-made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX>. But what seems
to make the biggest impression on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> was the extraordinary
shoulder-to-shoulder dispute over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s human rights record between the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> at their joint press conference. Everybody reports that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> defended
the suppression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> protests as necessary to preserving his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s stability, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> stated that on human rights, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is "on the
wrong side of history." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was similarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forthright</ENAMEX> regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s trade policies, noting that he said right to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s face, "Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> can compete freely and fairly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, so our
goods and services should be able to compete freely and fairly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> calls the episode a "cordial but frank clash," but says
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have agreed not to let their continuing rights differences
stand in the way of strategic and economic ties. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
sees things a little more starkly, saying that the public disagreement
"appeared to broaden the gulf between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> on human rights."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that the summit
agreement for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reactors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in return for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
stand-down from helping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> go nuclear was immediately denounced by some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Yet neither paper explains what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can do about the
deal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> does a little better, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can
"challenge" it within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX>, but doesn't elaborate what form that
challenge can take. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that the deal calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to
"curb," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says it calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to "abandon," its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
nuke program, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> agreed merely not to
engage in any "new" cooperative programs with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, but will be completing two
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> already underway there.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> did, in private talks, discuss the
allegations that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> funneled illegal contributions in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election. But
apparently Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did not ask where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Ya Lin Trie</ENAMEX> is. The
Times also reports that at the joint press conference, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> was
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> asked about human rights, he checked his watch. And in search of clues to
the exact status of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton/Jiang</ENAMEX> relationship, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> closely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monitors Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> language. Results: No grip of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s bicep during
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handshake</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the free world did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> some elbow and back.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> each report on their fronts that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has
ordered all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> working for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> arms inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> there to leave
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is considering a response and discussing the situation
with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a cluster of articles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> dealing with various
revelations from the newest batch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> tapes to see the light of day. Newly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exposed Oval Office Nixon</ENAMEX> no-nos include: early plans to destroy the tapes,
thanking a supporter for supplying funds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> knew were being used as hush
money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> burglars, a plot to "shakedown" the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> lobby for more
campaign contributions, and various schemes to interfere with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
primaries by creating spurious grassroots campaigns for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX> and Jesse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.J. O'Rourke</ENAMEX> has an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> screed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
What's new is his reason: to rail at many of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> for
drifting away from discussing the realities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> in
favor of indulging in wacky conspiracy theories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> all have front-pagers
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s decision to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> to racial and
ethnic category questions on federal forms to, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever, check
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> (the alternative of having a separate "multiracial" box was
rejected). If you feel the proliferation of such questions promotes
Balkanization, the decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> gives you a legal way to fight back: Just check
them all .

         
      
   
