
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza the Action</ENAMEX>

            Everybody's lead is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision not to appoint an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate campaign fund-raising calls allegedly made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice-President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> also decided there was no reason to have
an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> see if ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel O'Leary</ENAMEX> solicited a
charitable contribution in return for meeting with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX>.)
Everybody has the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> concluded that the only fund-raising calls
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made were from the residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, which is
okay legally, and concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> did not know that some of the money he
was soliciting would end being improperly placed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> "hard money" account.
Everybody also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> stated that this doesn't mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> is
through with the issue, saying that her decision "does not mean that a person
has been exonerated." Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times accompanies its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> story with an off-lead piece reporting that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> continues to investigate the major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> on the other end of the
phone.

            The development is widely reported as good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and great news
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, who now has renewed hopes of heading into campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">sans</ENAMEX> scandal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the others emphasize the hot, hot <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> reaction. Both
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>'s comment that "The question is: Will the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have confidence that no cover-up is going on?..As a result of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s announcement, the answer remains, 'no.'"

            Everybody makes a big deal about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX>'s eleventh<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-hour</TIMEX> memo to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> urging her to seek an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, citing inherent conflicts of
interest in her investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> makes the biggest, using its
lead editorial to laud him, saying, "It was a momentous act of duty to lob
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hand grenade</ENAMEX> of truth into Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s legal fantasy land." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>
uses his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> to retail an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX> quip about the tension between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> cannot survive half slave
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> observes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision probably saved both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of thousands of dollars</NUMEX> in legal fees.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "Tax Report" contains at least a
partial explanation for why individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> feel more beleaguered than
ever. They're paying a lot more of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s total tax bill than they used
to: total corporate taxes now represent <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 12.5 percent</NUMEX> of total federal tax
revenues, down from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 20 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 60s</TIMEX>.

            The metro edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tawana Brawley</ENAMEX>'s speech at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bed-Stuy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, her first
public appearance since she made her never-substantiated claims <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, abducted
and raped her and left her smeared with excrement. According to the story,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brawley</ENAMEX>'s still in the never-substantiated business. In her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty-minute</TIMEX>
speech, with few details, she said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had followed her and that she
had once been stopped at gunpoint by law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX>.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brawley</ENAMEX>'s charges drew plenty of national attention when she
originally made them, the national edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> doesn't cover
her speech. The metro edition does, though, complete with front-page color
picture.

            
               Political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Watch</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s response
to the good news included going out for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> (wonder if he called his order in). And the
paper also reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX> filmed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Hut</ENAMEX> commercial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> defended the move thus:
"I thought it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s matter--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may get the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorby</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $1 million</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
