
   
   
      
         
            Now <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">She Tells Us</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>'s announcement that in the
wake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s hearings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> will hold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the revelation that in more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> murder cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> police ignored high-quality leads supplied by
federal cops. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> doubts about the prospects for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
fast-track trade bill, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s refusal to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> to use
modern statistical methods in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> census.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT IRS</ENAMEX> lead reports that the open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> with
grievances will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly Saturday</TIMEX> sessions running from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9 to 5</TIMEX>. The paper
points out that the new measure is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s plan to
avoid the perception that it is too protective of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. Another possible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might propose a major overhaul
of the tax system.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts don't mention the open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. Nor does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report." On its front, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has only a tiny box "reefer" pointing to the story deep inside.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s fast-track bill for negotiating global
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> accords is in trouble in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and it's his fault because he hasn't
brought along enough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, many of whom are opposed to new trade bills
that don't include stiff labor and environmental provisions. Administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> tell the paper they see the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> comments mostly as a
negotiating tactic for wringing more concessions out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on other issues
in return for saving the legislation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> census lead says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s vote against allowing
sampling techniques in the census might ensure an inaccurate count and cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion dollars</NUMEX> in lost revenue. But the piece doesn't adequately
explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> animus against sampling. The reason is the fear that,
for the purposes of reapportionment and federal revenue distribution, the
techniques will help <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> artificially inflate the numbers of
traditionally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwellers</ENAMEX>, who are hard to reach by
traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-counting methods.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> apologized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for its silence in
the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> collaboration with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> states that
the apology was "an expression of remorse more complete, uncompromising and
anguished than anything previously pronounced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>."

            A good example of using reporting to break through the generalities of a
policy issue is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's front-page piece about the agony of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> trying to decide which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should lose their disability
payments under the tough new welfare law. Nationwide, the story says, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with various developmental and emotional problems must be denied the
payments.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> have inside stories about how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> Lt.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth "Betsy" McCaughey Ross</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that she was now
proud to call herself a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> had already been yanked off the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
gubernatorial ticket by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX>. Her perceived inexperience and
uncontrollability alienated not just him, but also most other leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonse D'Amato</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> had never held
elective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> before and got the nod mostly on the strength of her New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> cover story <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savaging</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s health care reform plan, which
was widely credited with helping to sink it.

            After her announcement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> took a "welcoming" phone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> says health care reform didn't come up.

         
      
   
