
   
   
      
         
            Tamrazmatazz

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Tamraz</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> --and grabs plenty of front-page space
elsewhere. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the guilty pleas entered
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Teamsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in connection with a scheme to launder
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>-election contributions. The shake-up announced at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">congress</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with the record surpluses accumulating in state coffers.

            Tamraz, a naturalized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>
hearings that the only reason he gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> was so he could gain
high-level government support for a pet project. This sort of statement of the
obvious is known in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> as "candor," and especially because Tamraz
showed up without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and smiled and laughed throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, his brand
of it was enthusiastically received by the powers that be, including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says he "entertained" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes his quickness with one-liners. The picture running with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story makes it look as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamraz</ENAMEX> was feeling the tremendous pressure
of a prosecutorial grilling. But in fact, the only sort of question he had to
answer was: Did you get your money's worth? ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX> time, I'll give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX>,"
was his reply.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> picture of the witness table is more in line with
reality: Just a bunch of rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in suits having fun. (To get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>'s take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> hearings, read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s daily
dispatches.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> details how <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> top campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX> pleaded guilty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to funneling illegal contributions to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s re-election drive. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> stated that their scheme--disguising
improper contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>--involved
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s re-election campaign.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USAT</ENAMEX> brings news that state treasuries are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX>, primarily because the economy's surge has boosted tax revenues and
shrunk welfare rolls. Just about the only exception is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, which is
experiencing a nasty recession because (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>) tourism is down. The paper
reports that in general, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are reacting conservatively, plowing most
of the found money into tax cuts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and contingency funds.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> firmly established himself as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointments</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> and nonappointments of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. This story also runs above the fold at the WP
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's national edition.

            In the business and finance news box of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , there's word (credited to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit News</ENAMEX> ) that in a move to retain white-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>
is offering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> nonunion salaried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> a grant of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> for
family-related expenses like elder care and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s college tuition.

            The LAT front page gives an early picture of a stratagem sure to
become popular among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of affirmative action in college admissions. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino Eligibility Task Force</ENAMEX>, composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all nine</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>, warns that continued use of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> test as an admissions criterion could mean a drop of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 70 percent</NUMEX> in
the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, the system's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most
selective campuses. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> has a solution: eliminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> as a
requirement, which would "more than double the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Latinos</ENAMEX> eligible for
admissions." Surprisingly, given that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 209</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX> is on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.C. Board of Regents</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that the regents are "receptive"
to the idea.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> column states that, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashcroft</ENAMEX> took to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to argue for defunding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>, he quoted approvingly
from the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> and frequent LAT contributor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Breslauer</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Kamen</NUMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> didn't mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breslauer</ENAMEX> also recently wrote a
piece for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Stacked Like Me</ENAMEX>" describing her recent
decision to perk up her boring life by getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34D</NUMEX> breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">implants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamen</ENAMEX>'s
piece appears under the subhead "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ashcroft Takes on Two Endowments</ENAMEX>."

            A question for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> copy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>: Shouldn't that be "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three"</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
