
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fowler Deeds</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with local political stories but their national
leads concern the testimony before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of the most prominent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to appear thus far. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the shocking fine print in a
foreign relations bill. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the latest dustup between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX>.

            The big news at the fundraising hearings, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , is the
admission by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Fowler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election, that on several occasions, he intervened with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> on behalf of large party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the most
questionable piece of networking is one that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fowler</ENAMEX> testified he couldn't
recall, but which documents revealed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time yesterday</TIMEX> strongly
confirm: namely, contacting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> at the behest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Tamraz</ENAMEX>, an
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> "with a questionable reputation" (says the
Times ) who was angling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> support for a proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian region</ENAMEX> oil pipeline, and who had given the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$300,000</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says such interventions are probably not illegal, but against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> guidelines, which state: "In no event should any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> ever promise a
meeting with or access to any government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in connection with
a donation, or ever imply that such contact or access can be arranged, or ever
contact an administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> on behalf of a donor for any reason." When
this rule was quoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fowler</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Collins</ENAMEX>, his
response was: "I am not a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>. I
difference there." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fowler</ENAMEX> story emphasizes a part of his
testimony that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> mentions only in passing: that the fund-raising
scandal was really more the responsibility of then-presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Ickes</ENAMEX> who, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fowler</ENAMEX> said, often countermanded his advice.

            Both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> run strong companion pieces to their hearing
coverage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> weighs in with the news that during the last election
cycle, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> took <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $2 million</NUMEX> in contributions restricted to generic
use by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that, in violation of election laws, it then spent directly on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s re-election campaign. And the LAT delves into
another aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamraz</ENAMEX>'s activities: his secret talks with top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> of--talk
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> covering your political bases--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to discuss donating <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s presidential campaign in return for his support for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Caspian</ENAMEX> oil project.

            In covering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s goal of getting "fast-track" authority in
order to enter into free-trade agreements with more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> notes, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>-den reporting
strategy, that even in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> congressional district of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arch-protectionist Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX> it is obvious that, post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nafta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are
creating jobs and increasing pay due to increased export sales. In fact, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> accompanies the piece with a chart showing that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only three</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>--are exporting fewer goods since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> flyspecks the latest revision in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Relations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Authorization Act</ENAMEX>, engineered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, which puts
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>--including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least seven</NUMEX> big tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
the line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> funds frozen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, and
puts <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Gulf</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, many of whom are suffering the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemical</ENAMEX> munitions, at the end of it.

            Incidentally, it's nice to see that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> isn't afraid to express an
opinion within a news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX>--generally a no-no at the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>. Note the
scare-quotes in the following: "The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> covered...would be injured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1987</ENAMEX> missile attack upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">frigate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS Stark</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> who died in that 'accidental' incident already had
been given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27.3 million</NUMEX> in compensation by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> before the gulf war."

         
      
   
