
   
   
      
         
            Message: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wee Care</ENAMEX>

            Everybody's big story is the inability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX> jury to decide
on his sentence, which under the federal rules, means he won't get the death
penalty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> will decide instead and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> say that he'll probably
go for life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> is reminded all around, still faces
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of state murder charges that could result in the death penalty.

            The most striking part of this installment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> story is what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> calls the "sharply critical press conference" held by the jury
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forewoman</ENAMEX> afterwards. She is quoted as saying that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> dropped the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ball</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> implies that what she meant by this was that "it was hard to
say from the evidence presented exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX>' involvement was."
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times say the "dropping the ball" comment was about her belief that the
government had failed to search for other suspects

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> seems to reveal that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> ended up with at least a touch
of militia-style animus against the feds when it quotes her
remark: "I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s attitude.is part of where all this comes from
in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place..I think maybe it's time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> be more
respectful.and not with the attitude that we know and you don't, we have the
power and you don't." Indeed, in its lead paragraph, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> attributes
the sentencing outcome to a belief by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> was arrogant and
sloppy.

            Continuing the time-honored tradition of drip-dripping the key elements of
the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> speech ahead of time, all of the front pages
cover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposal of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nearly $22 billion</NUMEX> package of grants
and tax breaks to help working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> pay for child care. The plan would also
include tax credits for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that build or expand employee child care
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>. Congressional rumblings are noted--both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ways and Means</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX> referred to
the plan as another of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "small ideas" that "taken together, return to
the era of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>"--but there is no mention of the federally subsidized
state-of-the-art workplace child-care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            The news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> has brought its first criminal
charges in its investigation of the tobacco industry makes the fronts of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , and is flagged in the
front-page news box of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> carries it inside. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feds</ENAMEX> say that DNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plant Technology Corp.</ENAMEX> conspired with a tobacco company
(officially unnamed, but widely reported to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX>) to develop
a high-nicotine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> has agreed to cooperate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s ongoing
investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Biotech Firm</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Tobacco</ENAMEX>
Probe"--makes the whole thing sound like good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> rather than a plea
bargain.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit starts right
off stating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> plans to be physically present when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is
questioned under oath by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> at an upcoming deposition. But the piece
waits until the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> paragraph to note that this was reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> . (This story is also inside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an op-ed complaining that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is single-handedly
resisting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> attempt to reduce the worldwide use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child soldiers</ENAMEX>. (More
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-million children</ENAMEX> are currently serving under <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, the piece
says.) It seems we are balking at accepting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 18</TIMEX> as the cut-off because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> allows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-year-olds</TIMEX> to enlist with parental consent. But, counters the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">op-ed</ENAMEX>, nearly all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> reach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> before being assigned to combat
positions.

            In his column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> goes off on an extended rant against all
the ways in which privacy is imperiled, from your dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, to airline security and deadbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> tracking. It's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gratifying</ENAMEX> to see that some <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-five years</TIMEX> after leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enemies List</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> has come to appreciate the awesome dangers of information
trafficking, but it's interesting that his proposed reforms still smack of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon M.O.</ENAMEX>: "Sign as little as possible" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Above all</ENAMEX>--pay cash."

         
      
   
