
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affirmative Negation</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to let <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s anti-affirmative
action <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 209</ENAMEX> stand leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congressional campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration small-scale health care reform--and sticks the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX> victory deep
inside, on p.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> of the national edition.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX> decision "marks a major victory for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> of a new colorblind standard for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> papers
leading with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX> all make it clear that the decision will probably spur
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">209</TIMEX>-style laws in many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. And the LAT mentions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> will consider a federal version <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this week</TIMEX>. The three
also point out that although this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> decision was probably the watershed,
there might well be other eventual appeals based on cases where plaintiffs
allege actual harm as a result of the law. The WP mentions another
factor that could lead to further legal challenge: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX> bans "preferential
treatment" but does not define it. So look for cases that, for example, claim
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">209</ENAMEX> doesn't prohibit preference-based recruiting for programs with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX>-blind internal standards.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> health care lead states that the same business and insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> who teamed up to help kill health care reform in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> are mobilizing
to block the more modest, piecemeal federal quality-of-care proposals--like
mandated-length hospital stays for certain procedures and government standards
for health plans--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has subsequently endorsed.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> recently organized
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> strategy briefings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also notes an interesting
split within the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> concerning this issue: Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>,
convinced that managed care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have cut into their autonomy and their
incomes, are in favor of many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> provisions reigning them in.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs a front-page feature about a group
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allendale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are striving to hold down
the jobs that have gotten them off welfare. The piece makes the point that
getting off welfare by working is even harder for the rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX>, who often
have no access to public transportation, or, surprisingly, phones.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead is an update on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>/weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> situation.
The latest is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> continues to block the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, and to threaten to shoot down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> surveillance <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, has warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> that time is running
out for him to avoid "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> action." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> story is also carried on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front, and in the "world-wide news" box on the front of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , but doesn't make the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . Or of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
which runs it on p. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a piece inside on the first-ever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> study of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The piece opens with the report's observation that,
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 2.3 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the developing world,
live in places where the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic has barely begun, and even mildly
successful prevention programs could have enormous benefits." By contrast, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> inside piece on the study emphasizes not the possibilities of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prevention</ENAMEX>, but the scope of the disease's surge, saving for its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">13th</NUMEX> paragraph
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> leads with, about the relative scarcity of
the disease for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the world. As if to back up its more alarmist take,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a front-page piece about how <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is suddenly ravishing
Kaliningrad, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> that connects <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            Back to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX> decision: It seems that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> have picked up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> habit of overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stars</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar night</ENAMEX>, the
papers' coverage of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX> victory mentions such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Wilson</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX>, but there is no front-page mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wood</ENAMEX> or Glynn
Clustred, who wrote and conceived <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

         
      
   
