
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headlights</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> all lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to
support the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">IRS reform</ENAMEX> bill bound for easy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> passage. The story also tops
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's world-wide news box. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s stockpile of
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> has become increasingly vulnerable to theft and sabotage.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> report raising "serious concerns"
over the physical security at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX> nuke storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX> report that talks of a "developing crisis."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> turned the groundswell of emotion loosed by abused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> at hearings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> into votes for such ideas as putting the
burden of proof on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in tax disputes and establishing an independent,
largely civilian, control and review <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. And ever since, report the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has been looking for a face-saving way to sign on. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the key legislative adjustment was allowing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to retain the power to appoint the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>.

            The USAT front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> piece quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX> official
saying that the reform bill is "going to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>'s worst nightmare"
because "shifting the burden will mean more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> intrusion into taxpayer
finances."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" brings word that because of the recent changes
in the capital gains tax rate, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Schedule D</ENAMEX> form for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s returns will
no longer have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> lines--it will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the global warming plan to be announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> "falls short" of more stringent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> proposals, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says it calls for only "relatively small reductions" in greenhouse
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gasses</ENAMEX>. By contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> emphasizes the plan's system of rewards (in
the form of pollution credits, tax breaks, and subsidies) for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that
achieve greater emission cuts than its standards require.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-page piece reports that a rigorous test of science
knowledge, given to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> nationwide, shows that upwards of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
percent of high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one-third</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>- and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eighth-graders</ENAMEX>, couldn't meet minimum academic expectations. Want to guess the
total number of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-graders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> achieving a score of
"advanced" on the test? Zero.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a piece inside on the trouble the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> is having
retaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the retention rate was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX>
percent. Now it's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 30 percent</NUMEX>. The main reasons: family separation and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> are hiring.

            With campaign reform dead for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to plunk down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> each for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> weekend
retreat at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of October</TIMEX> featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> for a
sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX>. In response to criticism of the event, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Grossman</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "I don't think it's unseemly.
It's open, it's transparent...." Definitely transparent.

         
      
   
