
   
   
      
         
            Presspourri

            As often happens on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are dominated by non-breaking
stories, which could have run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> or a month from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
the lead is word that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are talking about radically overhauling the
tax code. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s comment that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are hurting the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX> by systematically blocking
his appointments to the bench. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with details of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> abduction of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> have begun an
intense debate about how to follow up the balanced-budget amendment, reflecting
the fact that polls show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are becoming less responsive to mere tax cuts.
To lay the groundwork, reports the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, the
majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.J. Tauzin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that
they were embarking on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-city "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scrap the Code</ENAMEX>" tax tour in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> to
debate the merits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX>'s flat tax vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tauzin</ENAMEX>'s national retail sales tax."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Thursday</TIMEX>, the two kicked off this philosophical quest by throwing copies
of the federal tax code into a large garbage can.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead asserts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> now has convincing evidence that a
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> who was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> away from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizenship</ENAMEX> was abducted from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> human rights conference with the help of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and spirited off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> where he was murdered. This finding
is said to have upset relations between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that
throughout the course of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>' investigation of the incident, their
requests for help from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> have produced only limited cooperation, and that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> privately demanded that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hosni Mubarak</ENAMEX> order a full
investigation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> begins the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pieces on educational testing
with a piece on the failure of the field's largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testing Service</ENAMEX> (a nonprofit with an annual revenue <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400 million</NUMEX>), to get
cheating under control or to disclose security problems to the test-taking
public. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, says the paper, prefers to sweep its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> under the rug to
protect its dominant share of the testing business instead of spending the
money to tighten security. The story details widespread cheating on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> state school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>' test and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> proficiency
exams it administers as part of the citizenship process. And as first reported
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> recently, federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> have busted a
nationwide cheating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> on graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESL</ENAMEX> exams.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> is very much blowin' in the wind, with an omnibus review of his
oeuvre on the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts and Leisure</ENAMEX>" section and a picture
on the top front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> of him performing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>.

            In the wake of its handling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marv Albert</ENAMEX> story, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s column asked
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> to clarify its policy on naming names. Almost as if to oblige,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ombudsman"</ENAMEX> column examines that policy, primarily by
surveying the spectrum of views held by various senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. But a lot is
left unclear. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s policy as stated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> story was "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> does not identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of alleged sexual assaults."
The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ombudsman"</ENAMEX> column says the policy is to not name "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> accusing
another of a sex crime." (These are not the same thing: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> accusing
another of a sex crime against a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> would be covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
policy, but not by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>.) The original problem, previously pointed
out, was that, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> violated the policy stated
in that story within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">mere column inches</NUMEX>, by identifying the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
testified in the case. It can be pointed out now that the revised policy has
the same problem. And even the latter doesn't seem like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s de facto
policy. Can we really believe, for instance, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Bobbitt</ENAMEX>'s name was never
used during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's coverage of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s trial for sexually maiming
him?

         
      
   
