
   
   
      
         
            Fundseekers

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> mission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and the national edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
(the metro edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with the coming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC Democratic</ENAMEX>
mayoral run-off). At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , it's tobacco politics that leads and at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , it's military reform.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> differ from each other about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> paints a picture in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>'s statements upon
arrival emphasizing security drew criticism from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, but praise from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>. (This is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor</ENAMEX> of the USAT front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>
piece.) In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> even says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> praised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> emphasizes instead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s resistance, saying
that he "rebuffed" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s "appeal to cease economic restrictions to
encourage the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> to crack down on terrorism."

            There is no mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mideast</ENAMEX> diplomacy on the WP front, where the
lead is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s repeal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> tax credit for tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that had been inserted with little fanfare into the budget bill under
the prodding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>. The vote was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">95</NUMEX> for, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only three</TIMEX>
tobacco state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> against, and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> spoke in favor of the
credit.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead is the news that in the first major changes since
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> will announce <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that it's expanding basic training from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight to nine weeks</TIMEX>, with the extra time being used for lessons on values and
mutual respect, especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who now make up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX>.
Tougher screening of drill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeants</ENAMEX> will also be implemented.

            The heat on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> gets turned up another notch as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> each run above-the-fold front-page pieces detailing
how at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> hearings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, an internal memo was produced,
apparently signed off on by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, that explains that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> was routinely
dividing all solicited funds into hard (targeted to specific campaigns, highly
regulated) and soft (not for specific campaigns, not highly regulated) money
accounts regardless of the nature of the actual solicitation. These papers all
point out that the memo strongly suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> knew that the fund-raising
calls he made from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> were at least in part to raise hard money,
which he had initially denied--as well he might, since the amounts he
apparently raised in those calls exceeded legal limits for hard money.

            Incidentally, that memo also has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tell-tale left-handed
backwards check-mark on it too, which is noted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy"</ENAMEX> column, which
makes the case that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s investigation into whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
fund-raising activities merit an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s scrutiny will almost
inevitably push her into also investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s role.

            A further sign of fallout from the fundraising morass comes with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's front-page revelation that several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> with approved
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> clearances were initially prevented from entering the grounds
because security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> assumed their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> surnames meant they were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>. And double oops--one of the stymied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rights Commission</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this week</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, a religious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, wrote an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
op-ed complaining that the casual sex atmosphere of the coed dorms <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> is
requiring him to live in meant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> was forcing him to violate his religious
principles. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> contains a letter from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Dean</ENAMEX>, who
doesn't address the op-ed's charges that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> co-ed dorms, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are
frequently forced into "sexile" while their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates</ENAMEX> are having sex, and that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> are full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the opposite gender in various stages of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undress</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX> does write, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> has a long history of working with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to accommodate their personal values, and we would happily explore
accommodation in this case." "Accommodation" of modesty and abstinence--could
you ask for a clearer example of backwards campus values than that?

         
      
   
