
   
   
      
         
            Ad Nauseam

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> all lead with upstart <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>-based
telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldCom</ENAMEX>'s bid to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the latest target of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alleged Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> use in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> of state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> as a vehicle for end-running
legal spending limits.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> spending practices is unusually free
of legal qualification. It straight-out says "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>
quietly transferred <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $32 million</NUMEX> to state <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX> election as part of an elaborate plan to spend more money than federal
election law appeared to allow on a massive advertising campaign that
indirectly helped re-elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> makes it clear that
the strategy was directed not independently by the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> but centrally
by the campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> is among those quoted in support: "It was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">charade</ENAMEX> to say those were ads of the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>....I never spoke to anyone
from any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>."

            The story also notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> used similar strategies
during the last election, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> is reviewing its
spending in this area as well, but doesn't note this until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the twenty-third</TIMEX>
paragraph. And it's not mentioned at all in either the story's headline or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subhead</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story has this juicy detail indicating that there were some
worries inside the campaign about the scheme's propriety: During the campaign,
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> pressed for an indemnification clause in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>' contract that would have forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> to pay any
fines levied if the plan was found to be illegal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> refused.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldCom</ENAMEX> bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> seems to have enraptured the press because of its
size--it would be the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> takeover ever--and because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard</ENAMEX>
Ebbers, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">high basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> and motel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>, is good copy.
(Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> that if
he wanted to join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldCom</ENAMEX> he'd have to come to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pantingly</ENAMEX> describe the fabulous returns enjoyed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldCom's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> focuses instead on
how the deal might lead to more competition in local phone service.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lead reports that after a landmark study finding
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple SIDS</ENAMEX> deaths within <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> was rebuked in the leading medical journal
that originally published it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> have
reopened dozens of SIDS cases.

            With negotiations on an international global warming treaty coming up in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto</ENAMEX> soon, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , roiled
in internal debate on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> position for the talks. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side, says the
paper, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
Sperling, saying go slow. And on the other are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Wirth</ENAMEX>. Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself has emerged as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enviros</ENAMEX>'
strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, normally in that position, is distracted by his
fund-raising troubles and concerns about not alienating manufacturing states
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2000</TIMEX> election.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that, as part of the run-up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> invited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> national and local television
weather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forecasters</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> for briefings on climate change in hopes
of rallying public support for new measures restricting greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that the weather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> "appreciated being
treated as something other than airheads."

         
      
   
