
   
   
      
         
            Putting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Out the Best China</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead is a rare interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with news that the federal
investigation into a suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> scheme to buy influence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
politics has bogged down because the money trail has gone cold. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead is that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of relative price stability brought about by the
spread of managed care, the cost of health insurance is about to go up
significantly.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> that he urges <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to tolerate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
political system and to seek "common ground despite differences," and that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> "share the responsibility for preserving world
peace and stability." According to the story, during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s visit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will
pledge to end sales of cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and will receive, in return for
its promise to stop all support for nuclear programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>,
permission to purchase nuclear-power equipment from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>.

            The conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> was highly structured. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> submitted
questions in advance and when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> posed them face-to-face, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> read
written replies to them. (There was also eventually some informal discussion as
well.)

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> says in the interview that the theory of relativity can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to politics in that democracy and human rights are relative concepts,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> is apparently worried that you might not get his reference to
the theory's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> without the provision of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name, which it adds to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s remark: ".worked out by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">[Albert</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>."

            The WP front page reports that the agreement to loosen up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">port</ENAMEX> procedures for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> worked out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> shipping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> under the threat of banning them from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> is widely believed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to demonstrate that every so often, to
achieve trade fairness, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> must be "hit with the economic equivalent of a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-by-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>."

            How to explain that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s gathering at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arlington National Cemetery</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of female military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> for the dedication of a new memorial
honoring them was, among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>, deemed front-page news only at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> uses the latest round of presidential videotapes to serve up
a one-two anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> punch. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s lead editorial says that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 1995</TIMEX> tape on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>'s issue
ads were being used to drive up his poll numbers and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> was being
used to avoid the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> limit on individual contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> ads "is
smoking with evidence." And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> calls a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 1996</TIMEX> tape covering
much of the same ground "a smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>." Safire castigates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> for being obtuse in the face of this evidence and urges the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to
step up its investigative efforts to fill the void because "a widespread,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> conspiracy to violate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> election laws stares the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in the
face."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> run stories inside reporting on a piece
coming out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> concerning
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> salaries. It turns out that recently retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeastern</ENAMEX>
University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prez</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Curry</ENAMEX> made out the best with a total compensation package
of just under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>. Almost all the other top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> made over
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> reports that the average total pay for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> of research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$333,239</NUMEX>. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> points out that
these salaries are effectively even higher because most college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> have
housing provided to them.

         
      
   
