
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photo Opportunism</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>'s warning to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
against counting on a federal budget surplus. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with remarks by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Budget</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX> and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX> to the effect that expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> coverage to include younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> would be a mistake. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> go with the sudden threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>.

            The crux of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> situation is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Levy</ENAMEX>,
resigned on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> because of dissatisfaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s performance on
both the social welfare and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> fronts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that
the move only leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-vote margin in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>. The
Times says that without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> is likely to grow more dependent
on right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, and thus to become more resistant to pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
concessions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> run the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> story as their off-leads.

            In what is no doubt the payoff for concerted auto industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> lobbying,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> each
run front-page stories about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Three</ENAMEX>'s renewed interest in producing
less-guzzling, less-polluting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> are advised to clip and save these
for when the car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> howl the next time the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> tries to
lower <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">fuel</ENAMEX> economy and emission standards.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's story about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX> trial (run
on the front in the national edition, inside in the metro edition), the point
is made that the case's story of "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> fighting to save the life of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> he turned in" is "a tale of literary dimensions." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
apparently doesn't feel such an observation can stand without expert testimony,
so it drags in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kennedy</ENAMEX> and a lit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> to repeat it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> recently overlooked scads of
Agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> it should have invited to its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">50th</NUMEX> anniversary gala. Why?
Because it couldn't find them. How many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni spooks</ENAMEX> didn't get to come in
from the cold? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">As many as 30,000</NUMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamen</ENAMEX>, but he's just guessing because
"the numbers are secret."

            A piece inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that wonders when the downsizing trend will hit higher ed reports that between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984 and 1994</TIMEX>, the cost of college tuition went up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 150 percent</NUMEX>, outpacing
even medical care (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">111 percent</NUMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> started a hunger strike on the steps of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Hall</ENAMEX>. What's the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">causa</ENAMEX>? A protest by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardeners</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s imminent ban against
gasoline-powered leaf blowers. "Unfortunately, we feel a hunger strike is the
only way we can be heard," one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strikers</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . Well no,
we still can't hear you because of the... goddam leaf blowers !

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" included an overview of the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meals</ENAMEX> requested by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> executed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s wish was that his final
meal be given to a homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. Request denied.

            
               They're both clad only in bathing suits, alone on the beach. He clutches
her in to him with his hand on the small of her back while she's looking up at
him adoringly. The fade-out still from a new romantic movie? Or one of
those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> ads for a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> getaway? No, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lady</ENAMEX> on the top front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . Nothing inherently wrong here, but
think about it....This isn't a candid shot: there isn't an inch out of focus or
a blurry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> being parted. And nary a toe being sucked anywhere. And do you
think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> would let a paparazzo get even telephoto close to the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> Couple in seclusion on their vacation? No, this is a genre that hasn't
been so blatant since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>: the romantic photo-op. And what's wrong
is that, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paparazzi</ENAMEX>'s click-clicking, it's the exposure of what should
be an intimate family moment purely for gain, in this case, political.
Inflicting privacy is as unseemly as invading privacy.

         
      
   
