
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PAC Men Yes, Pac Man No</ENAMEX>

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> the lead story is the investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fund raising. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> abuses. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with a new national database designed to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deadbeat parents</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are intensifying their
drive to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged campaign-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> soliciting. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also has a front-page
story on this upwelling of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> pressure.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> should have commenced a review "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months ago</TIMEX>," and
that, "It seems to me there's politics being played all the way around."

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports a nonpolitical if not exactly
confidence-inspiring cause of the delay: The records of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
fund-raising calls, although turned over to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> task force
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, were not examined by the relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes front page with the results of a survey it did of
corporate political giving. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">544</NUMEX> biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, the paper
reports, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX> made no political contributions and didn't operate PACs
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1995-1996</TIMEX> election cycle. Included in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soup</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead tells of the inauguration on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX> of a federally
administered "vast database" of all new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hires</ENAMEX> in jobs nationwide that is
expected to yield a considerable increase--possibly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX>--in the payment of
child support. That's because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> will be able to use the directory to
locate deadbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and dun them, typically by getting court orders that
force their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to deduct the owed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support from paychecks. The
Times does however quote a privacy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> who expressed concern that
"private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> will find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> or a child
welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to give them access to information" from the new database.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports in its lead that the battle over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s tactics and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">powers</ENAMEX> is due to intensify <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> opens
hearings on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. The inquiry will look into whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is
overzealous in its use of liens and levies, and tends to pick on small "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>" returns that are less likely to mean a challenge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> in
court--rather than major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> run front-page items
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a new</TIMEX> breakthrough in computer chip technology to be announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>--using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> in semiconductors, which will mean
smaller, faster, and more powerful computer chips. This development, the papers
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observe</ENAMEX>, could be a boon not just to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s computer line, but also to its chip
manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>, which has already grown quite a bit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> buries this story <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> pages in.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> recounts on its front page how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> are cracking down on
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> use of computers for nonwork-related activities. Some
of the new management measures include software programs that allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to
track which Web sites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are visiting during work, and the provision of
stripped-down computers that don't take games, and a software package called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antigame</ENAMEX>," that scans <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> PC <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> for games and zaps them.

            The fight, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , has hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauch Faircloth</ENAMEX>
became so incensed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> when he caught <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his staff
playing PC games in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that he has introduced an amendment to a pending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> that would require federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to remove any games installed on their
computers and prohibit the purchase of new computers that have games
pre-installed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has unanimously approved the amendment, which now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">awaits House</ENAMEX> action.

         
      
   
