
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Riady for Prime Time Players</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$28 billion</NUMEX> bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s testimony before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> about her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> fund-raising probe.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>'s move is the
biggest cash offer in corporate history and that it sets up a fight for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WorldCom</ENAMEX>, which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> made a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> all-stock
offer. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Telecommunications</ENAMEX>, which had previously reached an agreement
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> to take over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 billion</NUMEX> in cash and stock, might make
it a three-way bidding war, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> suggest the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> concern
will drop out. No matter the particular outcome, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> sees the
dealing as indicative of the telecommunications industry's trend towards
increasing consolidation, noting that a combined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE-MCI</ENAMEX> would be the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> since the breakup of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> to have a large presence in both local
and long-distance markets. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> will "give this thing a very, very hard look" precisely because the
deal would produce a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> like the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> in its scope.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees the possibility here of "a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980s</TIMEX>-style hostile takeover
battle." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> also sees a return to wild action, possibly to include
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX> jumping in with a bid.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> have front-page coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> testimony, and all
report the open hostility from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. But they vary in what
aspect of her remarks they stress. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> lead emphasizes her
revelation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that she has agreed not to close out any line of
fund-raising inquiry unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX> also agrees. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also
stresses this, calling it an "extraordinary arrangement," but then goes on to
quote a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX> have entered into such
agreements before. But it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that specifies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> examples of when:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800. The WP highlights <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s admission
that her fund-raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> has had problems, including internal disputes about
how to proceed.

            More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> fundraising tapes were released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and several of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> suggest that they are damaging to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the
tapes show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> conferring easily, at times on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name basis, "with
some of the most notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign." The papers note that
in this batch of videos, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> can be seen in friendly banter, not just
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Riady</ENAMEX>, but also with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yah Lin Trie</ENAMEX>, and the
recently convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Teamster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Davis</ENAMEX>.

            In his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX> explains how it can be that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s popularity is up since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s bungled attempt to
assassinate a top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> operative. "The silent majority in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> stopped
caring a long time ago about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nablus</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hebron</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
As far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> silent majority is concerned, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> can have
them all. But...if they can't eat in peace at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apropos Cafe</ENAMEX>, shop at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> or ride the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>, then no amount of serial bungling by Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> will turn the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> silent majority against him." That fear of
suicide terrorism, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>, is "the most important political fact in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> brings word that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, acting under pressure from
a federal lawsuit, broke a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-year-old</TIMEX> budgetary silence and confirmed for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> intelligence budget: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26.6 billion</NUMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX> spends that kind of money, it knows what it's getting.

         
      
   
