
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Guise</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolls</ENAMEX>

            The decision by a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Teamsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX> from
running for re-election leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . The terrorist attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with a federal court decision that ensures that next
year <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> will be able to vote across party lines in primary elections.
A party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying that such open primaries are like "letting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> choose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USC</ENAMEX>'s head <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> was barred, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, because he misused his power by tolerating
and engaging in various laundering schemes to funnel money from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s
general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> to his own election effort. How much money? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says
"<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$735,000</NUMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> agrees with that total in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place but elsewhere
says "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $1 million</NUMEX>." (If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> is rounding up, it should have
said "nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three-quarters of a million dollars</NUMEX>.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the
ruling is a major blow to organized labor's recent resurgence, and runs a
companion piece elaborating this point. Oddly, the main piece doesn't mention
the high-water mark of that resurgence--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> in last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike--while the companion piece relegates it to the twelfth
paragraph.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration is quietly trying to negotiate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> by offering
to loosen the current constraints on what he can buy with his oil proceeds if
he will let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> back in. But death flashes in the region
anyway. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, mostly foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>,
were killed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> outside an ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> in an attack by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
militants, who have for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> been trying to overthrow the moderate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mubarak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooters</ENAMEX> and
that they were all killed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is alone in
suggesting that there were at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> and that several might have
escaped.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> massacre also tops the World-Wide news digest box at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , and is on the front at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . It looks as if, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , there were no American
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. Presumably, that's the reason the story isn't everybody's lead? Is
that a good reason?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has an intriguing detail about the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei Jingshang</ENAMEX>:
namely that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> signaled the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> that he would be allowed to
leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>'s visit here went well. As a result, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deliberately avoided mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei</ENAMEX> by name during
his joint press conference with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> when the issue of jailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> came
up.

            In his op-ed column, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> have gotten a "hold" put on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s choice to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hormel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hormel</ENAMEX> is openly gay and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> fear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hormel</ENAMEX> "might use this post to promote [the gay] agenda."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> observes that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX> is not a post conducive to
promoting any agenda more daring than a wine list."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> has just hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>. The piece says it is now estimated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20 percent</NUMEX>
of the world's online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> handles its phone traffic with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600,000</NUMEX> modems.

            Playing off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s front-page WSJ story reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> is
scheduled for breast reduction ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" missed that one, being too
preoccupied with other pressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> news), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> assigns seven
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to the story. They come back with interviews about the impending
surgery with little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who love <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbies</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>'s current dimensions puts it this way: "I don't want her to look like
somebody I know."

         
      
   
