
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenhousekeeping Seal of Approval</ENAMEX>

            The approval in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> of a global warming control plan leads all around. The
dailies note that it puts the first-ever mandatory limits on greenhouse gases
like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX>, assigning various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> different output reductions to
be implemented from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008 to 2012</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> would be required to cut emissions
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> levels. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> says developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are exempt from
the emissions cuts and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> agreed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-backed emissions trading
system for industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> but will spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> deciding how it will
work.

            The coverage is confusing, since, for example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says the meetings simply tabled until next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> the issue of whether and how the world's poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> would participate,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says the industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> are required to reduce their emissions of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
main greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.2 percent</NUMEX> below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> levels, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times says they're bound to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.5 percent</NUMEX> reduction. (But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> headline says <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>. No small matter--that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a percent
represents a lot of pollution.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>' work was no doubt made difficult by the same rigors faced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>, who kept working even though the interpreters went home and, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> was down to just a few <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>.

            The papers convey the overall impression that environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are
fairly pleased by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> protocol and that industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> hate it.
"This agreement represents unilateral economic disarmament," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . And all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> agree
that the plan's prospects in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, which must ratify it for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to
become bound to it, are at best iffy. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a separate piece about this under the headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Declares Kyoto Pact Dead</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> will alter the way "global <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>" do things.
Question: are there any other kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>? But give the LAT
credit for making the most straightforward observation about why some reform is
necessary: "...1997 has been the warmest year on record." Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headlines</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Global Warming Pact OK'd</ENAMEX>," overstate a bit, since it's
a plan, not a deal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> hits the nail a little more squarely: "Tentative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reached to Cut Greenhouse Gases</ENAMEX>."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that the scientific journal
Nature reveals <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have achieved a primitive form of
teleportation, by replicating the exact properties of a light particle into
another <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one three feet</NUMEX> away. After reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> pieces, it was surprising
not to find an outraged quote or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> here from airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>.

            Lingering question from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">l'affaire Lawrence</ENAMEX> for assignment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>: Why not
do a story about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> came to seize upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bushnell</ENAMEX> sinking as the
fabric for his fiction?

            No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is complete without a quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, who rarely misses a chance to bite the hand that no longer feeds him.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s example comes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's story about the new presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>
weighs in with: "I think the phenomenon of unconditional loyalty is probably
something that he could use as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>..But if I were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, I would watch
my back, because I'm not sure the quality of unconditional love is always
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reciprocated</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that prior to setting out for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Bronx</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> in "a" <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,500</NUMEX>-night presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldorf-Astoria</ENAMEX>. (Question: do they really have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>? If so, why?) After touring the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports
he went shopping, buying among other things, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> in jewelry and some sweaters
and briefcases. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> said he couldn't charge the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> produced his credit card, saying, "Yes, you can." Question:
Does that mean we also get to charge him for that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waldorf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
