
   
   
      
         
            Diaper Rashness

            The possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> will back off its attempt to prevent or modify
weapons inspections leads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
will endorse a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s rights bill.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> story took a big turn late in the news cycle, when early this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Geneva</ENAMEX> meeting of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>,
was told by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> had relented. The papers report
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s reaction: "I will believe it when I see it." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> states
that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> does indeed back down, it will represent an
important victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> diplomacy. But only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> seems to notice what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> might have accomplished in
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three uninspected weeks</TIMEX>: the production of "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX> liters--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 92</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gallons</ENAMEX>--of anthrax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. That's enough to fill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> warheads or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
bombs."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> intends to call on all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> to adopt
standards , endorsed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>, for easier
patient access to treatment, better health care information flow and improved
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">appeals</ENAMEX> procedures. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> broke the story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s
recommendations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks ago</TIMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s call is his
largest and most controversial foray into health care since the defeat of his
reform plan <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>. And as with that plan, the paper notes, there will
be much discussion about the cost of these new rights.

            The live births of those septuplets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> grabs a lot of front-page space.
And uncomplicated boosterism suffuses most of the coverage. The LAT
reports the event under the headline "Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby</ENAMEX>!" and displays
their names and birth weights inside drawings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby booties</ENAMEX>. The WP
waits until the thirteenth paragraph of its story to mention the fertility <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> involved and that such
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are frowned upon by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. USAT
waits more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty paragraphs</TIMEX> before raising an eyebrow, with this
contrarian quote from an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on multiple births: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> were not meant to
have litters." The . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> flashes much more awareness than the others of the
ethical, medical and economic problems inherent in the births.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s quote: "God gave us those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and he wants us to raise them,"
makes everybody's story. Well no, it was actually science and a huge amount of
charity: The coverage mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forty specialists</ENAMEX> attended the births and
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has been hospitalized for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a month</TIMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes
that the part of the bill not paid by insurance will be covered by a fund set
up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> has announced that the
state will build the family a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs a feature on the first-ever relieving for cause of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Trident</ENAMEX>
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile submarine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skipper</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ran the story several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>, but the tale bears repeating.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skipper</ENAMEX>, a real-life Captain
Queeg, deserved to get bounced. He reamed out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX> in public over such
trivialities as a missing dinner fork. More seriously, under his command,
botched communications led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>'s not knowing where his ICBM-laden sub
was for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine days</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> brings closure on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> prank. It seems that one
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Virginia</ENAMEX> awoke to discover a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> perched on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotunda</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">fifty feet</NUMEX> above the ground. The prankster
was never identified. Until now. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">culprit</ENAMEX>, fearing unmasking by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX>,
stepped forward and paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,755</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> who investigated the incident.
He is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred R. Berkeley III</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ</ENAMEX> stock exchange.

         
      
   
