
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Stonewall of China</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> is the big story. It's the national lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
have a huge money-raising and spending edge over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> for the
elections coming up, but also gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> plenty of top-front coverage.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> headlines at both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> emphasize his
reference to past "mistakes," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headline focuses instead on
the applause he received during his speech. The "applause" and "laughter"
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) or cheers ( WP ) came when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> said his current trip to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> gave him a more specific understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy than he'd had
previously. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> were the largest there since
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>.) The "mistakes" came in this way: when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> was asked why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> had chosen confrontation over dialogue in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, he replied, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It</ENAMEX>
goes without saying that naturally we may have shortcomings and even make some
mistakes in our work, however we've been working on a constant basis to improve
our work."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> seems to take the applause as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> approval of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>, but
isn't it more likely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> was applauding the power of raucous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> protest instead? Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and LAT make much
of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s mention of mistakes was an unprecedented policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concession</ENAMEX>, but
since he didn't say anything at all about <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> or political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> when he used the phrase, why couldn't it be taken to be no more than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> "mistakes were made"--in
other words merely a simulated apology, not a real one? After all, within
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of speaking of mistakes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> was adamant in his defense of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s actions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interestingly</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> doesn't even mention
the "mistake" line.)

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, here's what academic freedom means at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> where
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is involved: The questions asked of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> were chosen by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> insisted that there be no questions
from the floor (although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> ended up taking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> anyway--one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he
called on turned out to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> moderating all this "was almost apologetic" when repeating
non-softball questions.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial includes a list of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political bigshots</ENAMEX> who are
now against soft money: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Baker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Michel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Brock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Simpson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Kassebaum Baker</ENAMEX>.
Isn't it amazing that they all waited to retire before telling us how they
really feel?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has agreed to address for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever the validity of polygraph evidence. The argument isn't coming
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, but from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> who claims a polygraph result would have
cleared him and hence the current prohibition violates his right to present
favorable evidence.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece reports an attempt by family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> to create
new revenue streams by staging, for an admissions fee, demonstrations of
various farm activities, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">branding cattle</ENAMEX> to making <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane syrup</ENAMEX>. The
Times calls the trend "agritainment."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that a certain segment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is furious
about the case of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> convicted of killing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in her
charge and wants to do something about it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Nanny Association</ENAMEX>,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , issued a press release recently with the headline:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journalists Make Horrendous Mistake</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurts Entire Multi-Million Dollar</ENAMEX>
Industry--It's an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Au Pair Not Nanny on Trial</ENAMEX>!"

         
      
   
