
   
   
      
         
            Let's MIG a Deal

            Election <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'97</NUMEX> leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , and the major local races lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision that could lead to cheaper
consumer goods. The political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> that get most of the ink are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s big win in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Todd Whitman</ENAMEX>'s close
call in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> as "once considered a future
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>"--an odd appellation since pulling out a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term
over a strong challenger would seem to enhance her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> was being rewarded for presiding over his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent</NUMEX> crime
drop.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's top national story is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s nomination of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lann Lee</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>'s top civil rights job is in bad
shape. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are feeling their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision letting <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 209</ENAMEX> stand and are suggesting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> and any other future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> to the post will face a tough new standard on
affirmative action.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's top national story is what it calls "one of the most
important antitrust decisions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s unanimous ruling
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> does not automatically violate
antitrust statutes by placing a ceiling on the retail price that may be charged
for its products. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, which filed a brief in the case supporting price
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caps</ENAMEX>, notes that it's widely believed the decision will lead to lower consumer
prices.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead story on this decision includes the provenance of a
common ad phrase: "offer good at participating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> only." Prior to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the paper explains, this rider was required because independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> could not be forced to charge the price in question. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also
carries the price cap story on its front, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> includes it in its front-page business
and finance news box. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> doesn't get to it until p. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> of its
business section.

            Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> inspection crisis hasn't really changed that much, the
papers, never really that engaged, have dropped it down a couple of notches.
The story is featured in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's "world-wide" news box, and it's above
the fold of the LAT front. But it's below the fold at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and on
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. A6</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p. A29</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a top-front story about "a novel tack" the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has just
used to keep some advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>-era <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> out of the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>--buying
them <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. It seems the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> recently bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG-29</ENAMEX> jet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX>
of them capable of carrying nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>--from the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moldova</ENAMEX> out of the fear that they would otherwise end up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s
possession. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> will study and fly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> says.)
Defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> wouldn't say what the purchase price was, but,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> put up not just money but also food and
supplies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story on the deal reports that the cash put up was less
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that the purchase funds came from a "threat
reduction" program established to help dismantle the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>.

            The latest circulation audit shows that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s fifteen largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> recorded an increase in daily circulation, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .
And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly two-thirds</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> with circulations <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 200,000</NUMEX> recorded
gains. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> aren't doing so well, though.

            Did you know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> allows some of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to use pseudonyms
when dealing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>? So says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "Tax Report," which states
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX> says these are only allowed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> who fear being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harassed</ENAMEX>, threatened or assaulted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. There are currently <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pseudonyms</ENAMEX> in use at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.

            Back to those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIGS</ENAMEX> for a minute: Note that our "threat reduction" money
isn't being used to buy back similarly capable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-15s</ENAMEX> in
the inventories of such combustible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>. That's
because those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> were made and sold for a nice piece of change by
us.
            

         
      
   
