
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Au My</ENAMEX>!

            The au pair reversal of fortune leads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> --and takes lot of prime front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> elsewhere. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>'s
decision to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WorldCom</ENAMEX>'s merger bid leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s retreat on fast track.

            The USAT front features, besides the lead, a big picture of a smiling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Woodward</ENAMEX> and a cover story on the discretionary powers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>. The
WP front runs the same picture and another of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> cheering the news.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs an almost-cherubic picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> in court and an
editorial praising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s action, under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Justice Restored</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> looks out of touch playing the story below the fold, below
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Katzenberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> settlement. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder</ENAMEX> what his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">au pair</ENAMEX> pulls down a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>.)

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> are struck by the difference between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s hysterical reaction to the original verdict and her poker-faced
demeanor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. In general the discussion of the legalities is informative,
but there could have been a bit more in the coverage about the nature of the
"malice" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> found crucially missing. In the relevant legal sense,
it's not ill will, nor even necessarily an intention to do harm, and it doesn't
have to be expressed or a conscious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of mind. It's weaker: it's doing
something in disregard of the fact that it's likely to be harmful. The upshot
is that the absence of malice in the case is less obvious than ordinary
language would suggest.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead on the fast track fizzle calls it the most severe
legislative setback for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> since his national health care plan died, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that many on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> are saying that it marks the
beginning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame-duck</ENAMEX> status. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> says as much to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> : "The last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> are going to be largely a rhetorical
presidency....Legislatively, it's over."

            The coverage makes it clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>'s decision to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WorldCom</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> buyout offer--the largest in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history--is great news for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> don't effectively explain why they think this is
also potentially earth-shattering news for everyone else. For instance, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's lead sentence in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> story states that the deal could
"redefine competition in the telecommunications industry," but never really
explains how this would be so. And some explanation is required, because to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uninitiated</ENAMEX>, mergers mean less competition, not more.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs some excerpts from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX>'s diary. Here's one:
"Experiment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">97</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 11, 1985</TIMEX>. I planted bomb disguised to look like scrap of
lumber behind <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rentech Compute</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>.... The device was hidden
inside a hollow piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, so that when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> were to be grabbed or
picked up, the bolts in the trigger would come out. The device was deployed on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 11th, 1985</TIMEX>." That "deployment" was the murder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who picked up
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also has a stunning revelation about the way the Ivy League
used to do business. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darmouth</ENAMEX> used the occasion
of dedicating a campus <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student center</ENAMEX> to haul out a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> letter between
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumnus</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of admissions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alum</ENAMEX> complained
that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> seems more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> each time I arrive in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover</ENAMEX>. And
unfortunately many of them (on quick judgment) seem to be the 'kike' type." And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth</ENAMEX> admissions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> wrote back, "I am glad to have your comments on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> problem, and I shall appreciate your help along this line in the
future. If we go beyond the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> in the Class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>, I
shall be grieved beyond words." In reacting to the revelation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elie Wiesel</ENAMEX>
summons a simple fact that suggests how much times have changed: the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
