
   
   
      
         
            Funds and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Games</ENAMEX>

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scandalous</ENAMEX> political fund-raising leads. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , it's news of dramatic drops in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> welfare rolls.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> 's top story is that a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> is warning that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s public and private computer systems are gravely vulnerable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cyber</ENAMEX>-sabotage.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cyber-commission</ENAMEX>'s findings won't be handed in until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says they include such measures as establishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for
collecting information about all computer security breaches and creating a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to coordinate all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s computer security
efforts. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Nunn</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that the issue is right up there
with nuclear, chemical and biological weapons security.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> denies that the coffee
tapes mandated the appointment of an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and repeats that the
failure to turn over the tapes in a more timely manner was a "simple mistake,
not deliberate defiance." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> also says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are using
the tapes to divert attention from their defeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>-Feingold reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made these remarks before embarking on a campaign fundraising
swing through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, made necessary in part by the large
number of contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> during the last election cycle that had to
be returned because they proved questionable. Meanwhile says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> hearings, former senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickes</ENAMEX> also staunchly defended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign finance practices.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's campaign finance lead is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> landfill
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has pleaded guilty to funneling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$129,000</NUMEX> in illegal corporate donations
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--including the presidential campaigns of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>--and agreed to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a record $8 million</NUMEX> fine. The scam here was the
disguising of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> donations as individual donations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> involved state that they had no reason to believe that the purported
individual <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> donations weren't legit, even though some came from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> will announce
that it has persuaded handgun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to provide child-safety locks with
all their products. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accidental</ENAMEX> shootings, says the paper, killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">185</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>.

            All the majors give front-page space to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s inflation warning
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>--and to the downward spiral it predictably caused in the financial
markets. In recent testimony, the fed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> had suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> has entered some new sort of anti-inflationary era where tremendous
increases in productivity enable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to absorb cost increases they would
have formerly passed along as price increases. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>
returned to a straightforward reading of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillips</ENAMEX> curve: increased
employment leads to higher wages, which leads to higher prices.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that flu shots drive down business absenteeism and
health-care costs so much that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are starting to entice and pressure
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to get them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastman Kodak</ENAMEX>, for instance, says the shots saved
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.8 million</NUMEX> in absenteeism just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. But even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> gives
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX> for free, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> "won't take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the deltoid
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>." The leading causes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> reticence seem to be fear of
getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> from the shots and fear of needles.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has word that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> study <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> reports that when people
stop smoking, overall health costs decline only in the short term, and after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, actually increase. Look for this study to be used by tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> in an attempt to whittle the cost of any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> or national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tobacco</ENAMEX> deal, even though it merely illustrates the truism that dying of old
age is the most expensive way to go. After all, issuing handguns to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> would cut overall health care costs too.

            How have recent meat health scares affected the restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>? Well,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , you can still get a rare hamburger at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mountain Mist Ice Cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stand</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saranac Lake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>--but you do have to
sign a liability waiver <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
