
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Race Ipsa Loquitur</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the dust-up over the expulsion by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> of some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a weapons inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with more bad news about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
metro edition leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stumping in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
mayoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> and then in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> gubernatorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> national edition leads with a story you could be
excused for not worrying about--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> plans for
spending all those future federal budget surpluses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> front has
a truly spectacular color shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX> in the NYC marathon going over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Verrazano-Narrows bridge</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> accounts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> situation emphasize
that congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> are all on the
same page: if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> can't negotiate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> into reversing itself, then it's
ass-kicking time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page piece on this quotes the
explanation proffered for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s behavior by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the weapons
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>: namely, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is probably still in the biological and
chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead reports that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> internal audit found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s
focus on disseminating as much information as possible to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> via phone
has resulted in serious breaches of confidentiality. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> operated a sting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that established that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> could easily
obtain income data on other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> using only name, address and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security Number. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> tried this in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">109</NUMEX> calls and got improper
information in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX> of them.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> charted its own course and ignored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s oblique
remark at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> about "mistakes" his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has made. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in its
front-page piece on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> accomplished with his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trip (a lot: he got
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and nuke equipment, and looked good here and back home), the
Times plays catch up, now likewise seeing the remark as significant.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece
makes the point that cultural exchange between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is wreaking
bigger changes back there than could ever be arrived at via summitry. In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past decade</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter of a million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to study in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000 or so</NUMEX> who have returned have brought
back "impressions of an open society, a thriving market economy, the rule of
law and the role of minority rights."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that a growing number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> now say it will be difficult if not impossible to avoid doubling the
amount of heat-trapping gasses in the atmosphere before the greenhouse problem
is brought under control, which could mean anywhere from a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>- to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-degree increase in the earth's temperature.

            The USAT front section cover story states that a new poll of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teenagers</ENAMEX> shows that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX> of them say they've dated someone of another
race or ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. This up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 17 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. And another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
percent who haven't dated inter-racially say they have no objection to doing
so.

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT IRS</ENAMEX> story contains the following explanation: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outside</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> warn, however, that business conducted over the telephone is generally
less secure than by mail." For this, we needed an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
