
   
   
      
         
            The Check is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tail</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>'s suspicions that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has been tampering with his surveillance cameras in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s absence.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s resounding passage of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
reform bill. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the meaning of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s
elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
metro edition leads with the meaning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s election, while the
paper's national lead is the soon-to-be-announced decision by major mail-order
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to start collecting sales tax from their out-of-state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.

            The upshot of the camera tampering, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> can't verify that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is not currently producing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass
destruction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has this story on its front page too.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT IRS</ENAMEX> lead calls the reform bill's passage by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">426</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> margin a
"spectacular display of bipartisanship" created by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearings
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> mismanagement and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> abuse. The paper points out that the bill,
which includes such taxpayer protections as shifting the burden of proof to the
government in tax disputes and the creation of a civilian oversight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, will
likely be even further strengthened by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> reform is on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and in the "world-wide news" box on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front, but inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            A WSJ front-page piece makes the point that while political debate
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> portrays it as abusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>, in the world of corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>, waging a constant war against a
stream of ingenious and complicated new tax dodges.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> concludes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> victories were mostly
due to lavish financing, widespread social conservatism among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, and an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unwillingness</ENAMEX>, bred of the healthy economy, to dump <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX>. In light of all
this, says the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are viewing the goals of recapturing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
and gaining parity in governorships as more difficult than ever. And according
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the lesson for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> is keep talking about
taxes.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story inside stating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who used the
Internet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX> to accuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> of shooting down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800 is now
saying that action was "reckless and a mistake." Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Salinger</ENAMEX>, who championed the accusation, has quietly backed off too. He
says he still believes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was behind the disaster, but he has told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> that he is no longer actively investigating.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a story inside reporting that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence
official, "apparently a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>," has left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> after being caught
wiretapping the phone of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX>. The piece goes on to point
out that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> have been caught spying in, and
kicked out of, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> all run
front-page stories about how an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> has for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX> concluded that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acupuncture</ENAMEX> is an effective treatment for some kinds of pain and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nausea</ENAMEX> and
shows promise as a treatment for a variety of other conditions. Health experts
say the decision will almost certainly lead to more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> opting for the
technique and more private and government insurance paying for them to do
so.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a story inside based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> reports saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">junkyard</ENAMEX> have made an interesting discovery in the trunk of an
abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>: a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> Madison <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guaranty Savings and Loan</ENAMEX> check for more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> made out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. The paper points out that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
testified under oath in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James McDougal</ENAMEX>'s bank fraud trial that he had "never
borrowed money from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Guaranty</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>
has been investigating the check.

            Go figure: That mail-order sales tax agreement will apply to products sold
over cable TV and the Internet, but not to those sold via online information
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">providers like America Online</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
