
   
   
      
         
            Herzo Good

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Family</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herzogovina</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , and is the top national story at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> stories--all accompanied by big top-of-the page photos of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, the best one being the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea</ENAMEX> up close and personal with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>--all point out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s quick mission had the dual purpose of boosting the morale of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and urging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnians</ENAMEX> to work harder on their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s recovery. The
pitch to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnians</ENAMEX>, both in private consultations with national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and
in a public speech in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarajevo</ENAMEX>, included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s insistence on the importance
of isolating and arresting indicted war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> all go front page with the
news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has approved prescription of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-baldness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>. This comes
after experiments showing that the substance either promoted hair growth or at
least stopped hair loss in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who took it. The approval came
despite recognition that the pills carry a slight risk of impotence and reduced
sex drive. (That there is expected to be a strong market for the medication
despite these possible side-effects is yet more evidence of the growing
narcissism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, who apparently is more interested in looking
sexy than being sexy.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs a front-page piece about the career-ending spinal injury
suffered by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linebacker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reggie Brown</ENAMEX> in a game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. The piece focuses
on the inspirational story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> praying for him on the
field while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> worked on him feverishly, but treads lightly around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>'s dirty little not-so-secret: namely, that because of the incredible
increases in the size, strength, and speed of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, serious spinal and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> injuries are becoming more common all the time. So much so that pro
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is now far more dangerous than those "ultimate fighting championships"
that are outlawed in all but a few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.

            Call it the integration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and (solid-) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports in a front-page feature on a
new trend: telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> paying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> for the right to put
wireless transmission equipment in their steeples. It's a match made in heaven:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> get a nifty end-run around local bans on new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> and the
churches get an income stream far more reliable than the collection plate.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s LAT front-page story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fund-raising juggernaut bears revisiting</ENAMEX>. Closer inspection of the illustration
accompanying the piece, purporting to be of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s schedule for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1996</TIMEX>, reveals that it is deeply deceptive. Although as the fine print
says, it is compiled from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official sources</ENAMEX>, it is not a photograph of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s daybook, but rather a representation of his schedule concocted
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> made to look like one. And not a very accurate one
either: for instance, in a trick that's repeated throughout the graphic, the
fund-raising entries for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 17</TIMEX> form a solid block of type, but this
is a trompe l'oeil achieved only by leaving a bunch of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> out of the
"daybook"'s format. This sleight-of-hand is just as unacceptable as the similar
newsmagazine cover practices of sinisterizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OJ</ENAMEX> and beautifying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quint</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>, or
the bygone TV fad of "re-creation." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> hopes that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> variant can
also be shamed out of favor.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts report on that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $5</NUMEX>
million verdict won by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter Tylo</ENAMEX>, who sued because she was hired to
play a seductress on 'Melrose Place' but was then fired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spelling</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> when it was revealed she was pregnant. Spelling officials
had claimed that a visibly pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> couldn't be credible in the sexy
role. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tylo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> saying it was important for the jury
to see that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tylo</ENAMEX>, who was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> into another pregnancy during the trial,
"looked unbelievably sexy and terrific" as she came to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in short, tight
skirts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spelling</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> says there will be an appeal. But the main way
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> deals with onrushing bandwagons is to jump right on, so stay tuned in
the fall for the new voluptuous pregnant chick series, "Cervixens!"

         
      
   
