
   
   
      
         
            Butting Out

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the national tobacco accord's plummeting prospects. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>
Teresa funeral is the top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> (taking a back seat to the opening of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">new Redskins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>) as it is at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times (behind a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> tax cut and a story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> declares the dramatic <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$368.5 billion</NUMEX> tobacco deal, which
promised to revolutionize the marketing and regulation of cigarettes when it
was proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months ago</TIMEX>, "all but dead." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has been less than
enthusiastic because many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> view the prepackaged deal as trespassing on
their turf of working out bills. Other big factors: the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>'s
impolitic attempt to slip a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> rebate into the budget bill, and the
widespread belief that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are willing to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$368 billion</NUMEX>, they
must be able to afford more. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
helped shaped the deal, it has steadily backed away from it--so much so that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is being urged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> to offer only a general outline of
a national tobacco policy rather than a detailed piece of legislation.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> can't help but think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> have spent a little
too much time on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> coverage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week</TIMEX>.
Their headline for the tobacco deal story? "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tobacco Accord</ENAMEX>, Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Applauded</ENAMEX>, Is
All But Buried."

            Because of its time-zone advantage, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> was able to put its
initial coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> edition. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> couldn't cover it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> account
emphasizes something that the others missed, namely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> in
attendance were far smaller than expected. The main reason, says the paper, is
that "the poor, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped</ENAMEX> and the troubled--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> Mother <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teresa</ENAMEX>
spent her life helping--were barred from taking part, at the insistence of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> military, largely for security reasons."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a front-page story about a graduate entrance exam
cheating scheme recently broken up by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. It had been
operating from coast to coast for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and before it was discovered had
enabled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to gain acceptance into graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fraudulent GRE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> that some had paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $9,000</NUMEX> for. The
scheme involved paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> test-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX> on the east coast, lots of cell calls,
and the distribution of pencils with answer keys on them to the cheating
test-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX> on the west coast.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has a front-page piece about one somewhat surprising
consequence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> sex scandals: the service is planning to put into
effect very soon new physical training standards for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are much closer
to male norms.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reveals on its front page that it has gotten ahold of the
deposition recently given to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickes</ENAMEX>. The depo makes it clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickes</ENAMEX> isn't exactly spilling his guts on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> fund-raising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. In response to the usual request to
describe his background for the record, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickes</ENAMEX> replied, "I was born. I grew up.
I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also covers the fundraising scandal in its lead editorial,
which says that in light of all the recent revelations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s continued
failure to call for an special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> "looks like a political blocking
operation to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>." The editorial goes on to
call for a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and says it would be a political subterfuge to limit
him/her to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. "His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> has earned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, too."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corrections</ENAMEX>" page carries this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX>: "A report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the wedding</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily Changchien</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Richard Middleton Jr.</ENAMEX> misstated
the honors with which they graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX>. They both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">graduated magna cum laude</ENAMEX>, not cum laude." At press time, corrected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPAs</ENAMEX> were
not available.

         
      
   
