
   
   
      
         
            Brewing Scandal

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> video revelations lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> . They are also the lead national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and top off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World-Wide</ENAMEX>" news box.

            The situation, now reported by everyone, and broken by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , is that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> gave congressional and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> videotapes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> coffees in which potential
or actual campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> met with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The tapes could shed
light on a question <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have been looking into for some time: Did
inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>? The tapes have already set off a political firestorm
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> didn't receive them until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, the day
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> announced she found no evidence that the coffees broke the
law. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>'s remark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> that with the latest flap,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> "may have crossed the line of obstruction of justice" is quoted
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> points out that such tapes
were ostensibly covered by congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> subpoenas going back to last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> had previously
been told that no such tapes existed.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> each report that one segment
of the tapes appears to show then-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Fowler</ENAMEX> being offered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
checks by an unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendee</ENAMEX>. Also drawing wide attention: the only
segment of the compilation without a sound <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
seen meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>. "We have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Mary Woods</ENAMEX> problem here," an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> presses the questionable timing of the videos' release a bit
more than the other papers, pointing out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> investigations
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> was notified about them on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
met with committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> tapes story has the same basics as everybody else,
although unaccountably reporting the non-news that at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX> coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi to George Steinbrenner</ENAMEX> before getting to the potentially
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explosive Fowler</ENAMEX> story.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will announce his first
extensive use of the new line-item veto authority to cut funding for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 to 50</TIMEX>
military projects worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $300 million</NUMEX> from a defense construction bill he
signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> claims that these projects were not requested
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, but rather are political <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> all feature front-page stories
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s botched attempt to kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahyu</ENAMEX> has
been gravely damaged politically by the failure both domestically and
internationally. (Of course if the plan were successful, his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
would have thought he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>.) But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also has an excellent
narrative of the mission, right down to a (literally) blow-by-blow account of
the fist-fight in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were captured. Also, it's the
Post that has a named <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> saying it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> himself who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> the assassination plan, and that makes it clear the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> was deeply
involved in the post-botch negotiations resulting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s surrendering of
the antidote to the poison they used in the mission and in the release from
prison of the spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>.

            It's a staple of the assassination attempt coverage to call this operation
the worst blunder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mossad</ENAMEX>'s history. It's odd that none of these stories
mention <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lillehammer</ENAMEX>, which would have to be considered an even worse snafu--a
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> assassination of an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            In case you weren't sure, a "reefer" headline (that is, one referring to an
inside story) on the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> makes it official: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cycle Speeds Up</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
