
   
   
      
         
            He's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Going to the Long Bomb ... YES</ENAMEX>!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s call for
ratification of a comprehensive nuclear test ban. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the imminent return--under very tight regulations--of the approved
use of thalidomide. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s first comments about
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> fund-raising activities since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> announced she was taking a
look at them that might lead to an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s advocacy of the test ban came during his speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> leader
in the world to sign the treaty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, and says his position sets the
stage for a confrontation with congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. Additionally, the
paper points out that in his speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also promised that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> would pay off the bulk of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX> in back dues it owes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, and supported a special international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to prosecute crimes
against humanity.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> appearance covers the same basic
material, but also has some good background on the test-ban treaty, stating
that the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">domestic-policy</ENAMEX> obstacle to a ban since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> first sought
one is the fear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> cannot maintain its nuclear deterrent
without testing. The paper points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is trying to address the
former problem by ensuring that a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5-billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> nontest-explosion
research program will adequately maintain the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s nuke stockpile. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> put their coverage inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has the
detail that the ban may take a long time to go into effect because the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> believed to have some sort of nuclear capability would have to
approve it first. It's amazing to live in a world where that number doesn't
make the front page.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> "believed we were acting within the letter of the law" when raising funds
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '96</TIMEX> campaign. This is contrasted with the stronger position taken
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> main reason for the softening, says the paper, is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't want to appear to be pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>. Another is that if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>
finds an infraction did occur, the issue may well shift to the question of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s) intent when soliciting contributions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s response makes the same main points, and has the same
explanatory quote from him, but juxtaposes this with an interview with Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>, in which he says his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s investigation ultimately would
demonstrate the need for an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , in its front-page business and finance
news box, reports that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX> sharply criticized the proposed
national tobacco settlement, concluding that the cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> could reap
big profits that far exceed the penalties the pact imposes on them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX>
stand, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , strengthens the hand of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
others who want a tougher tobacco settlement.

            A hearty "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Duh</ENAMEX>!" goes out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> for its headline over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
installment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s series on political fund raising: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where Big Donors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tread</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Favors Seem to Follow</ENAMEX>."

            In an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erika Niedowski</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inside-the-Beltway</ENAMEX> newsletter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> , points out that several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> who sit on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> fund-raising investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> have
themselves paid stiff fines for violating state and federal election laws.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> covers the opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marv Albert</ENAMEX> trial on the front
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX> (it's taking place in nearby suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>). The headline reads "Marv
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trial Opens With Graphic Descriptions</ENAMEX>," and indeed, there is mention of
(allegations of) three-way sex, oral sex, bite marks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s back, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">semen</ENAMEX> in her underwear. One thing that is not mentioned, however, is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s name. She is cited in the article merely as a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> follows the same practice in its trial coverage, which
is inside the paper, differing only in saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
