
   
   
      
         
            InSecurities

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the collapse of a major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> brokerage. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s designation of
certain areas as off-limits to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s push for
insurance coverage for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 55-64</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a poll story: Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Californians</ENAMEX> have
tremendous confidence in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s economy.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> story says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamaichi Securities Co.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>-largest
brokerage, has closed down while in debt to the tune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24 billion</NUMEX>. The
collapse could have major negative impacts on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> markets, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is stepping in with financial backing to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamaichi</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>.

            Various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> took various angles on the story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's
above-the-fold article calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "upbeat" on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies, and
the paper front-pages the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamaichi</ENAMEX> failure only in a small "reefer" to a page
A11 story. The LAT splits the difference with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> side-by-side,
front-page stories: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> covers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamaichi</ENAMEX> gloom, the other centers on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "upbeat" assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> finance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's front-page
analysis departs from the upbeat line, emphasizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s wariness
despite its public show of confidence: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> fears economic weakness
could lead to political fragility in the region. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamaichi</ENAMEX> is the largest corporate failure in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> since
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamaichi</ENAMEX> on the front page in its
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business and Finance</ENAMEX>" news box.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead follows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s latest ploy in the continuing standoff:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> are being denied access to "presidential" sites. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> says an
inspection of them would be akin to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> searching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are potential hiding places for illicit weaponry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also front-pages the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX>, and says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> form the
bulk of the contested sites. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> article centers on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>'s "hard line" reaction--shunning leniency and demanding
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> be opened. While the story is prominent and above the fold at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LAT</ENAMEX> leave it
off their front pages altogether.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> editorial takes its cue from the standoff, using it to decry
the weakening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. Since crushing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, our armed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> have been cut by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and are less well trained. A new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> conflict
might prove far more costly, and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> would be too small to fight a
simultaneous battle elsewhere in the world.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will push for insurance coverage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three million</NUMEX> uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 55-64</TIMEX>. Too young for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, not poor enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, and largely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downsizing</ENAMEX>, these "near elderly" are old enough to contract expensive,
age-related illnesses. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will firmly resist any new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entitlements</ENAMEX>.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> (on its front page) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> (on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A2</NUMEX>) track a
new psychiatric disorder: Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodybuilders</ENAMEX> develop a kind of reverse anorexia,
thinking themselves puny no matter how much they bulk up, and obsessing over
gaining and maintaining weight. (Now if we could just get fashion models hooked
on weightlifting...)

         
      
   
