
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottoms Up</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s announcement that she's expanding her inquiry into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising phone calls. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the news that juvenile violent
Times with the word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is likely to OK nuclear power deals
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> to propose civilian review <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> to oversee the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that while deciding to go forward on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>
rejected the need for an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> coffees and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom-</ENAMEX>visit arrangements. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has till the
middle of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> before deciding whether or not to expand her inquiry into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising phone calls.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also reveals that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has hired to help
with his mounting problems is doing the work pro bono. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Neal</ENAMEX>,
says the practice is legal and ethical. The WP front-page piece about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision has virtually all the same information, except that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> missed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-pro bono tidbit.

            However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> does break ground in a long front-page piece about
the disarray surrounding what it calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s "crippled" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-month</TIMEX>
investigation into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> fund raising. The core problem apparently was
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> wanted to focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, and other senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> wanted a "bottom up"
investigation. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are defending their point of view in the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>," saying the
case against naming a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> is "pretty strong.") As a result, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> didn't even interview senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, and the information that may eventually result in the appointment of an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> came not from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> but from a "newspaper
account." (Apparently, modesty is still on the style-sheet at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's story about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s nuke trade opening says that the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stance comes "amid intensive lobbying by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear industry." A
company the paper names as a likely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westinghouse</ENAMEX>. Also, it is
revealed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s OK will probably be given at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cot</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28-29</TIMEX> meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says, criticizes the deal, saying it would stand as a "testament
to the role financial interests play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>." The
story's details suggest he has a point, inasmuch as it relates that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is
still providing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> and chemical/biological warfare technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>.

            Meanwhile the front pages of both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> national
edition state that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> has given the green light to
test-firing a powerful laser at a satellite orbiting <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 200-plus miles</NUMEX> up.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> had been against the idea, particularly because of concern
about what moving forward in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> area would do to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s attitude
toward the latest arms-reduction treaty, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">START II</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> hasn't ratified
yet. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> reveal that the laser is known by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strangelovian MIRACL</ENAMEX> for
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Wave Infrared Chemical Laser</ENAMEX>." (There's a sneaking suspicion here that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acronym</ENAMEX> came <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, followed by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> required to make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> that
fits it.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">global-warming</ENAMEX> talks will be singing the praises of pollution credit markets,
which, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> says, have contributed to a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30-percent</NUMEX> drop in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur-dioxide</ENAMEX>
emissions here just since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. Something this powerful is needed for all
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">greenhouse gases</ENAMEX>, since as a chart accompanying the piece points out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
is the world's biggest CO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emitter</ENAMEX>, producing almost twice as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
and at a per capita <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times greater.

            (A thought: Maybe there's a solution here to the cloud of graft and
corruption hanging over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>: scandal credits.)

         
      
   
