
   
   
      
         
            Stock Coverage

            Wall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>'s big comeback is everybody's lead. As if to illustrate the
transitoriness of the stock market and journalism about it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
headline--"Markets rebound"--is in the same bold type as its headline
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Massive Sell-off</ENAMEX>." At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> stroke, the Dow Jones industrial average
posted its biggest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> gain and its heaviest volume ever--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 75</NUMEX>
percent greater than the previous record, which was set <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. One investor
pointed out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.2 billion</NUMEX> share volume would
have been a whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s worth of trading in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">trading day</TIMEX> started off down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 200</NUMEX> points, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> agree on
the main reasons for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX>-session turnaround: the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman Sachs</ENAMEX> recommended that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> boost the stock portion of their
portfolios, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> and several other blue-chippers announced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> buy-backs
of their stock. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> adds some political reasons: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> briefly interrupted a speech he was giving on education to reaffirm his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX> in the strength and soundness of the economy, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>
issued a report about worker wages that indicates inflation remains under
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>.

            Ultimately, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, it had to do with the decision of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to
get back in the market (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duh</ENAMEX>. What else could it be?), which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>
calls "a sweeping reaffirmation of their love affair with stocks," and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
describes as "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street</ENAMEX> [riding] in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to rescue Wall Street."

            In general, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> handled the volume glitchlessly, although, notes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ</ENAMEX> ran into bottlenecks as the rally built. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> also confirms <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story that on-line trading
was hit-or-miss.

            Everybody's coverage continues to focus heavily on the DJIA, which is a
basket of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 30</NUMEX> stocks, some of them hardly key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the emerging world
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, instead of broader market measures like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> 500.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> front page brings the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Brown</ENAMEX> declared his
candidacy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> made the
announcement in the gourmet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> of his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> combination home and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workspace</ENAMEX>. No mention of whether the uniform of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1500</NUMEX> suit or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">flannel</ENAMEX> shirt and jeans.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> have front-page pieces reporting that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> has picked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referees</ENAMEX> to work the upcoming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">regular season</TIMEX>, a
decision believed to be a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s top-level professional sports. For
tips on what it will be like to work in a testosterone-addled workplace, the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> might want to check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page picture of
happy floor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> shows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 30</NUMEX> faces, just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            In her column today <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> charges that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, entertainment
pooh-bahs are "skittering away" from its recent spate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-bashing movie
releases out of fear of losing access to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> markets. Similarly, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section piece that quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM-United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> responsible for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Red Corner</ENAMEX>," which depicts an oppressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> court system, as saying, "the film is presented solely for its
entertainment value." The piece also has the marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seven Years in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>" saying "We never thought of this as an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">anti-China</ENAMEX> movie."

            Back to the stock market: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> tells the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, "I'm the lousiest market timer in the history of the world."
Hmmm...don't remember seeing that in the brochure. .

         
      
   
