
   
   
      
         
            Thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> storm. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with a questionable loan to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the vanishing budget deficit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>'s visit.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlins</ENAMEX> win in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> gets plenty of front-page play, even at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> would have missed the story, but
now doesn't because its new printing set-up allows for later deadlines.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's game wrap-up has good details on the presence at the game of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX> MVP <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livan Hernandez</ENAMEX>. It seems that her
visit, too late for seeing any of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s stellar pitching, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> of negotiations, including a written plea to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> signed
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> does some good deconstruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> visit, pointing out
that his laying of a wreath at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> memorial was designed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">remind Americans</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> was once a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, and noting that the full
military honors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> received upon his arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> were one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
requirements for agreeing to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> summit. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
observe that the summit won't produce as many substantive agreements as was
once hoped--the main result will be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s agreement to stop exporting nuclear
technology in return for access to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear power equipment, but probably
neither trade issues, nor human rights issues, nor the status of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> will
get resolved.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will announce <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that the federal
budget deficit has fallen to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22.6 billion</NUMEX>, the lowest since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>,
and far below any other major industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. So low, says the
Times , that "it almost does not matter whether it is eliminated." The
paper says most of the credit goes not to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> planning but to a healthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> and a surging stock market.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> says that a look at the current economy
also shows that the alleged bad consequence of raising the minimum
wage--increased unemployment in the low end of the service sector--just did not
happen, turning the minimum wage increase into "one of the nonevents of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>."

            A good test of the coherence of a news story is how much sense could you
make of it if you could only read the first few paragraphs or at most only to
the "jump" to the inside. (Indeed, the pyramid style of newswriting came about
because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> were often interrupted in their filings by down
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telegraph</ENAMEX> lines.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s LAT lead is a good example. The story is
supposed to be that the celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> how they really came to donate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>.
The headline says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Indonesians Contradict Democrats on Donations</ENAMEX>." But
unfortunately, neither the DNC explanation nor the nature of the contradiction
makes an appearance until after the "jump," a full <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> paragraphs in. Ditto for
any explanation of the law that would explain why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> would opt for its
story rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And "Today</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX>'s" can't answer those
questions because, as of filing time, this column doesn't have access to the
end of the story.)

            The LAT front page has news sure to add to the medical marijuana
controversy: the discovery by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> in marijuana that could
serve as an effective remedy for serious pain, without morphine-style side
effects. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also has a fresh new brain research result: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cal Tech</ENAMEX> have created silicon chips that interface directly with brain
cells. The advent of such neurochips is probably the biggest human science
story ever. And fraught with trouble: imagine what will happen when rich people
can pay to instantly smarten themselves but poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't.

         
      
   
