
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Us</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> giving a speech there
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> saying that if it doesn't reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s dues, there will be serious
damage done to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> relationship with the world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times each lead with the announcement by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> and her top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anti-trust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> filed a federal lawsuit against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> alleging that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s current marketing practices are in
violation of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> consent decree it signed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> flags the suit in its business and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> news box, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> dedicates its front page "cover story" to
it.

            When a story dominates a day like this one does, it's the differences that
stand out. Everybody makes it clear that the central bone of contention is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s practice of requiring PC <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to include its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Internet Explorer</ENAMEX>
browsing software on each computer sold with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>'s Windows operating system. But
some accounts of what could be legally suspect about that are more successful
than others. The most concise is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , which says that a section of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> consent decree "bans <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> from signing licensing agreements that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> PC <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to also license other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> products. In parentheses, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> adds: 'provided, however, that this provision in and of itself shall
not be construed to prohibit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> from developing integrated products.'"
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> argues that Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> constitutes a separate
product. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s position, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , is that the browser is simply
an "extension" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>.

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has the detail that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> unnamed
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> were turned down when they asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> for
permission either to remove the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> browser entirely or just the
desktop icon for it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> says, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> threatened to withhold Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX> from one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s largest
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> if it didn't include Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> is asking for the imposition of a daily <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> fine until
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> complies, and also asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to force the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to revise the
non-disclosure provisions of the contracts it has product licensees sign, on
the grounds that such provisions have a chilling effect on those wishing to
complain.

            Question: Is it sloppy writing or just <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> that leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> to
state that "for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has required personal computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">license Windows</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX> to also install Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>?

            A front-page LAT piece details a little noticed post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
military development: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine arms</ENAMEX> race among Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Some
of the least stable, most hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> on the planet--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>--are, reports the paper, "buying, building and arming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">submarines</ENAMEX> seemingly as fast as their treasuries will allow." Most of the subs
come from former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipyards</ENAMEX>.

            The headline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> at the WP distinguish themselves with their
effort over a story about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> suing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> she says promised marriage to her
only as a way to cultivate her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> as an organ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> for him: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Woman</ENAMEX>
Alleges <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fiance Stole Her Heart, Brother's Kidney</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
