
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ships Hit the Fan</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> dust-up
concerning shipping. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with yet another use by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of the line-item veto. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> goes with news that major car
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> plan to raise rates for sports utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> to bar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> cargo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> and to detain those already here. The action came, say
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> cargo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> companies
refused to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> in fines levied because of their costly and unfair
treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say the development
inspired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>-point drop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> calls it the
most tense situation between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>. The decision was
made by a federal maritime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> and could be overturned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tells USAT that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are in negotiations.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> used his newfound
line-item veto to kill a provision that would have allowed many federal workers
to switch to a different pension <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, boosting their annuities but costing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $854 million</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. In response, a major federal
of the line-item veto. In a separate action, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> also filed a similar
suit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> against a previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> line-item move. Hence, for the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, there are anti-line-item suits in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> alleging
actual harm.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About a month ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ran a front-page story revealing that
crash tests show sport utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup trucks</ENAMEX> are inflicting very
high levels of harm to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and their occupants in collisions, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the
Times brings word that in response, some big insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are
raising their liability rates on the oversize <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>. The move might be, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, the largest overhaul of liability insurance since the advent of
no-fault, meaning perhaps increases of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> for the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and cuts
of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> wonders whether the adjustments will hurt oversize vehicle
sales, but goes on to observe that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> are perhaps too prosperous to
be affected, reporting that the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Suburban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> is now more
affluent than the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>, and that the average household buying
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Range Rover</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LX450</ENAMEX> makes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$360,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> all run front-page stories about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fertility</ENAMEX> breakthrough: the first successful pregnancy in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> using a
frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> in this case came from another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, this
development sets up the possibility that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will be able to freeze
their own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> (which are less biologically problematic) and then much later,
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are ready to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, have them fertilized. The technique
would also allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> undergoing chemotherapy to save some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later</TIMEX> use.
According to details in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>" of the frozen egg
that produced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> was paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $46,000</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost five</NUMEX> times the going
rate for a full-term surrogate pregnancy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> are very unhappy that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> devoted much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> news
conference with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s campaign-finance woes.

            If you want proof that even at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the front page isn't always
so objective, check out the headline on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> front page: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>
Present Their <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> to an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Admiring Argentina</ENAMEX>." Who gets sober, respectful
headlines at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> if not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? Well on the same page, over
a story about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s speeches and ceremonies at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> marking
the retirement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Ochs Sulzberger</ENAMEX> and the succession to
that title of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sulzberger Passes Leadership</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Son</ENAMEX>." Not "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sulzbergers Present Their Act to Admiring Employees</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
