
   
   
      
         
            Dialing for Deals

            
all lead with the latest developments in the investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> can't even find room for that on
its front page and leads instead with the historic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish Republican</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> task force investigating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s phone calls is recommending that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> take no action in that
matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, says his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> hasn't made a
decision yet. (She could, besides ending the investigation, also continue
looking into it, or ask a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to name an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>.) USAT
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quotes Clinton</ENAMEX> as saying that "I have gone out of my way to have no
conversation with her about this or, frankly, anything else." In their lead
stories, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> adding, "...which I'm
not sure is so good." The additional observation seems right and newsworthy.
Wonder why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> left it out.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is willing to be interviewed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> for this investigation. And the paper quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in reaction to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s recent statement that she was 'mad' about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s lag on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coffee</ENAMEX> tapes: "You should have been there when I heard about it." (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has this too.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes further, saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> are in fact negotiating an agreement under which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
would answer questions about his knowledge of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> re-election
fund-raising efforts. The interviews would not, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , be
conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>, but by lower-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. This deal is being worked
out, because, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says, citing "law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>" and
disagreeing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the phone calls investigation will probably go
forward.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story includes this explanation for why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Agency</ENAMEX>, "a military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> that provides the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with secure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX>," originally didn't produce the coffee tapes: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WHCA</ENAMEX>'s chief
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> got the full memo requesting any such videos, but when he put it into
an e-mail format to send it to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, he accidentally
omitted the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pages. The paper quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> saying he doesn't blame
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WHCA</ENAMEX>. But why isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> at all concerned that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> responsible for providing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with "secure communications"
can't email a memo without losing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pages?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with a "gesture of peace so fraught with controversy
that it was made behind closed doors," namely, the handshake <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in
Belfast between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>. The meeting lasted but <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX>, and was,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports, immediately assailed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hard-liners</ENAMEX> as an
insult to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of IRA terrorism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> later
would not confirm that the handshake occurred, and that he had arranged that no
pictures were taken of it. The history of such handshakes suggests that such
caution is not crazy. Think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>. Think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sadat</ENAMEX>. Think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabin</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">powerfully</ENAMEX> describes a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> among people
with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>--that between those who can afford the powerful new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> like
protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> that promise to transform <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> from a fatal to a merely
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chronic disease</ENAMEX>, and those who cannot. The story reports that the federal-state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnership</ENAMEX> that pays for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for the indigent is broke in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. As
a result, poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> often simply go without.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column notes that for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who like to surf the Internet at work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripod Inc.</ENAMEX>'s Web site has a
"panic button" for use when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> shows up. Press it and the screen suddenly
switches to a nominating form for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX> of the Year." Through much arduous
research, this column has discovered a more subtle variant: A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Triple-X</ENAMEX> site
operating from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> has a panic button that instantly kicks over to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> Web site.

         
      
   
