
   
   
      
         
            Dow <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bites Man</ENAMEX>

            Everyone leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s action on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall St.</ENAMEX> Nobody calls it a
"crash." At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , it's a "global stock market blowout." At the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , it's a "sell-off." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> goes with "correction." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
favors "plunge," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , "waves of selling."

            Despite the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $700 billion</NUMEX> in stock value and the
halting of trading, not once but twice, by tripped "circuit-breakers," the
papers make the non-crash case in their primary reporting. They all point out
that the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.2 percent</NUMEX> drop in the Dow was far less than the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22.6 percent</NUMEX> drop in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, and not even among the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> biggest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> percentage losses. (It was
12th.) And that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> is still up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 11 percent</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. The WP
produces a particularly interesting pro-calm nugget: It has the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Mercantile Exchange</ENAMEX> saying that within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> after the Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> closed, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 80 percent</NUMEX> of his market's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> had paid off what they
owed from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s trades. This, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , is a sign that firms
are healthy enough to absorb their losses.

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> observes that thus far the stock market has not seen the
explosive growth in volume that characterized the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> crash. (But, notes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , there was one growth of volume compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>--that of on-line
trading, which as a result <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> provided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> to non-existent
execution.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> brokerage house stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> to the effect that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> isn't tightening, interest rates aren't rising and there isn't a
recession in sight. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also quotes a second <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall Streeter</ENAMEX> saying, "There
is no sense of urgency like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987..It</TIMEX> seemed far too quiet for a day with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 700 million</NUMEX> shares traded and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX> points." Then the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> tries to take the temperature of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off the Street, but in
doing so, demonstrates a bit of a tin ear about the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX>, since the
paper immediately comes up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Hollywood</ENAMEX> hair <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylist</ENAMEX> getting his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes Benz</ENAMEX> washed, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychotherapist</ENAMEX> who spent a session
calming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> thinking about selling.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s events show one thing above all else: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To</ENAMEX>
an extent never seen before, the world's stock markets are interconnected and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co-dependent.</ENAMEX> When <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> market quakes, others can tremble." Indeed, the papers
say another down Dow day is likely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> based on poor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> openings in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> markets.

            Despite the generally evenhanded reporting, there are still some hyper
graphic elements. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> run their headlines in
extremely bold type. And to boot, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT 's</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-column banner. And
(as was pointed out to this column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Ferguson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> ) somebody
should tell the photo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> that those pictures of anguished-looking floor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> that so often run with "sell-off" stories are a bit misleading. Those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> aren't necessarily bummed out when markets go down big-time. They're
just tired. Unless they're carrying their own long positions, they make money
on their transactions either way.

         
      
   
