
   
   
      
         
            Verdicting It Up

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX> verdict leads all around. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
calls the conviction on conspiracy and manslaughter counts but acquittal on
1st-degree murder charges "a surprising compromise." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
calls the result "a nuanced verdict." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> emphasize that the decision
considerably lessens the likelihood that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> will be condemned to
death.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> "appeared
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crestfallen</ENAMEX>" at the news. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> finds them "stunned." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> are
relentless in their programmatic use of "balancing" language to describe family
reactions--"many" are angry, "some" are shocked, etc.--despite producing no
family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> saying the verdicts are just. Instead, when it comes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">particulars</ENAMEX>, we have everybody quoting the comment of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent husband</ENAMEX> was killed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> blast: "It was a slap in the
face."

            The reactions noted are often incisive as well as anguished. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandsons</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McVeigh</ENAMEX> conspired for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> to blow up that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. That's not
involuntary manslaughter. That's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree murder." Similarly, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
lost a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> saying, "He conspired to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>;
what the hell did they think he was going to do with it!" In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> stories, the juxtaposition of these expressions of
dissatisfaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remark that the verdicts "should offer
a measure of comfort" makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> look particularly tin-eared.

            When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> strive to make sense of the verdict, they tend to look that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says that the manslaughter verdicts mean that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> held that the deaths were foreseeable results of a lawful act. But what
was that lawful act? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> doesn't say. (Surely not helping to build a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX>.) Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorial on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> decision ably frames the
puzzle: "At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> blush it seems contradictory to find that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> was
guilty of conspiring in the bombing, a crime that seems to have required
premeditation, but then not to find him guilty of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree, or
premeditated, murder. Involuntary manslaughter usually involves recklessness
but not premeditation." But then the paper trots out a dubious answer: "Still,
that may be a reasonable decision in that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> may not have planned that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> be set off with the purpose of killing these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>." But what
alternative purpose did he have? Not one word in all the coverage about
that.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> comes closest here, venturing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> must have
accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>'s defense that he had abandoned the plot before the explosion.
But neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> nor the other papers pass along any information
that makes such a possibility plausible.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> makes a rookie mistake in referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s "innocent"
verdicts. It's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Not Guilty</ENAMEX>," not "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Innocent</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front carries word of a clearer resolution to another
terrorism case: the conviction in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jackal</ENAMEX>"--once the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s most feared terrorist--of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> murders. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs this on
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.8</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, in an obvious bid to plug holes
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> schedule (that damned yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> has to go in the shop for
a tune-up sometime), is poised to launch investigations into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and
DNC activities that could involve fully half of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>.

that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are blind, deaf or have other disabilities are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36 percent</NUMEX> more
likely to be injured on the job. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s issue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">JAMA</ENAMEX> contains the news that although <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 90 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> don't get
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anesthesia</ENAMEX> when they are circumcised, they should get it because "study of
infant heart rates and crying patterns during circumcision clearly showed there
was pain." So, to sum up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s scientific breakthroughs: a) If you're blind
avoid working in sawmills and b) Getting your brand-new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">knicky-knacks</ENAMEX> carved on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">HURTS LIKE HELL</ENAMEX>!

         
      
   
