
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenback Green Cards</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the scores of injuries and one death on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX> jumbo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> enroute to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with exposure of a little-known
program giving visas to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant investors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the revelation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">major</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> domestic goal for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>: sign up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> health insurance
but not currently enrolled. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a striking drop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> murder rate.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead details how a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> immigration program enacted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> reserves up to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> green cards a year for rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and their immediate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The
program has led to the growth of consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> handling the details--the
leading <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> boasts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> on its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 80 percent</NUMEX> of
these visas are going to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> push on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> coverage for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, which will be featured in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upcoming State of the Union</ENAMEX> message, apparently came, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was dismayed to discover that most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> had made little
progress on this since he first started talking about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early last year</TIMEX>. The
piece is by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's long-time social policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pear</ENAMEX>, but
it will be interesting to see how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> handles any subsequent
coverage of this by its other main poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason DeParle</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> expansion point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that fewer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been killed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Angels</ENAMEX> than in any single
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, which, the paper reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with head injuries, was when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> cites a number of factors that might
explain the drop: a stronger economy, stabilization of the drug-trade, stricter
sentencing laws, improved police tactics, periodic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> truces, and a decrease
in the young-adult demographic. But shouldn't the Brady Bill, with its waiting
period and background check for any handgun purchase, also get a mention?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> all run front-page
items about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s decision to combat that new strain of chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> by
killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all 1 million</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs it on p. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>. (What
kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> there drink when they get the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX>?)

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> run columns wondering if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
economic downturn is good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy or the beginning of a recession
here. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> run through the arguments, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> coming
down on the side of optimism and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> piece, while avoiding a flat
prediction of impending doom, says that with the "myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> invincibility"
gone, "we have lost a foundation stone." (Did you ever believe that myth?)
Taken together, the two columns prove nothing so much as that the world economy
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>-rabbit.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s installment in the series about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> focuses on a little-noticed obstacle confronting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women officers</ENAMEX> trying to rise to top command jobs: a key route for getting them
is serving as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-camp to those in them now, and the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> hardly
ever pick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" contains selections from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearings on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> disaster, which convened
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> after the sinkings and hence are shot through with searing details.
The lowlights include testimony that there were no binoculars on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Bruce Ismay</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> 's parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, was
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and, despite the inadequate number of lifeboats and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>-first policy, managed to get himself into one of them.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" heard from many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> countering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
animadversion about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's use of the phrase "innocent verdict." The
main point they expressed was that, while not legally precise, "innocent" was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preferable</ENAMEX> because it doesn't run the risk of libel that "not guilty" does if
the "not" is inadvertently dropped. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> style book takes this point
of view. So perhaps this column erred in calling this a "rookie mistake." It is
apparently a very experienced mistake. But it should be noted that, especially
in the case of public figures like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX>, it takes far more than a
dropped bit of type to constitute even a prima facie case of libel. Moreover,
if this were a coherent policy, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> should ban the use of "not"
altogether, since dropping it always carries this same risk.

         
      
   
