
   
   
      
         
            Hear Them Roar

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s march in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s condemnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s handling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
War veterans' medical problems. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times 's lead is a report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> strategy of isolating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> from the world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is failing as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>' desire to make business
deals weakens their support.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> summarizes the rally's agenda: investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s role
in "allowing black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> to be flooded with crack <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>," programs to
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women prisoners</ENAMEX> make the transition back to society, the establishment of
black independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and the release of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>. In
discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> size, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> uses as a reference the size of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Million Man</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, but, curiously, doesn't refer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> rally
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> back--even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> massive front-page
coverage.

            The rally coverage signifies an odd new journalism trend. In their extensive
front-page coverage, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and the LAT
dutifully report the size of the rally as "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX>," yet they
each persist in referring to the event as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Million Woman March</ENAMEX>," apparently
because that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> called it. So look for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> to call
its next use of force "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Operation Only Objected to by Draft-Dodging Reporters</ENAMEX>,"
and don't be surprised when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX>'s would-be blockbuster is called "The
Best Movie You'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ever See</ENAMEX>." (Question for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>: Why isn't it
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Million Wom e n March</ENAMEX>" anyway?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead is written off a copy it has obtained of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>'s report to be released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this coming week</TIMEX> that says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX> should be stripped of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>' sickness because of their mishandling of the
issue. The report states that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should either create or designate an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> to take over. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reveals that a separate forthcoming study
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> will be nearly as critical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ran a front-page story about the problems under
welfare reform faced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> fresh off the rolls whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
has had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> in rapid succession. The story was accompanied by a
front-page picture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> sucking her thumb and staring blankly at
television while holding one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. That picture has drawn a firestorm of
protest from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, many of them black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
distinguishes itself by being the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> covered here that has an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ombudsman</ENAMEX>
who writes a regular column, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> she takes up the issue and concludes
that "deciding not to put that picture where we did would have better served
the truth." Avoiding the truth is more like it--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> didn't turn on
the TV or tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to suck her thumb.

            In the run-up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>'s visit, there is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> action <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , in a story about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> political exiles, runs
the following precis of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s recent human rights record: "After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> crackdown, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> of public political debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> came
to an end. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> if not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> died. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> were
jailed, and scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> fled abroad....Most [had been] beaten or
tortured. All have seen family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> harassed, even persecuted to death."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> at least, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> seems fixed on looking the other way. It runs an
op-ed piece about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> that asserts "while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and special-interest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are free to give human rights absolute and unqualified priority,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are not," and which reports that "the number of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> currently is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX>--which is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.00023 percent</NUMEX> of the total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>."
Meanwhile, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> front-page piece details how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> loves to break
into song and play the piano and recite poetry, all of which, says the paper,
"points to an unpredictable, wacky side." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homework</ENAMEX> assignment: find a single
front-page piece in the entire history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> emphasizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s
fondness for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.) "Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student protester</ENAMEX> to
another, "stop with the wacky stunts, with the piano, with the poetry. You're
killing us here."

         
      
   
