
   
   
      
         
            Mining: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Own Business</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> lead is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> demanding changes
in the national tobacco deal, a story that the other papers handled yesterday
on the basis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> background leaks about what he would say. At the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , the lead is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> decision to not join a proposed
international land-mine ban. (And this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lead at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> decision to withdraw from negotiations being conducted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>, was defended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on the grounds that the ban
could put <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> at risk in time of war. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the decision
was "greeted with jubilation and relief by humanitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and countries
that support the ban" because they feared the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would dilute the
treaty at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>. The treaty arrived at without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> participation
prohibits all anti-personnel land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Signatories</ENAMEX> will have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> to
destroy their inventories and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> to clear areas that have been mined. It
will probably become international law within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the ban will be "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> arms control treaty to limit a
conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> is mistaken, and give credit to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> for providing the correct historical background: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX>, exploding
bullets were banned, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899</TIMEX>, so were dum-dum bullets. Poison <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> was outlawed
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> it was ixnay on blinding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lasers</ENAMEX>.

            Of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> covering the ban <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> mentions the
momentum derived from the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, who embraced the cause
shortly before her death.

            The overall mining coverage is fairly steeped in the arcana of international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treaties</ENAMEX> and weapons systems, giving it a rather remote flavor. One wonders if
the papers would have been this low-key if it were--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qaddafi</ENAMEX>, say--standing
almost alone against the world in clinging to a maiming technology.

            The other story that gets most everybody's attention is the testimony
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Heslin</ENAMEX>. Heslin
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> of pressure applied to her by the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thomas "Mack</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLarty</ENAMEX> and other senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to make her help a once and future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
presidential campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Tamraz</ENAMEX>, in connection with his pet oil
project. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heslin</ENAMEX>'s voice was "full of anger" as she
described being called a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Girl Scout</ENAMEX>" when she resisted what she saw as
inappropriate attempts to help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tamraz</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that, during the
testimony, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLarty</ENAMEX> issued a statement declaring that he did nothing improper in
the matter, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heslin</ENAMEX> was "received as one of the
most compelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> yet."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> brings word <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of an Internet
defamation lawsuit. The printing technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presstek Inc.</ENAMEX> is suing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> people it identified as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">short-sellers</ENAMEX> of its stock, who, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presstek</ENAMEX> says,
posted defamatory and inaccurate statements about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in various online
chat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in an attempt to drive down the stock price.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> column is an entertaining speed tour of how the
Internet has come to the various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
stories he includes is how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> recently went to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and bought <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> satellite photographs of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scud</ENAMEX> missile bases
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, and then hired a private <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on satellite photos to analyze
the pictures. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot</ENAMEX> published the package as a scoop,
without ever quoting a government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s gloss on the episode:
"Good news: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s global market you can buy anything. Bad news: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> is
still preparing for another war."

         
      
   
