
   
   
      
         
            Currency Events

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> sell-off leads all around. Where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> vary is in their
ability to say what happened. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> says the event was "the most widespread
reaction to the spreading <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> currency crisis," but doesn't say a
further word explaining that crisis or how it caused the sell-off. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> quotes this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> "explanation": "The
government is willing to sacrifice its equity market to the currency peg." And
offers this "clarification": "But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> say the peg won't be easy to defend,
however. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> would have to draw heavily on its own reserves and on those
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to support the market in the face of selling by currency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
does better, explaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> sought to support its faltering currency
by sharply raising overnight interest rates, to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">300 percent</NUMEX>. Then, explains the
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> responded by driving down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> stock prices on
fears that higher rates would mean shriveling profits for the financial and
property <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that are the market's backbone. But still, nobody explains
why it wasn't obvious ahead of time that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">300%</NUMEX> interest was a tad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incendiary</ENAMEX>.

            And there's the usual quote<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-a-bull</ENAMEX>, quote-a-bear approach to what it all
means. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall Streeter</ENAMEX> saying, "This is
the end of equity mania." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> finds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> who says the problems with
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s currencies could shave <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two-tenths of</NUMEX> a percentage point off the growth
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> GDP, (Over what period of time? Is that a lot? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
never says.), and that this might please the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>, which of course, would please
the stock market. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> developments
"could lead to a broad regional economic slowdown that would dampen the sales
and earnings not just of local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, but of major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> that operate there." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also says
many market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> believe that lower stock prices are a good buying
opportunity, and would bring stability to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stock market. To review:
Stock prices could go up, or they could go down. Either could be good. So, the
question about such "day after" stock market stories remains: "Why give them so
much space?"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, responding to recent disclosures about
his use of soft money-fueled presidential campaign ads, has offered to testify
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> fund-raising hearings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>, says the paper, will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invite both Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> to testify.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a piece inside reporting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> has determined that a set of chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> logs, that veterans'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> say could provide valuable information about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> exposure, was
mistakenly destroyed after the war. And a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> set is still missing. It's
good to see that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> tradition continues: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> indicating what happened to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of nuclear
warheads no longer counted as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX> are missing too.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> own
homes than ever before--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66 percent</NUMEX> of them--which breaks the previous record
set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
set the goal of breaking this record by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Snapshot</ENAMEX>" provides an interesting window into the minds
of the rich, revealing that in a survey, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s wealthiest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> said they'd pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$640,000</NUMEX> to get into heaven, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$487,000</NUMEX> for true
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX>, but only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55,000</NUMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. But more, apparently, to have a cup of
coffee with him.

         
      
   
