
   
   
      
         
            Really <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juvenile Reynolds</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with revelations from newly disclosed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.J. Reynolds</ENAMEX> internal documents that seem to show that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persistently</ENAMEX> attempted to market cigarettes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>. This is also the top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX>'s vote telling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to honor previous
promises to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> complete access to suspected weapons
sites.

            The new tobacco documents (many of them marked "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Secret"</ENAMEX>), released as part
of a lawsuit settlement, show a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> strategy of attracting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>
through advertising and various youth-oriented promotions such as, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASCAR</ENAMEX> sponsorship," "inner city activities," and "T-shirts and
other paraphernalia." And says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the documents show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX>'s
introduction of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX>" fits in to this strategy.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> point out that since, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, the then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> testified
before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> does not market to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, these new
documents have prompted congressional interest in perjury charges. They also
report that former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kessler</ENAMEX> says the new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> is "a smoking
gun" that shows why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> shouldn't approve the proposed national tobacco
settlement.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> responded by repeating its denial of youth targeting and stating
that the documents are being taken out of context, telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , "Our
documents reflect the social attitudes of the times in which they were
created."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , which flags the story in its
front-page news box, passes along another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> defense: that one document that
seemed to be suggesting pitching product to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-olds</TIMEX> contained a
typographical error and was really about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-olds</TIMEX>. However, according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , some documents refer to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-olds</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> really goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> story, backing up its lead with
two more stories inside--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on how the revelations will play politically and
the other a collection of extensive selections from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> documents. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> plays the story inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead passes along a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX> report that arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> have
photographic evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> biological weapon experiments on human beings.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also states that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> was wavering on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> action,
but was finally brought along by the decision to "deplore" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s behavior
rather than "condemn" it. (No telling how many votes could have been garnered
if they'd gone with "not really thrilled.")

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hallmark Cards</ENAMEX> is coming out with a sympathy card
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of those who've committed suicide.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that on educational grounds <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zell Miller</ENAMEX>
proposed as part of his state budget spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$105,000</NUMEX> to make classical music
available to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> born in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. During his budget address <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>,
he played a bit of "Ode to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX>," and then asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX>, don't you feel
smarter already?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Q. Wilson</ENAMEX>, in a
Times op-ed piece, makes the following argument for the sanity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kacszynski</ENAMEX>: "There is nothing in the [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Unabomber</ENAMEX>] manifesto that looks at
all like the work of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">madman</ENAMEX>. The language is clear, precise and calm. The
argument is subtle and carefully developed, lacking anything even faintly
resembling the wild claims or irrational speculation that a lunatic might
produce." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> also observes that besides the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX>'s manifesto, his
"skill in manufacturing bombs and the clever ways in which he concealed his
identity suggest to me that he was clearly sane." Of course, the legal
usefulness of these observations is somewhat dubious, because this attempt to
show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Kacszynski</ENAMEX> is fit to stand trial depends on the assumption
that he is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX>, which in turn requires a trial <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, which first
requires showing that he is fit to stand trial, and so on.

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s deal to retain "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>" at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX> an episode getting
front-page coverage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , maybe
the next big domestic policy issue will be controlling television health
care costs.

         
      
   
