
   
   
      
         
            Call Guys

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> agree on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s lead: the decision by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> to begin the investigative process that could result in appointing
an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election
fund-raising activities. This news comes on the heels of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX> to take the same look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says the decision is based on new
information developed by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may have made
campaign fund solicitation calls from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and reports that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> response is two-pronged: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says he doesn't remember making
such calls, and there is no clear legal precedent to show that they would be
illegal anyway.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> decision a "potential turning point" in that "until now, the
investigation buffeting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had swirled around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>
but had not touched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> personally...."

            The new evidence apparently includes solicitation call sheets that were
prepared for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, for calls to fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> who indisputably gave money to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>. What's in dispute is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> actually made the calls. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
refers to a call sheet for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Busch IV</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> opts
instead for ones for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Zappa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail</ENAMEX>.
The natural assumption that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> had access to the same call sheets
leads to a homework assignment: Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> or any
Post <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> television station carry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch product</ENAMEX> ads?

            Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> makes the observation that puts this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> in the proper context: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has already been under the scrutiny
of a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>. (Remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitewater</ENAMEX>?)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wasn't informed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>--he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> on his way to a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> fund-raiser (!)--which meant that the story was kept out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
headlines and newscasts. But what's the gain? It's dominating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
papers, which in turn set the agenda for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> political talk shows.
There's just no escaping the news cycle anymore.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a front-page explanatory piece on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s Teamster
guilty pleas. Worth doing, because the case could well lead to deeper trouble
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, the piece doesn't excel at explanation. True, it
has the understandable problem of trying to be clear about describing schemes
that were designed to be murky, but it doesn't help that the story doesn't even
begin to explain until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">26th</NUMEX> paragraph why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamster</ENAMEX> fund-raising deals
in question were illegal, and even then none too clearly. Isn't the relevant
law that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> can't donate money to either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, and hence can't
create schemes that do that while appearing to be donations from somebody else?
And shouldn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> just say so?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a piece about the decline in the accuracy of directory
assistance information, saying that the trend arises from increased competition
and hence decreased cooperation between local phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>.
They used to freely share numbers, but now they charge each other through the
nose. The result is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and many regional phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are now
attempting to compile their own data bases from other sources, like credit card
files, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMV</ENAMEX> records, etc.--with decidedly mixed results.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Editorial Notebook</ENAMEX>" item about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX>'s arrival
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> makes a good point. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> are so concerned that the media
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">respect Chelsea</ENAMEX>'s privacy at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, then perhaps they should have let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX>
arrive on her own "attended perhaps by a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> agents
rather than arriving in a Presidential motorcade and trailed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and cameramen...."

         
      
   
