
   
   
      
         
            Sein-Off

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with a surge in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>'s financial markets. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with a story on sluggish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> retail sales. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is under pressure to
offer a tax cut before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> midterm elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the malfunction of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-launched satellite. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX> fell out of orbit, and there is some chance that parts could impact
on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead says foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, seeking bargains, have suddenly
flooded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>'s markets, buying blue-chips like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samsung</ENAMEX> at basement
prices. The won gained <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> against the dollar in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a single day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts the story in its World-Wide
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newsbox</ENAMEX>. A front-page piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes in a different direction,
explaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korean-Americans</ENAMEX>' mixed feelings over their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX>'s financial
difficulties. While they are concerned for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, and send money back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> there, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korean-Americans</ENAMEX> also feel some relief: "A poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>
makes the sacrifices of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> easier to justify."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> sales were slow for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third year</TIMEX> in a
row. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX> thought the strong economy would mean a big <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">buying season</TIMEX>, but
estimates see just a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">three percent</NUMEX> increase over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX>'s sales
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> of the expected gain). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> see a paradigm shift: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> no
longer concentrate their gift-giving around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reefers the story on its front page.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead predicts tax-cut proposals from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Streeters</ENAMEX> forecast a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 billion</NUMEX> surplus for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the current fiscal year</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> want
to use the money to cut taxes, looking for points with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next fall</TIMEX>'s
elections. The surplus could also lead to a renegotiation of the budget deal,
with an eye towards ending the deficit by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> story tracks <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s economic comeback. Their 1990s recession
was twice as bad as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, but their recovery may be even more
impressive. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s secret? Severe austerity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> cut back on its
famed social programs and laid off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX>) of its federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. After
peaking at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.5%</NUMEX> unemployment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> now has the fastest growing
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy in the G7</ENAMEX>.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>'s list of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s best films puts
Titanic , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Confidential , and The Apostle</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>,
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, respectively.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX> has opted to end his TV show after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>, prompting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> to devote a big block of above-the-fold space, plus a photo, to the
news that a television sitcom will go off the air...<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months from now</TIMEX>.
Yadda yadda yadda.

         
      
   
