
   
   
      
         
            Pulp Fictions

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> challenge to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economic sanctions--negotiations on a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 billion</NUMEX> deal with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British-Dutch</ENAMEX> conglomerate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shell</ENAMEX> hard on the heels of its recently consummated
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> offshore <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> deal with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with an apparently surprising crime statistic. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s call for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> to avoid making
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> look cool.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> data, property crime has
fallen sharply in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">since 1980</TIMEX>. Indeed, burglary rates are down by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, now has a lower burglary rate than
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> is, fortunately for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> roving crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fox</ENAMEX>
Butterfield, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with one of the most precipitous drops in burglary,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">larceny</ENAMEX>, and auto theft, so he could rove there instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Duluth</ENAMEX> to find out
what's going on. Theories bandied about by the various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> he quotes
include: improved police tactics, a decline in the teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, longer
prison sentences and greater community involvement with law enforcement.
Perhaps the most plausible explanation offered is this: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>
increasingly tend to commit violent crimes rather than non-violent ones. For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> have nearly the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
having <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66 percent</NUMEX> more thefts and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX> more burglaries but only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fifth</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> robberies and only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-tenth as many</NUMEX> murders. In other words, maybe the
headline to this article shouldn't have been "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Property Crimes Steadily Decline</ENAMEX>,
Led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burglary</ENAMEX>," but rather, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Criminals Becoming More Violent</ENAMEX>." And
then the question is, "Why does a newspaper pick the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over the other?"

            In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> radio address, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> in its lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> urged the entertainment industry to "do its part" by avoiding the
depiction of "warped images" that promote <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. Addressing the movie and
music video industry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying, "Never glorify <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, but
more importantly, tell our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> the truth. Show them that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use is
really a death sentence." The "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry</ENAMEX>" will no doubt raise all the usual
First <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> points in response, but more to the point, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
challenge really relevant to current movies, as opposed to those made 25 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>? In most films nowadays, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use is practically a convention for showing
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is seedy or at least going to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX>. Things aren't looking up
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Hill</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goodfellas</ENAMEX>" when he starts using <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke</ENAMEX> and we know it. And
what was attractive about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uma Thurman</ENAMEX>'s habit in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulp Fiction"</ENAMEX>? It's
interesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, who knows movies quite well, doesn't give any
actual examples of what he's decrying.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> have run stories recently about the
impugning of a collection of alleged JFK private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that were being used
for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> documentary and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX> book. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> develops
the story further, breaking the news that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 140</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, had, before the
controversy arose, bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of these documents, forking over a total of
perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $5 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> include
sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> and a network news anchor (could that be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>,
would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> of the now-in-doubt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> documentary?), and says that although
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have discredited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, others continue to insist on their
authenticity--despite the discovery of such anachronisms as mention of a ZIP
code and evidence of lift-off correcting tape.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> starts an occasional series about genetics with a fine
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> installment on the controversies surrounding cosmetic gene therapy.
According to the piece, many sorts of this type of therapy--for say, getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">taller</ENAMEX>, thinner, stronger, tanner or unbald--could be practicable within just a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, yet no regulations govern them, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> only recently
discussed them for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. The piece raises doubts about the basic
distinction of "cosmetic" vs. "medical" here: Why isn't a genetically-induced
permanent tan just a form of melanoma protection?

         
      
   
