
   
   
      
         
            Koppeling a Plea

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s announcement of a plan to combat
global warming. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead is a presidential advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s recommendation of numerous new
rights for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the news that during the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX>
campaign, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> steered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>' funds
to sympathetic outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Right to Life Committee</ENAMEX>. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>'s announcement of the largest loss in
company history.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> greenhouse plan, to be submitted to an upcoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">international</ENAMEX> conference on the problem, sets up a pollution credits market
under which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> profit from getting below emissions standards, promises
further incentives for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> cutting emissions before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX>, and also
invests <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> on energy-efficient technology. But, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, the proposal is considered not stringent enough by many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalist groups</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, and developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, yet too
stringent by many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , in its front-page piece,
points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposal falls short of the goals he outlined in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, when he called for voluntary cuts in greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> emissions back to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> levels by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>. It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in its front-page story,
that most clearly explains the relative smallness of the plan's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 billion</NUMEX>
investment in global warming control: "enough to give every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> an annual
rebate covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fourth</NUMEX> of the cost of a high-efficiency light bulb."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> howled upon learning that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
helped steer givers to congenial outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s WP lead shows
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC</ENAMEX> did it too. The stratagem allows both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and political parties
to spend on their pet causes without being identified (unlike political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> don't have to disclose their money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>).

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' rights should include the right to an external review of denials of
care or coverage by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>, and the right to such information as how
often and how successfully a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> has performed a procedure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is expected to endorse all this, although, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> points out,
nobody has explained how these new rights would be enforced.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's report on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> (which the paper describes as "the world's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>." Isn't that just a little boosterish for a front-page
story?) says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> shocked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall St.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> with its surprise
disclosure of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6 billion</NUMEX> loss. It seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> orders are rolling
in, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can't keep up because of part shortages and the hiring of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            More detail comes to light <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s case against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reveal that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> says
it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> that was prevented by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> from offering its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> easy keyboard
access to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netscape</ENAMEX> software. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
petition also claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gateway 2000</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micron Electronics</ENAMEX> were told by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> that they could not remove Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> or its desktop icon from
their machines. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s evidence includes
some email from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s executive committee.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is trying to neutralize the coffee
videos by getting the release of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> tape in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> admits that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC</ENAMEX> was financing ads that were helping his campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
has refused the request. On the tape, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> explains to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Koppel</ENAMEX> that the ad
is okay because "it never says, 'I'm running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.'"

         
      
   
