
   
   
      
         
            Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the news that a special civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> appointed
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> will release a report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> reversing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
gender-integration policies by concluding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should go through
basic training separately. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s announcement that all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX> (active and reserve) will be inoculated against the deadly biological
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">warfare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> anthrax. The lead national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lann Lee</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s top civil rights job.

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s present co-ed
training approach "is resulting in less discipline, less unit cohesion and more
distraction." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>, can, says the paper,
implement the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s recommendations without congressional approval. (The
story is also on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> anthrax inoculation
program will consist of a series of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> shots to start with and then annual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX>. It will, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX>
received the initial dosage only.) Completion of the program will take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also leads with this
story, and it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the second</TIMEX> lead at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has the story
too--on p. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>.

            The anthrax stories all mention the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> explanation that such
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> have stockpiled anthrax <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX> is considered a rising terrorist threat. Yet none of them breathe a word
about the idea of inoculating the civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> as well.

            Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s interim (that is, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> adjourned) appointment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> as acting DOJ civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> a snub of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, (which turned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>
down)? That's a little hard to tell from the headlines. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bypasses Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appoints Lee On Acting Basis</ENAMEX>," while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Softening Slap At Senate</ENAMEX>, Names 'Acting' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
Rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Defies GOP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Names Lee Rights</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>."

            In reporting on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> sting that collared <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> trafficking in
stolen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parts</ENAMEX> across <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the theft of computer
hardware and software is hitting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> issue of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suicide</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Life-Threatening Behavior"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bitchin</ENAMEX>' swimsuit issue!) includes a study
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purporting</ENAMEX> to show that in the major gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>--the suicide rates are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to four</NUMEX> times higher than
in comparably sized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> where gambling is not legal.

            In case you're distracted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> by deep worries about who the lead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Story</ENAMEX>" were based on, relax, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is on the case.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reported that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long day</TIMEX> on the road, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
sidled up to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> traveling with him on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> and in the course
of the conversation allowed as to how in college, he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Segal</ENAMEX>, and in fact he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tipper</ENAMEX> were the models for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed lovers</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segal</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Story</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Segal</ENAMEX> denies this
(and denied it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in a phone call). The author claims that he got some
character traits for the male lead from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, but others from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>
(and eventual movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Lee Jones</ENAMEX>, and nothing at all for the female
lead from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tipper</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> responded by saying he was misquoted, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spokesperson</ENAMEX> said the conversation was off the record anyway (which reporters
who were there deny). Today, Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX>'s op-ed column tells us what this all means: that "disingenuousness,
not stiffness, is [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s] real character problem." Stay tuned for more
Times coverage--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> has reportedly also been investigating. Or
maybe she's pursuing something else, like the rumor that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur C. Clarke</ENAMEX>
was writing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> he used <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> as the model for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAL</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
