
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solitary Men</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Kaczynski</ENAMEX>'s apparent suicide attempt and his renewed attempt to be
his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> lead at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The worsening <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> economic crisis leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . The sentencing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mastermind</ENAMEX> leads at the New York
Times .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> jail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> deduced from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kacszynski</ENAMEX>'s missing underpants and a red mark on his neck that he had tried to
commit suicide in his cell <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before. (Presumably they could rule out a
really hot date.) As a result, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , he's been placed in a
psychiatric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> where his movements will be monitored <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours a day</TIMEX> while the
court continues to ponder the issue of his legal representation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead says these latest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Unabomber</ENAMEX> trial developments
have left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kacszynski</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> "reeling." The story also gets
front-page coverage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> mentions
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> was about to be sworn in but was instead "sent home" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.
But none of the accounts mention whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is sequestered yet. If not,
then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s been exposed to the suicide attempt, the controversy about his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competency</ENAMEX>, as well as to the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> turned down his offer to
plead guilty in return for having his life spared. Won't all this tend to
promote jury sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kacszynski</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that concerns about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s ability to turn things around--because he's infirm and
because he has too many family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> with fortunes to protect--have gotten so
bad that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarkets</ENAMEX> were jammed by those trying to stock up on
essential goods.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> focuses more on the crisis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
focus more on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> are doing about it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
has the most detail about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> role, reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
insisted in a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-minute</TIMEX> phone call with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> must put in place strong economic reforms. The crisis is also on the
front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> sentencing reports that
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Duffy</ENAMEX> sentenced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">240 years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and
urged that he spend it all in solitary confinement, without phone privileges.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> mentions that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> have been
so confined, but leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> wondering who they are and what they did.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> gives the example of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang leader</ENAMEX> who directed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> murders from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> makes it clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> can
only recommend sentence conditions, which ultimately are determined by prison
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. (Although a word or two about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duffy</ENAMEX> arrived at the 240 years
would have been instructive.) And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has the detail that Yousef
was also ordered to pay a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 million</NUMEX> fine and restitution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million</NUMEX>,
because, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duffy</ENAMEX>, leaving no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX> unturned, "someday I can see
someone being perverse enough to buy your story."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a
front-page story based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> interviews reporting that, contrary to
opinions expressed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> jury forewoman, there was "a strong
faction" on the jury leaning towards the death penalty.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> run stories inside reporting a new
study concluding that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> are locked up because
of criminal activity linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and alcohol abuse. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
doesn't address a crucial distinction: how much of the criminal activity is
violation of the drug laws and how much is something else. (A lot of the former
might be grist for legalization. A lot of the latter might be grist for the
status quo.) But the study does apparently get into this, because the
Times reports that "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, more than any illegal drug, was found to be
closely associated with violent crimes..."

            It's no big deal, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to
a fund-raiser at the toney "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dakota</ENAMEX>" apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> lived there and "it was outside this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> where
he was murdered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>." Actually, it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
