
   
   
      
         
            Phone Bill

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with news the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> is going
international in a big way. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with the formation of a new coalition
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> dedicated to saving the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead is: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mideast Leaders Taking First Step to Reviving Talks"</ENAMEX> (that's key F4
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> keyboards, right next to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">F5</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teamster Officials</ENAMEX>
Indicted").

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> law
enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> organized crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, operating out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> and flush with cash, are forming alliances with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. These alliances, say some experts
quoted in the piece, are the most dangerous trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> smuggling in the
hemisphere. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> mobs offer the drug cartels access to sophisticated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weapons</ENAMEX> siphoned from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> inventory. Recent undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> have
detected, says the paper, attempts by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> drug
lords a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX>, surface-to-air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> are
especially dangerous, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , because "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
are talking [about] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhDs</ENAMEX>, former senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> with access to
sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have [already] laundered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of
dollars."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> heralds the formation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Learning First Alliance of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school boards</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>,
which is dedicated to improving public school education. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX> includes
such educational policy power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFT</ENAMEX> and its principal
goals include establishing tougher course work and making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> safer. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> will be holding a summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> to address improving
reading and math achievement.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Murray</ENAMEX> observes in a front-page
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Outlook"</ENAMEX> column that now with the diminution of the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> the most influential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> is broadcasting. For proof, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> points
to the fate of the concept of free television time for political ads. Once a
staple of campaign reform legislation, it is now MIA, because "broadcasters
complained" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> cowered."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are on the rise:
nowadays a newborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> chance of contracting the disease by
age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> tend to implicate increased environmental exposure to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carcinogens</ENAMEX>.

            After virtually ignoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> hearings story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> when the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">majors</ENAMEX> had it splashed all over their front pages, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes
front page with the news that, as a direct result of testimony revealing agency
abuses given at those hearings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has suspended a number of mid-level
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reports that the hearings have given the flat tax a
new life on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports on its front page that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
fund-raising calls now causing such a political furor produced far smaller
contribution totals than they were supposed to. The principal problem was, it
seems, that neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> was comfortably in bluntly asking
for the sums the professional fundraisers specified. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> were
convinced their goals could have been met if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would have made more calls
himself. So they came up with the concept of a "touch-up call" in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
would call potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and talk about everything but money. That
was handled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> asking for large contributions in orchestrated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">follow-up</ENAMEX> calls. "The answer," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , "was almost always
yes."

            It was easy to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to make touch-up calls, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX>
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> loves to schmooze on the phone."

         
      
   
