
   
   
      
         
            Winnie the Poo

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times 's national lead is an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that
focuses mainly on tax policy and campaign finance. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's metro
edition leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s decision to uphold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>'s right to remove a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> who wouldn't seek the death penalty.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> internal audit revealing that too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> have too much access to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' personal records, opening the
door to theft and misuse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with a sharp decline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
abortion rate. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the agreement by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> to phase in a total ban on tobacco advertising and
sports-event sponsorship.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says that he's weighing a tax cut but
warned against spending a budget surplus that doesn't exist yet. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also
says he would judge any proposed tax cut by whether it was fair to average
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>, good for the economy, and conducive to a simpler tax code.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> also tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that he is prepared to flout
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> by making a recess appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lann Lee</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>'s
top civil rights post. And he also addressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision to curtail
the investigation into his campaign fund-raising. "She did what she had to do
based on her reading of the law. And everybody knows that she is an
indpendent-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>." (Just not an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> also sits down with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but his interview is all access, no content. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> refuses to concede any
mistakes in either his campaign activities or in his defense of them. He says
it's unfair to dwell on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months</TIMEX> of controversy. "A snapshot," he bromides,
"does not have as much accuracy as a moving picture." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay or Dave</ENAMEX>
would surely say, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, a moving picture is a snapshot.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> abortion story (played inside by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) reports
that despite a rate drop of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, abortion remains a common
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> experience--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> eventually get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> all give prominent front-page play
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnie Mandela</ENAMEX>'s testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmond Tutu</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth and Reconciliation Commission</ENAMEX>. Complete with big pictures: the WP
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> run a shot of her embracing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> she is widely
believed to have had killed, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> shows the former
liberationist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> decked out in all the major jewelry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>-inlaid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> glasses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headline is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnie Mandela</ENAMEX> Is
Defiant, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Calling Accusations 'Lunacy'</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reporting agrees, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> denying
even the most minor allegations against her and offered no reconciliation until
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tutu</ENAMEX> begged her to do so. Finally then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> said things went horribly
wrong, but she gave utterly no explanation of that remark. The LAT
apparently was at a different hearing. It emphasizes that last bit of vacuity
above all else.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
recently visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> before a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle NBA</ENAMEX> game, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supersonic Greg Anthony</ENAMEX> drew cheers from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX> by
asking when the capital gains tax cut takes effect.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of consumer and health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> handed
out sarcastic awards to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> for bad ads they'd made. Included was one to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX>
whose "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Buy the Beer, Get the Gear</ENAMEX>" campaign required drinking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27,000</NUMEX> bottles
(or cans) of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> to win a pool table.

            
               And that makes them horses' asses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that
recently after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> criticized a multi-part series his
paper did, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of the series sent him a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in a box.

         
      
   
