
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arms</ENAMEX>

            The apparent break in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> crisis leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspectors</ENAMEX> have gotten clearance to go
back in, and, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> including an unspecified
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> is scheduled to be on the ground in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>.
However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is taking a wait-and-see attitude, and so extra air and naval
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> are still heading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>. Concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is quoted in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> as saying, "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming days</TIMEX>
we will wait and see whether he does, in fact, comply with the will of the
international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s turnaround
by suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> "bent a little." Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports,
some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> agreed to renewed inspections because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
had guaranteed it easier inspection procedures, such as changing the
composition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and limiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U-2</ENAMEX> surveillance flights. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WP</ENAMEX> attributes such a sentiment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy prime minister</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> adamantly deny this, saying there were absolutely no concessions.
And, true to recent convention, there is a "livid spotting" about this: The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that
national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Berger</ENAMEX> was "livid" at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> leak
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carrots</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> accompanies its main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> story with a fine piece of reporting
by its crack technical military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Jeffrey Smith</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s biological
weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>. The piece, based on scores of interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, details how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> have spent the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> years
looking for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> warheads filled with the world's deadliest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">germs</ENAMEX>, capable of killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. This weapons program, reports
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , was seeded by a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> mail-order shipment of germs from a
Rockville, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Morning-</TIMEX>after thinking about the septuplets is creeping into the coverage.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> tells of intense criticism from ethicists and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and of
their warnings about promiscuous use of fertility treatments, which produce
extreme medical risks for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>, at growing public expense.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> doubt the claim by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">septuplet</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB/GYN</ENAMEX> that she used the same dosage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fertility drug</ENAMEX> that she had used
previously to produce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s prior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also runs a piece
inside reviewing the risks posed by drug-induced multiple births.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story inside reporting that the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> contracting <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> at birth dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1992 and 1996</TIMEX>. The credit appears to go to aggressive use of the
antiviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AZT</ENAMEX>.

            There's an intriguing headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> over an LAT front pager: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Major</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Donor</ENAMEX> is Focus of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Burial Probe</ENAMEX>." The story has to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>, the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Del Coronado</ENAMEX> and a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and now a subject of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s investigation into
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> rewarded campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> with burial
plots in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arlington National Cemetery</ENAMEX>. (The perfect gift for someone too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decomposed</ENAMEX> to really enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX> is buried there even
though his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX> marine service ordinarily wouldn't have gotten him in.

            If the aforementioned qualms about multiple births don't seem decisive, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a more prosaic consideration: the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,000</NUMEX> diapers that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">septuplets</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will have to change.

         
      
   
