
   
   
      
         
            Mine Kampf

            The top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is the crash of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> at an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airshow</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Redskins</ENAMEX> game at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> dominates the front page),
and that accident and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> others involving military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> are the lead at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> . At the New York
Times the lead is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>'s possible shift to endorsing a land mine
ban, while at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , it's a new study about the impact of
immigration on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> economy and what to do about it--on a front page
dominated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX> picture and the accompanying headline "'3rd <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>,'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Seinfeld</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stars Win Emmys</ENAMEX>."

            The immigration study, prepared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rand Corp.</ENAMEX> warns that the
increasingly skill-based <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> economy cannot continue to absorb large
flows of poorly educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> and calls on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to: reduce new legal
immigrant admissions to "a moderate range," allow the rate of immigration to
fluctuate with general economic conditions, and add education levels and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English proficiency</ENAMEX> as admission criteria. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant advocate</ENAMEX> is quoted in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> denouncing the study as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank poppycock</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> land mine story reveals a major policy change: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> that it could sign a land mine ban
provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> was allowed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more years</TIMEX> before removing them from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> peninsula. Administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> admitted that the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, who had embraced the ban, raised the pressure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to make a
move. Some hurdles remain however, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> : the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> would like
at least a limited exemption for anti-personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> used in conjunction with
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank mines</ENAMEX>, and also wants an escape clause allowing exemptions for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> who are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of aggression.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX> has escalated its
campaign to advertise hard liquor on television by preparing ads including a
caveat about responsible drinking. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> said that this latest move will have no impact on their
existing policies prohibiting liquor ads. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> didn't return the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s
call.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> has a big photo-essay inside called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Battle of the Sexes Invades</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boot Camp</ENAMEX>," in which the paper takes a comparative look at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina</ENAMEX>
basic training installations--an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> of both sexes train
together and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> one where they are sexually segregated. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> even
found a female <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> who had previously gone through the basic training at the
Army <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>--she prefers the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marine</ENAMEX> way of handling the sexes in training. The
piece says that "the future of gender-integrated training in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is on
the ropes."

            Following a revelation first made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ,
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> run pieces about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' tax audit. The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> headlines chosen emphasize opposite sides of the dispute. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's
reads: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS Audit of Paula Jones</ENAMEX> Is `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harassment,' Adviser Says</ENAMEX>" and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT 's</ENAMEX> is: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Lawyer</ENAMEX>: No Link To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS Audit Of Jones</ENAMEX>."

            The top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front features a sprawling piece about how private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are using online resources to dig ever deeper into private
information. The piece explains that certain Web sites specialize in selling
such personal data as unlisted telephone numbers, bank account numbers, beeper
numbers, and even annual salary and investment portfolio information, but in
effect serves as wonderful free advertising for them by mentioning their names
and quoting their rates for these particular services.

            There's an odd lacuna in the piece, where it describes the formidable
staffing of "one of the best-connected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investigative Group International</ENAMEX>. It identifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> by name
and says also that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Kelly</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of police</ENAMEX>, used to run the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, but does not elaborate on the following fascinating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tidbit</ENAMEX>: "The promotion brochure features <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who
now work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGI</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
