
   
   
      
         
            Dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's Diary</ENAMEX>

            The coming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> tax reform debate leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . At
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
it's the decision of major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> to trim benefits for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the news that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
types are turning up the pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> and reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> for inspection access to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> presidential "palace" sites. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with a look at the alarming
number of unexplained deaths of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>. It
seems that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, on average, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> between the ages
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 and 44</TIMEX> have died there under circumstances that have never been cleared
up, a rate that appears, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says, to be the highest in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> lays much of the blame for this on the inadequacies of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, eager to counter
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> proposals for the flat tax or a national sales tax, is considering
various other simplification proposals, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that would exempt as many
as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> from having to file at all, by letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
calculate their taxes for them, which would then be withheld by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>.

            The companion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> news section cover story
reports that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s poll on the topic say
they want a change in the system, and yet a majority of them do not support
either the flat tax or the national sales tax--and want to retain deductions
for home mortgage interest and charitable contributions.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that for cost containment reasons, managed care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> nationwide are starting to cut some of the
generous benefits--such as low- or no-cost prescriptions and eyeglasses and no
membership fees--that attracted elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> to their plans in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. The changes are due, says the paper, to rising <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> costs and
a cap set by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>.

            These increases are significant because, observes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had been counting on managed care to help
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contain Medicare</ENAMEX> costs. A similar point is made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's front-page piece about the spiraling
management problems at the leading HMOs: namely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> are not proving to be
a brake on the system's problems, but rather arenas that readily reproduce
them. What we're learning it seems, is that regardless of the setting, the
market will tend to punish coverage of those, like the elderly, with the most
health needs. And so the question that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> health care reforms at least
raised--What to add to the marketplace to ensure availability?--remains in need
of an answer.

            On its front, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> continues the comprehensive look it began
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s involvement during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> presidential campaign
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">237</NUMEX> fund-raising events that brought in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$119.2 million</NUMEX>. The
story is illustrated by a shot of the presidential daybook for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17, 1996</TIMEX>, during which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,562,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the piece
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, spent far more time raising money for his re-election than any other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent president</ENAMEX> in modern history.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story inside that brings home the high cost of poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> policies insides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days ago</TIMEX> a veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> fatally shot a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>. But, says the
story, this was hardly the first sign of trouble. Prior to that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had
been in and out of counseling--once because he held a gun to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>--and had undergone alcohol abuse treatment <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times. And oh yeah, there
was the time he shot and killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> during an argument. The shooting was
ruled justifiable, but it was also determined that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> beers in
him at the time. So what was his posting at the time of this last shooting? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Miami High Intensity Drug Trafficking Office</ENAMEX>.

            How about this for a good idea? According to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Janklow</ENAMEX> started a program that puts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> to work building <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> for the elderly and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>. So far, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">161</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Dakotans</ENAMEX> have bought <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> built by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">convicts</ENAMEX>.

            And the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No-Duh</ENAMEX>!" Award goes to...the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> headline
says it all: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF Cuts Asian Growth Forecasts</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
