
   
   
      
         
            Still <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleazy After All These Years</ENAMEX>

            The showdown congressional vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on fast track trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> is the
lead all around. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times says neither side has the upper hand. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times says the vote will be a "cliffhanger." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is more pessimistic, saying that pro forces
have "hit a brick wall in their attempts to muster the votes." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
notes the strange alliances forged by the bill, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>, not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> points out that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti Democrats</ENAMEX> are mad at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> for
his comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> suggesting that they were putting personal needs
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s (and the paper implies that eventual presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> may ultimately pay the price for all this bad feeling). And
yet much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reportage</ENAMEX> describes how, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the eleventh hour</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
is striving to meet those needs. Votes are being promised to the administration
in return for pledges of campaign funds, and for assurances about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vintners</ENAMEX>' and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX> and citrus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">growers</ENAMEX>' rights, and those of cattle
ranchers too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes a signal drawback of all this attention
going to the last-minute pole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitters</ENAMEX>: those who took a stand early are pissed.
"I should have held out for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1billion</NUMEX> for wetlands restoration," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>.

            Even though the run-up to the fast-track vote probably should be the lead
today, the story fits a recent LAT trend that's worth noting: on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> has a weakness for leads straight out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> radio address, no matter how un-gripping the topic. No doubt because
that sure simplifies the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> reporting--just turn on the radio and
type.

            Just wondering: Why didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech to a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>--the first
ever by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--get on anybody's front page? (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts it on p.
A18.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>'s about-to-be-released book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> gets plenty of
ink: front page at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , a front-page "reefer" to a piece inside at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and a long inside piece at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The overall point of
the book is familiar--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headline is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Depicts JFK as Reckless</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Immoral"</ENAMEX>--but the details and sourcing are new. Although this book was said
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point to depend crucially on the recently discredited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> papers,
it's apparently still plenty lurid without them. Details the papers mention
include: a) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>'s help in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> election was secured in a
JFK-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Giancana</ENAMEX> face-to-face meeting arranged by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>; b) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> that she knows the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>
election was "bought"; c) Four ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> describe the large
numbers of sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>--many of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>--ushered into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
and hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics</ENAMEX> was able to parlay its discovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s
affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Campbell Exner</ENAMEX> into a huge fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> contract. Hersh
even pulls in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, mentioning that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>-era <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> discovered he had
taken a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> bribe.

            Sleaze in high places seems to be the order of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs
an op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Beschloss</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>
taping that includes a conversation between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Fortas</ENAMEX> in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">married Fortas</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> that he's out with a "beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in red"
who's not his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and that "We're doing good, and I'm going to try to do bad
before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>'s over."

         
      
   
