
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX>-for-all

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with new congressional pressure on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> regarding campaign fund-raising investigations. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the changing role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
appearance at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> church during which he called for greater
independence for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX>, remarks criticized by many local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> for
not including a call for voting rights for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX> says that his investigating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> may have to cite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> for contempt if she doesn't turn over a
memo written to her by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX>. In it, to no avail, Freeh
explained why she should appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to look into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
campaign fund-raising. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> plans on asking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX> to open up his own investigation of these
matters independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s. Meanwhile, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>
will ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> to consider perjury charges against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> who
testified at his fund-raising hearings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past summer</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also has
a front-page piece concerning these developments.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead points out that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> bailout package for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> is the latest example of how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund</ENAMEX> is pushing deeper than ever into the day-to-day
operations of the economies it aids. Chastened by compliance difficulties
surrounding recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, says the paper, for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korea</ENAMEX> bailout, Fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> won concessions to many detailed provisions
covering the cronyish connections among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s major
industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's lead feature notes that the latest global economic
developments challenge the widely-held view that an emphasis on short-term
performance weakens an economy. The piece claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>'s strong growth
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> and the collapse of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> long-term-oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial system
(where, unlike here, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and not financial markets are the primary source of
capital) after another show quite the contrary. Another WSJ front-page
piece notes that while the current economic differential between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and
the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies will amp our trade deficit somewhat, few think the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis will derail <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s current economic expansion--because the
other major legs of the economy, like consumer confidence, business profits and
government expenditures, are robust.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a front-page interview-based piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> , the
follow-on to a presidential chat piece that ran <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> effort
dwelt on the personal side of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s life nowadays: his knee injury, his
hearing aids, his love of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>, his empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s installment concerns
domestic policy, specifically the series of modest initiatives he has put
together since failing to sell wholesale health care reform. Among the
piecemeal efforts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lauds are insuring overnight hospital stays
for new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, school uniforms, cell phones for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrols</ENAMEX>,
keeping liquor ads off the airwaves, restricting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> sales, creating a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> registry for sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX>, and suspending the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s licenses of
deadbeat dads.

            Amid all the hand-wringing (especially on the sports pages) about whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latrell Sprewell</ENAMEX> has been dealt with too harshly comes the voice of reason in
the form of a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which points out that if Sprewell
had a real job, he'd be looking at permanent unemployment and criminal
prosecution.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> column looks into a complaint that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Thomas</ENAMEX> was recently spotted driving like a jerk on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. In the
course of his investigation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamen</ENAMEX> learns that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>,
which causes him to ask exactly the right question: "Just how big was that last
raise for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>?"

         
      
   
