
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terrorists</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Convictions</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> terrorism dominates the front pages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead with the conviction of the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planner</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb van</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> bombing case. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times puts the story on the front, but below the fold.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> lead about this story emphasizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that
the verdict could lead to more terrorism against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, especially in light
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s murders in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with an exclusive:
that a "rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATF</ENAMEX> accelerated the approval
of import permits for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> modified assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> could
be sold legally, despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>' full awareness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
clear intent to keep such <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is "livid" about this and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> was so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irate</ENAMEX> "he put his hands around the neck of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>." (Given all the
reporting of his famous temper, don't you think that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead states that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> murders trial has
ordered the jury sequestered while it completes the case's penalty phase. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has this in a separate front-page story that includes this added
detail: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>, after voting to convict in the case, sent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> a note
inquiring about dangers to them, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> then ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>' names
sealed.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has its first mention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> shootings on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
front. Despite recently instituting later deadlines, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> couldn't get the
story into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s paper (unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs a front-page feature about how, after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of depending on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> defense umbrella, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> are now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rearming</ENAMEX> themselves--at nearly double <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> spending rates. The main reason,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>, is that they aren't convinced that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in
the region will stay put and are plenty worried about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">build-up</ENAMEX>. The upshot, says the paper, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> "is likely to become a much
more dangerous place."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial page doesn't think much of the travel sanctions the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> passed against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>: "No more shopping at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrods</ENAMEX> for Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tariq Aziz</ENAMEX>-that'll show 'em."

            In contrast to the quadraphonic media coverage when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> launched its
investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800 crash, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> announced yesterday
that its inquiry was over because there was no crime, the volume was pretty
low. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT 's</ENAMEX> is the only major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> to carry the news--and on the
bottom at that.

            Could there be serious security leaks at some of the primo op-ed desks?
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a piece on the discovery of tapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Buchwald</ENAMEX> effort on the discovery of
tapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> study suggests that an experimental
oral contraceptive for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> might work. Of course, a question remains for women
that no amount of science will ever overcome: "Can you believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> when he
says he took it?"

         
      
   
