
   
   
      
         
            Freeh at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX>

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> the
lead is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX>'s joint appearance before a congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> air
quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are considering imposing stricter smog rules on pick-up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s call for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to quickly
pony up some cash that has been promised in the recently concluded bailout only
as a last resort (yet another case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> leading with a financial
story nobody else even puts on the front page). Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> rejected any early injection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> funds. There was
no immediate reaction from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. There's politics on both sides of the matter,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> want up-front money to soften what
are widely viewed in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as the bailout's regulatory intrusions,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has tried to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> contribution to the
deal--estimated to be potentially <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 billion</NUMEX>--more palatable by suggesting
there's a chance it would never actually be needed.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> stresses the "unified front" put on by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> (as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> in its front pager), while the WP
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emphasizes Freeh</ENAMEX>'s testimony that he continues to support an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> taking over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>'s ongoing investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign
fund-raising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has spent a lot of time in
front of congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mikes</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s appearance marked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX>'s first
extensive public comments concerning the investigation and his disagreement
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> about how to pursue it. He is quoted describing that disagreement as
"the biggest open secret in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>" because of leaks to
news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. Probably so, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX> had as much motive as anyone to do
the leaking: publicizing the dispute served to demonstrate his political
independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has been pilloried repeatedly for not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">demonstrating</ENAMEX> (see, for instance, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> column).

            The context for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead is that the boom in light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and sport utility
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vehicles</ENAMEX> has accelerated pollution because they aren't subject to the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emission</ENAMEX> and fuel economy controls as passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. An editorial in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that even though these heavier <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> as
numerous as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, they already produce as much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX>, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX> if
the rules aren't changed, they may produce <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 75 percent</NUMEX> of all smog coming
from personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>.

            Although even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Farm Workers</ENAMEX> considers the strike against table
grapes to be "dormant," until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> it was still going strong, reports
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>. That's when the
results of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>-wide referendum were announced: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54% percent</NUMEX> pro-grape, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX>
anti. There will be grapes on campus tables for brunch this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. Some
anti-grape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are planning a no-grape eating table.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "Tax Report" brings word that some rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> have been tangling
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> over the deductibility of clothes worn on stage during
performances. Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie Nicks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleetwood Mac</ENAMEX> told the government
that her flowing on-stage get-ups are not suitable for ordinary wear, and that
much of it is discarded after shows because it can't be re-used. The column
reports that a tentative settlement between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicks</ENAMEX> and the feds is in the
works.

            The WP front page reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latrell Sprewell</ENAMEX> held a press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. He
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apologized</ENAMEX>, but his main goal was image repair: he was accompanied, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>, his tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>' union, several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>, and....<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cochran</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprewell</ENAMEX> took no questions from the assembled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and did not
address any specifics of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incidents in which he punched and choked his
coach. "We're not here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to discuss the facts," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cochran</ENAMEX> explained. No word
yet on the search for the real chokers.

         
      
   
