
   
   
      
         
            No <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czechs</ENAMEX> Please?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s protestations that her probe of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> fund-raising is
far from closed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a simmering debate about the costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion.
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> front, dominated by local stories, gives
some play to the new stricter rules for disability aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (a story
done in greater depth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> leads are the product of her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet The Press</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counteroffensive</ENAMEX> in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> charges of being duped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
the handling of the coffee tapes. "Nothing has been closed, and nobody has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exonerated</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> juxtaposes its report that as of right now, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> still feels
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> videos are not indications of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> criminality with mention of
the appearance in the tapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arief Wiriadinata</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> who identifies
himself on camera as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emissary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo Bank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Riady</ENAMEX>, and of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> having <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> who, it is now
known, each contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposed expansion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to include <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech Republic</ENAMEX> depends on the joint
approval of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and the parliaments of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, and
that cost will be the decisive issue in those votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, led
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , don't want to pay too much of the total
expansion bill, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, who need to cut their deficits to
qualify for the Eurodollar, are not much inclined to pick up the slack.

            And apparently, nobody agrees on what the bill is. The current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
estimate is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $35 billion</NUMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2009</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> think that's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>
too high. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, not to be outdone, intend to pay nothing extra. The
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget Office</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> estimate is too low.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> has given some good coverage lately to the upcoming global
warming meetings and to the political debates they are provoking, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook"</ENAMEX> column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Murray</ENAMEX> takes the issue seriously, saying that in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next century</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s average temperature probably will rise by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two to six</TIMEX>
degrees. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> says that the question dominating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> debate
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, the question that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is faced with, is, "How much should the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> sacrifice now to buy
insurance against threats in the future?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
"know that proposing even something as modest as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25-cent</NUMEX>-a-gallon gasoline
tax for this purpose wouldn't sell with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, which is busy
buying gas-guzzling sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, or with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>." But is that so obvious?
In southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, where the economy is roaring back, gas prices went up
nearly that much <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past summer</TIMEX> and it was hardly a back-page story, much
less the cause of any political ferment. If the economy is good, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will
pay extra for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, and what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> tends to downplay is that almost
all the environmental controls implemented thus far have proven to be good for
business.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caracas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, where he made his
initial pitch for what will be the main theme of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX>
trip--the expansion of free trade. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> puts this story on its front
(although below the fold) and it also is the top item in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's
world-wide news digest. But it's buried by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> (picture on the front,
but story on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>), and by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (the national edition has a
picture on the front, the story inside, while the metro edition dispenses with
the picture). Now, not every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is equally important to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, but it's hard to understand, given the increasingly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
demographic of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, how it is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> could show less interest
in this trip than say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s vacation on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
