
   
   
      
         
            More <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> Cheesiness?

            A new game of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> over arms inspections leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , it's signs that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> is ready to
shoulder real economic reforms.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> halted the work of yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> both report that the official reasons are that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has too many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and that the team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Scott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ritter</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> visit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ritter</ENAMEX>, a
seasoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>, discovered smuggled-in missile guidance equipment. The
Post adds the detail that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s latest tantrum followed a day of
aggressive surprise inspections conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ritter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> reaction
is to re-emphasize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> must comply and that all diplomatic and military
options are on the table.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> emphasize that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> president
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> has received more international attention, in the form of visits from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegations</ENAMEX> and calls from numerous foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, than he has
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and that he seems to be responding with a real austerity pledge,
including the postponement of several major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> investments in the
dubious projects of family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports on another public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buck</ENAMEX>-up: a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">finance minister</ENAMEX> for
a televised purchase of the local currency.

            Although prior press reports have wondered if the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">76-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s
failing health would impair his ability to lead his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> out of the current
crisis, neither of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> stories emphasize this.

            According to the LAT front, a study coming out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiesenthal Center</ENAMEX> will charge that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> were confined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> during
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> in special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, sometimes behind barbed wire and at gunpoint.
Often, says the paper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were forced to work for little or no pay, and
even forced to pay special taxes to defray the expenses of their
confinement.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> quotes fresh government research
indicating that total <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> health care expenditures rose but an
inflation-adjusted <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.9%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the slowest growth rate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly forty years</TIMEX>.
The study cites the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX>'s explosive growth of managed care as a major factor.
But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> points out, with spending in the public health care
sector (primarily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>) coming under firmer budgetary control,
the growth of private medical costs may be poised to rise above <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> per year for
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 90s</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports a major policy reversal on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIDS</ENAMEX>
service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. After years of actively opposing the reporting by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to state health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gay Men</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Crisis</ENAMEX> has just endorsed the practice. (But prefers tracking via a code
system to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> using actual names.)

            Despite all the budget euphoria swirling about, business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Sloan</ENAMEX>
uses his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> column to point out a familiar but forgotten
fact: There is no surplus if you eschew "fedmath" and instead calculate assets
and liabilities the way a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> does, i.e., not letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
pension system, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, be used to draw down the deficit. Figured this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, states <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sloan</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> budget deficit was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$103.9 billion</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports on an unpredicted consequence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
economic crisis: the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> race is cooling off because most of the region's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> are suddenly unable to go through with planned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> purchases. Just
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> announced that it would put off buying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> are delaying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> purchases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> is unusual in that it is canceling outright a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> deal,
but most of the other deals will probably only be delayed. Here's an idea: why
not require these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to swear off such <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> deals as a condition of
receiving any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bailout money?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of sensitive negotiations, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has finally agreed to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110 million</NUMEX> to compensate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> who are living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> and the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. While information is comparatively fresh and large numbers of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> are still around, why not institute similar reparations to be paid by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gulag</ENAMEX>? Again, why not make such payments a condition
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and international aid packages?

         
      
   
