
   
   
      
         
            Take That, You IMFers

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> crisis. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s vote to defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan to pay off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> debt to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> and to make extra contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> overlooked
evidence it had collected of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s attempts to influence domestic
politics.

            What happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> ousted the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> responded by pulling nearly
all of his multi-national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> headline is
about the ouster, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headline is about the pull-out.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead is about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> struck the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
fundings from a bill to hold them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> until conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> can get
progress on an unrelated issue--tightening further the current rules against
abortion-related uses of federal money. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> points out that this
non-action could hamstring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> efforts to forge a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> agreement on
action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and could hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>'s attempts to contain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
economic crisis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> is quoted in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> (which carries the story inside) as calling the
congressional action "boneheaded."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead is another water molecule in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>'s drip-drip
campaign against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Justice</ENAMEX>'s campaign fund-raising investigation.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s installment is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has admitted overlooking evidence about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s domestic political lobbying until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> hearings had already
shut down. The evidence even includes, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , indications that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> boasted that it had thwarted the congressional inquiry.

            The story reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> was "livid" when she learned of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foul-up</ENAMEX>. Note that this has become an essential politico-journalistic routine:
a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> screws up and the press reports how angry
he/she was about it. Other recent examples include the alleged off-camera
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tantrums</ENAMEX> had by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> over the belated discovery of the
coffee videos, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s report about how somebody high up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> nearly throttled an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> over the discovery that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATF</ENAMEX> was letting
scads of assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> survey released
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are stalked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> So
are, the study says, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">370,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> each report that new studies of
the breakthrough triple therapies for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> indicate that the regimen doesn't
eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>, but tends to make it dormant, which means that the therapies
should be continued even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are completely asymptomatic.

            An op-ed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> by former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gates</ENAMEX> calls for a
strong military response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, not just a few cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>.
This comes on the heels of similar calls from the keyboards of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX>.

            This column is sentencing itself to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Corrections</ENAMEX> for
several offenses committed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. First, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakistanis</ENAMEX> aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s lead should not have spoken of the dominance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s news by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it turns out that while the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11/12</NUMEX> national edition of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> didn't report the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> shootings and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of the
metropolitan press run didn't either, the story did make it into the latter
half of the metro edition. Similarly, although early copies of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11/13</NUMEX>
Times didn't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s drawdown of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA 800</ENAMEX> investigation on the
front page, most of the press run did.

            
               Hmmm...most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> want it on the outside. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merck</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Propecia</ENAMEX> is
effective in restoring hair in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>
panel found...."

         
      
   
