
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burial Plot Thickens</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s refusal to hand over to a congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> a memo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX> had written her urging an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> for investigating allegations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign fund-raising
wrongdoing. The national edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX> wrote a joint letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> defending and explaining their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noncompliance</ENAMEX>. (The metro edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> leads with a proposed
reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> and subway fares.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s vague speech at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto</ENAMEX> global-warming conference and the lukewarm-to-hostile reaction it got.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> promised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> "flexibility" in arriving at a deal on such issues as how
much constraint will be required of developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the latest development in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>scandal concerning
the interment at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Larry Lawrence</ENAMEX>: the decision of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> to have her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> removed
from there.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead explains that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX> disinterment comes in
response to a rising outcry over evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> didn't have a right to
an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> plot because he invented his story of being on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merchant Marine</ENAMEX>
ship, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace Bushnell</ENAMEX> , that was torpedoed while ferrying emergency
supplies to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> points out that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dust-up</ENAMEX> is a particular embarrassment for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for whom military issues
have always been a matter of special sensitivity. (Can you say "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX>
letter"?) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilbur Wright</ENAMEX> Community
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> say that their records show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> was enrolled there at
the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bushnell</ENAMEX> sinking. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> both also have
this detail in their pieces, which they run inside. Moreover, both these papers
somewhat out-report the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> finds a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bushnell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> who doesn't remember
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> finds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of one who is none too pleased about
the whole affair. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>'s claim to have
graduated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arizona</ENAMEX> appears to be false. Plus, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> would "struggle with his emotions" when he
would talk of his near sinking, which he did at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> confirmation
hearings.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads also cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s
turn-over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> of a new batch of internal documents relating to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> under investigation
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> and congressional probes. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the
documents quote <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> observing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> would not be able to finish its investigation of foreign
contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> until after the election and then quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> as saying, "This will certainly help
move campaign reform forward."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reports on the
advent of Web sites that offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> a chance to vent about their troubles
at work. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> site
posts anecdotes sent in by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>' antics and features a
satirical advice column. Another offers tips on how to relax before job interviews (have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tic Tac</ENAMEX>).

         
      
   
