
   
   
      
         
            Paint It Black

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s surprise announcement that his
proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> federal budget will be balanced. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with turmoil at the opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX> trial (which also gets
considerable front-page coverage, along with big pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the two
Times ).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the budget announcement marks the shift from the
"politics of austerity" to the "politics of prosperity." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says it is the "fiscal equivalent of the fall of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX>." After all, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> observe, the federal budget was last
balanced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has even
tried to offer a balanced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>. No wonder that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
senses "euphoria" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. "You'll see surpluses as far as the eye can
see" is the quote of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> from presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Sperling</ENAMEX>, and
everybody has it. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> observes, this is a pretty dramatic shift
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this past weekend</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were discouraging
talk of a near-term surplus. (A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> explanation for this is that the
administration wanted to preserve the momentum that comes with a big
surprise.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to propose a balanced budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> and the
Times remarks that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> never mentions it, but a tax increase signed
at great political cost by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> began the work of deficit reduction."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> totes up the political causes, but says the development arose
"mostly because of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of relentless economic growth."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> budget lead stresses high up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s view that the first
order of business for any surplus is balancing the budget, not cutting taxes or
increasing spending. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> budget story also goes high with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
warning against any big new tax cuts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that a spokesman
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ways and Means</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX> complained about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
"pre-emptive strike against tax relief."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that as soon as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> took the bench on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kaczynski</ENAMEX>, in a low calm voice asked to "revisit" the issue of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, apparently referring to his desire to jettison them because they
still intend to introduce non-medical evidence of his mental instability. (The
paper also cites an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kaczynski</ENAMEX> objects to the presence at the
trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.) Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> went into a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-hour</TIMEX> conference with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> present.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column gives some insight
into the concept of going postal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, it explains, can't strike and
so their grievances accumulate unresolved in much greater numbers than in other
lines of work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> quotes a government report stating that the
current backlog of them numbers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 70,000</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> also brings news of a coming marketplace battle as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> enters the sports equipment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biz</ENAMEX>. Among its products will be a lightweight clamshell baseball glove,
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and wire instead of laces. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is considering lining the
glove with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather</ENAMEX>, because right now, "it smells like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX>.") Entrenched
equipment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rawlings</ENAMEX> is set to respond with such products as a
baseball containing a microchip that enables it to calculate the speed at which
it's thrown, a datum displayed on an LCD on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s skin.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> run stories <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> reporting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's words, "fuming," about that
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX>-Couple-on-the-beach picture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself says he feels the picture was an invasion of
his privacy and also reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agence-France Presse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> (a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>) who assigned the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> says that if the president
didn't want them there, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> could have made it happen." In
short, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> faces a dilemma: either it is being less than straight
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> whether the pictures were staged or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> suffered a major
security breakdown.

         
      
   
