
   
   
      
         
            Mergers and Inquisitions

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with a big Wall <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX> merger. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>' revelations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> abuses.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall St.</ENAMEX> news is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers Group</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX>
deal in which it will acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salomon Inc.</ENAMEX> and merge it with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith Barney</ENAMEX>
unit, thereby creating the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, coming on the heels of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>'s similarly-sized merger of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean Witter</ENAMEX>, is widely viewed as signaling the onset of even
further combinations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brokerages</ENAMEX> and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. In setting
out the basics, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> tend towards breathlessness. This deal, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salomon</ENAMEX> "cachet" overseas and "brings together <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liveliest personalities</ENAMEX> in finance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanford I. Weill</ENAMEX>,
respected as one of Wall Street's savviest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealmakers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> investor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren E. Buffett</ENAMEX>...." Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> gets so caught up it quoted one
Wall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St. guru</ENAMEX> as saying the merged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has "all the ingredients to be
competitive with the bulge-bracket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>," but forgets to explain what that
term means. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> seems thrilled to relate that the deal was first
broached over <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> and oysters beside the pool at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons Hotel</ENAMEX>. Leave
it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> to be detached enough from the buzz of it all to wonder if
the resultant dwindling number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in the brokerage field will lead
to higher costs for individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> gives a lot of its top front to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' testimony at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing investigating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>. Besides a large headline over the story
proper--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxpayers Tell of Mistreatment</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> Issues Apology"--there's also a
large photo of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> and thumbnails of others, all under the headline,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxpayer Horror Stories</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> calls the hearings "unprecedented" and
includes details from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> accounts of being hounded by overzealous and
incompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the trump testimony was that of an 82-year-old
priest telling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' erroneous attempt to grab <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,000</NUMEX> from a trust fund
for the poor set up by his dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the apology offered
by the acting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> leaves "little doubt about the veracity of the
allegations."

            In its lead coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> hearings, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> emphasizes the
testimony of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, who said that her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> routinely pursues the poor
for more taxes. She testified that she commonly finds herself going after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> territory whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> lack air conditioning, forcing her
to wonder why she is there. (She doesn't mention noticing any oysters.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has a fascinating front-page feature
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a federal court case involving a rancher, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildlife</ENAMEX>
Service, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>. It seems that when federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> executed a search warrant
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Berger</ENAMEX> to look for signs of poisoned bald eagles
(they didn't find any), they included in their raiding party <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> with video cameras, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> themselves were wearing wires that
went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX>. None of this was disclosed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
are now suing the feds and the network for violating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX>
Amendment rights against unreasonable search and seizure.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a piece inside detailing serious trouble with a book on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> that My <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lai-exposer Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX> is coming out with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. It
seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> had based his project on a cache of secret papers that were
said to provide the strongest evidence yet for such long-rumored Camelot dung
as a prior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> marriage, his relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mob</ENAMEX> and his agreement to pay
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> in hush money to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little, Brown</ENAMEX>, had been gearing up for a blockbuster, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> was planning a documentary. But now, says, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> has
concluded that the secret source materials are fakes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX>'s comment to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> : "That's journalism."

         
      
   
