
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Beats Clinton</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s stern words to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Both
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s last-ditch attempt to generate support for the
fast-track trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> bill. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' attempt to
salvage the nomination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lann Lee</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>'s top civil rights
enforcement job.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that it
could face military action or economic sanctions if it continues to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> out of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> is
quoted as saying "sufficient warnings have been given." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports
that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> canceled a port call so as to be able to stay
within striking range of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> television appeal for
support of the trade bill as "extraordinary." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that the vote
count was looking so unfavorable that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> cut short his trip to the
opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>--where he got a ringing
endorsement for the bill from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>--so he could return to work the
phones to lobby <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the bill is hanging
"by a thread" on the eve of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> vote.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is also staring at
defeat with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> nomination. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> has, says the paper, faced no serious
questions about his credentials, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX> has become a lightening
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rod</ENAMEX> for congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, who have taken to
portraying him as an unabashed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for race preferences

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a front-page zinger detailing all the free travel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">congress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> have been copping lately. These pieces have
long been a newspaper staple, but the news is that, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's words,
"In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> when congressional gift rules have all but eliminated the free
lunch, the free round of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> and the free <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, congressional
travel is the last great perk."

            It seems there's blowback from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story stating that
most direct-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> were about to collect sales tax. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that resistance to the idea on
the part of some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> is so strong that any such agreement will be put off
at least until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, not announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> had reported.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the deal fell apart because of widespread customer
complaints prompted by its story, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX> is among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defectors</ENAMEX>.

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> opening was the occasion for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ladies</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Newton</ENAMEX> to get together. The photo op gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> good shots for their fronts. The weirdest of
these being the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> picture, which takes the warm fraternal fuzzies now
felt by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to a new level of intimacy by depicting them as
power-suited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> keeps it light, but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story keeps hitting current geopolitics, mentioning that as the
ceremonies were unfolding, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> was again thumbing his nose at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>," and quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s reference from the podium to "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vigilance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> displayed in dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, [which] as we all
know, is required again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." The piece also mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has endorsed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stance on the current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> imbroglio.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> mentions a letter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincolnesque</ENAMEX> proportions displayed at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wrote to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> during the run-up to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX>.
"When the question is asked, `How many lives are you willing to sacrifice'--it
tears my heart," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wrote. "The answer, of course, is none--none at all." He
added, "Every human life is precious, the little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' too." If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had
been able to put himself across like that in public, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might never have
become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            Very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> have been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, so they have a
consistent tendency to boot matters martial, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story on the
library opening provides an example. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> refers to the exhibit of
"a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> Avenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter plane</ENAMEX>" like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was shot down in. But
it's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>. It's a torpedo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
