
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sheepskin Game</ENAMEX>

            The top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> marshalling support among
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> as it heads into another stare-down with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> over arms inspection
access. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the decision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> to make no further withdrawals
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> satisfy a series of "stringent"
conditions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the explosion in cable TV
rates, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with the news that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s rate of
inflation now stands at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32-year</TIMEX> low.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that for now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is, in the face of
the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> provocation--the blocking of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons search led by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Scott Ritter</ENAMEX>--opting for a cautious diplomatic path aimed at
orchestrating a condemnation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs
a profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ritter</ENAMEX> inside, revealing that he once rattled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Schwarzkopf</ENAMEX> by turning up evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> air campaign
had not destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile missile</ENAMEX> capabilities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> story features a top-of-the-page close-up photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ritter</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> top-front effort is accompanied by a wider-angle shot of him.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> just issued a report showing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> rates are rising at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times the rate of inflation and
that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and a few other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> are looking at
double-digit price increases. None of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> runs this story.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> have answering machines and that fully half of those use them to
screen incoming calls.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports on its front page that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic crisis is
affecting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thais</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX>, attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The piece has the example of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX> packing to go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> after getting a call from her mom
saying that the currency collapse had in effect doubled the cost of tuition. In
addition, states the paper, "Wealthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>
say their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have pleaded with them to tighten their belts or even sell
them, especially if they carry chic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> or DKNY labels."

            The WP front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX>'s interest in going back
into space on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> mission (first reported widely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>) is still being
seriously considered at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the answer will be no unless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> can produce a solid rationale. The decision about whether or not to
include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> on a flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this October</TIMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , could come
anytime.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post TV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX> takes a long backstage look at the meddling by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> that led to the firing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX> from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX>"'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Update</ENAMEX> anchor chair. Many people
quoted in the story seem puzzled by the new level of interference from the
suits. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possible explanation <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shales</ENAMEX> doesn't consider: Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> honcho and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson buddy Don Ohlmeyer</ENAMEX> wanted to punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX> for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>
gags he did on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/12</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" was mistaken when it credited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> with
breaking that story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> asking and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> telling about a possibly gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sailor</ENAMEX>. The reason for the error was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's shabby sourcing.
Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> didn't mention it, the story had already appeared in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> , and before that in the on-line version of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and (on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>) at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX>news.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and before that, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu Star</ENAMEX>-Bulletin , which--for now--should be credited with the
scoop. (Thanks to the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who helped fill out this backstory.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs a "talker" across the top of its front reporting that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Study Finds Highly Educated Have Less Sex</ENAMEX>." But the results, based on a survey
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, aren't quite so straightforwardly anti-intellectual. It turns
out that there's sort of a sexual bubble: while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've been to grad
school average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> sex acts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and those who've only been through high
school average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> after college average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>.

            Note: If most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another fifty years</TIMEX> after college and if college
costs a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $100,000</NUMEX>, then the additional sex achieved by
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> over their high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> is purchased at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi</ENAMEX>
Fleiss rates: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1,000</NUMEX> per.

         
      
   
