
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tooth</ENAMEX>(air)brush

Times lead with news on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial crisis from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pacific</ENAMEX> economic summit. Having led with that story for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> switches its lead to the corruption charges leveled at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ex-Teamsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with continuing scandals in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police department</ENAMEX>.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> give front-page play to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic crisis (and they
all call it a "crisis," except the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , which calls it "fiscal
turmoil.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> stories: Their lead says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> at
the summit vow action to limit the scope of the crisis. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> front-page
story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is concerned, but thinks it unlikely, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> could collapse the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>'s did. An analysis piece inside sees
the crisis as an affirmation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s economic power (parroting a piece in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> front-pagers: The lead says
summit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> want to reassure global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s stability; the other
story claims the public is pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to rescue its ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. The
WP front-pager reveals the plan for bailing out the troubled economies:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, too.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead tracks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX>'s mounting woes. A federally-appointed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> will bring corruption charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>, and he may be banned from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> for life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> all put the story on their front pages.
The charges stem from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s illegal diversion of "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$885,000</NUMEX>" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> to
his election campaign, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has "more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX>"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$735,000</NUMEX>"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> goes with "more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750,000</NUMEX>"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> has temporarily resigned the presidency to focus on his legal
problems.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead is essentially a long quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> on the prevalence of chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">weaponry</ENAMEX> in the world, and the
imminent dangers it could pose to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The WP trumps with an op-ed
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> himself.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> have front-page stories on a revised
estimation of the global <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> had "grossly underestimated"
the number of worldwide cases, which they now number at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30.6 million</NUMEX>, not the
previously thought <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">22.6 million</NUMEX>. (The overwhelming majority of cases are in
sub-Saharan <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts the story on page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A6</TIMEX>, but is the only
paper to offer this grabber of a stat: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> (of
reproductive age) is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> positive.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> catches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> in a bit of hypocrisy. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> cried foul when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> electronically darkened a
photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> on its cover. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> its
cover photo of septuplet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobbi McCaughey</ENAMEX>: It fixes her teeth. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's
concurrent cover, untouched, clearly shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCaughey</ENAMEX>'s (authentic) imperfect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">choppers; Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover shows straight and pearly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. To view the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cover images, see 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Other Magazines</ENAMEX>"
column.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> will take off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> in observance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX>. This
column gives thanks for each and every one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, and wishes each and
every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of you a wonderful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
