
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ironic or Irenic</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with a call by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> for a "dialogue" between his country
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with a report indicating that homelessness
and hunger are on the rise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with a report
on a rift developing among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> based on whether or not it's
okay to grant any sort of legal immunity to tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in return for
public health gains--just the sort of deal at the heart of the proposed
national tobacco settlement before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            The WP <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatemi</ENAMEX> made
the irenic remarks at a press conference, and described them as the most
conciliatory made by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
revolution there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khatemi</ENAMEX> said, "I declare my respects to the great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." True, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khatemi</ENAMEX> also said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> mistakenly
believes it is the sole world power, trying to "impose its will on the whole
world at any cost," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> official
responded by saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is ready to sit down and talk to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khatemi</ENAMEX>'s remarks are "authoritative." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead covers pretty much the same ground except that it
mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Khameni</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatemi</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s supreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>. But even the
Times could have elaborated on this to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> try to decide
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatemi</ENAMEX>'s statements are worth. The WP piece doesn't even mention
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khameni</ENAMEX> (although another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front pager, on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s loosening of
domestic social restrictions, especially on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, does so in
the course of an informative paragraph on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> power structure).

            Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> mentions as a possible Khatemi
motivation the desire for eliminating obstacles to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian-Sea</ENAMEX>-based oil deals
involving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> petroleum <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, now hamstrung by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Iranian</ENAMEX> sanctions.
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also have front-page coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khatemi</ENAMEX>'s
remarks.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead reports on a study just released by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Conference</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayors</ENAMEX>, which found that the demand for emergency food and housing increased
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 13th straight year</TIMEX>. Cited as factors are: increased substance
abuse and mental illness, the high cost of housing, low-paying jobs and
reductions in federal welfare and food stamps. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries this story
on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs a front-page feature reporting
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are responding to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
downturn by putting off opening up their financial and currency markets and
by overhauling the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. Plus, interest rates will probably
be cut by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year's end</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sandel</ENAMEX> puts some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed space
to good use <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with some useful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homely</ENAMEX> examples suggesting what's wrong with the emissions credit system
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is advocating as a significant element in its greenhouse gas control
approach. Turning pollution into a commodity to be bought and sold, he argues,
removes the moral stigma that is properly associated with it. A fine means
something a fee does not. If, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandel</ENAMEX> wonders, a busy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> used the
handicapped parking near his work site and willingly paid the fine as a simple
cost of business, isn't he still doing something wrong ?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> statistics,
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX> executions carried out thus far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> represent the highest number in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any one year</TIMEX> since capital
punishment was reinstated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> and the most in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four decades</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has had
the most dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> walking, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> placing a distance <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. All the executed
were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> convicted of murder: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> "other." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> executed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> had been on death row an average of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX>. Polling indicates, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , that the percentage of
those favoring the death penalty has nearly doubled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past thirty years</TIMEX>.
(This piece is by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lardner Jr.</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was murdered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.)

            
               Say it ain't so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs this headline: "Fraternity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> Among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heaviest College Drinkers</ENAMEX>, Study Shows."

         
      
   
