
   
   
      
         
            High <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel</ENAMEX>-ity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the growing economic crisis in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s
decision to oversee finances for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the possible resignation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C. Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> was caught leasing a luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> for less
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> its fair price (his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> they
needed the space for an undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads center on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
statements that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> must stabilize its economy to keep the whole region out
of crisis. After previously terming <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s economic woes "a few little glitches
in the road," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> now says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> market volatility should be taken "very
seriously." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> was the only paper to lead with the collapse of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamaichi</ENAMEX> brokerage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> give front-page play to
its aftermath: a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.5%</NUMEX> plummet in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> stock market. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs two
front-page stories--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> market, another reappraising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
economic model. In the first piece, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has the detail that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamaichi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> wept openly on television in announcing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s
collapse. The emotional display, especially rare in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, underscored the
starkness of the situation. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> piece, free-market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates crow</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s recent setbacks, claiming victory for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's front-page piece is more specific on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s words
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>: He suggests deregulation, avoiding cheap exports as a solution, and
strong governmental support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's lead says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> will again oversee the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>' spending practices--a setback for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had
begun supervising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, but ceased in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, soon after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> was elected as a purported <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>. Recent scandals necessitate renewed
scrutiny. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> put the story in small, front-page
boxes; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sends it back to the business section.

            A piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal Workweek</ENAMEX> section says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s becoming
a farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s economy, a microcosm of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's</ENAMEX>,
makes it a good "test-bed" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> currently head the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> units
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kraft</ENAMEX>. (No comment is offered on why women
need a foreign "test-bed" while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> can stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> run front-page stories on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s approval
of a new diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, sibutramine, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two months</TIMEX> after having banned diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redux</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pondimin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pondimin</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">fen-phen</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts the
story on page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A3</TIMEX>. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sibutramine</ENAMEX>'s side effects: headaches, dry mouth, and
possibly physical addiction.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> has a story on TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marti</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> propaganda
station that's beamed at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>'s televisions. TV <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> say the job
would be great if not for one thing: Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> blocks reception in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, very nearly no one is watching. This column suddenly appreciates its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> in a far more profound manner.

         
      
   
