
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roll</ENAMEX> Call

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S./U.N.</ENAMEX> reactions to the
continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> stand-off. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with congressional fast-track maneuvering. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the announcement of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> job cut.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> to put
enough pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to compel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> to give internal access once
again to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
is especially focused on getting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to stay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.
Meanwhile, says the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> made a statement on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> television that
appeared to be bucking up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> to continue the impasse.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is proceeding on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fronts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, he is making it
clear that military options are not off the table--"We will not," he said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s vow to shoot down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-piloted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">surveillance U-2s</ENAMEX>, "tolerate his efforts to murder our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>." And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, trying
to ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> maintains a united front against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> both report that the fast-track roll call
will probably take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> seemed unable
to persuade enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to vote his way and so the emphasis has
turned towards the hunt for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> votes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> predict the bill will pass.

            You have to sympathize a bit with the situation the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> are in with
fast-track. Fascinated by the bill's strange bedfellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of supporters
and convinced that a dramatic vote was imminent, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> started hitching
their leads to the vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of last week</TIMEX>, which meant that as the
vote kept not materializing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> were stuck in bed with a story that
wouldn't undress and was ugly anyway. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> didn't help themselves out
much--they could have been doing much more substantive reporting from the
outset about what sorts of trade agreements fast-track authority was likely to
spawn. Why, for instance, is there no mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX> in these
stories? The whole episode is a good example of the press's weakness for
covering the how of a political story over the why or the what.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> announced his plan
to cut <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of administrative jobs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> under pressure from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to reduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> before ordering cuts in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s plan could save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.
(That's only a little more than a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> cut.) The plan also includes
proposed base closings, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes, require congressional
approval and may not get it. And shades of the balanced budget deal, none of
the projected pain takes place until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is out of office. The WP
runs substantially the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> plan story on its front as well.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs a front-page feature about a
federal affirmative action program for female highway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> (the only one
that cites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as a disadvantaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>) and the backlash it has created
among black, male construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, who feel squeezed out of the trade by
it. Under the program, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s share of federal
highway funds has tripled. But meanwhile, the share going to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, the
program's original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>, plummeted. "The white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> of them are
fronts," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> quotes a black trucking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> as saying. Now
there's a move afoot in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to end the program, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports,
might well mean a lot of female <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcontractors</ENAMEX> will go bankrupt.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a front-page piece detailing how since returning to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX> has used <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $240,000</NUMEX> from a special
unaudited fund, generated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> hotel tax and political contributions,
for such goodies as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterford</ENAMEX> crystal wedding gift, a lavish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
party and extensive travel abroad. The story runs under the headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>
Used <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unaudited Funds For Gift, Parties and Travel</ENAMEX>." That's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">F6</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
keyboards.

         
      
   
