
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restless</ENAMEX>

            After a string of party-line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, news diversity breaks out. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>'s testy meeting with
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> emergency aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> designed to help bring financial
stability back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court decision that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> may sue their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> for injuries they
received in the womb from unsafe working conditions experienced by their moms.
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> lead is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">2nd</NUMEX> degree murder conviction returned against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">au pair Louise Woodward</ENAMEX> in the death of an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-month-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in her care. The
paper reports that when the verdict was returned, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>, wept
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hysterically</ENAMEX> and shouted, "I didn't do anything!"

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s closed-door congressional meeting had
the same rather tempestuous atmosphere as did his press conference with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> gave no <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> as he was asked by members
about forced abortions, harvesting of human organs from executed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>,
religious repression, foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> sales, jamming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> broadcasts and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s takeover of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> presented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> with lists of
political and religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> to be released. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX> tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
that there was no discussion about allegations of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> illegal campaign
contributions during the last election cycle.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says he replied by
saying he would hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> would greet him there alongside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>. The
LAT front-page account of all this depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> in a somewhat more
ironic light, quoting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> as saying that in his discussions with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>,
he saw "no defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>" of the sort the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> used to make. Yet
after the meeting, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> gave a defiant speech in
which he made no concessions about human rights in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> aid package lead fits the mold that so often
applies when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> decides to lead with an international finance
story--not only is the story not anybody else's lead, but it doesn't even make
any other major's front page.

            The top of the LAT front page features a large photo-and-graphic box
addressing the stepped-up rate of deportations by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> of illegal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 111,000</NUMEX>, an increase of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 60 percent</NUMEX> over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> before. Of those removed, says the paper, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX> had criminal records.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> spirit, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> will unveil a "horror stories of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>" web site.

            A piece inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> about the use of songs by law enforcement
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in hostage situations notes that the music used at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Koresh</ENAMEX> "was selected ad hoc from the personal cassettes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>."
There wasn't, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , exactly deep reasoning behind the
selections. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'These Boots Were Made for Walking</ENAMEX>,' for instance,
was intended to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koresh</ENAMEX> and others to walk out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>."

            Back to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision about fetal injuries: if the
Court is consistent, shouldn't we also expect to see decisions allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to
sue their moms for <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">prenatal smoking</ENAMEX>, drinking, and drugging?

         
      
   
