
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chicken Flew</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to abandon a
mental defect defense. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the decision by international
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> to delay debt repayments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with a guilty plea by the world's
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyson Foods</ENAMEX>, in a political corruption case.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead also reports on revelations that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> turned down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaczynski</ENAMEX>'s offer to plead guilty in return for a sentence
of life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, referring only to "published accounts." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> should
have given credit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which broke the story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> does give that credit in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaczynski</ENAMEX> story, carried inside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
but not until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> paragraph. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">C'mon people</ENAMEX>! Admit it up front: Sometimes
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> get there first.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story quotes a Kaczynski family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> asking what purpose
going for the death penalty serves "except to punish [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> for the
rest of his life." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also runs an editorial questioning the DOJ stance, as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . On the other hand, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> column in the
Post quotes badly injured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Unabomber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gerlernter</ENAMEX> saying, "I
would sentence him to death....If someone handed me a gun or showed me the
switch on the chair,...I would kill him myself."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> story reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> pleaded guilty to
giving former agriculture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,000</NUMEX> in illegal gratuities and
consented to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 million</NUMEX> in fines and costs. The gifts were given to Espy
while his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> was considering poultry-related actions that portended
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> in extra costs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>
account of the matter on p.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that as part of the deal, company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Tyson</ENAMEX>
and his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> were granted immunity from prosecution. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
doesn't make the point, but this is all too typical: Something abstract called
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>" is fined while the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> (think what that word
means: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get things done) go merrily along.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" received a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage emails</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> pointing out
an oops in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s column: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s gun control climate wasn't affected
by the Brady bill because it already had in place a much stricter
waiting-and-checking statute covering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">handgun</ENAMEX> purchases. Still, that waiting
period was increased in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> to its current <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 days</TIMEX> and it would be
worthwhile for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> to study and report on its
relationship to the homicide decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>

            In anticipation of congressional debate on the topic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>, the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> serves up a primer on the
marriage tax penalty--when married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> end up paying more in taxes than they
would if they each were single. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> explains that it's actually
a fairly nuanced topic. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, more married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> enjoy a marriage
bonus than suffer a marriage penalty (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51 percent to 42 percent</NUMEX>). For another,
it's hard to make any changes that don't create a huge drop in revenues and/or
even worse inequities: for instance, eliminating the marriage penalty
straight-out would simply lower the tax rates on most wealthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> who says that while not a primary
factor in deciding to get married, "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">A $500</NUMEX> increase in taxes decreases the
probability of marriage by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1% or 2%</NUMEX>," and quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who says she's just
living with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> despite their desire to marry because she doesn't
want to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,700</NUMEX>. On the one hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> like this are
thinking too much--isn't marriage to the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,700</NUMEX>?--and on the
other, they're not thinking enough. The odds are very good that if that woman
and her beau got married, they would buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> together and have at least one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kid</ENAMEX>, thereby putting a huge dent in their tax bill.

         
      
   
