
   
   
      
         
            Guystock

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the news that some insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are skirting the new law
that's supposed to guarantee available health coverage to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
who change jobs or who have pre-existing conditions. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> big-time.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> insurance story is dramatic proof of a gaping hole in last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy-Kassebaum</ENAMEX> bill, which was viewed at the time as taking the first
important step towards universal coverage: namely, the bill says insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have to extend coverage to those they had tended to cut off, but it
doesn't say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can't gouge them for it. (This is a feature <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
could have easily added. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> points out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has had
such a law since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.) For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design Benefit Plans</ENAMEX> charges <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX>
extra to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> purchasing policies under the new law, and the paper
quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Stark</ENAMEX> as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> in many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are charging
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with pre-existing conditions.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> rally is all-out--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pieces
on the front page and another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> inside. The lead story credits name <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> describes the event as one of the largest
gatherings ever in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital and one of the biggest religious
gatherings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s history, and says the crowd numbered "perhaps a
half-million <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." Although the official program was multi-racial and
multi-ethnic, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> were "overwhelmingly white,
reflecting the composition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> comments to the
paper that she was "surprised by how clean-cut and how educated" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Keepers</ENAMEX> were. "I guess," she adds, "that makes it even more scary."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> appeared to number "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well over half a million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" and that it "contained large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, as
well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> belonging to the Lesbian
Avengers, which has protested PK rallies across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, took off their
shirts and marched bare-breasted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bare</ENAMEX>
breasts are okay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX>."

            Lots of presidential sidebar stories <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>
dispatch revealing that a new biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> states that within days
of naming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> as his running mate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wrote in his diary: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It</ENAMEX>
was my decision, and I blew it, but I'm not about to say I blew it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> op-ed calling for the end of soft
money. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> takes a long look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimers disease</ENAMEX>.
According to the piece, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> handshake and barely gray hair
is steadily, surely ebbing away" and "appears to recognize few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> other
than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>." There's also the detail that one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physicians</ENAMEX> first suspected trouble when he had an odd conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September, 1992</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two years</TIMEX> before his condition was publicly
acknowledged.

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> while attending a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
demonstration at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> took the
wheel of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camaro</ENAMEX> and executed an evasive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX> degree turn. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evasive</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX>? Bet he
was good at it.

         
      
   
