
   
   
      
         
            Send in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clones</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposal to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> coverage leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and is the top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is aiming to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> available to
those retiring at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> and even to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> as young as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 55</TIMEX> who find themselves
without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> health insurance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> claims the expansion will
pay for itself through increased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says this represents
another incremental step toward providing health insurance to all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
part of the piecemeal strategy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> adopted after the failure of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> health care reform. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says it's the largest expansion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter century</TIMEX>, and notes that an enthusiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief lobbyist</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX>, dismisses cost-based objections by commenting that
until recently everybody thought there was a budget deficit too. (This is a
form of argument you can bet you will now hear again and again, in all sorts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contexts</ENAMEX>.)

            When everybody does the same story you get to compare headlines. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clearest</ENAMEX> and most succinct is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expand Medicare</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a top-of-the-front photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> of a massacre in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-lead gives some of the details:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX> are abandoning their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> to avoid the viscious attacks by Moslem
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> that have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>--on top of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 75,000</NUMEX> such murders since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incredibly</ENAMEX>, reports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have not yet traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> to look into this.

            The death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bono</ENAMEX> draws a surprising amount of coverage.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> dedicates its front section cover story to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX>, and both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> Bono stories apiece above their folds. Only
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> holds back, with only a small picture "reefer" to the inside on
its front bottom.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> calls Bono a "respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also states
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who "grew up with the comedy and singing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of 'Sonny
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX>'," credited Bono with an "astute perspective." In its second
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-page Bono</ENAMEX> piece, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> memorializes him as "one smart cookie"
capable of "piquant clarity." But in these pieces, examples do not abound. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> joins the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX>, saying that Bono "made his mark on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>."
With all due respect, what mark was that?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" notes that although the
Alternative Minimum Tax was originally designed to ensure that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">upper-income taxpayers</ENAMEX> fork over at least some tax, if it isn't changed in any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2007</TIMEX> it will apply to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.4 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>, including many in
the middle class.

            The USAT front reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist-entrepreneur</ENAMEX> has
raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> towards his goal of opening a
for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> that will clone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> from the genetic materials of
childless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>. His announced goal is to produce such a pregnancy within a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year and a half</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries this story inside.

            Coming on the heels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s death in a similar accident, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX>'s death prompts a number of pieces about skiing safety. Both the WP
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> stress that many serious skiing accidents occur in the late
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, with the LAT observing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was killed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:15 PM</TIMEX>,
Bono at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:30 PM</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> both note that despite these
dangers, far more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are killed bicycling. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes
that the use of ski helmets is on the rise. (Look for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy/Bono</ENAMEX> deaths
to spur much talk of mandatory ski helmet laws, and look for the same sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libertarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> that has marked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> helmet laws.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> apparently decided that enough time had passed to entitle it
to publish an article looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy/Bono</ENAMEX> deaths' lighter side, about
wacky fatalities caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
