
   
   
      
         
            The Things They Carried

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s refusal to let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
inspectors tour its presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with a story on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> spies
infiltrating a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial crisis is
further destabilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s already fragile economy.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads cover <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s about-face on inspections:
Having previously promised access to its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> now says access will be
denied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, and will be offered only to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> insists that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> must search the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>
before sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> are lifted. (On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> said there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">palaces</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, it says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>, offering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.) While
the story's the lead at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the WP front page has just a
"reefer" to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> article buried on page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A35</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> doesn't cover
the story at all. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts it in their World-Wide news
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">box.</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead exposes an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> ring in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>: A group of spies
has infiltrated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military training program for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croats</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hopes the program will help these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bosnians</ENAMEX> defend
themselves against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> can go home. The program
teaches the value of "secular, democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> wants to nullify
these teachings, and gain a foothold in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is aware of the infiltration, but unconcerned.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> article echoes the conventional wisdom taking hold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>:
The piece argues that the current fiscal turmoil in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> signals the victory of
the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy over the once-proud, authoritarian <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> system.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> had a nearly identical piece on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
parroted on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>--now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> falls in line.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> article tracks the resurgence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thalidomide</ENAMEX>.
Originally prescribed for morning sickness, the drug was banned in the 1960s
when it caused <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of birth defects. Now, it has proved successful in
treating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and some other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. Problem: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> are terrified (and
sometimes unwilling) to prescribe it for fertile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who, if on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>,
are required to be also on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> forms of birth control.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-lead follows up on their cover story from earlier in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>; clearly, they think it's something <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> care about deeply: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airlines</ENAMEX>,
emboldened by new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> guidelines, are cracking down on carry-on luggage.
Overcrowded cabins are unsafe, so some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> now limit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to one
carry-on bag, instead of the traditional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
