
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat Chance</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> mission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> continues to get big play, leading
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and topping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> worldwide news-digest box. The release
of official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> studies revealing widespread sexual harassment in the service
leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s passage of a national educational testing
plan.

            What's most interesting about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> story is the
amount of story-shaping on display. The same picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> shaking hands
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> accompanies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stories. It shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beaming</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> anything but. Which raises the question, was this really
the best picture they had or were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> trying to "say" something with
it? And although these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> all communicate the same basic
facts about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s events--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> responded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s demands by
promising full cooperation in the fight against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Israeli</ENAMEX> terrorism and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> was very cool toward her entreaties to him to cease land
confiscations, home demolitions, settlement building, confiscation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDs</ENAMEX> and
the embargoing of tax revenues belonging to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>--their
headlines differ in what they emphasize. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs its story under
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arafat Promises Albright a Steady Anti-Terror Effort</ENAMEX>," while the WP
uses "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Albright Urges Israeli Restraint</ENAMEX>" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs it under
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Albright Asks Israel To Take a 'Timeout' on Settlements</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s largest-ever investigation of
sexual misconduct in the ranks found that it was very widespread and that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> was to blame. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> concluded that most female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were unwilling to report instances of sexual misconduct out of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-founded</ENAMEX> fear that they, and not their harassers, would be punished. Both
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> stories quote statistics from the studies about
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> perceive the atmosphere they serve in, such as "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47 percent</NUMEX> of the
female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> polled reported that they had experienced 'unwanted sexual
attention,' " or "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> said they
had been sexually harassed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>." These are good examples of a
chronic newspaper gaffe: the uncontextual stat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> doesn't know what
such claims say about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> because he or she doesn't know the corresponding
numbers for the same claims in other lines of work. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> fail here
(as they often do) to provide them.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> treats this as purely a story about workplace gender bias.
For the most part, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> does the same until late in its piece when it
observes that the problems unearthed are "evidence of a larger breakdown of
trust between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>." It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> that recognizes this as the most
damaging detail, emphasizing it above all else in its headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soldiers Lack</ENAMEX>
Confidence in Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX>"--and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX> have deep misgivings about
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> and don't feel confident about following them into combat, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harsh Army</ENAMEX> report said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perhap</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s biggest story is nobody's lead--another in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's
series of investigative pieces on campaign fund raising. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX>'s effort
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Duffy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that they had credible intelligence indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
Sioeng, a prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>, acted on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to
influence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election races via illegal campaign contributions.

            The fronts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> bring news of a
government report saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> deaths dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and that
the disease is no longer the No. 1 cause of death among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 25-44</TIMEX>,
as it had been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous two years</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Highway Traffic</ENAMEX>
Safety <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> "advises its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> not to comment on inquiries about
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> could have survived her car crash if she had worn a seat
belt."

         
      
   
