
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Exercise Program</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, everybody had the same lead--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, nobody does. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with a major new comparative study of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' life spans. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>'s acceptance of the largest international economic
rescue ever, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55 billion</NUMEX> bailout engineered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX>'s decision to make its
largest single capital investment ever, in the form of a new computer chip
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead is a survey suggesting that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> with medical insurance had a problem with their
health plan, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> who reported denials or delays in
getting treatment, which often made their medical conditions worse.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's longevity study lead reveals that the gap between the longest
and shortest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lifespans--where life expectancy can vary by as much as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> to another--is about as big as that found between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> with the longest and shortest lifespans. For instance, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> woman
living in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>, can expect to live for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96 years</TIMEX>, while the average
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, lives to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 58</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> finds the results incredible, adding that they will probably serve as a
blueprint for research into disease and urban violence.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a front-page piece driving home the study's applications
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> region, noting that it reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have
nearly the shortest life span in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> just across the Potomac
in suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> have nearly the longest--a difference of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14.5 years</TIMEX>. Not
surprisingly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> quoted pins the difference on economic status--in
other words, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>'s only going to make things worse.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains in its lead that in return for the bailout money
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> and such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> will have to cut
public spending, open its market up to more foreign goods and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and put
growth constraints on its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate industries</ENAMEX>. All of which, says the
Times , could be very good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> (that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> number; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and USAT
say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX>) gathered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottawa</ENAMEX> to sign a comprehensive land mine ban.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> was the most conspicuous non-signer. As you'd expect, the story is
front-page news at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts it on p. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> give front-page coverage (with pictures)
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> meeting on race, held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>. And
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> give a lot of ink to an exchange between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and Abigail
Thernstrom, a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of affirmative action. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, on his feet,
"towering" over the seated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thernstrom</ENAMEX>, asked her if she favored the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>
abolishing the affirmative action program that "produced" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> version makes it look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thernstrom</ENAMEX> didn't respond very clearly.
want <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to be treated as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Business Bulletin" reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Microfilms</ENAMEX>, long the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s main repository for doctoral
dissertations, has now made them available on the Web. Which means, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , you are but a few clicks away from reading the Ph.D. theses of
the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX>. But not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s--he asked that his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers on Economic Theory and Policy</ENAMEX>" not be
made available.

            Back to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead about health plan problems: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX> who
probably doesn't have these difficulties is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poohbah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>, who,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> in a nearby front-pager, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> had the single biggest
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payday</ENAMEX> in history when he exercised stock options bringing in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$565</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. A little perspective on that sum: it could pay the salaries of every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a decade</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
