
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisneros</ENAMEX> and Aphrodite

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s order that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> must, at least temporarily, stop bundling its Internet browser with
its Windows operating system. This is also the top national story at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes instead with a look at the coming debate over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> greenhouse
protocol.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> describes the federal court decision as "a major blow" to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and "a big victory" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>. The decision not only
applies to current versions of the software programs but could also hinder the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> and marketing of new versions set to roll out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> also made another ruling that gets less attention: he refused to order
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to stop asking business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> to sign "non-disclosure" provisions
that require notifying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> when passing information along to the
government. His reason: there is no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> is using the provision to
prevent signatories from speaking to government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> it
would not submit the proposed global warming treaty for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> ratification
until developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> agree to participate in its restrictions, something
these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> refused to do at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> until they see developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cut their own emissions <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. Perceptions of the treaty's softness on
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , have already prompted many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> to
come out against it.

            In politics, what could be worse than having your cold, dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ass</ENAMEX> dug up from
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arlington Cemetery</ENAMEX> when it's discovered that your tombstone there is full of
lies? Well, maybe it's being indicted for lying along with your ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>.
Anyway, the front pages at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the WP
report that this is exactly what's befallen former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton HUD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisneros</ENAMEX>. The indictment charges that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was choosing his first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cabinet, Cisneros</ENAMEX> lied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> conducting the requisite routine
background investigation, saying that he had stopped paying money to an
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>. But the money, alleges the indictment, wasn't for support but for
silence and the payments continued. The papers all mention that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ex-Cisneros</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are indicted too, but it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that makes it
clear why: the charge is that they also lied to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> about the
financial arrangements with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, in hopes of securing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> jobs for
themselves.

            For those who persist in arguing that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> need salary increases,
please note that according to the indictment, somehow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cisneros</ENAMEX> was able to
scrape together a quarter of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs an interesting front-pager on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic turmoil's impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. The piece points out that
it depends on the business--the best situation is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagate</ENAMEX>, who have a lot of production <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in the
troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, but sell mostly to other, healthier regions. The worst is
the reverse: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Materials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAM Research</ENAMEX>, which make
products in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for sale in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>.

            
               USAT repeats <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Adams</ENAMEX>'s account in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> of her
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> getting thrown out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Club</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Adams</ENAMEX>
says it might have been because she was talking on a cell phone and because she
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX> were spritzing each other with her new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">perfume</ENAMEX>. (How it must
have pained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>'s sense of journalistic integrity to have to mention the name
of that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">perfume</ENAMEX> in her column.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's account doesn't mention the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phoning</ENAMEX> and the spritzing, which makes the whole episode utterly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incomprehensible</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has sent a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> card to just about every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>.
In case you were wondering if it was wise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to spend all that money on
just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, don't worry--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> paid for
the leafleting. Isn't this exactly the sort of soft-money-for-hard-purposes
shenanigans that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s just dodged a bullet over?

            In a long WP profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldo Rivera</ENAMEX> , prompted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX>'s
new lush contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX>, which he hopes to use to ride back into teevee
news respectability, he's quoted saying, "I would debate with anyone, on any of
the meaningful issues of our day--with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
Moyers, all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are always kissing their [expletive]. I
happen to be one of the most educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in television. Not only am I <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>,
but I have had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> fellowships!" Yeah, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Moyers</ENAMEX> never did a
show where he had some of his butt cells transplanted into his face.

         
      
   
