
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, They've Shrunk the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Op-Ed Page</ENAMEX>!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the latest maneuverings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unabomber</ENAMEX> case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with a new push to train <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> for
computer-related jobs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> effort to turn
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> economy. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the cold snap that has left the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of</NUMEX>
downed power lines.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that after the chaos in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomb</ENAMEX> trial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were considering a new offer from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Kacszynski</ENAMEX> that
would, if accepted, deliver him from the death penalty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
reports that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the weekend</TIMEX>, the new plea deal had been rejected.
The story doesn't reveal until its eleventh paragraph that the new round of
negotiations was first reported by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> defend this suppression practice on the grounds that such sourcing
issues are only of interest to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, and not the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>.
Well, if this were a good argument, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> shouldn't use bylines
either (general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> hardly ever notice them), or at least should put them
in the eleventh paragraph.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which credits (sister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> paragraph of its inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX> story, treats the new round of
negotiations as still open.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s computer
training effort will include <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> in grants to fund educational
programs, an Internet job bank and a campaign to glamorize computer-related
professions. The campaign's goal, says the paper, is to remove the "nerd"
stigma from the computer profession. (This is probably cheaper than actually
removing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead reports that a high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s mission to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> has the goal of meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to persuade him
to carry out the economic reforms mandated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> rescue
story is also carried on the WP front and inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . The
further weakening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> currency is covered on the USAT
front.

            
               Don't ask, don't type. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> breaks an astounding story inside about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> is attempting
to dimiss a sailor for homosexuality because his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> profile, which doesn't use
his last name, states that he's gay. Apparently, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> to identify the profilee, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> supplied the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s name. (Which is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX>! No relation.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's main "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece
points to an emerging health care issue: given the increasing degree to which
HMOs make medical decisions, should they continue to enjoy limited liability
protection against malpractice? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has
already passed a law eliminating that protection, and that the bill's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> are being consulted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> elsewhere.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> inclined to think of prostitution as a victimless crime are
encouraged to read the first-rate piece about the international flesh market by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Specter</ENAMEX> on
the front of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX> reveals that the latest trend is
Slavic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who are lured by false ads from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> in great numbers to
such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> where whoremasters confiscate their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">passports</ENAMEX> and work them until they are arrested and deported. Complainers have
been known to be thrown out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> or beheaded.

            One linguistic quibble: the piece revives the old-fashioned term "white
slave trade," which brings with it an unnecessary implication that slavery is a
special insult to white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Far better to go with "sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> opinion page is defaced by another of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
patented unfunny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> tryout <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX>--this time by miniature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moranis</ENAMEX>. It's something about a future <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> where gambling is king and
apparently every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> reference gets big laughs. Wouldn't you love to be a fly
on the wall when these pieces get assigned? Who calls whom? And why?

         
      
   
