
   
   
      
         
            Hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Video</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s attempt to resolve the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> crisis via diplomacy leads at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . A big bank merger leads at the New York
Times .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX> met in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Premier</ENAMEX> and emerged to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has "a program" to resolve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>
showdown with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> that will allow weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> to return to their work
there. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , are keeping their distance
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">demarche</ENAMEX> while sending more warplanes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>.
What's in it for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>? Well, there's superpower envy, of course, but also,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> suggests, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> would like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to be in a position to pay
back some of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> it still owes from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of military sponsorship, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> is also interested in developing some of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s oil resources.

            Lest anyone lose sight of what this is all about, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LAT</ENAMEX> states that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> "has enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> and biological weapons to wipe out infantry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divisions</ENAMEX>, if not whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>." (Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>: when you refer to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX>, say how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that is--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">somewhere between 10,000 and 20,000</NUMEX>.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> haven't been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and don't know.) And a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed
piece tells a likewise cautionary tale about nukes, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has
arrived at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scud-</ENAMEX>launchable atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> design and that to make it work,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> only needs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> pounds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">enriched uranium</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead throbs over the imminent convergence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Union</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corestates Financial Corp.</ENAMEX> The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17.1 billion</NUMEX> transaction, would,
notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , be the biggest bank deal ever. And, the paper adds, it
would leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s first banking capital, without a major
bank that calls it home." The bathos of this sentence and the placement of the
story--a lead nobody else but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> even has on the front page--is a
reminder of the penchant the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has for overplaying money.

            In its "talker" position across the top front, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> puts the news
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> held a press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in which it explained at length
why it does not believe the crash of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> involved a crime. The story also
gets front-page play at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . But the
nature of that coverage varies considerably: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's piece dominates
the top front via the use of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> color shots from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> video the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
presented, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs it as a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two-inch square</NUMEX> box "reefer" well
below the fold.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial praises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> for letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in on
its reasoning--rather than, as it so often has in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> (like at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> for
instance), simply saying, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX> trust us, we're the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>.

            There are front-page wrap-ups of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> horror at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . The big news there is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s largest
fundamentalist terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> has claimed credit for the atrocity, saying that
it was undertaken to seize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> to trade for the cleric imprisoned in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> for plotting to blow up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> landmarks.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>'s TV
commercial urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to cut back on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas materialism</TIMEX> by participating
in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Buy Nothing Day</ENAMEX>" has been rejected by the major broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> (it has
been accepted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, for instance, rejected the ad on the grounds that
such an event is "in opposition to the current economic policy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
