
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay there we go so do you play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		okay great
 		yeah i do i'm a player i i'm kind of embarrassed i'm talking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> cause i'm sure that you are you play a lot more than i do oh really
 	
 	
 		actually i don't no uh i uh when i was younger i played a little bit and i was horrible  so i just stopped playing
 	
 	
 		oh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is is a very good golfer he's got like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> handicap
 	
 	
 		wow that is real good
 	
 	
 		so um and he's been playing since we we've been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two years</TIMEX>
 		so i had to start playing because he was you know such an avid golfer
 		so i've been playing now well i have had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> you know but but i really enjoy it so i i had to check that you know and and uh and uh talk about it well have you played recently
 	
 	
 		wow so you've been playing
 		no actually i don't even know if i checked that or not to be perfectly honest um  it seems to have been a mistake i don't know um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh that's okay
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't played in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> um when i was
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five or six years ago</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> who plays every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then took me out with him and and i basically um i had a horrible slice or hook i forget which one it was it wound up tossing the ball into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> virtually every time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah the slice goes to the right and the hook goes to the left i think
 	
 	
 		yes i was slicing actually and as it turns out uh i went and took some lessons for a while because i just i would lose so many balls and it uh make it a horrible time for everybody i went and took some lessons and i got a little bit better but i still but then i sort of
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know time you know went went back to school and didn't have time and this and that and and the only thing i do now is i occasionally go out to a driving range and hit a couple of balls and see what i can do and i
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's really a good thing to do so where are you in your life i mean are you in school oh okay at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Rochester</ENAMEX> oh great
 	
 	
 		and i still have this slice
 		i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yes as a matter of fact um so i don't have time to do much else except for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> work
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so i so i hang around this way and uh occasionally uh uh a bunch of us i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who are pretty avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers golfers</ENAMEX> so we'll go out and we'll uh we'll we'll play you know um
 	
 	
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and you don't have the time you don't have the length of the playing time that we do
 	
 	
 		no i have i have very little at the moment i have very little playing time when i when i go on vacation my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and i uh play a little bit but i don't you know we play a par a par <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three nine</NUMEX> hole course is because
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh that's my favorite kind to play because uh for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> it's really nice to play a
 	
 	
 		yeah my
 	
 	
 		a par three <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> because that's my i can't hit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> very far and in fact i don't even like to use a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> i use a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three iron</NUMEX> off the tee because i have more control over it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i can i can just have better contact with the ball that way so i'm still using a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three iron</NUMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> trying to get me into using a you know like a high number <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> instead
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right but those are uh still not your favorite huh
 	
 	
 		no it's not my favorite but i i uh i enjoy i i really do i think i'm going to like golf the the older i get and the more time i have to play i we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh wow so so you must be very busy
 	
 	
 		one is uh yeah yeah i'm very busy i have a part time job and and during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> i don't play much golf but i'm when i'm we're on vacation i love to play just like you said
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh we got to play in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterrey</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> uh right you know along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past spring</TIMEX> and that was i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that was the way to play you know that was  i would if i could play there every time i want it was it was great
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		really a a neat experience
 	
 	
 		miniature golf there's my game uh miniature golf there you go putt putt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">miniature golf</ENAMEX> is great yes  well that's the thing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like to do that with you know on dates and stuff but golf is um we we we probably are talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> because i did check it you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 		i don't i don't i don't know i may have actually i may have just checked random things i don't i don't recall anymore
 	
 	
 		well yeah if you ever played i mean i feel like anybody that's ever played golf can talk about it and maybe if you can even talk about it if you've if you've um watched it on TV
 	
 	
 		right yeah we actually we have a very very um we had the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah tell me about your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> up there what
 	
 	
 		well we had i haven't played around here too much we have a very good one called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Locust Hill</ENAMEX> though
 		there uh the L yes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPGA</ENAMEX> comes here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester International</ENAMEX> and then we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGA</ENAMEX> actually a very big PGA uh tour stop here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locust Hill</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh right
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		and it actually um they say the the i haven't played the course but they say the course is very is is is pretty tough pretty challenging
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's um not only that but it's exceedingly well kept apparently because
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		those those are the comments i kept hearing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> you know they kept saying you know we we hear  you know on on television so granted that it is biased but they keep saying it's just wonderful uh the course is so well maintained and you know it it it rained through half the um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		tournament so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had to finish it down and stuff but they still the grounds keepers were absolutely wonderful about getting things back up again and this actually when when the um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPGA</ENAMEX> came here i guess that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half ago</TIMEX> it was just it it takes over the whole town you know it's all over the news and lots and lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take off work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh sure yes
 		yeah to go and watch them yeah
 	
 	
 		to go to go and watch the the uh the ladies play so i mean i think it's actually wonderful to see
 	
 	
 		the ladies
 		yeah i'm sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> love golf up there like they do down here i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> is just it's just the coming thing i mean a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just crazy about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it seems to be it seems that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really you know either um either you haven't played it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or or you you've played it and you sort of stink like me and you sort of play every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> or you
 	
 	
 		well it's it's just such a difficult thing i mean it's i just i watch my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and he's he was a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> he he's a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> and he's got the coordination that God given coordination and he just struggles
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know all the time to um to master this game
 	
 	
 		yeah well same here i mean i'm a brown belt in karate at this point in time and uh and and i can't and i can't hit a golf ball  you know i
 	
 	
 		oh my really
 		yeah because it well i watch my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> swing and his swing you know when i compare to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> is so it's ridged it's like he's trying so hard it's not that flowing movement you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right that's because he's probably doing what i do worrying about is my head straight is my arm right is this correct am i holding correctly stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		or if how how far he's going to hit it i think you know and i worry about that you know oh i've just got to get this drive you know really far i've got to hit it a nd then so yeah well that that's interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah oh yeah
 		yeah yeah i have this nasty habit of doing things like either turning my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last second</TIMEX> or or just keeping my arm wrong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> or
 		yeah turning your head is probably the most common thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> they say you know you are always so anxious to see where it goes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		is it
 		right ex actly exactly it's just like i i don't watch the ball die i have to it took me a long time to learn to wait until the ball was in the air before i looked up
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i have to do that especially even more so with a short iron than a long iron you know than with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> or something because those short irons it's just you want to look up
 	
 	
 		oh on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because you are getting close to the green and you want to hit the green and you know that's why yeah so
 	
 	
 		it depends on where it's going that that is certainly true thank you
 	
 	
 		can i don't know whether i'm supposed to ask questions about i'm not supposed to ask questions about this whole procedure i know that i i well when i
 	
 	
 		that's okay go ahead i it's no big deal
 	
 	
 		do you get get um reimbursed for the calls you make or the calls you talk on too both okay okay well i really didn't know so i was just
 	
 	
 		both
 		i believe so
 		i i i actually don't know i get sort of random reimbursement every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> and don't really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		don't really figure it out i mean until afterwards
 	
 	
 		okay because this is only my second day doing it and i just didn't i didn't know and that was the detail yeah we i just started yesterday
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		i've been doing this for awhile actually and it seems like it's been a while and they just i just get these random checks in the mail every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i both do it as a matter of fact
 	
 	
 		have you oh good yeah i haven't
 		i see
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and we both just sort of get these random checks in the mail and to be honest i i really have not been accounting i just sort of figured well it's going to work you know if it works it works so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well my uh
 		
 		
 	