
 
     		
 	
 		on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s side we've really there uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> normally have a reunion do you have one that's been
 	
 	
 		on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s side we've really there uh on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side we've had several not it's not really on a regular basis but usually sometimes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every few summers</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well see all the family lives in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">place</ENAMEX> except for
 		a few of us that are scattered about so they're pretty much just reunited always so it's it's
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just once in a while we get the special gathering with everyone together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it might be a good time for you to begin to to start a tradition you could be responsible for that yourself
 	
 	
 		i know that's
 		they do that that's true how about your family
 	
 	
 		sure
 		well in my family
 		let's see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last October</TIMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">forty fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> uh reunion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first Sunday</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> gets together
 	
 	
 		wow you're a pro at this
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		and all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">descendants of the Civil War</ENAMEX> i mean yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> veteran come together and they come as far away as from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and there's usually
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between a hundred</NUMEX> and fifty and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred and fifty</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		and then where do you meet
 	
 	
 		in uh there's a big community hall in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vernon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and uh that seems to be sort of a middle ground for all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> family
 	
 	
 		okay do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vernon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then okay
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh a lot of the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vernon</ENAMEX> um all of his direct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants descendants</ENAMEX> have now died and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> are in their seventies and eighties
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so we're talking about <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great children</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i take my boys
 		well i took them up till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they're grown and gone from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> now so they take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh let's see that would make them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather great grandfather great great grandfather</ENAMEX> okay so it would be the second great grandchild
 	
 	
 		okay so this town hall that you meet in is that like a um
 	
 	
 		it's uh
 		well it's a community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> it's a community hall it's a great big open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that has a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh you just bring the covered dishes every every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> brings a a dish of some kind and you get all the wonderful old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> recipes that have been handed down for years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato salad</ENAMEX> and the
 	
 	
 		well we try to stay away from those things which might have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">salmonella</ENAMEX> in them
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		and we choose to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">congealed salad</ENAMEX> you can bring a congealed vegetable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato salad</ENAMEX> and we are very conscious of most of us are very conscious of of uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		sanitation aspects whatever you've got to carry for any distance i always take home baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		huh
 		oh that's nice
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		uh that happens to be my specialty for that family i do other things very well but there are others in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who do them better
 	
 	
 		do they always have  the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who knows or everyone thinks they know how to make this the best and that's what they get to cook
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's good well i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> in anthropology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> who studied family reunions so i learned a lot about them i haven't been to a lot but we talked a lot about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rituals</TIMEX> you she equated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> pilgrimage it was it was an interesting theory she talked about the um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> all it's a home centered you know it's all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> centered anyway so you usually are living where your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live and it's all your you don't have to come home so the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> would make a pilgrimage in older <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 		but when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> ethic happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who ever went out and you know went away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to seek their fortune and then had to come back home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the reunion so that became their version of the pilgrimage
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but she had it was interesting you know i  don't know how valid it is but she talked about that and how the the big picnic table was the symbolic communion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gathering together and
 		um you know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and the ritual placement do you have a a certain way that everything's
 		placed out on the table <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every every year</TIMEX> is there kind of a you know salads go <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		well it's uh we have uh uh kind of a core <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that that serves as quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and they plan the reunions they
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		organize the you know who is going to see to it that the coffee pot gets there who's going to rent the tables who's going to see to it that the silverware gets turned back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caterer</ENAMEX> uh and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> it's done a little bit differently because different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> serve in those roles
 	
 	
 		that's pretty fancy
 	
 	
 		we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> who who continues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> to save clippings on any family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> and they're entered into a a wonderful uh scrap book
 		and pictures of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been added and and obituaries to those who are gone And it keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> alive even you know even though it's very fluid and they're very dedicated to that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> does that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		it's been really wonderful it helps you hang on to your roots
 	
 	
 		yeah i wish we'd
 	
 	
 		and it helps you feel a strong sense of belonging my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> on the other hand was not very close to his family his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was very scattered and very diverse
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i asked him i got to talking to him i said well how is his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> doing well i don't know i haven't talked to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> well how's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> doing i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> keeps in touch with him i think but i don't i said hey wouldn't you like to know what's happening with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> yeah but i'm you know it's too much trouble
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i got busy got together and put a reunion together for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and succeeded in getting all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and all of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> but one
 	
 	
 		wow you're just uh
 		oh that's incredible
 	
 	
 		to our place down at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Tawakoni</ENAMEX> liked to kill me because i had it was i didn't have that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> cooperation i did it by myself
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh nobody brought covered dishes we had a great big <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fry</ENAMEX> and you know i fixed a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> in a number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> tub and  and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it was an enormous task to bring all of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one or two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> helping and uh we had to provide sleeping arrangements for all of them and i told him
 	
 	
 		have you have you done this repetitively or just once
 	
 	
 		we did it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following summer</TIMEX> we did not have all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there we sent invitations we said please let us know if you're coming it was when uh his mother his
 		step <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> before his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was alone and so they came to support her and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by one his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> you know his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> he began to lose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> members
 	
 	
 		see that's we've we had a problem with that
 	
 	
 		and it was difficult to hold them together and then of course he died t wo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> so
 		and you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has gone down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh it i think that's what happens when they get scattered the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> unit
 		you know falls into disrepair
 	
 	
 		right that's what was our problem we had uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> reunion or the first you know major reunion was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven years ago</TIMEX> and then the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> reunion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who maybe you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sacrifice things to come to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one though oh well it's not that big a thing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and so it kind of wound down and then finally
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're lucky to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shreveport</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> there but no one else
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well see we manage those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are at that core <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> manage to keep keep the vigor alive they'll send out news bulletins <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> you'll get a news bulletin hey guess who got
 	
 	
 		shows up
 	
 	
 		you know elected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> or guess who's our local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	