
 
     		
 	
 		okay i guess we're ready to go uh what are your favorite types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		we enjoy uh various types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> uh there's some excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> here there's some good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cajun</ENAMEX> cooking of course there's always steak
 	
 	
 		and barbecue right
 	
 	
 		and barbecue right
 	
 	
 		uh do you eat out quite frequently
 	
 	
 		oh not as  much as we used to but uh still at least about once a week
 	
 	
 		really and where's the last place that you went to eat
 	
 	
 		let's see we ate at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana Purchase</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> just recently we had a craving for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> and uh they have some good catfish there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we enjoy there's an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> also called Taste of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> i don't know if you've tried any of those there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> of them around town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		but it's good home style <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> cooking it's not the fancy veal and things that you get at some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they make excellent spaghetti <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> and little garlic rolls and things like that
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i also recently we had Jacolya out at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> cajun cooking
 	
 	
 		okay uh what areas do you usually eat in do you find
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> area we live out near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richardson Square Mall</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so it generally in that north side of town
 	
 	
 		do you ever get down to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Elm</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes there's an excellent uh i guess it's Tai it's one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast Asian</ENAMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Elm uh West Wind or</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've heard of that i've heard several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say that so it must really be i think it's part <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes i believe so i am really not sure exactly what style it is but it's very very good
 		now right in the edge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> there at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skillman</ENAMEX> just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> there's another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Yoli's Y O L I</ENAMEX> S
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		which uh serves some excellent food too in that in that style of food
 	
 	
 		so what would
 	
 	
 		it's not a fancy place i've eaten their lunch primarily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh  um</ENAMEX> so what is your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's hard to say but the ones that we like most are out of business now but
 	
 	
 		unfortunately everyone else didn't like them quite as well right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um
 		right but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Papillon</ENAMEX> is one we go back to quite frequently for uh continental style cooking
 	
 	
 		we haven't tried that one i uh we belong to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Passbook uh Club</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		and so we tend to use their coupons whenever possible and i know that's in there and i'd like to get over there
 	
 	
 		i think you would enjoy it it's a tad on the expensive side uh probably run uh with dinner and uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five thirty</TIMEX> dollars a person
 	
 	
 		well when you have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> price coupon it's not quite so bad then
 	
 	
 		it helps quite a bit right yes we have used some of the coupons also at some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that is i think one of our favorite our our most most favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> was LaLouve which was here on uh in north just off of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Expressway</ENAMEX> in north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but that's been gone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh well it's just a shame all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that you know open and close you seems you go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and find one that's your favorite and the next thing you know it's gone
 	
 	
 		it's gone right it's
 	
 	
 		well i heard that there are more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> per capita in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> than there are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that doesn't surprise me
 	
 	
 		i know it's they're everywhere <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> eat out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> like i have never seen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well we we've enjoyed it the there've been some excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> here through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and of course some go up some go down and uh it just depends on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> in some cases of course
 	
 	
 		yes
 		have you been to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bryan</ENAMEX>'s down in uh uh West the West End
 	
 	
 		no i haven't uh haven't been to that one
 	
 	
 		well i have not been to the old one for that matter but i thought that since there's a new one opening perhaps it'd be easier to get into
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well again the the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bryan</ENAMEX>'s up there by uh what is it by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist Hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is it like over on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemmon</ENAMEX> or something okay
 	
 	
 		up on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inwood</ENAMEX> uh yeah that one is not really it's it's it's a it's a barbecue stand really it's not really a restaurant
 	
 	
 		well that's what i understand you sit at school tables or out on the hood of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and um-hum
 	
 	
 		that's right they make some really good barbecue there
 	
 	
 		well that's fine for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> but i don't think i'd be too interested in the winter
 	
 	
 		right
 		but uh i used to live work over on just off of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stemmons</ENAMEX> and we'd go over there about once a week for barbecue for lunch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		there's uh oh there's
 		a lots of good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> here i think the really hard thing is you want fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> of course uh we're a little bit away from the coast not as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> so believe me it was harder to get in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> than it is here
 	
 	
 		you're right yeah yeah
 		but uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> just all around good eating seafood <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent</ENAMEX>'s has some really good seafood
 	
 	
 		you know i go by that place all the time over on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well there's several there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> one on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX> there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love Field</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> of them here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and we've gone to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX> and also to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> matter of fact let's see we were there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on Plano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we'll have to try that sometime because uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you'd really enjoy it
 	
 	
 		well we went to or i i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kacoos</ENAMEX> for lunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and i've heard good and bad about that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Guide</ENAMEX> always reviews it very poorly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but what i had and then uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i went to lunch with they both let me taste what they had and it was delicious
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we had dinner there we have a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> we go out once a month with and we had dinner at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kacoos</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we were there and it was excellent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> that we were there
 	
 	
 		well you know how these restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i think their tastes are jaded
 	
 	
 		it depends on whether they got  the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i guess we probably have talked about our <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> worth
 	
 	
 		i think we have i certainly enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well and i've also written down the Taste of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> we'll have to try that sometime
 	
 	
 		uh you'll have to try it don't expect anything fancy
 	
 	
 		that's all right with me
 	
 	
 		it's home style food it's not expensive and uh get the dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> with the olives on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and do they have good lasagna
 	
 	
 		so
 		yes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> swears by the lasagna
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay okay okay because that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s favorite
 	
 	
 		yeah they have excellent lasagna and if you get like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spaghetti</ENAMEX> with uh get with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> sausage it taste like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> sausage you'd get in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		thanks for the tip  bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thank you bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	