
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i guess we're supposed to talk about music
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh let me go ahead and push <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here
 		
 
 		uh do you have are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> yourself
 	
 	
 		uh well i sing i don't play an instrument though
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh where do you sing in in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> or a choral group
 	
 	
 		oh not right now
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what kind of singing do you like to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh pretty much anything
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh Um are you uh are are have you have you been singing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> or have you studied uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah a long time out all through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and everything i was in the choirs
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i've had some classical vocal training um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh great did did you do that in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or somewhere else
 	
 	
 		no i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh whereabouts
 	
 	
 		in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh that's wonderful um well i likewise sang in high school and in college in choirs and
 		then i didn't sing in a choral group um until after i was uh married and i sang in a couple of uh community choirs and then  um
 		waited for a while and now i've for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the last eight years</TIMEX> i've sung in a church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i i enjoy just the chorals singing a lot as well Um are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soprano alto</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">soprano</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soprano</ENAMEX> yeah so am i do you and uh what kind of music do you like to sing um you were saying you had classical training do you have a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> that you like or a particular type
 	
 	
 		oh well as far as opera goes i'm i think most fond of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verdi</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i've been listening to um some um some advertisements for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Madam Butterfly</ENAMEX> and i'm wondering if you if you have ever done anything like that have you ever done any uh if if you had done <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madam Butterfly</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no i haven't done um
 		i'd love to but
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um that's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puccini</ENAMEX> i think right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yes uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Madam Butterfly</ENAMEX> was um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years ago</TIMEX> now and then i went to see that and it was really wonderful it was particularly well the acting was particularly nice i thought and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it was quite popular um you don't play um an instrument so ah
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		uh um have you ever wanted to like guitar or piano or
 	
 	
 		uh i think it would be nice if i played the piano
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that i think that's always a good instrument for anybody who sings or does you know some other kind of instrument i think piano is always good background beginner Um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i played piano all through well i guess from the time i was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five five</NUMEX> until i graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and uh then i was a piano <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> for a while while my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so um
 		that was the instrument both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> started on but neither of them stayed with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them um turned into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">violinist</ENAMEX> and the other one is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is um guitar and and percussion so um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the i i think that the piano background is very um useful and um i'm sure that it for you it would have been great to be able to accompany yourself just for practicing and so on
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you have any other kind of music that you like
 	
 	
 		um oh i like to listen to all different kinds of music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i have a i used to work with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who had um although this was a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> he had his uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> in musical uh i guess it was in composition actually from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of North Texas</ENAMEX> and uh
 		when i would go into his his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now</TIMEX> and then you never knew what kind of music he'd be playing on the radio
 		It may be country it might be classical it might be rock you know it was just he said that that just about what you said that he just liked all kinds of music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that was that was neat for for me to hear that somebody is
 	
 	
 		there's you know some of the really totally country stuff i don't really particularly like but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		um do you have any plans to uh do anything with your music in the near future or
 	
 	
 		well i have i have like we i wish i could but i i don't really know how to go about it without having a degree or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i know that there are if you're interested in choral singing i'm not sure where you are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but i do know that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> have uh
 		uh community choruses and uh that's often a good way to get back into it again um it's not really terribly demanding you might have to audition but that probably wouldn't be a problem but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there usually you know that they take <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tours</ENAMEX> and things like that and you get to know you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um socially as well as as in a musical setting so that's always fun i think that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why i have enjoyed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> so much is that not only do we sing wonderful music but we've gotten to know each other quite well um
 		in on a a social level and i think we sing better because of that i think you know i think we sing more like uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who trust each other  which is really nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so whereabouts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are you if i could ask
 	
 	
 		oh i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flower Mound uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower Mound</ENAMEX> okay well i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> so um we're just not too far apart actually
 	
 	
 		yeah that's pretty close
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it was funny um  um it's you know i talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all over uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> so i'm always asking where where in the state you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is from if they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um are do you have a family
 	
 	
 		um i'm married
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i was wondering if your if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> or if you know if you had uh other musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in your family
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		uh if you have other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who are also musical
 	
 	
 		oh a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you come by it naturally was your were your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that musical yeah yeah that often is the case um
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		the you know it's it sometimes it will skip like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is not musical at all but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is very musical and um and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are very musical so  you never know where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> is going to show up i guess sometimes
 		so um  well i'm not sure how long we've talked i haven't paid haven't been paying attention to the to the clock but uh
 	
 	
 		i think
 	
 	
 		i'll bet we've done we've done at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">least five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably
 	
 	
 		well i 've enjoyed talking with you uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX> and um maybe we'll talk again uh-huh bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay
 		all right thanks
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	