
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right well i'll just start by saying that we we spend our time you know having a formal dinner on on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> and that's when we try and get together it might be breakfast it might be and we try and talk about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		things and we try we have dinner <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> too but not everybody is always there our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fifteen seventeen</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		how old are they
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		are they all living at home
 	
 	
 		they are at home um our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is going to be a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		so she's home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> school and living at home um right now and we we but we very rarely do things as a whole family
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well when they were little though you did didn't you
 	
 	
 		yes yes we used to like
 	
 	
 		yeah because they're all close enough in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> that you would have had to take them all
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah we we used to like to go to oh parades the circus um
 		you know we used to like to take them to the park um we had a we have a swimming pool at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> which we've had since they were very small
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		so we we have many memories of swimming um together in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> you know and by the pool and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> uh learned to swim when they were real little you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and then they had their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> there and all that
 	
 	
 		yes they had their their pool parties um
 		so that was one of the things we did together was the most uh i guess the most often was swim by the swim in the pool that's
 	
 	
 		yeah well see i mean you know since we haven't had our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> yet but um
 		the thing that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i do could very easily be incorporated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because we like to go camping and we like to we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> so we go in the boat all the time and so
 	
 	
 		oh that's great if you like to do those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things
 	
 	
 		yeah and so you know those things could <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> could very easily go you know and just go with the flow
 	
 	
 		very easily yes
 		yes i think you will enjoy that i we never camped and we
 		we aren't we aren't into boating either uh mainly because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> doesn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> that much and he uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's mainly what i you know what he wanted to do and and he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swimmer</ENAMEX> he's a golfer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		did he teach them how to play golf
 	
 	
 		well he has taken them out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> but he hasn't and they've never showed any any any real interest it's got not enough action for for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know so um but we we like to um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but now you know now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next weekend</TIMEX> we're taking them to a show we're taking them down to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fair Park</ENAMEX> to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chorus Line</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and that's kind of their reward for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school year</TIMEX> successful school year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's a great one
 	
 	
 		so we're we're doing that
 	
 	
 		well that will be fun
 	
 	
 		but um but i you know as far as having a family it sounds like you've got some good ideas
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 	
 	
 		how about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are they close by your immediate your um
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and i have my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives there with her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and these are the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> at this point so they're getting tons of attention but um they're a lot of fun and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>'s in to tee ball and so they spend a lot of time but they're in this little bitty small hole in the road <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> so you know they have a lot of time that they can spend with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes that's nice
 	
 	
 		and that's you know that was another question that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i had is that what we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and we barely have time to play with them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> dogs well that's
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah those are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's i think that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> that everybody uses to get used to taking the responsibility of caring for something and then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it was real funny because we were walking out of a store <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> and he turned to me and he said did you feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> this morning and i said no didn't you and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> looked at us like we were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abusers and  so we had to explain to her we were talking about our dog
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's great yeah that's cute because i know our dog i didn't think he got fed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> but our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> fed him because we have we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> that are away right now they're at a camp
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh uh not a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> they're on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> tour that's were they are so they're they're gone so it's just me and our older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> but um but you will um i i think that's neat that you're going to start a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		yeah it's
 	
 	
 		and and i know everybody around you your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> will be very supportive and very anxious too i'm sure
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they they
 	
 	
 		i i have to tell you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um grandparents</ENAMEX> are very important to have close by i think and ours were never close by
 	
 	
 		oh i know it
 		really well see <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> since like i said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> started out so late having us my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> all but one was already dead even when before i was born so i didn't get to have that but
 	
 	
 		that's interesting
 	
 	
 		i had aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> that were so close to me that you know replaced grandparents i think in every way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah so how old is your little
 	
 	
 		so it's really neat that i can do that now with my niece and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> now then
 	
 	
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s seventy three
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well that's exactly how old my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and um but but they are the reversed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seventy well</ENAMEX> actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s seventy two my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well they're a lot of fun now
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm sure i'm sure they are
 	
 	
 		but also it was neat too because
 		um there was so much age difference between my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and me that i was kind of like the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and i did tons of things together we i mean she didn't drive but she'd load me up on a bus and we'd go across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and just had the best time
 	
 	
 		yes
 		isn't that wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah it was really neat so we were really close but that's
 	
 	
 		oh you must have such great memories of that
 	
 	
 		oh i do it's really neat yeah because it was real funny because in high school all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were fighting with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>  and i wasn't i was having a ball i mean on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> break that
 	
 	
 		that is so good
 		isn't that
 		that's really interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> break i'd go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> and all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> would go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Padre Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that is great i because that's very that's rare
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it was so much fun
 	
 	
 		yeah because i was the i'm the oldest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and we had a we have a very close knit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i i just i am just very blessed
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but being the oldest i had you know the responsibility of of doing a lot i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and a sister a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> so um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well see that's another thing that scares me about having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because i was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> so i haven't even really been around kids
 	
 	
 		yes yes well you'll well you have your niece your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> and to to look at that and and learn from that and you can read lots of good books
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but um but that's real fun so and you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carrollton</ENAMEX> yeah and where what what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> do you go to do you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh good yeah so are we
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah so
 	
 	
 		yeah we've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> for thirteen years
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have grown up here and i think i think Plano
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think the fact that you have the boating and the camping is a good good thing i think it's hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to find things to do with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> once the sports aren't there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		you know anymore like we have we always have the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> games to go to that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in and the you know tee ball soccer stuff like that but uh after they as they get older it's harder to find things to do together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah well we have all i mean and i both have camped since we were little with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and so i think it's very natural and i'm sure that's the way it will be and oh we've already looked in the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		catalog to to find a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> ski jacket
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well where do you go camping
 	
 	
 		um we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Whitney</ENAMEX> a lot which is it's a beautiful lake and then we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well i was just down near there i i had to drive to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday last Thursday</TIMEX> as a matter of fact my i saw the sign
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i didn't know it was pretty i just i
 	
 	
 		oh it's a very pretty lake
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's real clear which is kind of unusual for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> lakes
 	
 	
 		yeah and they have campgrounds
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they have some great camp grounds and then we like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> too because that's where i camped when i was little and there's some beautiful lakes there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah well that's interesting i am not timing this conversation because i guess you're supposed to be in control it says
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 		well yeah but i just kind of keep talking until we quit
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well this is my first call so um yeah yeah i i enjoy uh this is really going to be a neat thing i think
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah
 		yeah i do too
 	
 	
 		but um  i it's it's i think i'm going to need a pencil you know to to jot down what they say in the beginning and that because it's hard they're it's like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	