
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		hi you want to start first
 	
 	
 		of course we're talking about the elderly and uh whether or not we would we like nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and as a matter of fact i can tell you something about that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you apparently have somebody there in one
 	
 	
 		no actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> owned and operated a nursing home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and her mother
 	
 	
 		oh you are kidding
 	
 	
 		no she did and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> also owned and operated a nursing home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and then uh went on back to school and became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> at a nursing home
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i will be darned
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> both are geriatric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh for heaven's sake
 	
 	
 		so i do know something about that
 	
 	
 		you are very very much aware of what goes on  that is great
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		actually the motivation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> entering the business was that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was very old and couldn't seem to find companions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she was lonely and she needed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and so she opened a nursing home and initially started with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> and then uh it it grew into a very prosperous business from that point uh then they
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		i will be darned
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		now see that is a nice attitude to go into uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it seems like they must be waiting until it's a necessity
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there is no chance of uh good companionship or doing anything
 	
 	
 		well that is not really true either uh i think that is a stigma and an i and an impression that has come from some few bad experiences you see those who had bad experiences talk about them
 	
 	
 		um right right
 	
 	
 		and those who don't may write a letter to the nursing home and say you did good but they do not talk a whole lot about that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that is true but what i mean is instead of maybe entering a nursing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when you are still able to have good relationships with maybe other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure well now
 	
 	
 		they wait until they're you know unable
 	
 	
 		that's right well that is because they wait until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> make those choices they choose to not make those choices themselves however my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter-in-law</ENAMEX> also is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she works for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> which is more a retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> than it is a nursing home and these these i love watching these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> come they will come and tell her well i am going for my tennis lessons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh would you would you you know call down and have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> come around and take us for our tennis lessons and they're very active and very enthusiastic and they have some excellent programs right there on site
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		their dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> looks like you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafeteria</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's great
 	
 	
 		or or one of the lovely cafeterias and they have you know pink <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">linen napkins</ENAMEX> for their dinners and a a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> equipped library
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that sounds great
 	
 	
 		oh i am certainly very much for a nursing home and i think when the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> gets old enough to the extent where they just don't want to be bothered with keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and with taking care of themselves anymore that is a wonderful alternative it is expensive it is costly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		see if they could could get this idea across though better than what it is
 	
 	
 		it is costly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> uh lived in a a retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> and she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> had side by side duplexes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom duplex</ENAMEX> she still had her individuality
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they were there close and they did have uh you know the button that you could push the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> if you got into problems and there were lights that you could flip on and so forth and they he did have security
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i am very much in favor i have heard horror stories
 	
 	
 		oh well you have that with anything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> can easily be abused but i would be willing to bet they are far less abused in a nursing home than are they are in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		in the homes
 		yeah well we used our nursing home as uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> was real bad before she died uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we took her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half</TIMEX> into a nursing home and they were super with her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		they were uh
 	
 	
 		well now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> of course all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> lived to be very old and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> developed <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hodgkin's Disease</ENAMEX> when she was in her late eighties uh late seventies i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> she had surgery she got the treatments and during the period of time that she was undergoing those treatments
 		she was in a nursing home she got better she got well she got out and went dancing again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do that they left them temporally maybe they had a broken hip or something or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh i think it is a wonderful interim place it is a place that you don't have to struggle with hospital problems and uh yet it is not you know you have
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and it can become home to them
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum it certainly is
 	
 	
 		it it it depends upon the individual right yeah
 	
 	
 		it certainly does but you see we have had excellent experience with that and uh i
 		i did not put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> in a nursing home when he became ill but i would not object to going to one i might i might like to be uh coherent enough to make my own choice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i would not particularly think i would want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to say well i think this is what i need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and then dump me there but i would like
 	
 	
 		this this is the age and  there has to be consideration taken on everything so
 	
 	
 		that's right um-hum um-hum and i think you would shop for a nursing home just like you would shop for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> or anything else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right you would look into it thoroughly and do do the best job you could in choosing choosing one
 	
 	
 		um-hum sure
 		um-hum when you get to the point where you are in trouble and you have got to have that help you are in no position to make those choices
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no and you do not have the time to look that is what i am saying most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will not even look at that until it becomes a necessity
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		absolutely i think that one of the best ways to do that is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to realize they're going to be needing those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and to actually get involved and participate on a community level with community service go out to the nursing home help guide some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> programs perhaps work on some music programs whatever their talents are and work with those senior citizens
 	
 	
 		whatever their talents yeah
 		yeah i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> who's uh  he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that was epileptic from birth and he did fine at home they lived on a farm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but she made arrangements so that when she was gone she didn't want her her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> her other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> burdened with his care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so he they she has made arrangements that when she she was gone that he would go into the nursing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he's i would say he adjusted very well and uh he he he's been there quite a long time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he don't know me usually  but he goes wheeling down uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> to bingo somebody else he's helping him out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you know and uh he has adjusted very well
 	
 	
 		well one of the things i think that is most desirable for the elderly and that is routine
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh yes yes
 	
 	
 		routine and uh constancy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the only real problem with that in a nursing home is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> turns over i do not think they pay the nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> sufficiently to to get the dedication
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> to keep them there uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that they have in some other profession and that's sad because i think the health profession is one of the most critical
 	
 	
 		true
 		yes yes but for for some reason
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> resist uh the fact that they should be paid as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and that type of thing you know
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		it seems to be a resistance
 	
 	
 		care for the elderly and care for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i can't imagine a more costly and a more a more uh better area to invest your money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right but there seems to be a resistance
 	
 	
 		you're preserving your heritage and your future there
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and as a matter of fact i don't see why they don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s programs in nursing homes
 	
 	
 		well around here we have some you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh take your the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
 		i know our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> thoroughly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> thoroughly enjoy
 		
 		
 	