
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i've had i've had a number of them in my lifetime and i've i am a golden retriever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> but i had to replace it with something that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> could carry yes yes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh  instead of being carried
 	
 	
 		yes well they were they really wanted something teeny tiny and i uh really wanted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retriever</ENAMEX>'s disposition uh the ultimate to tolerant trainable disposition so i called
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		really
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog trainers</ENAMEX> because i don't like the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and and i asked them you know these are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> what do i get
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they all said golden retriever and i said okay put it under <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> pounds and the only thing that they could come up with was a bichon frise which is a do you know what that is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh yes i've seen those they're cute
 	
 	
 		they're cute they look like an airheaded <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> but let me tell you they're calm they're not yappy they're trainable
 		they're uh very personable in a different way that a golden retriever is they're not dignified like a retriever can be yeah so how old is your retriever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> she's not completely pure we got her from the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> when she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> she looks like a golden she looks just like a golden retriever but she's a little bit smaller she's like fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> pounds
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well actually you know that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> standard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> what you yeah what you see shown and bred now as golden retrievers this you know plus eighty to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a hundred pound</NUMEX> range
 	
 	
 		is it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that is not breed standard fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> is the minimum but they usually run about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty to sixty five</TIMEX> and the ones that are shown
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		they are inside that weight allowance you cannot show your retriever if it's you know a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred</NUMEX> plus pounds so don't say she's small just say she's perfect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh huh
 		yeah she's perfect well she's got a brown nose instead of black too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which makes her i guess unshowable even if she had papers which she doesn't but but we love her anyway she's just a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to us we didn't
 	
 	
 		yep
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we haven't had any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and we're expecting a baby <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> but up until then she's been our substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and she was a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		well they are they are the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> to have around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so long as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> not scared of a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> because i had a retriever actually i had a retriever <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">setter</ENAMEX> cross
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which is a really nice animal and fortunately it was just like a retriever and then i've had a retriever
 	
 	
 		i bet it had a pretty coat too
 	
 	
 		it was gorgeous it was just gorgeous i mean just gorgeous um and they both you know both the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> breed and the pure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> had the um
 		what i consider the the the perfect disposition but you know what you know what scares me about golden retrievers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		since they've become so popular you get what i call backyard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeders</ENAMEX> which is probably where yours came from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't know what they're doing and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they breed them you know for a certain characteristic and in the retrievers it happens to be they like them big for somehow big is perceived as better and when you start doing that you really tamper with you know the all the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of uh
 		culling litters and and uh you tamper with what the dog innately is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we when i was when i bought my last purebred retriever i mean i looked all over because i wanted one that still looked like retriever you know the short to the ground stocky golden
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> trainable tractable quiet animal that could hunt and still be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i ended up getting one that uh came out of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a hunting stock because i wanted one that could still perform like a retriever did
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i've seen an awful lot of lately really dumb
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">retrievers</ENAMEX> and i'm and i really fear for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> because i love that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> but i really figure right when it becomes really popular that it's going to be ruined
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> golden retriever and those <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> have been having seizures and i wonder since both of them are having them if it's some kind of a breeding problem
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah you bet you you bet you you know how they came up with the retriever don't you the golden it was bred out of several different retrievers and they bred it for companionship and uh uh disposition and and ability to hunt it was kept only by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but they selectively culled those litters i mean for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and since it slept in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> with its master i mean it had it had to be of a disposition to make it you know an animal you could keep around that closely but
 		but they would go through all the litters and destroy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> if they were anything other than perfect now you know that seems like a cruel thing to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		on the other hand you sure you know they sure created a a wonderful breed i mean a wonderful breed
 	
 	
 		yeah they did
 		i i had never really had a golden retriever before we were going to get a shepherd and something mixed because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shepherds</ENAMEX> and all the other we looked at some of shepherd mixes and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> weren't very
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh social and stuff and we went to a pen of a little bit bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and all the others were standing there barking and jumping up and down and one dog would stand there wagging her tail and smiling  and that was mine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i tell you you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> shepherd is the classic case of what i'm talking about because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that's called a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rin Tin Tin phenomena</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is there a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> called a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> shepherd that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> is bred out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> dogs the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> Tervurien a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> schutzhund and
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i always forget the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one i can see it uh  but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		there are distinct breeds in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> now what happened over here was is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saw the the first um which would actually have been a schutzhund which is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rin Tin Tin</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and everybody wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rin Tin Tin</ENAMEX> and it was known as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> shepherd here
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so they created a breed standard the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Kennel Club</ENAMEX> did that said anything that is a schutzhund a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tervurien</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alsatian</ENAMEX> that's the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> Alsatian
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		any inner breeding of that can be called a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> shepherd here and what happened is is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wanted this shepherd to shepherd and protect and they bred a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i the it's called a an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>'s critical span which basically translates to how much shit will it take before it bites you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> shepherd the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American German</ENAMEX> shepherd here was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a such an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">unreliable animal</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Seeing Eye Institute</ENAMEX> refused to use them because they would turn on their on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even um uh police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> which started you know finding other breeds to use because this thing this this thing known as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> shepherd here its personality and its dependability and its reliability was just terrible
 		so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about fifteen years ago</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">German Shepherd Club of America</ENAMEX> decided amongst themselves that they were going to change this so they went back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 		and brought back some good examples of each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> breeds and bred
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to a standard what they wanted an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American German</ENAMEX> shepherd to be which is a very heavily now schutzhund and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alsatian</ENAMEX> and it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alsatian</ENAMEX> that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s dog it's just you see them in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and they're just lovely
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but you'll see i mean if you ever start looking in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> now and you start seeing these ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shepherds</ENAMEX> they will say on them bred for disposition AKC conforming
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		which means that their advertising that this is no longer an indiscriminate dog this is bred for and they had to go through and destroy a for a while there about seventy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> that they bred
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		because they were looking for this disposition and nowadays you you'll get you'll get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> trainer to recommend a specific you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeder handler</ENAMEX> they'll recommend their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shepherds</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s dog but
 	
 	
 		huh
 		
 		
 	