
 
     		
 	
 		okay uh could you give me your thoughts on uh on any trends
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh longer term trends i think that uh like past oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or fifteen years uh
 		there there there seems to be a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 		trend and maybe it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer than that of</TIMEX> of politics is is strictly a what can i get for me or what can i get for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and not what's
 		best for the whole uh kind of a thing uh does that make any sense or
 	
 	
 		yeah um you're talking about the uh political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		i mean the
 		yeah political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> that and i think it i think it ties in with the the budget deficit that uh the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and and uh is is they get they get reelected by what they do for their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> uh in terms of bringing in and bringing in money and and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		in order to bring in money for their district they've got to vote to spend it in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> and and uh the heck with the overall uh deficit and it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		districts is geographical but it can just as well be interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in terms of of uh
 		whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> or or anything that that uh it's it's what what you get for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> one way or another not what what's necessarily good overall
 	
 	
 		yeah we're uh  we feel it up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> because we're small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> so we don't have the represent and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have you know like like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> um but we've got we have political clout only because of the tenure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in there like for uh uh the sub
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		building you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gratin</ENAMEX> and they're building down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newport</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah okay but you
 	
 	
 		but once uh somebody's got to do it somebody's got to build the subs and i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> can do it also in fact i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the latest contract that was awarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia</ENAMEX> sued or has got a lawsuit against uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gratin</ENAMEX> to stop construction because it was unfairly obtained or something like that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh yeah but let's see you you do have uh long time uh long time power <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there in terms of i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>'s got uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		this um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaffey</ENAMEX> and and and been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> forever and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> yep yep
 		yep
 		but when those when those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> leave uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX>'s going to go um there isn't really anything here because we're not really big enough so the economy is going to going to suffer i think because the the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the base that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> always had the textile base the uh the uh costume jewelry base most of that now has moved out here to overseas to overseas or down south so we're prone to
 	
 	
 		yep yep
 	
 	
 		um uh recessions like the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> were before we were kind of stable uh the political power is the only thing that can stabilize it at least i think up up this neck of the woods
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but there's too many now uh political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and where the money is coming from is coming from those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that have the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> that can afford to contribute to those
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so those are going to get uh uh the squeaky wheel gets the oil they're going to they're going to catch it and somebody has to do it somebody has to do the work like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics</ENAMEX> or wherever wherever they happen to be you know you've you've only got a few plane <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 		well i guess i guess i'm a little more cynical than that i'm not i'm not sure that it that all of it has to be done even but uh
 	
 	
 		well i i think they should be outlawed myself the the the packs i don't think they should be
 	
 	
 		uh but well in it
 		well i
 		but i i mean in terms of of not necessarily all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> buys they really need or not necessarily well in in in in particular uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		true
 	
 	
 		you know i see this here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that that uh got uh
 		oh i can't even remember which of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> it is but they've they've got a they've got a tilt rotor
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> that they've developed and they want to sell but developed for the defense department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> is saying well no we we don't we don't really need it it's going to be too expensive and it's not going to do what we need and
 	
 	
 		oh like the yeah
 		yep yep
 	
 	
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are fighting to have it built for just to just to keep and create jobs here
 	
 	
 		right yep
 	
 	
 		rather than because it's uh you know they they they certainly use the words well it's needed but but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		look at look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> now look at that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">New Abrams</ENAMEX> tank
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i have no idea what the cost is uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five million ten million</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		for each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> now you can make you can make a a missile or or a hand held rocket that can take one of those out pretty effectively
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		what what do we need all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> for
 		i mean you can make you make you can make probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> for each tank
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and you can give <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> of a relatively uninvolved uninvolved untrained uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and he can take he can take one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		but yet i'm not sure who is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> that makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> or one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
 	
 	
 		i think i i think maybe so and i think that or
 	
 	
 		and i don't think we really need all that hardware and again and again like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> and and some of these things they they put on their drawing boards and they never fly or they never they never run right
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> is it because of of political clout
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		rather than need i think in a lot of cases yes
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but we don't have a watchdog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to the military overlooks their own testing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which is good for us i mean it creates you know we generate a lot of income at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> because of the military contacts
 	
 	
 		right right right you know that's true too but do you see any other trends or particularly interesting events that come to your mind
 	
 	
 		um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> crisis
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the political trends there are are most most of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> that are now in in uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> whether it's state or local most of them i guess you've been reading about the problems we've had in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> closed down a lot of the the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">credit unions</ENAMEX> and banks
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because of uh it was privately insured but but stated
 	
 	
 		well it certainly did certainly did when he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> did it but i haven't heard about it for a while i was at are there
 	
 	
 		yeah there's still a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh still can't get their money out
 	
 	
 		can't yeah
 	
 	
 		um they still have to pay their their bills like their mortgages and things they slip them under the door to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and but yet they can't get any of their savings
 		so it's it's it's a little bit difficult but most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there the trend was that on almost every single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> that were closed they were state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so they had a conflict of interest because they tried to get through uh a bill stating that they had to have federal insurance rather than private insurance and it was squashed
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	