
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so what were you saying
 	
 	
 		do you work with do you work around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> when you work with computers
 	
 	
 		no no not at all i work with computers
 		yep they what one thing i
 	
 	
 		okay do you have but you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh not that many actually
 	
 	
 		that have been
 		uh-huh what is child care like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> what is
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i do not really know
 		excuse me too much about child care in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you work for have child care on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		excuse me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one second</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		no not at all in fact my situation is a little bit strange i was uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> and then graduated and went and worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> for awhile
 		have just come back and was doing consulting work so i am just taking a little bit of time off right now uh and and i might
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh my
 		a sabbatical
 		well i hope you can stay as long as possible with
 	
 	
 		yeah well hopefully i can do some consulting work at home and if i can do that it will yeah i'll be able to spend the time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and not have to worry too much about child care
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh that would be wonderful right
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh i might start to go crazy with it too it is a little i i miss the intellectual stimulation
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but at the same time i really it would break my heart to give her to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> right now and
 	
 	
 		i think it does when when they're real little and they're changing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> there's and you just miss the little things and and uh
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		yeah
 		well i think for me the important concerns i do not think i would put her in day care for joint situation right now unless it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with a with a person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't want her to be into a in a large day care situation so young because i think a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> just doesn't get the stimulation they need
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		maybe if if i needed to work part time like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> a day i might do that because like you should get enough stimulation from me the rest of the time but uh i just think that you know when there's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year olds</TIMEX> running around
 		the whoever is taking care of them the care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">givers</ENAMEX> are going to pay attention to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year olds</TIMEX> and only when the infant screams are they going to go there and if not the infant is going to lay in the crib <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and maybe have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile</ENAMEX> above it to play with
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you know i play with her most of the time she's awake and i think that is so important
 	
 	
 		right well that it is important for the bonding that they do it with the mother this is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well such as things for learning gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> stimulation i think is important
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> when he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months old</TIMEX> went into a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a Montessori day</TIMEX> care system and they took <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> starting at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> and they have a program uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in that was devised by this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Montessori</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and uh a certain type of stimulations and there's times of day that even when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is awake that they they lay quietly
 		and look at certain things they keep deliberately keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">room</ENAMEX> not real bright and and uh they have different things they'll they'll put them down on the floor and of course they never have more than like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and they'll put them down on the floor and they will have oh i think one of them was a little mirror and some were just different objects that have had a definite purpose for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know and there's something about their eyes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well she's she's just been doing all kinds of stuff where she's you know
 	
 	
 		uh how old is she now oh yeah
 	
 	
 		she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months now nine weeks</TIMEX> and she's just drastically moving her eyes from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side to another and things like that and she's just started that like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so every days are different and i think that you know i think child care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> is much harder than when they are older and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'll probably be going back to work around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> whereas she'll be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight or nine months old</TIMEX> and so i think you know she'll be at a i have heard it's a roughage to put them into a
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 		it is because that's when they're clinging to mama so you might have a real problem with that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it it hurts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to leave when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is crying so it you know it would be ideal if you could get somebody in so you are not really leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in a strange place but that's unusual
 	
 	
 		but but i think it
 		yeah we're just going to have to see how things work out uh but i'm trying to you know leave her a fair amount even at this young age with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> just to go to a movie and things like that so that she's used to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> taking care of her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		is it your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s parents
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> so it's a little bit harder but during you know she she she's met them already
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		not that she will remember them but she's met them
 	
 	
 		right right that's nice when uh i my i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> coming in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> and i it would if they were
 		where i couldn't get my hands on them i'm afraid i would probably go crazy i you know i i like that but if it you do not have to put them in child care that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		are they all nearby
 	
 	
 		that's an ideal situation for you is to stay with them as or you can set up your work program and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s so that one of you is there all the time that's that's wonderful for the child
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but right and you need to look at when you if you do decide to go with child care you really need to to
 	
 	
 		well if i work part time that might be doable
 	
 	
 		look at what your options are and and look at the what they offer drop in at times that
 		are unexpected the
 	
 	
 		yeah well right now the situation is so tight at many places that it's even hard to have a choice
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh
 	
 	
 		incredible but you know since this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> before they get pregnant are finding child care for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  and you know i just find that incredible and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> is going to have a baby very very soon and she's intending to stay home with the baby
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and you know maybe do some freelance type work from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and so if i go back to work on a part time basis i'm hoping i can leave my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> with her because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> you know again will be a couple
 	
 	
 		oh that would be wonderful
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months</TIMEX> older than hers and you know it'll be a little rough when she is a very very little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> but like when she is a month or so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> has had lots and lots of experience dealing with babysitting for large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		she might be able to do it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours a day</TIMEX> and we could might even be able to do it on a trade off basis that i watch their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> when they want to go out to dinner or to movies or whatever or if she wants an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> off even if she wants an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> just to work
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and not be bothered we might be able to exchange that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh -huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we'll just have to see how things work out but i think the whole you know ideally i think the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> should have the day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> there whether it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who take turns watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or whether they hire a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> come down to supervise or whatever
 	
 	
 		i do too
 		really well trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> right and have have some kind of real good program set up so that you when you go you can be assured that if there's an emergency that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in charge knows CPR or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> aid or
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and and have some kind of program set up like you say to stimulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or educate them in some manner and have the you know the right toys and the right setting and
 		uh have a an organized type of program set up so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have a schedule you know that's real important to little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well she's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to be on a real schedule yet and it's  probably my fault because i do not have a real schedule now but
 	
 	
 		uh-huh they they adjust to what the parents
 	
 	
 		yeah well she's been staying up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX> and  you know sleeping late in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> and things is just fine by me
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we you know that works until they start school and that's a problem society is geared to a a day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and it's
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i have uh another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> have done this they stay up until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all hours of the night</TIMEX>
 		
 		
 	