
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well the topic is selecting care for the elderly and i don't have elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> yet but not that far in the distant future what about yourself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are both in their seventies my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and stepfather and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepmother</ENAMEX> are all in their seventies and my um
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepmother</ENAMEX> are not in very good health so this is
 		something that
 	
 	
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of yours right now is
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		are are they living independently right now
 	
 	
 		yes they are they are
 	
 	
 		oh have have you looked at any <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> for them or talked to them about that
 	
 	
 		not for them my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and stepfather have have um
 		set up an arrangement where they have a a large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my sisters
 		and and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> one of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and then all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are living in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> its got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX> and and uh they all share the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and den and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and and um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> bought this
 		uh my stepfather bought this thinking of a time when one or the other of them might need care and they felt like that would be their alternative to a nursing home unless
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds like the ultimate
 	
 	
 		unless unless they were so ill that they needed nursing care that could not be given in the home
 	
 	
 		well even at that point most care can be given at in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that sound like just an excellent solution you must feel real good about that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i i felt good about it because that's my personal feeling also i um
 		i read a lot and then i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that then have visited nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and
 		uh have had great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> in the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and it was not a happy situation for
 		for any of them and and uh
 		we have a very active nursing home here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> that that has uh activities going all the time and they have uh
 		even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are wheelchair bound and and really are are   incapacitated
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		go and uh participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">olympics</ENAMEX> and they make their crafts and sell them at a big fair that's held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> at a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know that so there are a lot of a lot of activities going on all the time and this is a nursing home it's not a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> home so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really uh
 	
 	
 		really in need of a nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		right they need the nursing care and and but it's a very expensive solution
 	
 	
 		well it's you know  i think we just
 		you you you know listen to is the fact that there are good solutions solutions both inside and outside of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> it's just a matter of
 		finding a good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and and then of course there is always the problem of being able to able to afford either of those solutions
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and that i think is what is scary and i also feel that that's where some of the bad images um of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> come from is when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and they really can not afford the best
 	
 	
 		right and that's right i well i took my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> to an emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> when he was in an emergency situation and uh they brought in a very elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from a nursing home
 		who had had uh apparently inhaled some chicken he was eating and uh he had apparently had not been in the home too long just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so</TIMEX> but when they brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> came in to see him
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they had not been made aware i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> when the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> brought him in from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX> and i overheard their conversation and when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> walked in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> they were not even aware of what had happened
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		so i told them he strangled on some chicken
 		and uh they said the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> said he was not even supposed to be eating any food like that that would require chewing or
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so you know and i thought
 	
 	
 		what a shame they put him in the home so that he could be cared for
 	
 	
 		right  right
 	
 	
 		and then then they could have done that well at home
 	
 	
 		and then she was upset he had on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different shoes one of which was not even his he had on a pair of slacks and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> said these are not his slacks and she said i just took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> for him
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that clean and
 	
 	
 		you hear these stories all the time
 	
 	
 		right right well i this was just
 		something that i was i witnessed to and and uh at no point did anybody from the nursing home come in and we were there in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you happened
 		right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and with just a curtain of course between us and and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they they revived revived the revived the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and cleared out his airway and so forth and he was definitely just by looking at him and the way he acted you could tell he was in need of
 		of nursing home care but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were all talking about um
 		putting him in another home they said he will not go back
 	
 	
 		well good good i'm glad they have a solution
 	
 	
 		to that one
 		i'm glad they the option
 	
 	
 		to do that yes i know
 	
 	
 		i i would hate to be in a position where
 		that was all i could afford and there weren't there was no choice
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly my um
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> had been in a nursing home now for oh it must be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven eight years</TIMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		it's it's just just her her condition deteriorated deteriorated instantly upon getting into that home as the situation is so
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		sad because
 		it it just takes all the dignity away from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been independent all their lives this was a really neat vital woman
 		and you get in a nursing home and the first thing that happens you have to share your your whole living space with someone that you have never known before in your life
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and oh i
 		i do not know what what the answer is but i do know that there are some wonderful places out there and
 		it i think it does a lot of it goes down to just money
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and family support uh if you you know have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that uh you can live with right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		visits everyday or right
 	
 	
 		right
 		i i really i think the way of selecting a nursing home would be similar to the way you would select child care
 		you know you'd do your research and you would go visit
 	
 	
 		visit right
 	
 	
 		and uh hopefully they would have they would have it so that you could go there anytime
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because if you could not go there anytime then that would make you a little bit right
 	
 	
 		uh suspicious
 		you know i i my i remember my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> when she was in a nursing home before she died and
 		i guess there was not a name for what she had at that time but i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> would come as close as anything she really was not aware of what she was doing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i can i can remember she had several strokes and the nursing home was right next to a hospital and they'd rush her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and revive her and just bring her back to the nursing home
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> and it was she was it was just like keeping something alive
 		
 		
 	