
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i hope you know more about the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and where they're going than i do because
 	
 	
 		oh i know a little bit about it i'm not a die hard fan but i i enjoy the i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Red Sox</ENAMEX> myself
 	
 	
 		well i of all the sports that there are that there is
 		i like baseball the best however i haven't been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but i have kept uh my eye on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and i guess they were doing pretty good up to a point and then they kind of fell on their face
 	
 	
 		well with uh
 		their biggest point of interest has been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> not the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> lately so
 	
 	
 		correct right they've got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> show going there  which is interesting you know um
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh it's amazing
 	
 	
 		i guess he can i guess he can really call down a salary  they're so astronomical i can't even imagine  that kind of money you know it's just uh phenomenal
 	
 	
 		right
 		well fortunately the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> last time i saw the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> were in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place and doing quite well um i
 	
 	
 		well good
 	
 	
 		been really busy at work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week</TIMEX> and normally on my way into work i'll pick up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and uh
 		it so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> i'll have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> at work and when i take a break i'll look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> i've been so busy i didn't even bother to stop
 	
 	
 		i understand i understand
 	
 	
 		but
 		hopefully hopefully <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> i'll get back to my normal routine
 	
 	
 		okay uh you are involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s uh speech um
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well not really i um i
 	
 	
 		how did you find out about it
 	
 	
 		i work at  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> from uh i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		i see interesting
 	
 	
 		they have a speech <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> from us
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		and uh the speech laboratory does some work
 		with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> at uh not in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> but uh in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> they do
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		quite a bit of speech work
 	
 	
 		well that's good well that's interesting and the topics are interesting uh they run a whole gamut of
 		of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> and uh i think we can address every topic but the depth of knowledge is quite different
 	
 	
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		so uh when they chose baseball i mean i'm i'm i can understand baseball you know i don't understand football um you know uh it's such a rugged game that it uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it seems to be too physical for my uh interest
 	
 	
 		oh i prefer to i i i like
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i never used to really like watching football that much but more and more these days i'm
 		i i'll like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game but i've always liked baseball i i prefer to watch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i guess i'm one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that also prefers <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and i i'd much rather go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game than to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		well i i can relate to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> because i used to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> but i can't relate to football because i've never
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">played football and</ENAMEX> and don't and have have any interest and i said if i ever had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he would not play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> so that wasn't a question but now i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> that is you know is gung ho for um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that doesn't please grandma too much
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i'm always afraid because the injuries are so uh can be very very devastating
 	
 	
 		well there's injuries in a lot of sport
 	
 	
 		i understand that but i think they they happen more in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> i think the odds are cut down you know i i know they can get hurt in baseball too
 	
 	
 		i i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the bat is a very heavy object can do a lot of damage but uh i think
 		that they have a a lower ratio of injuries ratio of injuries in baseball
 	
 	
 		oh
 		baseball that's true i i would say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> tends to be one of the less
 		troublesome sports but uh for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it's just uh
 	
 	
 		because the yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		a love for them
 	
 	
 		well that that not so much that but uh even in baseball you can like when i played baseball when i was uh growing up i had trouble uh
 		uh just throwing the ball because my i was very
 		i was always very strong and i could throw when i was young i could throw
 		harder than my uh like ligaments and all that should have been allowed to and so i was always throwing my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> out and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		having trouble i and i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> so i was constantly throwing back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> and then down to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> base and all and and that kind of stuff so i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was always a problem for me was just just the constant throwing
 		so
 	
 	
 		did you did you sustain any permanent uh injury with that
 	
 	
 		no i did that wrestling
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh oh okay
 	
 	
 		no i'd well i i uh i always been quite an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> and doing different things and um
 		the other thing was i'd never really let injuries stop me but interestingly enough you mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is like now i won't play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> anymore because of the uh
 		because i separate a shoulder wrestling so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but i stood the stood the injury wrestling but it
 		as long as i let it heal it never really bothered me then playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> this fall
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i it was just flag football too i separated it again and it seemed to be like the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> that broke the camels back so
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i have uh i have a broken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> that i had since i was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> it was never set right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh uh i liked bowling as a as a kind of a relaxing sport
 		and uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that was in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> in on our league uh noticed uh you know uh my broken arm and the way my ball would do and he says let me show you how to use your arm to your advantage
 		and so he brought me up from like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and fifteen</NUMEX> i had my high game of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eighty seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		my God
 	
 	
 		so uh yeah  uh it was really funny you know that he would tell me where to stand and how to hold my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> and and how to uh keep uh
 		follow through with my uh addressing that to put the ball the uh pins
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that was interesting so i really um i got a lot of uh recognition from the uh
 		uh the bowling league i guess i'm not sure where all my pins came from but but it's but that was quite awhile ago but i and i never pursued it and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said well you should have turned pro and i thought nah not um hum-um i don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my love wasn't there for the game i liked to as a as a method of uh entertainment and i uh fellowship but uh outside of that no i didn't and i and i still i like to bowl but uh
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i don't have um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> standing behind me to tell me what to do
 	
 	
 		are you uh you on any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i'm not no no uh at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> a junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> achievement and uh it's true bowling and i've never uh shared shared that with them i would have to brush up on my bowling before i ev en
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		tried to uh win a lot of money for the junior achievement uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> but that's the only thing that i would you know be allowed to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> has been bowling for gosh maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty forty years</TIMEX> i don't know a long time and she still she's got to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		still carries a good league uh average
 	
 	
 		well no she doesn't
 		
 		
 	