
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay now now we're supposed to talk about music why why did you check music
 	
 	
 		right
 		why did i pick music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh because i know a little bit about music you know so i thought that i would put that plus i
 		i like uh to listen to music
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what kind of music do you enjoy
 	
 	
 		um i really enjoy the oldies is what i really listen to most of the time
 	
 	
 		like what what kind of oldies
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		like the fifties oldies or older oldies
 	
 	
 		usually in the fifties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not really sure i think it's it's a fifties <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> and seventies <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> that i listen to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh they have the same kind of station down here and when i listen to music most of the time that's what i listen to uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh really i don't know a lot of the um
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>' names or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX>' names but i know a lot of the old songs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh we just got a disk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that was a um disk of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Nat King Cole</ENAMEX>'s greatest hits and it is excellent it it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty</TIMEX> of his greatest hits on it it's really an excellent
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		excellent CD we are we were really quite pleased with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you um do you listen have you heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nat</ENAMEX> heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat King Cole</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i have
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well um
 		um  do you play any musical instruments or anything
 	
 	
 		um i played the accordion for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and i played the clarinet for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> also
 	
 	
 		really
 		at at the same time or
 	
 	
 		no i played the accordion until i got into <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">about sixth</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade and then in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade i started the clarinet and i played that all through high school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> Like so you're in the marching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and stuff in high school yeah i i played the baritone horn in high school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and in college so and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> played flute in high school
 	
 	
 		i was yes
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and then in concert band i played the bass clarinet
 	
 	
 		really really actually that's exactly the same thing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> did  she played the clarinet and then she played bass clarinet during concert band
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yes yeah so
 	
 	
 		i like the low notes better than the high notes so
 		we didn't have any bass clarinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> so i asked him if i could play it because i was first clarinet and they end up playing a lot of the high notes and i don't
 		i don't care for the sound of the high notes so i asked him if i could play the bass clarinet and he said sure you know he didn't have anyone to play it so i played it and i really enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		um well i like it i i like the low instruments better too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um do you go to do you go to listen to much live music
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		do you listen to much live music like concerts or things there
 	
 	
 		no i really don't go to very many concerts
 	
 	
 		uh-huh we're we're going to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> the um
 		um i don't know if you follow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> much but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Crawford</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Phantom of the Opera</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> you know you know whom i'm talking about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and he's coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> on the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty ninth</TIMEX> and we got a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> going down to hear him sing a bunch of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Lloyd Webber</ENAMEX>'s music so that'll be good
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> are kind of into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> they they my my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and he's been to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phantom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Miserables</ENAMEX> and bunch of other things up there so
 	
 	
 		i would love to be able to go see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Miserables</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he does it he can go if they get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> dollar tickets to that thing yeah yeah and one of the uh the last time they went up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of his wanted to go and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> didn't want to go so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> went and
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he went and bought one of the low priced student tickets and they they gave him the seat that normally belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Bell John it</ENAMEX>'s his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> seat that's under his control and he said it was a great seat
 	
 	
 		holy smoke
 	
 	
 		so he he's been to they've been to see it several times
 	
 	
 		oh i would love to go see that and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chorus Line</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i would love to be able to go see those
 	
 	
 		would they do don't any of those ever come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they do but i work and i went to i go to college i had just gotten i just graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and so i really didn't have the chance or the money to go see them
 	
 	
 		sure
 		well we're kind of you know they well i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> shows of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Miserables</ENAMEX> and they were both excellent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so if it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> shows and i think they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that tour the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> um you should go see it because it's really it's really outstanding
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> doesn't even like that kind of stuff and he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> a bunch of there was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from high school that went and he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> with them and he saw it and he said it was the best thing he'd ever seen
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and he doesn't even like that type of stuff
 	
 	
 		well i think it's just incredible i and then you know those um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Miserables</ENAMEX> wrote a new show call <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Saigon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah it just opened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> were in a lottery to get tickets to it and they got tickets for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the opening night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and they went to it and they said it was it was great it was great
 	
 	
 		oh see now i like that type of stuff but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> doesn't really like it he's more into the New Wave music
 	
 	
 		yeah like depressed mode and
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess i don't know either you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't too much but my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> listens to some of that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know uh really weird names like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dead Milkman</ENAMEX> or sure i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh it's you know really weird stuff he likes and i thought oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		so he listens to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Wave</ENAMEX> and you listen to the oldies that's kind
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's kind of different well that's good though you know it's good to cover all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		well
 		i pretty i'll listen to anything basically except i don't like the real hard metal rock
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just refuse to listen to that at all i'll even listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i don't i like some country
 	
 	
 		well we don't now we don't listen to much <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but we just at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the same night</TIMEX> we bought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat King Cole</ENAMEX> album we bought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">album No Fences</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that is excellent
 	
 	
 		do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Travis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we well we i've never never listened i mean i've i've probably heard him but i've never bought any of his music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> is probably the only country album we have or no wait my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> bought an album of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams</ENAMEX>' greatest hits
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams Junior</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nope this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams</ENAMEX> senior so these are a bunch of old recordings
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she bought that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the same night</TIMEX> we bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nat</ENAMEX> King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well those should be good albums
 	
 	
 		it is pretty good she likes it it's a little it's a little too <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for me it's a
 	
 	
 		if you have the chance
 	
 	
 		little too uh
 		honky-tonk or something
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i like i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> album a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's pretty good it's pretty good
 	
 	
 		um i don't know maybe you wouldn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Travis</ENAMEX> he's really country himself but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i you know i i really enjoy listening to his music
 	
 	
 		which album which of his albums do you think is the best
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know If i were you i would get the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Greatest Hits album</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		if he had one because you know that would have a mixture of all his you know top songs on it
 		but um we have i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> records of his i can't you know name the names of them off hand but we have i think all his records so far and all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> listen to them even the ones that like the heavy metal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they really enjoy listening to him so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know maybe if you did like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth</ENAMEX> you know maybe you would enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travis uh Randy Travis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i i think we'll probably get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of his albums because we do kind of like it but you know it's kind of different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so so it's good
 	
 	
 		um do you know any oh i was going to say do you know any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country singers</ENAMEX> that you would you know
 		i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do you like the Judds
 	
 	
 		yeah we do like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juds</ENAMEX> in fact we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juds</ENAMEX> album
 		
 		
 	