
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so well she lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh uh-huh that's the way we always were we always lived away from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were growing up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		well i guess we're going to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		okay let's do it
 	
 	
 		so you ready
 		
 
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are all
 		gone already they're they're all out on their own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh do you want to start first do you you uh do you work
 	
 	
 		okay
 		no i don't i stay home most of the time but i know that it's very difficult to to find good help sometimes when and especially when your when you want your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to be taken care of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		um you know there's a my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> she tends <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> though and and um there's a big controversy whether they should have to um have a a law
 		a law to have them certified or or not and um
 		you know there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons on both side of that because if they were then you kind of know that they had to go through some kind of testing or some kind of something to be okay okay get an okay seal
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah but yet most of the problems we hear of course maybe that's what we hear about is from organized approved day care centers
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		but maybe we don't hear about the other ones though that could be you know the individual incidence or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum uh now usually when i have someone tend um my oldest tends for me now if i go somewhere but before
 	
 	
 		uh-huh how old is your oldest
 	
 	
 		he's almost a teenager  yeah he's he's very good um but um
 	
 	
 		oh well he's plenty big enough then
 	
 	
 		before that i would i would use uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and they did a good job for me um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i've never had to leave them like in a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> or anything and i've been very lucky just be able to stay home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's the way with me i i worked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years one time</TIMEX> but but my last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were uh both entering high school age
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they were of course gone while i was working working so
 		it wasn't a problem i saw and i stayed home the rest of the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i so i didn't have that problem either
 		now i have my my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they've been in day care
 		uh she works full time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's hard
 	
 	
 		it it's difficult but yet she's the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that i don't know if she'd be happy staying at home
 	
 	
 		well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't
 	
 	
 		uh-huh she uh she surprised me though she's done a lot of things that i never thought she would do you know with with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because she
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that said she was never getting married and never going to have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>  so she uh she spends a lot of quality time i think when she is with with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh is that  is that right
 		i think that's really important
 	
 	
 		and uh she they've used the day care most of the time they tried once once they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> come in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she she also had a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> she brought with her and it did not work out uh
 		at all  it she thought it was going to she was real excited because it was so much easier than taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> out in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> called and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> wasn't very old at the time and said she was having trouble and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> is the is the most pleasant uh real pleasant baby easy to satisfy usually and
 		and she was having problems with her and so she called and said things were okay settled down and was all right
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> decided to come and check and things weren't okay
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		her her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was watching the soapies which she doesn't allow them to watch the soapies
 	
 	
 		oh um-hum
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> was in his crib with the door shut just screaming his heart out
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 	
 	
 		and the babysitter was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> with her baby
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so that ended that  episode uh she was most upset over over
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		finding this
 	
 	
 		yeah i bet
 	
 	
 		so uh she they kind of had decided that the day care was better there is uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> they and the age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are separated and uh
 	
 	
 		well nannies have been an option uh but i know that at day care they have more of a a routine like at uh maybe in um preschool would have where they have lessons and so forth and so on
 	
 	
 		um-hum hum
 		yeah story time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the this one has been particularly nice it uh
 		it kept track of what they did and they would tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> what they did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> you know if they said anything or did anything so it kind of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kept it
 	
 	
 		gave you an idea of what your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> was progressing in or doing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i often i always thought that if you were checking into a day care that you would be good to get references
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that had been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> care but was no longer there
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		because they wouldn't have nothing to worry about saying you know if there was a problem they they would i think be more ready to tell you what it was
 	
 	
 		oh i think so because if they were still there you know they might not
 	
 	
 		they might not say anything
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		other than how else how do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> other than from what others have uh what you see uh the cleanliness and that type of thing
 	
 	
 		you can't really you can't really unless your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> would be old enough to say something and usually they aren't at that age
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know um
 	
 	
 		but it would be real difficult to pick you you know to find one and decide
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i know i uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> i i tended some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i i wondered if i would have to be certified or wheth er they'd just bring them and and we got to where well we were just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and so they said no don't do that we'll just bring them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then if it was a problem then then we'd sit down and talk about it but it never happened to be a problem and and so things worked out okay and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> played with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and it worked out well
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah yeah
 		uh it worked out good i'm going to i've decided i'm going to babysit my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> granddaughters
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		since they'll be going back at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		i'm going to give it a try i i i sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avon and Stanley</ENAMEX> products and
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i've got that worked out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he's retired so he's going to deliver my products so i'll do my orders and that by phone
 	
 	
 		well that'll be great yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh i'll be able to keep that up a little bit but i think i think i'll enjoy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i bet you'll have some great experiences with them
 	
 	
 		doing it yeah i i think i'll enjoy
 		i i guess i kind of miss having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> around  a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> around or something  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		sure why not
 		and and you know the grandparents uh i always hear it's always fun when you can send them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> instead of
 	
 	
 		right that's right  well they do say you enjoy them more uh somebody somebody said if they knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> where so much fun they'd of had them first
 	
 	
 		well
 		that's right
 		well uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lives right over here and she takes care of them sometimes for me and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just is a lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and have always appreciated when she's sat with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> always said she would not let me babysit because you do hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> complaining
 	
 	
 		and
 		oh  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know
 		because they're stuck with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> so much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they're the ones that complain a lot are the first
 		
 		
 	