
 
     		
 	
 		okay where have you been on vacation lately
 	
 	
 		um well the last vacation i went was to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cozumel</ENAMEX> and that was last uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March and April</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		have you got another one planned
 	
 	
 		not at this point
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		although if we take another vacation i think we might like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancun</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time</TIMEX> have you been there
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we went there well actually i went there before i got married i haven't been back with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX> yet but  he is very much wanting to go there and since i have some free tickets with some frequent flyer stuff that's where he wants to go
 		but um also since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> my in-laws just moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> we're kind of pressured to go up there and go snow skiing and i've never been snow skiing so i'm not really into that i would rather do the beach scene
 	
 	
 		i agree i mean if i'm going to go on vacation i want to lay out in the sun and relax
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		drink  tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		definitely do that
 	
 	
 		and someplace i'd like to go is like to the other side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> as you you know as opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> side i want <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink rum drinks</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		lay on those beaches over there
 	
 	
 		like in the in the Virgin Islands
 	
 	
 		that sounds good another place that i heard is really pretty is uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cayman Islands</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		although i hear they're expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah that's definitely true well i got a magazine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean Life</ENAMEX> and it had um
 		different charter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> in there where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> could could charter a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> and everything but um
 		you just pretty much go wherever you want to go and they had great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> rates so like if you do it before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> or something like that you really save <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a ton</NUMEX> of money and i would love to do that
 	
 	
 		well our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> anniversary is coming up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> uh-huh yeah and uh
 	
 	
 		oh really i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		i'd like to you even if we just get away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four days</TIMEX> i think it would be kind of neat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just to do something originally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> we were hoping to do a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't think that's going to be possible now
 	
 	
 		um that'd be fun
 	
 	
 		now that is probably the number one place on earth that i would like to go um-hum
 	
 	
 		really
 		wow well all the pictures i've ever seen of it has just been gorgeous but i don't know i think i think i'd
 		there's other places that i would rather go first i think maybe
 	
 	
 		like where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um Australia</ENAMEX> and down in there i mean the the pictures i've seen of that even um
 		oh i had a  when i was in school i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> that was from um
 		oh i can't even think of the island <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> but she told us just wonderful stories of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and and the pictures she showed us and all that i can't think of the place now it's a pretty big one oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think that's an island but that's okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh i wherever she wherever she was she was out you know on the edge but anyway she uh had some great pictures and i always thought that would be fun to go there and they have great beaches too
 	
 	
 		well the main place that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> would like to go is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really yeah
 	
 	
 		um-hum he's been talking about that for years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX> that would be fun yeah when i was little i always heard how romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio</ENAMEX> was but i would like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tahiti</ENAMEX> too that'd be fun
 		but even just like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> it was fun when we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mackinac Island</ENAMEX> that was pretty cool
 	
 	
 		that's uh up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> yeah we talked about doing one of those drive around trips you know you drive around
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Michigan</ENAMEX> and then you take the ferry over to the other side and um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but i'd only want to do that in the summer
 	
 	
 		yeah because it i was there at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of July</TIMEX> and it was still pretty cool
 		so yeah i'm not not a cold weather person at all
 	
 	
 		no neither am i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um um um i think that uh once we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> refinanced we're going to probably try to take our free tickets and either go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancun</ENAMEX> or
 		do the little uh trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX> and then on up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 		so i don't know we'll see
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nick</ENAMEX> just got back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> last night and he said it was absolutely gorgeous and i haven't been there since i guess it was seventy three
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and uh i'd love to go back that was just one of the prettiest places on earth i have ever seen
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i'm going to uh work in a business trip and go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do you work in a business trip
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you'll have to ask Bill how my business trips work
 		
 
 		they work very well  and i have definitely needed a business trip lately
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well since you already set up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX> there's nothing left for me
 	
 	
 		well that's true hadn't thought about that
 	
 	
 		and it doesn't appear we're going to be opening any new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well they could get really big though and hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and then you could have to go train
 	
 	
 		that'd be all right
 	
 	
 		yeah tell them to do that
 	
 	
 		i guess we're straying from the uh the vacation part of it
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 		but i mean a trip is a trip
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right i'll go anywhere
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh i would too in a drop of a hat fortunately we aren't tied down with uh any other little <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legged responsibilities we can go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you can do that yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah makes makes a big difference
 	
 	
 		as a matter of fact i was offered a free ticket air ticket <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> if i want one
 	
 	
 		well take it
 	
 	
 		well
 		eventually i might but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archie</ENAMEX> offered me a ticket um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		well good
 	
 	
 		and uh i thought we'd you know i wouldn't want to just take it but he has <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and a couple of other ones and he said they just go to waste
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>'s going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> i haven't been there for so long
 	
 	
 		ooh i love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		such good food
 	
 	
 		and drinks
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  well and even just to go sit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and listen to the jazz that's so much fun oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah or watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or the hookers go up and down the street
 	
 	
 		oh God yeah that's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i ever saw an actual transvestite i think was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i saw them in uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> i went to a shore a show you know one of those transvestite shows
 	
 	
 		really
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		that was something
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i guess i'll go take my shower i've been working out so i'll do that
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well i'll talk to you later
 	
 	
 		okay now do you push the buttons now
 	
 	
 		
  
 		no we just hang up
 	
 	
 		okay talk to you later bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye
 		
 		
 	