
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well we uh taxes
 		everyone thinks taxes are too high i'm sure but uh i think we do get quite a good value for the tax dollars we spend in most cases
 		what do you think
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i i think so i i
 		uh
 		i i think i'm i think i'm uh
 		a little out of the ordinary in that that i i uh
 		i think i'm more worried about the deficit the national deficit than than uh a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are and think that we need to we need to
 		either raise our taxes or or cutback on something and i don't know what to cutback on to to get to get that to get that settled and and uh
 	
 	
 		at this stage it's hard to tell
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i know i'm a real a real uh out of it in terms of taxes so i'm not i'm uh think that the we really ought to seriously consider what an income tax might do that
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and and
 	
 	
 		well at this stage i think we've taxed property almost to the limit because like the the property taxes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> have reached the point that it's precluding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from being able to own a home
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		because of the cost of the taxes on them i know i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> and it's up over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year for taxes on my house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but now we're getting public services the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and if it weren't for the taxes we're putting in there uh look what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> could cost you
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah now i'm uh uh oh i we'd when we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson Richardson</ENAMEX> one of the reasons we chose it was for the uh for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and and realizing that that
 		that quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> might well have higher taxes than other places but that we were willing to uh to go for that because we supported the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		then again the the community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college system</ENAMEX> here is excellent for the dollar spent and the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> also the tuition has got to be among the lowest in the country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh one of the uh i believe i don't know which one it is uh down there whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hobby</ENAMEX> or uh
 		the other ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> down there that are proposing doubling the tuition well if you double the tuition it would still be considerably less than the public school tuition in most other states
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah that would provide uh
 		possibly some relief there to utilize some of the property taxes for other things see the so called sin taxes on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX> and the cigarettes and such as that generate a considerable amount but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i pay eventually i think you may tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of smoking even
 	
 	
 		i i don't i don't know about that i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah  well i quit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		i i see okay no uh
 	
 	
 		i couldn't afford to start again
 	
 	
 		yeah well that that that would be true that would be true but
 	
 	
 		i know uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would give up eating before they gave up their cigarettes i think
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but all the various taxing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> that come through i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tax i resent the most though is the additional sales tax for DART which is probably never going to be in existence in my lifetime
 	
 	
 		yeah and and even if it is isn't going to uh uh
 		provide you with any any services in that it's not doing to provide a route from your your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to a business for instance you know
 	
 	
 		well this this is a thing i think it's like uh back east you had to start your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> transportation when you started your cities you can't come in afterward and really be successful or economical at it
 		if we had been like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> or someone like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and had a public transportation system starting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">buggy days</TIMEX> and when land was cheap and uh construction costs were cheap you could afford it but now digging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Expressway</ENAMEX> and things like that becomes cost prohibitive
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and
 		yeah and the other thing is that when it when it's the public transportation is established that early on then then the business uh
 		business and residential patterns develop to take advantage of that whereas in in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> here we've we've got uh
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		those patterns were well established <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">before</TIMEX> before we really tried to tried to do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DART</ENAMEX> and uh
 		
 
 		for instance all the all the the uh
 		office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and stuff that are out here in in uh north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> as opposed to downtown uh to try to to try to provide
 		efficient transportation from everywhere around the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the metroplex</TIMEX> to to
 		uh both those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> of of business plus everything else that's scattered around here and there
 		as opposed to having a concentrated business area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> does yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah just take like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> depend on the public transportation system to get them everywhere new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't even own a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and know how to drive a car
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		right right
 	
 	
 		someone made the analogy uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> as being like the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> an old cowboy would jump on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> to go across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street well</ENAMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> will jump in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to drive across the street
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i'm just as guilty as anyone else
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i drive to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> by myself uh without even even any thought of car pooling
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and uh most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are that way
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		because they're used to not having public transportation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so but i here again i think the thing i resented where they were collecting the sales tax for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> before they turned a spade of dirt
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so and doing all these studies and the things we saw about them traveling to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> to see whether they wanted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> foot wide or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve foot</NUMEX> wide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i felt that was a little uh wasteful use of the tax dollars that we were paying
 	
 	
 		a little bit much oh yeah yep
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yep we could
 	
 	
 		well that's about all i can say at this time
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i think so i think that will probably do it so
 	
 	
 		okay it's been real nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		good enough bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	