
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well this is a very timely topic in as much as we're going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		oh are you really where is it going to be
 	
 	
 		down at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Texoma</ENAMEX> lodge yes this is one that's uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and this has been going on at least uh i would say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least twenty five years or thirty</TIMEX> something like that maybe longer than that i'm going to get back into the fifties sometime
 	
 	
 		oh that's marvelous
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i got i married into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i went was about fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh this one has been uh
 		been well organized
 		and in fact it used to be at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Brownwood</ENAMEX> and now it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake Texoma</ENAMEX> because that's more central location for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> to come to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i'm sure location is really important as far as figuring out where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ought to be
 	
 	
 		very important because uh you'll start losing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if it's too far to go
 	
 	
 		um-hum we have factions when it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part we i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reunion on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side and we found that if it's in a certain part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come and if it's elsewhere other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come we never get them at both of them it seems like so i think we need to find a new place
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		never get them at both places
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		listen they've uh they've had this one well it just of course over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> it has uh built up as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is concerned but now they uh have a golf tournament on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		and then they have generally a show or an auction or something on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to help raise funds to cover the costs of such
 	
 	
 		oh that's a neat idea
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh everyone uh they get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> building there at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Texoma lodge</ENAMEX> and everyone brings in food
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> dinner they bring in like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Fried Chicken</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durant</ENAMEX> and uh it really uh has worked out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> are involved
 	
 	
 		uh generally uh i think it's been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as high as about a hundred and twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think normal is about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> or seventy
 	
 	
 		wow
 		yeah well i guess um ours probably isn't that big our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is dwindling for one thing
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i often feel funny because i'm in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> that's all but died i just have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and my family
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so sometimes when these other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> get together they're really pulling in aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> and we're kind of off on the sidelines
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it does remind us that we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and roots so we keep going even though we're not a real big part of it
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah well our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> started reunion started out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> the newlyweds so to speak
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now we go our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> go and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> are going now so it's uh wound up that uh we're the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but um they have various organized they have generally a volleyball net set up and horseshoes uh to pitch and they organize a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> bring boats
 		and there's a place they they take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> up to the lodge and go swimming up there in the afternoon so it it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full day</TIMEX> some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come down on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and spend the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> and some just come in for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there's lots to do
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it uh has worked out quite well and it's a chance to see some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> you don't see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> long except that once a year
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's true
 		well that's neat i i think they're really fun we go to mine regularly and then we go to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s occasionally down in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> and he has a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so it's it's fun when we go to that one
 	
 	
 		yeah my side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is from back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> and i think we've been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five years</TIMEX>  or something like that so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that's just too far away
 	
 	
 		oh it would be more yeah yeah that that is a problem with the distance the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we have that don't come are out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX> way and it's just too much for all of them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> drive just to get to this area
 	
 	
 		all of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to travel right
 		but then we have the same attitude when it's out there although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we're going out they're going to have it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Davis</ENAMEX> and we thought that would be
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		fun to kind of tie it in as a vacation time as well as reunion
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we have uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> of course they elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion and a number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> back in the early eighties my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> we discovered how much work it is just to organize and get it together and it takes a lot of planning and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and choose some place that everybody's going to like
 	
 	
 		assembling of stuff
 		right
 	
 	
 		as far as food and all that
 	
 	
 		that's correct
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		that's a heavy burden
 	
 	
 		yes it is  i i i don't really care for her to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but that is uh
 		it's it's a lot of work but it's a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've enjoyed it and
 	
 	
 		well i think
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> really enjoy it because it's the only time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> they see all their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and it's it's good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to know that they have other family
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they're all excited The show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend this weekend</TIMEX> is going to be a rock and roll show my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> grandsons and one of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> are are going to dress up and lip sing to a rock song you know in jeans and T-shirts and such
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 		oh what fun
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's uh it's going to be exciting for them and for us too
 	
 	
 		um-hum probably lots of laughs
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there have been some really wild shows put on there
 		they uh really get uh into it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it sounds like you really have a good structure and have it going along ours ours is still kind of loosely organized and the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> usually get stuck with doing it and
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		oh that generally happens
 	
 	
 		they do it as a labor of love so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> idea is a good idea
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah well we've uh had various things over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> uh to raise funds for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and again it's not it's not cheap to rent the lodge up there or the meeting meeting room down in the cabins and such but uh they've come up with they've tried passing the hat and they've had auctions and various things to raise funds and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's not fair that everybody not contribute
 	
 	
 		
 
 		excuse me
 		but um anyway that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion story
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well thanks a lot i enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		been nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	