
 
     		
 	
 		okay well i'll start off being controversial i'm in favor of it
 	
 	
 		that doesn't necessarily mean you're controversial
 	
 	
 		well it seems to be in the current situations but uh i still feel that it could be a deterrent to crime particularly with the increase of serious crime that's going on now
 	
 	
 		well i think that those crimes which are punishable by the death sentence
 		need to be reevaluated i think there are other crimes that could easily draw the death penalty and not make me feel bad at all crimes against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is one of them
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah i think that
 		oh definitely any any crimes against person
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i feel uh there should be more than a slap on the hand and being sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and being released in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		actually i would like to see the system revert a lot back to some of the forms of punishment that exist in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> if you steal you lose a hand
 	
 	
 		ooh yes that's yeah
 	
 	
 		you know uh  if you kill you lose your life what's wrong with that
 	
 	
 		i don't see a thing wrong with that i believe that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		well it's just an an example i think there's uh someone that's on trial right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area and they were interviewing the it's a a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> was killed sometime back a a young girl
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a personal trial and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> was asking a sup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> question of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> outside well how do you feel about this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they you know i  thought that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do they feel about it i'm sure that uh
 		they want it over with and they want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> punished and punished properly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		deciding what that proper punishment is is one thing i think that there should be no way
 		i i realize that innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could go to uh what is it lethal injection now
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could do that but for every innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who would be executed hopefully there would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> guilty
 	
 	
 		yeah well i feel like the the cost of someone someone was quoting figures made the cost at like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		uh the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum to maintain a prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> that's right that's stupid
 	
 	
 		to keep someone in prison
 		and well the problem there is they're not keeping the right ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in many cases there are more and more instances
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's right
 	
 	
 		being on the news where this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> was out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> on probation or parole and killed someone else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		or seriously injured someone
 	
 	
 		well i don't have solutions to the problems but you know you have these this would be nice if and there's probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of holes in that theory but i think that if you
 		did something for example to an individual and caused them to lose the ability to earn a living i remember a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> drove by
 		randomly shot a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> while she was driving blinded her
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think then that a life sentence to restitution is appropriate i think he should spend the rest of his life working to support that individual
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes indeed
 	
 	
 		or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of an individual
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh who has been harmed you're you you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen policemen</ENAMEX> who are killed in the line of duty they may or may not have been willfully intending to kill that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> still has no provider
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well here again anytime anyone goes out with a gun in their hand and crime on their mind
 	
 	
 		and i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the opportunity exists for someone to get killed
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		now i'm not in favor of gun control
 		to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n-th</ENAMEX> degree or anything because uh
 		there are uses for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> which are non criminal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it seems that the criminal element are the ones that are using them uh aside from domestic disputes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> or vice versa
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> if they have a gun with them i think that the the sentence should be even longer than if they don't
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't agree with the length of the sentence though i think expediency is the answer
 	
 	
 		well
 		well but here again uh if a matter of expediency part of these costs like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row</ENAMEX> is that their appeals can take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> there should be some uh i know there's a law i believe that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		it's automatic appeal if it's a death sentence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think that automatic appeal ought to take place
 		uh within a reasonable length of time say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a decision be made and not drag out
 		in the courts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> because of misplaced commas or whatever technicalities there might be
 	
 	
 		that's right technical i think that there should be a statute of limitations on appeals
 	
 	
 		right there's there's got to be a there's got to be a time limit
 	
 	
 		you you you can appeal it once
 		i think if it is appealed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and the appeal is turned down or the sentence stands then you might be allowed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more appeal if it is if if it is contradictory
 	
 	
 		a a legitimate a legitimate appeal not a technicality of uh if
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and they're not arguing that the guy
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> committed the crime they're arguing over <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> were his civil rights violated because uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		someone didn't file the proper paper at the proper time those are the things that have caused them to drag out i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right well one of the sad things is that so many of these
 		never actually come to trial because of
 		of the process in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> were apprehended
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is guilty you know he's done what he's done you you may have stood there and seen it but because he wasn't read his rights whenever he was arrested
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know he he goes free uh-huh uh-huh yeah
 	
 	
 		he didn't see his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> as quickly as he should have or or some some
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mickey Mouse</ENAMEX> type thing like that
 	
 	
 		right and i realize that that is designed to protect the innocent it's also designed to line the pockets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and uh i
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		i just don't think that i think we could get along a lot better in our criminal justice system if we had some statute of limitations on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>  i hope you're not a lawyer
 	
 	
 		yes
 		no i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> i it's i i i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> and i agree we practice law ourselves because it's too expensive to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>  to a degree
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		absolutely that's why you check books out from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> but i really believe that
 	
 	
 		there you go
 	
 	
 		our justice system is is the best around but it's not perfect and that doesn't mean that you leave it in tact
 	
 	
 		well it's it's a case that we have a a legal system which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> have found a way to
 		use and a way to benefit them rather than the public itself
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		that's how we get caught in this uh sort of a catch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but you have to continue uh
 		to protect the innocent you're giving an open door to the guilty
 	
 	
 		that's right and and it i don't know there just seems to be so many clever ways to avoid the real intent of the law by following the letter
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that just that really does ruffle my feathers at times i mean i can just get so aggravated about it
 	
 	
 		yes  it does most people
 	
 	
 		but
 		you know it's it's going to take smarter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than me to solve the problem and and i hope not lawyers
 	
 	
 		but again one of our
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our problems is that uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> and the state and our national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> there of are lawyers
 		
 		
 	