
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well let's see um i i like to go out to eat i really do but being from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> um i think we have an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that open and close <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> month
 		we have a really high turn over rate oh yeah and and this is i mean there are <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> just called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant Rows</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		uh you can get everything here from um a very spicy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> to you know the favorite barbecue and and uh just anything your little heart desires around here so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		here they have to entertain us to make us come back and i guess it's all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big game because you you just never run out of places to go you really don't  yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 		that's good i never really thought about that but uh a good turn over would be sort of nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> if you find a place you like and it works out that no one else likes it would be sort of sad to see it go under
 	
 	
 		really and and we go to you know like an older part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and we just notice how many oh well that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>'s changed and oh gee there they've changed  and oh we've got to go try that one you know and it's it's really you have the pick of the
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		are they big into ambience ambience down there or is it more like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> to me makes it seems like it would be portions would be the big thing
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		yeah you know your your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen</TIMEX> ounce steak with your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX> and stuff um you can get that too no they've got everything here from the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Room which is ultra ultra to um um
 	
 	
 		yeah right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Ferrings</ENAMEX> uh uh restaurant which is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mansion</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle Creek</ENAMEX> i mean we've got beautiful places to go you can get as dressed up or as you know just going to the local barbecue and just doing take out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so you know i guess uh some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> that we really enjoy though are the um um likes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we're always searching around for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and now of course they've added the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> and and um uh there's
 		you know
 		any any part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you want to hit they have got it i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> we went to you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> it's great it's good stuff you know but it's so it's very very mixed and uh you know i think
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> like we do i i don't know if that happened before or after we moved here but um  yeah you get a lot of uh great variety of things here
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so
 		but if you were going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> say um where would you go
 	
 	
 		oh well we had uh
 		we have a lot favorites here uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Virginia</ENAMEX> and of course we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> to call on you know and there's all sorts of things down there one thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> is that there are a lot of traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> where you know it's
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> used to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> and so he stays in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> you know and he's got a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so there are there are some hangouts if you want to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know it's it's sort of like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> in a way because there's there's favorite haunts for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		um
 		we don't hang around with them because usually it's you know ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> a plate or something silly like that
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		so uh but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that work runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> down there and we've been down there and had <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX> and
 		um i don't know i don't particularly care for that sort of thing just the the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> just because i do like uh you know getting a meal
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and uh most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> food always leaves me hungry for some reason i i don't know what they say about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> i'm always hungry after a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's true too
 	
 	
 		and uh but the the atmosphere is just wonderful you do feel like you've gone out you know and done something when you go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> downtown well as out here you might
 	
 	
 		to another place
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have enjoyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> and go away feeling satisfied it's not so much a an event you know out in the suburbs when you go to a local restaurant
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		and there's they're starting to get a little bit different um they're they're realizing that more of the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with the money are coming out and living in the suburbs getting away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> so there a couple of jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that have jazz bands playing while you're eating and stuff like that which is kind of nice
 	
 	
 		oh there you go yeah
 		oh we're sort of in the middle of uh the extension of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cajun</ENAMEX> country too so we have um a lot of ambience provided by you know the the bands and everything you know like you said jazz bands and things like that you know you go out and you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you eat your crawfish and jambalaya and stuff you know i i really don't like that stuff but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does he loves to cook it so he and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of his get together and they cook i mean you know like for a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's really in fact we do a lot more entertaining i think at home than we do going out so when we do go out we really you know want to be wowed by um the presentation so to speak
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh you know but but there are little places um and like i said some of our very favorites are the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> just to and we do a lot of take out because everybody's so busy running around and it's the fastest thing to do and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we sort of enjoy the you know both parts because
 	
 	
 		we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> very special places in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Virginia</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go to uh one's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Pell</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is a crab house you know being so close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland Maryland</ENAMEX> is you know a big place for crabs with the with the bay pretty much taking over most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ah
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Pell</ENAMEX>'s is a place with the big huge wooden tables inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just go in there and just
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> out and everything and then um
 		the other place is called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vienna Inn</ENAMEX> which is uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 		and uh that place is known for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rudest</TIMEX> waitresses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are are at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vienna Inn</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go there to be abused i mean
 	
 	
 		
 
 		just to be abused by the meanest waitress
 	
 	
 		you actually go in there to be abused by the by the waitresses and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bartenders</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's a talent
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> amazed at um the abuse they received
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then it's on the honor system you pay totally on the honor system
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and so you know you tell them what you've eaten and what you drank or whatever and they figure out the bill for you and you're lucky if you get change usually they they take your change and throw you a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mints</ENAMEX> in your hand and say thanks you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because um
 	
 	
 		got to carry through with the abuse huh
 	
 	
 		they
 		yeah carry on with the abuse they say you need needs <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mints</ENAMEX> here <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you don't get any change you know
 	
 	
 		oh gee well that's funny i we just went to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> this um just wonderful and they
 		and it's like being in it i mean i've never been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> okay but it's just this big beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> very um low key in terms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> you know so they have their own adaptation of
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> is i mean but it's it was a wonderful wonderful experience know they have uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> there going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX> going to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Methodist Univerisity</ENAMEX> and and graduating in opera or something like that and they're all singing arias to you and
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and just walking around the restaurant singing and they make the food right there so it's display cooking and
 		and uh then they have wine casks all over the place so you're lined up waiting in line for this place and you just take a drink of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and you know and they don't count that really they just
 		
 		
 	