
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um well do you uh keep a family budget or or do you have some
 	
 	
 		no i don't use a family budget my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who's very old has kept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> his entire life and i probably rebelled rebelled against it and probably should have kept one he keeps every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> that comes in and goes out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh interesting
 	
 	
 		on a very strict percentage
 	
 	
 		yes well um we sort of started doing it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> started graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> when we were first married and i sort of just got in the habit i guess and you know and never have gotten out of it
 		i can't really say that it's a formal budget it's more just a a pretty um a fairly uh accurate accurate um recording of what i spend and what i think i'm going to have to spend and
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		i think it makes much more sense and i've recently uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		gotten out of debt and everything and i'll probably keeping start keeping a little better track of it i just uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		spent whatever came in and and uh didn't never knew what came in what went out but uh just you know like about like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> runs
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah  sounds real similar
 	
 	
 		huh
 		so i think it's probably better to have some sort of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a at least a record</TIMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s was so precise that i mean if it said to spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> percent on something that's what it was spent and
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh my yeah
 	
 	
 		that was put over there and i mean uh of course he's from the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so uh you know it's his life but uh i i would i think it'd be smart if somebody would keep uh
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		some sort of a plan that works for them
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you're right um well it it what's been sort of interesting to us is to um it because since i have uh pretty much kept my record books for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last fifteen years</TIMEX> i guess
 		i can go back and look and it's real fun to just see what how things have changed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> uh for instance
 	
 	
 		yeah it is  i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had kept them i think since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen twenty seven</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 	
 	
 		but he burned the ones from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven</TIMEX> to fifty i couldn't believe he did that but then so i took the ones from fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> on to the present but
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 		yes
 	
 	
 		to look to have looked back into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenties</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> and forties it would have been fantastic to see that but uh
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		well as a matter of fact uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was going through some things uh not long long ago i guess it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>  in an old trunk that she had
 		and she came upon a budget a budget book that she'd had back in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> uh when they it was the late well i guess it would have been i take that back it must have been the forties because they had been married uh probably fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> at the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was just fascinating uh fascinating to see how little things cost i mean it was it was just almost laughable in some instances that you know of course it's all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> of course but
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i know right right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> never the less it was fun to see those figures next to you know for a price pair of shoes was uh like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i know well even in nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty three</TIMEX> i found a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a record</TIMEX> that i had  had traveled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> a lot and i what i'd paid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollars</NUMEX> a night now and i paid uh oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between four</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> in nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> and that's really crazy because that's about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh isn't that something
 		really oh that is that is really really something
 	
 	
 		oh but but of course it's just what the market'll bear and if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> then why charge ten you know yeah
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		yeah that's good that's right that's exactly that's just good old economics working
 	
 	
 		right right that
 	
 	
 		well uh we've tried to uh instill some sense some sense of uh of budgeting in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are just uh as um unlike as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night night</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> could care less about a budget and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> watches her pennies so closely that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she almost she almost just sounds like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> i mean she has everything planned so closely closely that if something goes wrong it just throws her for a loop
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well then you never know how they'll one they they may switch flip flop when they get to be uh older well older the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> may be very careful and
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		she may marry somebody and of course it'd be good because if you marry somebody a little loose then she'll have that stability of watching uh you should have one in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the in the</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think that's true i and and it's
 		i kind of think that's sort of what happened in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> because i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was not quite as uh good at saving and so on before we got married and i was i was really diligent about that i always putting money aside and when before i was married you know when i was working in and out of college and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh that really paid off because when it time came for him to go back to graduate school we were in in in fairly good good shape financially as far as not having many major debts and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's about the way it is here if it hadn't been for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> i would have probably been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">debtor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> if we had one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 		but uh what does you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> do now
 	
 	
 		well
 		uh he is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> he's uh an electrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and in fact went through uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> of graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and got his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> so we had a a lot of lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of budgeting
 	
 	
 		oh
 		um
 		oh yeah you have to do it when you're in school my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s still in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> getting her doctorate and so i it it and i've got
 	
 	
 		and you know yeah when you
 		uh yes
 		well i'm working i'm working on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> degree now so in fact this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three two</NUMEX> both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were in college our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has a year left our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> graduated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and i'm uh just about ready to finish my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> degree so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've had uh once again you know some really a real lean year for us
 	
 	
 		oh i i know we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in college plus my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> so that was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> so we're both in the same
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		yep yeah you know exactly what it's what it's like then and it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		which you learn i guess you figure that that's an investment that is um really a invaluable invaluable um-hum yeah and
 	
 	
 		that's the best one yeah with education you can't take that away from you
 	
 	
 		that's right so it's it's one that you can live through and i think that that's way we looked at it in our beginnings when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is that there was a light at the end of that tunnel you know that
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure
 	
 	
 		that it was worth it to save and then not have uh something and uh in return know that something  better was going to be at the end of it so uh it really makes it easier but uh well i've enjoyed talking with you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true yeah
 		i have enjoyed talking wit h you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i wish i could hear more about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> part of your life because that sounds really fascinating to me i'm interested in that
 	
 	
 		well if i had your address i'd send you i am also in the travel business i do tours and i can take some real great tours to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> so uh if you
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh wow well my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i just were there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> um actually we didn't take a tour we we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and and uh went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and just rented <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and and did it on our own but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i uh that sounds interesting do is your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		yeah it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quorum</ENAMEX> so i'm i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Hammond</ENAMEX> and i'm out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven College</ENAMEX> so you could just holler at me out there yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh you're kidding well i'm going to be teaching at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven</ENAMEX> in the fall  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuenzer K U E N Z E R</ENAMEX> and i'm i'm going to
 	
 	
 		all right well what's your last name
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K U E N</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh Z E</ENAMEX> R
 	
 	
 		well good i'll uh
 	
 	
 		and i'll be in the communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> teaching uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English one O</ENAMEX> one to i have a couple of sections yes yep that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who hired me yes
 	
 	
 		oh well i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zack Miller</ENAMEX> real well
 		so
 		uh all right well wonderful i'll look you up in the fall then
 	
 	
 		well
 		fantastic good well it's good it's been a good talk conversation uh-huh bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	