
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Maureen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		uh
 		we are supposed to be talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and spending time with them today
 		neither one of us have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but it might be interesting if we talked about what we thought we would do if we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or perhaps you know what some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> do and what we approve or do not approve of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh do you have nieces and nephews or anything
 	
 	
 		no unfortunately my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are both only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now we do have like some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> that are we're kind of close to and sometimes we see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that's going to be the closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nieces</ENAMEX> and nephews that we can come up with is our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins kids</ENAMEX>  they do not live close to us but uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact we were going to ask uh his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> to try to make plans to have her uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come maybe visit this way for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> and of course you know
 		things sometime you get to be the uh the tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and we will take them to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> Flags take them to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wet N Wild</ENAMEX> i mean they may not be real quality time but
 	
 	
 		it will be fun though
 	
 	
 		yeah it will be a real treat for them you know to kind of come and do that because they live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> so they will be something real out of the norm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i used to uh used to have a neighbor in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> i lived in and she had  at the time her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 		and i used to spend a lot of time with her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we used to go to the pool all the time it was an apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> so we used to the pool and
 		you know just kind of play around and do uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> games and you know uh have picnics out there that kind of stuff that was our normal thing we also uh
 		she had gotten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those uh laser disc <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and we used to get uh some movies which is kind of hard with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> sometimes to you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		get some movies that are enjoyable for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and not always a strict <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> thing you know when you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year olds</TIMEX> they want something a little more active than a cartoon
 	
 	
 		i'm sure
 		try <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Otis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis</ENAMEX> what is that with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> like the dogs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have seen bits of that like on uh cable or something picked it up i think somebody was showing it recently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's really good my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i rented it and as a matter of fact we kind of like shows like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bambi</ENAMEX> and everything sometimes we will go to this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> and we are the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> you know and we spend money  but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis</ENAMEX> is good and i think any
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would enjoy that
 	
 	
 		um that sounds cute well we had one silly movie that we used to watch a lot because
 		they were kind of expensive when she got that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> uh we did not have too many movies we used to watch Airplane over and over and over again i mean have you ever seen that movie
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it's real silly
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but um and it's it's fairly clean there was only one little section of it that they probably edited for TV  but uh we used to watch that a lot i mean that was just real kind of flap stick kind of fun stuff we used to watch that with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably some of that went over their heads anyway
 	
 	
 		some
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		you know
 		there uh her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer cried all summer</TIMEX> long they wanted to go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> Flags
 		you know and they see these ads on TV uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Flags</ENAMEX> looks wonderful and we took them there and then they were too scared to get on the rides
 	
 	
 		oh so you got to walk around and watch everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they wouldn't get on any of the rides even if they were you know tall enough they did not want to get on any rides
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they cried <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all summer long</TIMEX> when are you going to take us to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> Flags i want to go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> Flags you know they kind of chickened out
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i was noticing i have  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i i would say that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is probably like one of the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> she
 		it's just one of those kind of deals that she spends a lot of time with him she listens to what he has to say and he is turning out he is thirteen he is turning out to be a really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think uh whatever she has done you know she has done it right but i think it takes and awful lot of time and effort to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i watch our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and everything they do is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> related
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh it's like their whole social lives kind of flow around
 		where they are taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and what they are doing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um which may be part of the reason we never had kids
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but they are time consuming i it appears to me
 	
 	
 		well you know one thing that that you know i kind of say we have only been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> but um
 		you know i think so many times in the past you know like even <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years ago</TIMEX> i mean it was just expected or kind of pushed upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you get married and you have kids
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whether or not there was something that inside you really wanted to do
 		and i i like it now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make the decision you know okay i am going to be married
 		and then yes or no whether i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> it's not so much a  society dictating to you do this you know it's everybody is supposed to get married and have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> if you do not want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> fine do not have them
 	
 	
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are beginning to where they do not view you as such a social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh well you still get you know particularly if you are around a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they still tend to look at you a little strangely if you do not have them but i am running into more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have opted not to have kids
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i do not feel quite so bad
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean uh you hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> well there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that marry later and then they are very set in their ways and there are activities that they do and well i really do not want to make that sacrifice i have
 		you know been single all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and or you know we have been married and we have all of our  activities and i do not want to change my whole life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or i came from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that i had a very bad childhood and i do not know that right now
 		i could have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and and cope with it i have too many bad feelings with my own childhood and maybe i will turn out to be you know abusive like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they say you know i i do not feel that i want to do that which is fine you know i i think that's a wonderful decision on their part if that's how they truly feel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not you know everybody saying when are you going to have kids
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's none of your business
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		it's my option to do that you know you do not just have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because you know you are supposed to somehow as of the old days
 	
 	
 		right or you do not know any better or there's nothing available
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was from a family of of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and she was the youngest and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> when she was born and she said you know so there was hardly anything from her father
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		there was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> between her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was forty
 		so you know it did not make the best situation for her you know to have uh you know good family kind of situation there she had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> that kind of like pushed her  around a lot because they were so much older
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yea h it was not the best situation but yeah
 	
 	
 		who
 		yeah plus when they are that old you know it's not as though they are going to go out and rough and tumble with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> would
 	
 	
 		right right although i mean we are we are in our late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i and we are still considering it and
 		you know i think that i have kind of done the right thing i mean i have i was just really shocked to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> who is a bit younger than i and she was one of these types out of high school you know
 		
 		
 	