
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh yes yes i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> yeah she's only about uh uh a little less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you how old is she
 		
 
 		uh  i guess you have not reached the stage where you need to uh
 		promote a college or anything huh  i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and one that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> so we uh we started saving but that's all
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so do you is there are you planning to like encourage your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to go to a particular school
 	
 	
 		uh um  no uh um no particular school uh i think that's really
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no such decision that
 	
 	
 		that you are going to let them make
 	
 	
 		that
 		they well help them make in terms of you know what they are they are wanting to do you know that that's a big influence i think and you know what not only what you can afford but what
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		what's going to be best for them in terms of what their career goals are
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		uh you know you need to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that handles whatever it is you want to do
 	
 	
 		yeah where did you go to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh was that local or uh
 	
 	
 		uh well it was
 		well it was in within the state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it it wasn't necessarily local it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but i i mean so what's
 	
 	
 		what's the criterion for choosing to go there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh well at the time i was uh thinking of going premed and in the state uh they had the best premed uh curriculum for the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> it was choice between there and uh a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that uh was a bit more expensive at the time we really could not afford it so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i ended up going there although it was quite a drive away for me it uh i enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		so you did you commute everyday then or oh okay
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 
 		no it was a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six hour</NUMEX> drive
 	
 	
 		oh okay when you said it was quite a quite a way away i did not know it that meant you had to drive like an hour or
 	
 	
 		well well
 		i was uh
 		it it was like another world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		basically it was a no it was a
 		did not get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that often you know and at that age it's uh it's kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		kind of difficult sometimes too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		especially if you have not been away a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that that extended
 	
 	
 		so did you go there like straight out of high school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh see i did not get my degree until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> on so i just finished <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i guess
 		you know when you have to do it that way it makes makes your choices a lot easier but
 	
 	
 		uh that's true
 		yeah that that's like you know when i went on to get my my masters i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		basically
 		was you know it was where i was at the time you know i wasn't gonna
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		try to pick and go somewhere else because i was pretty much settled and i was trying to work
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but uh so when you are first going to school that you kind of have the luxury of being able to have some latitude in choosing the place to go
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		yeah
 		what which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> do you work in in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um uh the computer science center
 	
 	
 		oh uh where is that at
 	
 	
 		uh north building
 	
 	
 		i see
 		how long do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		did you work somewhere else like sounds like you got your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> before here or
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i have uh uh
 		no actually i mean i came straight from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to here so
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so cause this was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first first</NUMEX> real job after getting my degree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> after your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> or after your
 	
 	
 		after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> my undergraduate degree was not in not in what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		i see
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so i made
 		career change basically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i see
 		well let's see  i have not you know there's a lot of pluses and minuses for different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know just like you said
 		uh depending on what they want to specialize in and what you can afford different things like that so i i have not really made up my mind you know whether to encourage them to go different places or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i mean i would like to uh you know the uh i i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where i went i mean and i would not
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hesitate at all to uh to encourage her to go there if she wanted to or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where i got my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> at which which was a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		right right
 		right
 	
 	
 		i liked it almost as well uh but uh you know that i'm not going to hold them to that just because i went there i you know think that's If they want to that's fine but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		otherwise not although i can uh would get quite a break on on tuition  yeah because they uh allow for uh
 	
 	
 		um because you went there
 	
 	
 		uh tuition uh break for out of state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of alumnae
 	
 	
 		i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		well certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> do it this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> does so uh it's been  been interesting i i was involved in some uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh alumnae recruiting uh here in town uh recently uh well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> uh and it was kind of fun because you are trying to
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> interested in your school you know and they were this was a college <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at a at a high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> and it was and there were a bunch of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know and a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> probably there all competing for the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it's kind of interesting to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to to talk up you know your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and i was surprised by the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that came came by and had heard of you know our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and and were interested in it
 	
 	
 		yeah your old school
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh you know we uh you you situations like that you don't realize you know until you start thinking about it the kinds of advantages you school may have over others
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i i was real real pleased with that that worked out so well
 	
 	
 		yeah so did you drum up any interest then or
 	
 	
 		i think so i don't know offhand but uh it seemed like there were quite a few
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that were definitely interested in going there
 		so there there was one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who uh came by right even before we started who who obviously was uh very interested in getting her her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in or or
 	
 	
 		and that
 	
 	
 		having gotten her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in or something and she was wanting some more information but she was her her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was uh
 		a a majorette majorette drum a majorette or something you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">baton twirler</ENAMEX> or something and she was  she was letting us know she  how how
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was she had cards printed up actually describing you know business cards describing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s uh you know she had won several different twirling awards and all this and she was
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		had these business cards she was passing out and it was  quite a production  i think some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> go a little bit overboard
 	
 	
 		yeah it sounds like it well you know i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> is probably you know one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> that would definitely
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 		
 	