
 
     		
 	
 		okay i'm back on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um you say you watch evenings mostly
 	
 	
 		i watch evenings because i work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> i used to watch daytimes um mainly like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All My Children</ENAMEX> that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh so
 	
 	
 		and then sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> and sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donahue</ENAMEX> but now it's mainly evenings
 	
 	
 		do you have any that you like well enough that you tape them when you're not going to be there
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		which ones
 	
 	
 		i tape <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thirty Something and L A Law</ENAMEX> those are the two i like the best
 	
 	
 		oh
 		that's a
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> they're going to change well one they're taking off i don't know what's going to happen yeah we like L A Law we don't watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirty Something</ENAMEX> but that's kind of young for us my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> so we don't watch uh
 	
 	
 		i know it's going to be history i know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well well
 	
 	
 		that type of show but we like L A Law we like that we're just i'm sorry they're breaking the team up because we liked all the ones that were on there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i know i'm amazed
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure i like the new ones too much
 	
 	
 		huh-uh i'm surprised that i was surprised at the ending of you know with all the funny things happening and
 		different things
 	
 	
 		i just wonder if if uh they just want to go on to
 		other projects and not be
 		stuck in this show since it's gone on for so long it looks like it looks like it might be one of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight year</TIMEX> run things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where you kind of can spend your whole career on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> show of course i guess that's not bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Alda</ENAMEX> did it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MASH</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i know
 		i know isn't that funny
 	
 	
 		it hasn't hurt him at all so do you do you mostly like this type of like a story type of thing that lasts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i don't usually like stuff that continues that's why i'm surprised i like those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> shows because usually i like you know stuff that just ends sort of that you just you don't have to have watched you know
 	
 	
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Leap</ENAMEX>  that's one of our favorites
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean you don't have to
 		yeah you don't have to have watched it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in order to follow so
 	
 	
 		right which they do at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the season</TIMEX> to grab your attention
 	
 	
 		you know i usually don't like that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's always a bummer too sometimes it's better just to tape record both of them and then watch it all in one
 	
 	
 		i know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we we do that sometimes i i guess i'm i'm not into real heavy stuff L <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Law</ENAMEX> is about the heaviest thing i watch i i'll mostly i'm into it for relaxation
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so i like things like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Golden Girls or Cheers</ENAMEX> or uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> is real good with me you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Major Dad</ENAMEX> and and uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Northern Exposure and</ENAMEX> and uh oh what's that one with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burt Reynolds</ENAMEX>
 		that type of show is what we what uh we watch we generally just stay on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> all for all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> just to watch those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just uh some of the times they're continued but mostly they're just little vignettes a new one we found we really like is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dinosaurs</ENAMEX> have you seen that that is it's it's really funny they use
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		like animated it's not like a cartoon but it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummies</ENAMEX> and things that are used and uh it's really um and robots probably but uh there's always a a moral to each story
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and what night is it on
 	
 	
 		well you we watched it the times we've seen it it's been like on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> or excuse me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> uh but it's we've only seen it a couple of times but it
 		it's real the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one we saw um uh they were uh it it involved a tradition
 		of when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person person</ENAMEX> reaches <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seventy five uh</NUMEX> and i can't remember what day they call it but but uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>-in-laws get to throw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-in-laws when they're seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> over a cliff  anyway
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		anyway it it goes on you know and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> are sniping at each other and all and then when it comes time for him to throw her over well the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the teenaged</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before tried to save her by hiding her
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and she said no you can't do you know he ran her out was running to hide in a wheelchair to hide her and she said you can't do that uh this is
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		tradition this is what old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are supposed to be thrown over the the cliff and uh he said i don't understand it's it's real funny that they give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>
 		the as the one that questions um the what's going on and uh in the end of uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> when he did get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> up to the cliff uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> the teenaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> throws himself in the way and says no you can't do it and then and then uh oh well we've got to do it it's tradition and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was you know why and so in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> he doesn't throw her over and of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> thinks he's just terrible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh he doesn't
 	
 	
 		because that has been tradition for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and
 		he's broken it and then we saw one where this there was a teenage
 		when a boy teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> comes into his manhood they call it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of the howling or something like that and they all go out and howl you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> refused to do it he he did he thought it was not no he wouldn't go howl so all the all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that worked with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> ostracized him
 	
 	
 		so he didn't go howl
 		oh how funny
 	
 	
 		it is it it it's it's real interesting to watch the show and and what the relationship between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is is really now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> lives in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with them so it's our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> is the one that that got us to watching it but it really is
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it moves real fast it's a real short and there's always like i say a moral to it and right <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> that that's all there is to it and and uh they
 	
 	
 		it's just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX> or is it hour
 		oh
 		there's not many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> shows it seems like that much
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it they they're trying to liken the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in there of the teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Gleason</ENAMEX> Show uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the way he talks to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> and so forth and i guess maybe there are some parts of that but i didn't really see that in there but what i've read about it they
 		talk about that but anyway we've we've enjoyed that and and uh i guess mostly i i like the news shows too and the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty seconds Minutes</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah no i watch those if i around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prime Time Live</ENAMEX> or something like that you know all all of those shows if i if i can do it but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes to watch uh
 		old movies especially war movies or or uh sports which i'm not
 	
 	
 		oh see i like sports
 	
 	
 		no i don't well i i do i like ice skating and i like uh gymnastics
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> but i i and i'll watch snippets of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> games and i i just don't have that much time to sit and watch the whole thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't ever no matter what's on i don't ever just sit and watch TV i'm usually either doing dishes or i may be sewing or you know i always have or letter writing or i may be working around in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">room</ENAMEX> somehow but i don't
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		i don't ever just sit and i that's something that comes from your old age you know idle hands are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">devil</ENAMEX>'s workshop no it's it's uh
 	
 	
 		no i don't sit
 		i know who has time i don't have time to sit i know
 		that's why i don't get to watch that much i mean i watch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine o'clock</TIMEX> i do okay because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are all in bed but before that i really there's not much time or like at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six thirty</TIMEX> i'll watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wheel of Fortune</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		right well our yeah if our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> if our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> are with us that's they have to watch that we don't watch it unless they're here  but they uh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh no i like that no i'll watch game show kind of stuff but
 	
 	
 		it's it's um oh and you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will get you started on stuff like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funniest Home Videos</ENAMEX>  we've wound up sending in one that's something i didn't think that we'd ever do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		did you send one
 	
 	
 		yeah our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> pulling his tooth he's he's he wouldn't let us pull it and i mean it it got to the point he was eating a pear here and he bit into it and it was just hanging by a thread
 	
 	
 		how funny
 	
 	
 		and i and i'd tell him you know it's getting ready to fall out and he walked around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with his face face down toward the floor and his mouth open hoping it would fall out because he wouldn't let anybody pull it
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he wound  he wound up pull
 		
 		
 	