
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Pat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the interesting things that i have considered about the role change for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of my age my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> were trained and taught and brought up to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leave It to Beaver</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX> but we are not living in that world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we are certainly not our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have changed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> uh-huh oh yeah sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> has changed everything has changed yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's one of the and it makes you really concerned i am glad i raised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you know let the world train them what to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but characteristically you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are trained or have been in the past trained in the home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i really would be at a loss to to raise and train a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> i think i would
 	
 	
 		yeah it's well
 		even even raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> today is different though because they are expected to do so much more than they used to you know used to be they would just go off to work and come home and you know everything was done and it it's a different world
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's some good some bad uh
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's nice that there's a choice i i have chosen to stay at home and raise my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year old</TIMEX> and a twelve year old
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> for awhile and worked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that was great i was able to and i was able to provide for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and and you know that was wonderful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i um i thank God everyday now
 		that i have that choice and that i am able to do things at home and and uh i volunteer a whole lot
 	
 	
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that's my job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and i i love it i really love it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		i did very much the same thing until my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> got into high school and said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> please do not be involved
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		then i went back to work
 	
 	
 		right and that will come i know that day will come and i am looking forward to that too but that's a different phase in my life and i am i am glad that i am able to do what i want to do right now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure
 		right
 		right
 		well you know there's a lot of things that have happened actually and and it's
 		it's it's like the it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> on top of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> it changes but it's never different in a lot of ways
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time did very heavy physical labor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and were expected to maintain a household
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then as times changed
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we do not do a lot of physical labor even in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> even in housekeeping and homemaking there's not a lot of physical labor because there are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 		right you are not beating rugs you are not right doing laundry by hand and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 		and in that respect we have to make ourselves become involved in physical exertion or we really do develop some health problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so in in that in that respect i am not so sure that the hard work of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years past</TIMEX> was not better for us than we are willing to admit
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		but don't you think it's that way with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> too i mean you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are sitting behind desks a whole lot more
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely true it's that's true with society in general
 	
 	
 		than they used to
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but specifically the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s role in society has changed and you know medical medical reports tell us that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are developing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		diseases now that used to be predominately male <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases heart disease</ENAMEX> was characteristic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> now there's almost equally predominant in women
 	
 	
 		right right
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress disorders</ENAMEX> and things like that uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh right and i think that that's a that's a symptom of our society it's a symptom that there's there's a general illness that needs to be healed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do not know what the healing process would be or what was causing the problem i am not i am not God
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but i i do know that in raising my boys
 		i really did meet a lot of pressures saying you know you need to get them into music lessons you need to get them into sports you need to get them into this they need to be busy and they need to be active
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i fought all of those things i said if those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> want to be involved in that they will come to me and they will say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> this is important to me i want to do it otherwise i will guard  their ability to have quiet time
 	
 	
 		right right
 		you know it's funny
 	
 	
 		i refused to cram their lives full and that's the way it is with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's funny it's funny i was really i was really looking forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> thinking oh we are going to have some time off
 		and it's been real busy and actually today is really the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> as far as i am concerned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> of summer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because we have had so much going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you are right uh well that's how society has changed uh you know uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the family has changed we you know we find ourselves doing things that we never did as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh well
 	
 	
 		you know i do not remember being involved in things like this it's it's different it's just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just i do not know only time will tell whether it's better or worse than the way we grew up but uh it's it's just very different um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		of course
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i just am very much a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in quiet personal time if you do not have the time to talk to yourself who are you going to talk to right
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and i guarded my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s rights for that and i think that that's one of the things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are sacrificing that they should not do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they are sacrificing their time with themselves
 		there's nothing wrong with sitting and being bored if you thinking internally and you are working on your own self you are finding out who you are
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		right r ight but is not that difficult to do when you are working full time and have to come home and prepare a meal and get homework done and you know where do you find the time
 	
 	
 		well i think
 		um well in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place it's not your homework it's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s homework
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was always very careful to be there only when they came to me and asked me for help i helped them with exactly what they asked for and that's all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's a part of the problem that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have always had and that is accepting responsibility for things that really are other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s responsibilities
 	
 	
 		that's very true and then that way we have not changed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> have we yeah
 	
 	
 		they
 		they
 		that's right that way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> are crippled
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they are intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cripples</ENAMEX> and so are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they do not know how to think for themselves and be responsible for themselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for themselves i do not know why God made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> brilliant  i
 	
 	
 		didn't he though
 	
 	
 		yes but i do not know they tend to look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> as the one who solves all problems they are all things to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that's never changed
 	
 	
 		that's very true that's that's very true i as a matter of fact i was talking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> who said she has a new policy in her home and when her her family comes to her and says
 		fix this you know i am having a problem with you know another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> she said i have taken a new stance and i say no i will not you know you work it out for yourself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she said it's amazing she said you know every single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> expects me to get and they drain suck me into these arguments and these conversations and i have i am supposed to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		the one who is going to fix it all and and soothe everybody and she said i am not doing it anymore i i just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you know i think that's one of the things that we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that is very useful and i think every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> ought to deal with it or ought to at least be exposed to it and that is mediation training
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we are not talking about strikes or things we are talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> who get involved in family crises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> and employee those kinds of things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">interpersonal</ENAMEX> mediation because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> is an unbiased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystander</ENAMEX> who
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		
 		
 	