
 
     		
 	
 		okay what do you cook
 	
 	
 		well  i have dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> quite often and so we we really i really enjoy cooking um
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i like desserts and uh main dishes  i'm a chocoholic
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 		oh yeah well see i consider baking different than cooking though yeah i can i can bake
 	
 	
 		do you yeah yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well you know the best recipes that i have come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Living</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um do you get that magazine
 	
 	
 		no but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> tells me and gets it and just loves to get the recipes
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh it's wonderful you know i've never had a recipe fail that i've gotten out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Living</ENAMEX> and i've had dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> come over for dinner and
 		you know say i don't know what this is going to taste like  i got it out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Living</ENAMEX> it's a brand new recipe and i've never tried it before and and i've never had them fail
 	
 	
 		
 
 		wow that's great yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> used to like pick out a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and show us the pictures and say okay this is what we're going to have and we're like oh God no
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i well well that's what i do too and it has a it's been wonderful right
 	
 	
 		yeah she did really good she did really well but i mean like her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> they're frozen canned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">boxed</ENAMEX> and take home and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm a very picky eater so that's another part of my problem when i look at a recipe there's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredients</ENAMEX> that i don't like or won't taste and so it's kind of difficult
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah where you from originally
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and then i've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so you've had you you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tex-Mex</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing i
 	
 	
 		oh yeah definitely now see i love stuff like that but and a lot of it i will eat but there's ingredients sometimes that i'm just like i don't even know what that is
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah well i had never had chili in my whole life until i moved down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i had <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and i had never even tasted chili and i moved down here and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		where are you from
 		oh wow
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's hysterical because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have to have a refried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bean</ENAMEX> fix at least once a week  you know and it's like a week has gone by and we haven't had
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fajitas</ENAMEX> or or something and and i just laugh and laugh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would die if they knew all these things my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were eating
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 		how funny
 	
 	
 		that is funny that is funny
 	
 	
 		yeah we've always always had southern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is from the deep south and so she would do like the hominy and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX> and stuff and i couldn't do that
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		no no no i don't think i would i would care for that but you know what i recently discovered there's something um at the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cajun Magic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and it's like in the gourmet section of the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> it's on the bottom shelf and and it's um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">red beans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> already in it and all you have to do is add <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and and cook it and it is so good
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		that does sound good
 	
 	
 		it is good it is good and it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cajun Magic</ENAMEX> and i'm sure you could probably  you know i buy i buy it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albertson</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		okay i'll have to look for that
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">huh</ENAMEX> and it's in the gourmet section
 	
 	
 		well  you know where they have those kind of hard to find items you know the the real funny mustards and and that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> and things like that and that's that's where they have it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albertson's</ENAMEX> and it's really good i like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		huh
 		so your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't picky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eaters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		easy
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who will eat everything and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who will eat nothing so  as a matter of fact she's babysitting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> and she called and she said
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		mom they had the most wonderful dinner it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamburger Helper</ENAMEX>  and it's delicious
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		how funny
 	
 	
 		and i laughed
 	
 	
 		well that's what when i got married um
 		both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i had been living separately so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> wanted to give me uh a wine shower where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> brought recipes
 	
 	
 		what a neat idea
 	
 	
 		yeah it was really neat because they brought the bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and then they brought a recipe that went with the bottle of wine
 	
 	
 		oh how nice
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my girlfriends brought a really nice bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and she had written down the number to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domino</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i love it i love it when i worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one time</TIMEX> we had a thing where we had uh uh luncheon and everybody had to bring a dish and  somebody
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		gave directions to a to a bakery  you know turn left on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell Road</ENAMEX> and right on you know  and that was cute that was cute
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well
 		desserts are definitely a weakness but uh oh i love them and i'm definitely a chocoholic but i found something it's a white chocolate mousse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you like desserts
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that is just heaven
 	
 	
 		is it wonderful
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah but i wouldn't even know how to begin to make it
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 	
 	
 		but i need to definitely find the recipe and at least attempt it because it it's so good
 	
 	
 		oh i would love that i i like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm not crazy about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sweets</ENAMEX> but i really have a passion for cakes any kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> i i really like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate cake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um apple</ENAMEX> cake
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 		ooh i've never had apple cake
 	
 	
 		love apple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> oh i love apple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> or spice cake something like that yeah yeah i really like that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		especially in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> that's really good then
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah it is yeah it is
 	
 	
 		um
 		well i'm getting hungry now
 	
 	
 		and i just got done with dinner so  um we had beef ribs and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato casserole</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> yeah i do i well
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really what did you fix
 		um
 		God you really are a cook
 	
 	
 		you know it was so funny when i was when i was reading the things and they said you know checkoff different categories that you could talk about i thought food i could talk about food  have you not eaten yet tonight
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i i did i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> is really high and so he's putting me on a special diet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and that's what when the category came up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> i thought oh God i'm so glad this is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> and not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> because
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um he's putting me on a liquid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> diet and so
 	
 	
 		oh really was your was your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> that high
 	
 	
 		it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two forty</NUMEX> and i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only twenty nine years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so he said let's bring that down so he's putting me on some liquid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and i'm not doing to be able to eat for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		really wow
 	
 	
 		yeah i kept telling my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> while a go
 	
 	
 		is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two forty</NUMEX> really that high though
 	
 	
 		it is for for me and my age bracket
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		um so i think it's supposed to be one eighty and he thought <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two forty</NUMEX> was a little bit high for me
 	
 	
 		you know what i just recently got um a cookbook it's it's the oh what's the name of it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh Love Your Heart</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		cookbook it's a low cholesterol
 		cookbook and then i got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heart Association</ENAMEX> cookbook now this is not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Living</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah lots of yogurt and stuff like that but if you go to like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bookstop</ENAMEX> do you have one of those in Carrollton
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they have lots and lots of of uh cookbooks with low cholesterol recipes
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i every once in a while i get real ambitious and i think okay i'm going to do all this wonderful stuff and then that lasts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX>  and then i'm like give me the blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> dressing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i want a burrito
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah give me some more refried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> have you have you tried
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it's like like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX> says every once in a while you've just got to have ribs
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah oh yeah have you tried the the no fat no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> dressings like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kraft</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i i've tried them
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> is not bad
 	
 	
 		well see that that's part of my problem though it goes back to being such a picky eater the only one i like is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ranch</ENAMEX> which is like the worst as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> goes so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah and does it take have you tried that is it terrible
 	
 	
 		um i haven't tried the new ones that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart Smart</ENAMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">heartwise</ENAMEX> or heart yeah
 	
 	
 		i haven't tried the the newest one yet so what i've been trying to do is just cutback because i just recently even started eating dressing and the only one i like like i said is Ranch
 		
 		
 	