
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		and i guess the suggestion is that we maybe talk about a menu for a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> if we wanted to do something like that or share recipes or something um  are you one who gives dinner parties very often
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh sure
 		right
 		no
 	
 	
 		no nor am i  uh
 	
 	
 		i avoid them with all
 	
 	
 		they're a lot of work that's for sure yes yes
 	
 	
 		yeah they are i mean i do them but they're a lot of work i usually have them when i there's a special event in their lives and i i make a big deal out of it for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think i'm uh most happiest with my most familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> that i know are successful
 	
 	
 		yeah right yes
 	
 	
 		you know and i have uh i make my own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> and pie crust and you know i can make my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> from scratch i don't need a recipe to follow and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's great you sound like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who's been well i bake <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> too but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was always the famous pie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and she has the same the same technique i mean i guess after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> of doing it you just kind of do it <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> nature
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah you just know from heart i had one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that tasted my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coconut cream pie</ENAMEX> and she said make me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i made her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and when i when she gave me back the plate she said i didn't share this with anybody
 	
 	
 		ah
 		she enjoyed it huh  well there's a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> who is almost nearly famous for her apple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> and uh we had a
 	
 	
 		and i thought whoa  that was a big pie yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a an auction <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time at the church  excuse me and uh one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> was auctioned for fifty dollars
 	
 	
 		my word she must have a great pie recipe then
 	
 	
 		well i i think i i i've had it once and it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> but i do recall that it was quite good so um
 	
 	
 		wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah so that is her specialty um i like to bake um also i don't bake so much now that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are grown but i do enjoy baking and i guess i always liked making making um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX> and things like that that was more my specialty i suppose and they seem to last longer than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> around here <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> just would would go practically in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>'s time  yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah you that's right yeah they're meant for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> and you know it's got to be gone or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> gets into the you know the leftovers and puts <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two more inches</NUMEX> on his waistline and then he is  chastising himself afterwards
 	
 	
 		right  and not very happy huh
 		well it's interesting that uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> i had lunch with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and she was telling me that she had a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of hers for um a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her acquaintances one of her old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i guess had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and uh they invited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> over and so there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of them but uh i said well what did you have and she said what she had uh just <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food but you know she had uh uh you know guacamole and
 		uh i can't remember all she had but she also had made uh flan which is actually <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> i think have you ever made that or had it
 	
 	
 		no i have not huh-uh
 	
 	
 		it's it it it's um
 		i had used to work with a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX> who was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> who would make it uh and it's just a wonderful dessert it's like uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">custard</ENAMEX> in a uh caramelized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> uh was on top of it and it's it's quite
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		actually not very difficult to make but it's very very high in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> i'm sure with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> that are in it but uh
 	
 	
 		sure yeah
 	
 	
 		she said that she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had uh traveled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and and flan is almost uh a basic with every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> that you get there
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple pie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh it's just very customary to get flan so if you ever run into that you'll you'll sort of be aware of what that's all about but uh i would never have thought of making that as part of a a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> dinner but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">wow um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so papillas i guess would be another kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> if you decided to do something like that but  flan is something you can make ahead and have just uh you know have ready but uh oh i would have been thinking i would like to have a dinner party sometime soon but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i tell you it that i my it's one of those things where it does require some real uh planning and it's you know you don't just make the dinner you have your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to clean and you know the the whole business that goes with that
 	
 	
 		yes  um-hum
 		well when i have a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that's my motivation for getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> clean
 	
 	
 		yeah probably a good way to do it  oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> needs cleaning i guess i better have a dinner party yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we're catering a wedding um
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that is it at it's is at her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> she's not a a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX> so she's got to hire this crew
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to come in of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> prior to the wedding and get it ready yes and there you know she she must have found some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jewels</ENAMEX> because they start in the corner and work out
 	
 	
 		good heavens
 		uh
 		oh wow that's such a nice thing it's i you know until well we my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i've been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty six years</TIMEX> and until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i had never had another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> clean my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and then i got so involved and so busy i said
 	
 	
 		yeah so um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this is one luxury i'm going to let myself have every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> and so i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> come in uh once a month you know and which isn't very often but for me it was wonderful
 	
 	
 		sure yeah that's nice you know to have that that's a luxury today
 	
 	
 		well it is and it is it buys you time to do other things like have a dinner party  so it's just a real gift of time as far as i am concerned but well um i better
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i i have a pie crust that recipe that i that is unique that has vinegar and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i have heard about that but i've never tried it no um um well i should say i have heard of one that has vinegar in it i don't know that it has <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> in it uh-huh uh-huh do you have it right on the top of your head
 	
 	
 		have you okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar um</ENAMEX>-hum um-hum
 		um i no i think it would be too hazy because um the uh no i
 	
 	
 		you don't have it yeah i would i
 	
 	
 		well it's like the liquid is like a half of cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and then your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> and then your uh tablespoon of vinegar and you mix that together and then you you know your see it makes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		it makes uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie crusts</ENAMEX> at once so that's it's quite a volume of um
 	
 	
 		uh quite large yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cups of flour and like uh a tablespoon of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> and a tablespoon of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> and and you combine your dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredients</ENAMEX> and then you uh put in your liquid
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um what is it about the uh the vinegar that uh makes the crust better
 	
 	
 		it just it just makes it very pliable and and very flaky and you can really treat it rough and you're still going to have a flaky pie crust
 	
 	
 		ah
 		interesting
 		yeah yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that the that's the real secret um-hum
 	
 	
 		like uh it's not mine it was from uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> probably
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> and it said you can throw this on the floor and step on it and it will still be flaky and i thought wow that's quite a statement for them to make
 	
 	
 		oh that it makes me think of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> um
 		when i was visiting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> and she lived very near an apple orchard and
 		we just had we could take as many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> as we wanted from it according you know according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and so i decided to bake <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> ahead you know and freeze them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well talk about working with big amounts of pie crust and having it be tough  those were the toughest apple crust or apple uh pie crust that i have ever ever made it was just terrible i i could have used that recipe it sounds like
 	
 	
 		oh wow wow
 		well i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Detroit</ENAMEX> um-hum
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well we lived in um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's real close
 	
 	
 		yeah in fact i we were there from uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy three to seventy seven</TIMEX> and i was i worked for the little the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> there the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth Plymouth</ENAMEX> um oh what was it called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crier</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh how neat
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is from the upper peninsula so he was born and raised up there and that's where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> still lives so uh are you originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> or uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh okay um-hum
 		oh yes um-hum born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> um-hum um
 	
 	
 		i'll be darn and
 		
 		
 	