
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact are all grown now so i am assisting assisting uh them with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in their selections so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh great
 		great well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are grown but they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> so i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fifteen ages fifteen seventeen</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um about i guess about when the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> when the youngest one was in kindergarten i started working working at a preschool and uh you know doing some work and then i i took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> off and then went back as a music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in a preschool so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i am around not a day care situation but in the you know in the child care environment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		well i myself really feel like the structured day care program is more successful in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s environment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than  the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on one care is
 		uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were growing up i actually had them up and until they were in the preschool situation i had them in a in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who kept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i felt like that home environment was very important to them
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it was important to me and uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i feel like that they they had that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on one that's so necessary at that age however in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s environment
 	
 	
 		oh it is uh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it may be more critical to have the ability to interact in large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> simply because that's the way our young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are dealt with they're dealt with in packages
 	
 	
 		yeah in other words there're more people
 		yes yes that's that's an interesting point of view i uh you know seeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the school the way i do i
 		i mean i see the ones that we can always tell the ones that have not been around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at all when they come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as three year olds</TIMEX> as as opposed to the ones that have been in the program that started at twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> maybe and were were even in there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is all our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> provides for the you know for the under <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year old</TIMEX> but still they have an opportunity an opportunity to be with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		and it is true and uh i but i think that would but as far as looking for a place
 		you know i i the criteria i mean i think it's very important to have very caring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know to take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> if you're going to have the structure and you're going to have the large numbers you're going to need really
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely without a doubt um-hum
 		i recently stopped by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> and i was sitting out in their little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> while my granddaughter was playing on the things and was visiting with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who was there with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		and she was telling me that she was given the opportunity to manage a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and of course she was she had just gotten her degree and she was so enthusiastic and she was excited about it and she was going to accomplish all of these things
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		however uh when it came to hiring and staffing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who cared and who were willing to take care of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and spend that kind of time the pay is minimal
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		and it takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with total and complete dedication who really don't want to make a living for themselves
 	
 	
 		yes that's right that maybe
 	
 	
 		in order to be in that environment
 	
 	
 		yeah that maybe have another salary in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that where they can do that and that's what i had the opportunity of you know doing and and i could concentrate on the creativity and and
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know really having a lot of fun with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and and providing them with a great atmosphere
 	
 	
 		um-hum  well they ask so much of those caretakers for the amount that that they they pay they are to be there ahead of time you know they're there early to receive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		and they have to be there at sometimes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock in the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right and then then they have to work until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> until the place closes at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P M</ENAMEX> and then it's their responsibility to clean up and be prepared for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> because they don't have cleaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> in most of those
 	
 	
 		which is yeah
 		yes
 		yes that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh she just had a terrible time keeping sincerely dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> simply because they could not live with a kind of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and the salary uh and she
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't pay to provide and well ours is not you know ours is just is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and so we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we don't have the the expenses of a building you know we share the expense with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> but we don't have enough you know taking care of a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and that responsibility so uh it is it is a lot different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i know that when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> were small now my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was adopted so he went into child care at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>  and uh my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> went into child care at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so they were in that environment actually up until they became uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and at that point i said look they have been given the custodial care that they need and the after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> care has been as
 		good a quality as i can provide for them however they're going out into the school environment now they're under a lot of other influences i need to be here for them i need to be involved in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because i want to be the one
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		who influences the way they develop so i quit working after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> started to school and got involved in volunteer work in their private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so that i could help direct their their learning experiences and their development
 	
 	
 		oh you did
 		um
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i i felt like that anybody who cared and loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> could change their diapers and feed them and bathe them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and hold them but when time came to direct their ability to make choices
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to develop the kinds of things that that they're going to need to interact with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i felt like i needed some strong influence there
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's different than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do it i mean a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do it really the reverse and go to work after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are in school you know
 	
 	
 		so i did
 		i know
 		that's right once they get up in school um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well i just felt very strongly about that and i i did not work as a matter of fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade and when he started
 		uh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skyline High School</ENAMEX> i asked him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> when uh
 		you know where do i go to sign up for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTA</ENAMEX> and he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> don't do that to me please don't do that to me so i knew it was time to go back to work but i feel very good about spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX> with my boys
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yeah
 		yes that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i was just really grateful i only had one bad child care experience it was in a home uh the care taker that they had had since they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> just could not do it she was from um  uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Argentina</ENAMEX> and she was going back home and i couldn't just you know wait for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight three or four months</TIMEX> and then bring them back to her so i had to find a new place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		and i put them in this home the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> cried when i took them the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> cried when i could hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> crying when i went to pick the m up they were always cranky and irritable
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 		oh dear
 	
 	
 		so i just took off and went there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were left unattended in a room you know they they were not well cared for
 	
 	
 		oh how awful
 	
 	
 		and uh so it didn't take me long to take t hem out of that place but that's the only bad experience i had the rest of the time they stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Petite Academy</ENAMEX> and i was very pleased with their development and their progress
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they learned a lot of things in those public environments that you just as soon they didn't learn but they're going to learn it sometime so but for the most part they did have good care
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and it did appear to me that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who cared for them
 		had a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> for them and in one particular case they had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> program where they were to be taken to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> and taught to swim
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which just pleased me to death because i've always been have you know been afraid of the water however my uh older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> came home and he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> i don't like that man
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		oh
 	
 	
 		said he took me by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and dunked my head under the water and told me i had to get my face wet or i'd never swim
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 		oh dear
 	
 	
 		boy it didn't take me very long to hot foot it over to the school
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and relay that to them and she said well she said you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do exaggerate but she said let's go ahead and send him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX>
 		or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> and i promise you faithfully i will watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every minute</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh good yes
 	
 	
 		and see exactly what's happening
 		
 		
 	