
 
     		
 	
 		okay um do you own a PC by the way i'm guessing you probably do
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i don't have one in my home here my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um parents</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and they live just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about three miles</NUMEX> away so we use that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and my in-laws also have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and they're almost as close they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		right uh-huh uh-huh and what kinds of things do you use it for when when you use when you go to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> houses to uh use them
 	
 	
 		um usually
 		uh word processing something um
 		such as
 		oh forms for things uh also i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year old</TIMEX> that i've been home schooling for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and we got uh the one that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II E</ENAMEX> and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> who
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is who works in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> school district and so she got me copies of uh several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> programs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		great yeah
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> programs and so we use those and there's some whenever we go over and visit grandma the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> love to play the computer game so
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		that's part of it um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has used the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">folks house</ENAMEX> for
 		mostly business things uh his resume uh his uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		letter he's been applying for jobs and things so that type of thing uh forms for his photography <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well i tell you once you get used to having them you you get spoiled really quickly um
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm uh my father
 		had a software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and they have a bunch of computers leftover from that and we're hoping that they can put together something for us here that we can have the word processing here
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um they're kind of old older so i'm not sure that we'll be able to do get too many other programs for it
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah um i know i'm a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> by profession and uh when when i was first here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or in Plano
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and was finally able to this is oh been like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years ago</TIMEX> we moved here and i was finally able to afford a new typewriter and i got an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> Selectric i thought i had died and gone to heaven because  i thought oh they're so wonderful well then um
 	
 	
 		oh i have one of those yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>'s broken at the moment but
 	
 	
 		yeah  ours really needs to have some work done on it but but then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> um worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and i got a um this has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> he doesn't work there anymore but he got a um
 		um the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI Professional</ENAMEX> and brought that home and i learned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordStar</ENAMEX> on that and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> once that happened there was just no way that i could ever go back to doing anything of length on a typewriter
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah i learned i i learned WordStar uh i did some typing for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> when he had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and so i learned that on there too that was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah have you ever used do you use <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> ever have you ever used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		i haven't that's the one that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> well i guess i have used it once or twice uh it's the one that's on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX>'s computer he's got an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> and uh so that's the program that they're using there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah yeah that's probably where you've used it
 		uh-huh yeah um i have that on my uh computer here and
 		also um i work do some work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTD</ENAMEX> and um that's what they have there and it was just so nice to be able just to step into the position and
 		and already know the language you know already know the the software and um i don't know from my own experience um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> just just so much better than than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordStar</ENAMEX> at least the version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordStar</ENAMEX> that i used to have it may be improved by now but
 	
 	
 		that's what i've heard
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordStar</ENAMEX> was never very intuitive to me i mean you know you some of the commands just had nothing to do with what you know what you were supposed to be doing what they what they did on the computer computer but uh i mean like going um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		forward and backward a word or up and down a line that sort of thing just you know didn't match with the kinds of keys you were using
 	
 	
 		yeah you had to memorize it and
 	
 	
 		yeah and but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> is just a lot more intuitive in a lot of ways and you and it does a lot of things too that if you if you do any kind of uh
 		research or anything like that where you have to uh use footnotes it is just wonderful because it keeps track of all your footnotes
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh that's neat
 	
 	
 		and if you add it if you put a footnote in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the middle</TIMEX> you know if you come up with some new piece of documentation and you put that in the middle of your paper and have to footnote it you just change um it just automatically changes all your footnoting numbers for you
 	
 	
 		oh how wonderful
 	
 	
 		so you know it's just
 	
 	
 		that i had heard that that was better that was a better one
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and i think about how it used to be if you were doing a paper you had to go back and retype everything and uh it was just awful so um i don't know i think we have just become
 		really spoiled but i think it's a nice kind of way to be spoiled  so um well i have not really paid much attention to a clock although i think we've probably been talking <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least ten minutes</TIMEX> so um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i agree
 	
 	
 		if you um unless you have some other things you want to talk about as having to do with PCs
 	
 	
 		not too much what kind of what kind of things do you write
 	
 	
 		well um i was a technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> um and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i actually met in a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> um i was a tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and he was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and uh so i did tech writing for a number of years
 	
 	
 		oh
 		go talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> about it
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		excuse me  go on and talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> about it tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> i unplugged it for you but you don't need to drag it down the hall
 	
 	
 		got a problem huh um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy daddy</ENAMEX> came home and found her playing with the telephone that i had unplugged
 	
 	
 		oh oh trying to figure out what all that was about huh  but um i have um that that was the majority of my writing although um i have also done oh freelance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> writing and some educational writing and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um for a while i had a um uh a partnership with a in an advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who is a an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> so i did some advertising and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		now i'm actually actually i'm i'm not working anymore i'm a student i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> so i'm doing a lot of writing but uh now all of the scholastic scholastic nature so  i've done a little a lots of different kinds but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i just know right now that i couldn't have put out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of what i did if that much without the being in computers so that's been really great and uh i'm so i'm real spoiled
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm anxious some day to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here i'm they just talked to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day other day</TIMEX> about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		setting something up again so hopefully pretty soon we'll at least have the word processing my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year old</TIMEX> i've decided to teach her how to type using the computer so yeah i've
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		good
 		that's great
 		yeah well those are skills that she certainly will is going to need early on and you know the and it seems like it's getting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i think that that would be a real a real uh advantage to to her to have that and uh do it early so uh do you do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we've been we've been uh writing a story together and so i and i wanted her to put it into the computer and then print it out and make a book with it you know
 	
 	
 		oh neat
 		yes
 		right
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		and so i decided well if she's going to do that it would be a whole lot easier if she could type  so we'll slowly learn to to type here and then then put the story in
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's great
 		well that's a that's a skill that she can use for the rest of her life so  might as well start now huh
 	
 	
 		yes yes i agree
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nola i</ENAMEX> have enjoyed talking with you thoroughly this is really going to be fun i think and um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> and i think about all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that he talks to all over the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	