
 
     		
 	
 		what was one of the latest ones that you've seen actually
 	
 	
 		oh i guess i think we rented <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pretty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> a couple <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks months</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right the last two years</TIMEX> i have done more theater movie going than i have actually watched videos at home i've uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh become available to come and go more often so i said hey it's worth it i'll just go at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the matinee hour</TIMEX> and i can see what i please
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no more costly than renting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the last see i went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two or three weeks ago</TIMEX> and saw FX Two
 		and that is a really good movie if you like special effects kind of gory and lots of you know action
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh who's in that one i don't know if i have even heard of that one
 	
 	
 		um
 		do you know that i don't follow performers i don't follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> some i know some i don't um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that played in it he wasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> but the one that played in it that i liked best was the one who was in uh
 		oh
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> about the old people
 	
 	
 		Cocoon
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cocoon</ENAMEX> uh-huh he was a blonde haired heavyset alien
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		in Cocoon
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know what his name is
 	
 	
 		uh i think i know who you are talking about though
 	
 	
 		yeah at any rate i also saw not long ago Once Around that was with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dreyfuss</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and that one was just a very poignant story it it it had people it was it was
 		you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said it was a really funny movie but it was a very it was a poignant humor and there was it was like uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Steel Magnolias the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> played very well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		off one another and there was humor involved but the story was a very dramatic story
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i enjoyed it very much
 		what are some others that you have seen lately
 	
 	
 		oh i'm trying to think uh just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> we watched The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> For <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Red</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> again and that's one that
 	
 	
 		oh whoa yeah that's one i can watch over and over and over again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i was going to read while it was on but then when it started i just couldn't you know read that was a really good movie
 	
 	
 		it sure was and you know the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time you see it you understand more subtleties in it there are a number of good movies like that
 	
 	
 		yeah there's quite a few uh movies out now that i would like to go see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is not a real big movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goer</ENAMEX> and i guess more than anything that is why we don't go plus by the time you get a babysitter and then pay to go to the movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it just gets pretty expensive
 	
 	
 		right you don't work
 	
 	
 		no i stay at home
 	
 	
 		okay well you are going to have to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s day out and have him call in sick <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		go during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		that's right there's nothing wrong with that go in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early hours</TIMEX> it's a matinee it's not crowded the uh the price is as reasonable as renting a video
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's the way i do it and i go quite frequently if you are going to be planning on doing that now i was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warlock</ENAMEX> too which is supposed to be the story of a uh witch hunt that is you know magically shot into the present time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first five minutes or ten minutes</TIMEX> of the movie was i was very well persuaded to walk out
 		very well persuaded there was more gore than i was interested in seeing but then the movie settles down to a comfortable action uh i can't really that it would have gotten more than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half</NUMEX> from me either but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the action was comfortable and of course i enjoyed those good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> type conflicts things so i enjoyed that movie after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first few minutes</TIMEX> of gore and there were some others but they were done a little more tastefully
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh in the first scene the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warlock</ENAMEX> chopped off a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s finger because he wanted the ring and then
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		bit his tongue out and spit it off in the omelet and i could not handle that i said whoa i'm glad i have not had dinner
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		then uh i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Awakening</ENAMEX> that's a wonderful wonderful job by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter De Niro</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> yeah okay i think you said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> what did i say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter i</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> and he has done a really good job of characterizing
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled person</ENAMEX> and of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> always just has a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		an air about him that you can't help but enjoy what he is doing even when he's sad you know you have great faith that he will get happy again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then oh let's see there's a couple or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> that i would like to go see before they go into videos i guess i can wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another month</TIMEX> and they will be videos
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		one is Silence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> i've heard a lot about that one they say if you really want to be
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you really want some suspense that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to see and i understand that's a sequel to an earlier movie that showed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks ago</TIMEX> on television
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well you know i think i read about that too
 	
 	
 		um-hum  and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> i think it's time we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> abuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> movie
 		it's about time for one of those i want to go see that and i'm going to try to get in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh you haven't i've heard that is wonderful and
 	
 	
 		um-hum i've heard it's wonderful too but i it's just that they are both very long uh movies and the matinee starts before i get can get away from work and after after that i get involved in other things and don't want to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		don't want to go back
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard that's we uh we uh rented the other one i was trying to think of the other one that we had rented lately uh was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumed Innocent</ENAMEX> with uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> i guess he's in there and i thought that was really good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you know i saw that and i really
 		i cannot remember too much about it
 	
 	
 		it was the one where he was a defense uh not defense he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor prosecutor</ENAMEX> and there was a murder of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that was in the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DA</ENAMEX>'s office
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then he ended up being accused of it
 	
 	
 		oh that's right i remember now yeah i remember
 	
 	
 		yeah so i mean it really kind of had a turn at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> when you found out who it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum well i've had a hard time enjoying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> in anything since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indiana Jones</ENAMEX> movies i think he ought to stay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indiana Jones</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i realize that he would like his career to develop but i don't want to see him in other things
 		
 
 		but uh i tell you <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sean Connery in the Hunt For Red October i i</ENAMEX> never did care for him as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> movies i don't know he was too
 	
 	
 		i was never into those movies either but
 	
 	
 		i yeah i didn't care for the type of movie but he was always slick and greasy and seemed to be conceit ed and had more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> than he needed and  i didn't like him but he has really developed into a marvelous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character actor</ENAMEX> as he has come older i thought
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought he looked real good with a beard too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah he does and there is just a there's a
 		i don't know uh i think that beard gives him a look that he is always grinning whether he is or not and he he has that merry look about his eyes that looks like he stays in mischief all time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and i enjoy those and i enjoy i enjoy some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J Fox</ENAMEX> movies i didn't care too much for the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> either it just was not enough to it uh
 	
 	
 		what was the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i'm trying to think uh the last like Back to the Future then was the last one
 	
 	
 		no no no it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh  Hard Way</ENAMEX> where he was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> trying to portray
 	
 	
 		oh okay trying to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> or something yeah
 	
 	
 		trying to portay a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>
 		and uh that
 		
 		
 	