
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		i guess we are just to discuss trials and and punishment if it's to be given by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> or not did you did you catch your explanation of that okay
 	
 	
 		yes i did it's it's uh the uh
 		the uh maybe i'm a hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX> but i think that there should be some preset penalties in criminal cases rather than uh degrees of
 		sentencing
 	
 	
 		you mean the crimes or the punishment should fit the crime
 	
 	
 		right right uh again having participated in jury duty myself i know  i know how such a diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yes i did also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get together the different backgrounds different ideas that sometimes you can have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that can hold up what i consider the proper sentencing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> person
 	
 	
 		right
 		could you hang on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> minute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> thank you
 	
 	
 		yes ma'am
 	
 	
 		i am so sorry to keep you on hold are you at work okay i am too
 	
 	
 		no problem yes yeah um i think what you have is the way the
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		the justice system works is they bend over backwards trying to protect the guilty so many things in their back pardon yes i know
 	
 	
 		oh it's insane it's insane
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> participated in a jury trial
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years back</TIMEX> wherein the individual after it was over and they had came up with the maximum sentence
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		in the jury form they found out that uh the gentleman involved had a long history of the same type offense which was theft of uh property
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and yet the district the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX> could not enter these uh the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s background into it it was like this was a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time offender
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		whereas uh i think that's those that should be in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> should be in jail
 	
 	
 		it seems huh
 		that's correct and there's too much leniency there's too much uh um underhanded uh things going on that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> are not aware of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it seems as though we are uh giving the criminal the benefit more than the victim the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> has been victimized twice not only by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perpetrator</ENAMEX> of the crime but also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> that
 		try to do the justice
 	
 	
 		well i think this is one of the reasons that also that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> have such a a unsavory reputation shall we say
 	
 	
 		i do not have any
 		i don't have an ounce
 		in my body of credibility toward the the judicial system in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well what you got is the situation wherein uh if you ever get in trouble you want to hire the smartest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crookedest lawyer</ENAMEX> you can find
 	
 	
 		isn't that terrible
 	
 	
 		and uh that's not the idea it's the idea is not to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> off of the crime that he committed but to punish him for the crime he committed
 	
 	
 		well to punish him for the crime but also to try and reeducate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s thinking
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to get him out of that uh uh criminal mind that he has and to direct him into a more productive life
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well we have uh a situation again that i am familiar with where uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of an acquaintance of mine was killed while trying to stop a robbery
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh
 		yes how sad
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that killed him was a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had left the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with full intent to commit crimes carrying a gun in her purse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and anyway
 		it'd get to the she was sentenced to jail but then due to technicalities she was going to be out of jail within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> after she was sentenced
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		of course it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> for the thing the trial to happen so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		then uh there was a letter writing campaign that went in  and the parole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately a thousand</NUMEX> letters protesting putting this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> back on the street within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> after killing someone
 		and uh fortunately it worked they uh eliminated they corrected the technicality and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> now will have to serve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three to four years</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight</NUMEX> they were sentenced to
 	
 	
 		well if
 		yes if enough of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> responded
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to uh the direct the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> that are involved and if enough they will listen to the voice of the people
 		i have found that out that if enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> respond and rise up against the injustices being done something is going to change
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to be involved
 	
 	
 		
 
 		this is it and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't take the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and again the only reason  i took the time is because i was personally acquainted with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'm just as guilty as the rest in that respect
 	
 	
 		that's right you were
 		yes
 		uh but and i'm not making an excuse but we our priorities are a bit backward
 	
 	
 		oh yes well they again the and i'm not knocking the civil rights program or anything like that but we've gone
 		overboard to uh protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> from being having their civil rights violated to the point where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that is damaged is not
 		protected it's again the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> gets worse punishment then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that commits the crimes
 	
 	
 		that's correct yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		okay  i think we're both in agreement on this subject
 	
 	
 		well i am too i mean i i just can't i you know i served on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that was having a mental problem
 		and we found her not guilty because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> obviously was not in their right mind so if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is not in the right mind i mean they had to uh put her away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but for her own safety and for because she didn't know what she was doing
 		and we couldn't we just dismissed the case you know and and she was uh taken care of by the proper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		facility
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well another side of the coin that with our justice system there are a lot of frivolous cases that go to court there are a lot of things that could be settled out of court
 	
 	
 		yes that's true
 	
 	
 		which uh or should never have gone to court
 		and then the amazing thing of course is how uh
 		some cases can come to trial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX> and others it takes eighteen months
 		
 		
 	