
 
     		
 	
 		uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are both uh basically <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> they we've we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh one's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX> and one's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> and they they still live at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's that's a little unusual for uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of that age to have both of them that age at home but uh i guess the activities that uh we have with them are
 		uh  pretty few and far between actually the they're both going on their own most of the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh most of our activities are you know just discussion type things about what's going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and what they're doing and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		well we have a uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so we you know it keeps us pretty busy as you know
 	
 	
 		sure it does
 	
 	
 		and uh  most of the time with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year old</TIMEX> we're trying to to get him uh well we play usually in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> when when i get home you know about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five o'clock</TIMEX> or so until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight</TIMEX> and you know with exception of dinner
 		out in the front or back yard playing like uh tee ball off the you know off the ball and let him hit a lot of baseball
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> since we just got here here we got a uh a new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> wheel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> with training wheels on it for him and he really likes riding that around
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh yeah i
 	
 	
 		so you know i'm trying to supervise him with that and everything and uh playing squirt <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and all that and he really likes that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year old</TIMEX> just kind of follows along and does everything  trying to do everything he does
 	
 	
 		yeah is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year old</TIMEX> a boy a girl
 	
 	
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		ours is the older one's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> so and the and the younger one's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> so um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess uh what i see is so far as uh the trends uh uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh i don't know what kind of a area <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Beach</ENAMEX> is but course uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think uh the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> uh activities for for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now
 		are they're good but there's so much uh potential danger you know that you really have to watch your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so closely now that you you can't let them grow up the way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the way i grew up you know that i i'm from a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX>  and
 		i could you know go and do whatever pretty much whatever i wanted to do uh my whole life uh you know i never never had to worry about the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> being out there
 	
 	
 		hm oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i find that it's quite a bit different now that uh you know you have to watch your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so closely and uh keep up with them i i feel like uh that it's
 		it's really a sad commentary on uh you know on life in general that uh you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can't cannot be allowed to grow up uh you know without
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really close supervision
 	
 	
 		well i i agree with that and i seem i seem to feel the same way you know even just when i grew up and everything
 		and and the way it is now your it's a lot of supervision is in is in hand and everything uh the only other thing i have noticed though is that uh  it seems that there's been a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of or more emphasis emphasis at least in what we've been dealing with and and uh looking you know just start not even not really looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for him but uh like a preschool or something you know where he'd go maybe <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple hours a couple</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days a week</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year old</TIMEX> it's that uh there's a lot of emphasis on on on on education and what these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should know before they reach kindergarten
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it and it seems like it's a lot more they need they need to know and be able to do than when we are then when i had to go into kindergarten kindergarten
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it seems like it's more uh you know i don't know they're  expecting more or uh or just uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just because of the computer age or whatever it just know more but when they get to you know to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah  um i guess  looking at uh back at at what our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> did compared to what uh you know what i had to go through in school
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		the uh there is there does seem to be a lot more  in the curriculum it's a lot more complicated a lot more available of course
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh there seems seem to be a so much more to learn now that it it really makes it more difficult i would think i would i would probably have a hard time getting through school myself uh you know i just or at least it'd be a lot harder than it was when i went to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum one thing is i got a home computer too and uh  i play uh
 		with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year old</TIMEX> i play some computer games and stuff with him educational games like you know concentration type game  matching things like that  and uh he's he really likes it and and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think it's important because i think that uh you know it gives him the interaction with the computer because it sure looks like that's gonna be your you know the big thing for a long time
 	
 	
 		hm yeah i think uh
 	
 	
 		and given given that knowledge and stuff with it and he seems to enjoy it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh of course the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year old</TIMEX> hasn't hasn't gotten there yet but uh
 		and the other thing we try to do is uh since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>'s time's here is uh
 		sign him up for and her for uh different activities at like the rec <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> or something like swimming you know uh or soccer there's a little soccer thing that he's gonna do for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so</TIMEX> and uh you know where they go for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh because uh when he was a baby that we did the swimming too and he really liked it so we're gonna do that with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah that uh uh watching the little little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> is uh is more fun  i can't imagine that them having as much fun as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had watching them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know well we were just talking about that too and i guess it's not really soccer it's just kind of a well kick the ball around for a while  and see what happens
 	
 	
 		right yeah  disorganized disorganized disorganized play that's uh really really what it was but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah when ours was a he i guess he was probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> you know when he first started playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> and uh and it was it was more fun to watch those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> trying to trying to kick the ball up and down the field
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh and it i guess that was uh you know it was important uh  as much important to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> as it was to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that uh you know to get out and watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess one of the things that i think about is a you talking about education uh i kind of feel like uh
 		that uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> in uh particularly in this area the systems are not under enough control the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 		have a little too much uh too much leeway  excuse me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		and and and and that's kind of contradictory to what i said but you know you the have you have to be under control
 		so much when they're out but when they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they they don't have quite quite as much control over them as uh
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		as what i would like to have seen uh uh uh i kind of feel like there's there's too much allowed to go on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at</TIMEX> at school
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know it tends to uh
 		to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to not be as  you know to not concentrate as much on education you know they're they're there for a good time and you know to to see how little they can get by with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i know a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in the in the uh school district and down in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and uh it seems like it's a lot of the problem is to you know you always have the lack of funds but it seems to be getting worse and worse and so they don't have the resources to draw on to give as much supervision as as as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> need
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh you know that's just a problem that who knows how that's gonna that's gonna come out or anything
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		but uh i i i don't know i think uh you know some of the thing has to do with uh
 		with the civil rights program not that the civil rights program's bad but that there's it carried over into you know individual rights and it you know trickled out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	