
 
     		
 	
 		so what movies have you seen lately
 	
 	
 		well i saw um lately i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soap Dish</ENAMEX> which was a uh that was a lot of fun it was kind of a silly little film about soap operas and things
 	
 	
 		ah
 		well see that's something i want to see that's on my list to see
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it was it was okay it was not um
 		not a wonderful film but it was i mean it was it was cute but not the biggest laugh i've seen
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days ago</TIMEX> and really liked that actually i saw it twice because i  liked it so much
 	
 	
 		oh see that's also on my list
 	
 	
 		and it's very it's really disturbing but a good movie
 	
 	
 		a disturbing movie how do you mean
 	
 	
 		well it was um
 		let's see the um it's it's different it's kind of it's an action adventure kind of you know
 		shoot them up kind of film but it's with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in it instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> so that's kind of a
 	
 	
 		right
 		a switcheroo huh
 	
 	
 		that's kind of a twist on the normal thing And it made me think a lot about you know you would applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Hard</ENAMEX> if he was doing this but you might not be so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know so encouraging of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sarandon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gena Davis</ENAMEX> when they do it
 	
 	
 		when the shoe is on the other foot and see how it
 	
 	
 		so that was kind of interesting i've but i really enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so that was
 	
 	
 		because that that just reminds me of you know like back in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and you know the girlfriends just taking off for a day  or something just getting in trouble and probably not that much trouble but um yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's kind of what it was
 		right
 		they had started out with that then they got into lots of trouble
 	
 	
 		before we found the shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> that's  what we did  yeah well um i'll have to put that i'll have to keep that on my list then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i also saw that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> movie
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth and Dare</ENAMEX>
 		and that was pretty scandalous
 	
 	
 		scandalous
 	
 	
 		yeah it was kind of yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can imagine
 	
 	
 		she's pretty trashy so it was it was interesting
 	
 	
 		i guess she does it for the social value of showing you what trash is huh
 	
 	
 		right well i think she kept saying that uh they talked about her it it was a film of her concert
 		um tour she had taken through all all around the world and they were all  to her at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vatican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and wouldn't let her perform in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		kept saying that her show was not garbage it had a social message to it and
 	
 	
 		you just had to find it you had to wade through it and find it
 	
 	
 		right we never quite believed that so
 	
 	
 		you never quite  got to
 	
 	
 		i thought that was pushing it a little bit but she
 	
 	
 		all i know about that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is that she's an in incredible marketeer
 	
 	
 		yeah she's rich
 	
 	
 		yeah and she's rich and she you know so
 	
 	
 		she's smart at what she does she knows how to do that
 	
 	
 		she knows how to twist this around huh
 	
 	
 		yeah so what did you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well okay see we're getting back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that's probably the last  movie i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Dances With Wolves i</ENAMEX> just adored it
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		how can i tell you um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> i guess well maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> i i've read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bury My Heart at Wounded Knee</ENAMEX> and so you know just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the general theme of the whole movie was um pretty i mean i really liked it a lot i mean it was a real consciousness raiser i guess
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i only bring up <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wounded Knee</ENAMEX> because that was what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> you read and and understood you know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pop
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and then everything went away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> and now it's back again and you know it's
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		sort of a popular view of um what happened way back then of course no one will ever know really i don't know
 	
 	
 		right i know i was i wondered if uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> that they represented the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> that was the the evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> if they were really as bad as
 		they made them to be
 	
 	
 		well who knows i mean it it it sort of showed like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> like one was a warring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> and the other one was uh
 		vegetarian kind of you know feel good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> you know sort of thing so there possibly were because you know you always have conflict in the world nobody can get along peacefully
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah but i wonder i thought the because they made a big deal about how this this film was such a big leap for the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
 		who were the ancestors of these this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> and that you know that was so wonderful that they done that and they uh
 		i i wonder about how the ancestors of this warlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> if they were offended by the film if it
 	
 	
 		oh i see yeah
 	
 	
 		you know you didn't hear any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> about that i thought it was a very interesting movie
 	
 	
 		huh
 		well i think so i um i have come to respect a little bit more the uh
 		you know what went on here but but who knows how it's supposed to all end  you know on the on the broad scope i mean
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh-huh  right
 	
 	
 		um
 		like i said it it it had a much bigger thing i think meaning to me i think about you know just the meaning of um
 		the freedom of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and and what that really meant and that was taking over somebody else's freedoms and sort of trampling that and uh so
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it it meant something bigger i think but still it was a fantastic i loved the buffalo scene and
 		and i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> was just i got a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sick</ENAMEX> of his mug on the screen every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX> but he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> you know um but yeah i i just thought it was
 	
 	
 		i know the
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a really interesting intense film intense i think is the word for it because <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> went by really fast
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 		that was that was it was it was good i looked at my watch only a few times which is a good thing but it put me in a really it put me in a really bad mood i don't know why yeah we did there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us who went we were just all grouchy really grouchy when it was over
 	
 	
 		yeah ate a lot of popcorn
 		did it really
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so we decided that may be the mark of a good film it made us think and so we were grouchy we felt guilty
 	
 	
 		made you think
 		maybe it well maybe that was um but there are no answers you know
 	
 	
 		for being  i know and we we had  nothing to do with it we were not responsible but we still felt the thick blame for what had gone on we could have
 	
 	
 		that that can make you crabby yes
 		really that's true
 		but it it's
 		they sort of candy coated the western story for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> and um you know when the truth
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		oh well it always balances out one way or the other once you get the whole story but have you seen any other movies because you sound like you see a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well
 		right i do i'm just out of school so i've seen a lot of
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i don't have a job so i shouldn't go see movies all th e time um i rented a good movie um called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinema Paradeso</ENAMEX> which is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> movie
 	
 	
 		oh there you go
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which is probably the best movie i've seen ever it was just wonderful it's a uh story about a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> a little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> and he um
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		owns a um or he works in a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 		movie  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> and it it helps the projectionist there's a little oh an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who's the projectionist and he befriends this old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and then it just tells about their friendship that lasts through all these years
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it's just i mean if you don't mind reading subtitles i thought i had to kind of get beyond that those little you know reading the little words at the bottom of the screen but um oh i just laughed and cried and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i'll have to write that down
 	
 	
 		i really loved it that was a a great <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and other than that i
 	
 	
 		wow
 		have you have did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Texasville</ENAMEX> are you into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry McMurtry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i've had i hadn't i had read um <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Picture Show</ENAMEX> and but that's out on video now and i haven't seen it
 		but i was interested in reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texasville</ENAMEX> before i saw the movie did you like it
 	
 	
 		yeah um i i read a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry McMurtry</ENAMEX> books and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texasville</ENAMEX> is just like that it's like very peculiar circumstances and very peculiar
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do with each other it's it's you know and it's just sort of a
 		
 		
 	