
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh where you from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland Texas</ENAMEX> i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my lands  you're the farthest person i've ever talked to yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 		do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does yeah probably most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you talk to do huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh huh</ENAMEX>
 		most of them do now i don't have anybody that works for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> works for a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute</ENAMEX> of some something i don't know what
 	
 	
 		i see well that's neat
 	
 	
 		so i guess we're supposed to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess you have to push one though okay yeah
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh you ready okay
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh</ENAMEX> foods like you would plan for a a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or something like that yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so it may be interesting because probably here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we may eat a little differently than you do up there
 	
 	
 		well i don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> lives down <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> of us down there and i don't think they ate all that much different
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		uh i think as long as you plan your basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> course for a dinner party  you fancy things up a little bit more
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well uh the thing that i found interesting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i lived up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for awhile
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and up there of course they ate a lot of sea food and that kind of thing and down here sea <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is pretty expensive because you have to ship it a long way to get it
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		right
 		yeah and it's not as good as if it's fresh it
 	
 	
 		right and and uh and but here we eat a lot of like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> and um up there there was no no place that we went tasted like real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		is that right yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it tasted like they were trying to do the best they could but it just didn't taste right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they probably were trying to do the best they could yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and uh down here we eat a lot more fried foods i think like chicken fried steak is a real big thing and up there uh it was hardly ever heard of and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink ice tea</ENAMEX> with every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		up there hardly anyone drank <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice tea</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well they do in the summertime i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> big in the summertime mostly of course you have warmer weather most of the time
 	
 	
 		really
 		yeah
 		right yeah it never gets real cold so
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		yeah so i
 	
 	
 		yeah but when when we have a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> around here i think a lot of the time a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> menu is something real popular
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know that um i do a lot of planning with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and a lot of the times when we get together well everybody will bring a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> or and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is real big too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh more like covered dishes for those type of dinners
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah yeah how about you what is real popular up there
 	
 	
 		well i don't know just about anything
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah we we really uh use most anything i uh
 		i think are like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and that though are well like we had a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> here here not too long ago with a mystery dinner party  but basically we tried you know included all the basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uh foods</ENAMEX> that you are supposed to have in a meal here
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		your uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bread</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and your or least what it used to be the regular menu followed and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> and bake <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		uh something from each each area that you're supposed to choose from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we we we ourselves are into the wok cooking you know they been advertising that and we've really been enjoying those uh meals
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		they have a lot of vegetable to them and uh they really are very good
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 		oh yes i i love that kind of cooking my uh unfortunately i am married to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that eat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> things
 	
 	
 		is he a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>  well all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is is gone they are out on their own and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		they
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that probably makes it easier but
 	
 	
 		it it's much different and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah we find ourselves eating a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">macaroni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and uh  and of course
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> didn't like that so we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and we ate that when he he wasn't going to be home for supper that's what we had
 	
 	
 		uh
 		right yeah well that's pretty much what we do if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s not coming home we have macaroni and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they like uh spaghetti you know that's one meal i can fix and the whole family eats but there are several things that well as a matter of fact i keep chicken nuggets handy all the time because
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 		yeah yeah
 		oh those always go good
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> love them and uh they are real easy to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and that way whatever meat we have if they don't like it well and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		oh really well maybe that's good the way way the things are going
 	
 	
 		i guess
 		well yeah it could be because they don't i think it's the texture of it but it takes more chewing  and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> usually they like the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX> and that and it is easier to chew
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right so they're not too much into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i eat more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> than we should but at least we keep our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken nuggets handy</ENAMEX> for them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		we don't really have uh you know entertain too much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you do or not but we we don't a whole lot we're more once in a while but mostly family activities
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well most of the entertaining we do is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> associated we have a real tiny little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we don't have room really to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here but we do get together for what fellowships at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i do a lot of the planning in that and
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's good
 	
 	
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah we do a lot of that type thing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and our homemakers meet at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> also and uh that's what we do mostly most of the time for that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you don't really include any certain food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> you just bring what you like
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		sometimes you have all desserts sometimes you have all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's truth that's the only problem with just letting you bring whatever you uh like best
 	
 	
 		yeah but it doesn't happen very often usually you get a pretty wide variety and you can you can have a pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> from one of those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah i remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we had a progressive dinner it's the only time that ever yeah they are
 	
 	
 		oh those are fun
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the it's the only time that i can remember that i can't remember what food it was i it might have been the main <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> that hardly anyone showed up with
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were supposed to bring you know each like uh a an appetizer and a main dish and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> and we had tons of desserts and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of appetizers and
 	
 	
 		uh uh-huh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but when we came to the main main dish plate there was only like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		is there enough to go around
 	
 	
 		well not really you know we all took real tiny little portions and uh were kind of angry with whoever it was we weren't sure who didn't show up with the food
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they were suppose to keep uh
 		yeah that's kind of irresponsible but that what upset you because they are grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> usually and they know they know better even if they can't do it they can always need to get somebody else that could
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 		right either either go ahead and fix your dish or call someone that can i know it
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		well that sounds neat i can't uh believe you're so far away but you sound so close
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they said that we could share we share a recipe but i'm up at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s i don't even have any of my recipes with me uh you know
 	
 	
 		it sounds like you're here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		i don't know if i have anything handy we were just about we were getting ready to go swimming and we're waiting on my sister
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cara</ENAMEX> hold on just a second
 		as a matter of fact my little one is hollering
 	
 	
 		they're ready to go well i we probably have we talked long enough i'm i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i think it probably has been so i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay so i'll let you oh same here you have a good day
 	
 	
 		thank you thanks for calling bye-bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh bye-bye</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	