
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you subscribe to
 	
 	
 		uh the only one i subscribe to well i did subscribe to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i subscribe to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INC</ENAMEX> at the office
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosmopolitan</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		oh that's kind of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah it gives me a little variety anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's fun that's kind of fun well we have like every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in the world my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is kind of a chronic magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> he gets uh
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		oh gosh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bird Watcher Digest</ENAMEX> and i mean just almost  anything any interest he ever has for like a week he will subscribe to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of it
 	
 	
 		wow
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so we have got every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that that there is and then i get uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> because i like the the literature in it and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh uh i read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah they are always real interesting i remember even in high school that was one of our assignments to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and i kind of got hooked on it then and then um through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> then i kind of had too many other things going on
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		yeah i understand when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got in college my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		set up subscriptions for all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> because he could get them at the student cheap rate that we had
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of magazines
 	
 	
 		that's neat well do you spend a lot of time reading them or do you just pick out what you want
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i pick pick out what i want usually
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		read uh  read those cartoons in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> read the little synopsis find out who died in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and look at like celebrity pictures and i'm not
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the best informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i guess but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh you know if there is a news name that you don't know you can flip through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and try to find who it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that is a little bit helpful but
 	
 	
 		oh that's neat
 		well um i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INC</ENAMEX> magazine mainly for my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it's not my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> personally obviously but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have been selected as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INC</ENAMEX>'s top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX> yeah so it's really it's exciting to see your name in print and they do um
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the other things that i read are kind of they are all computer related because that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is about but um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they are not really magazines they are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX> but i do not know if they would really qualify as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i guess so because they have advertising and news print so
 	
 	
 		right are they like PC World or beyond that
 	
 	
 		yeah that stuff and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mainframe Journal and Computer World</ENAMEX> all that boring stuff but it's stuff you got to keep up with or else you you start falling behind
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right i know
 		yeah
 		that sounds good
 	
 	
 		and then yeah it's real funny because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> um gives me trouble still about getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosmopolitan</ENAMEX> and because that's mainly or not mainly but i think he thinks as it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as more of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> type of thing and i am like well i am going to get this until i start getting like
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Better Homes and Gardens</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really until you start getting those old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		yeah i can't see that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retirement Digest</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i said that i'll keep subscribing to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> until i started wanting to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> and then at that point if you just cut it off
 	
 	
 		yeah that
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parenthood</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		really <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf Digest</ENAMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		these are the bad signs
 	
 	
 		i can't see any of those
 	
 	
 		so i don't know where i don't what we do with all our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> we probably
 	
 	
 		you recycle them
 	
 	
 		cut down all all well we do we take them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and they sell them there you can not recycle the shiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of the magazine
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we recycle everything but the
 		paper of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> go back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and they resell them which i can't imagine who would want like back issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i guess maybe there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world
 	
 	
 		all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing all that research
 	
 	
 		that's right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can get them and have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do craft projects cut the pictures out and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well when i i was doing some research for a product i was doing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> on the microfiche which was really pretty neat
 	
 	
 		oh
 		which is bad i don't like those microfiche i
 		i we had this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> of school i had my last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of college and i am writing this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bette Midler</ENAMEX> i was decided i was not going to be very academic finally and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you had to look through all these old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX> and use microfiche and i just got seasick the little things zipping by your face so it was
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i just thought i was going to throw up right there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> it was
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		not a good day
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i guess i went slow enough that it did not make me nauseous
 	
 	
 		yeah well they have like the the automated machines now you just press the button and the
 	
 	
 		oh and it zooms
 	
 	
 		words just go zipping by and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i do not think i could do with that
 	
 	
 		it it's bad uh
 	
 	
 		but it was really neat cause i was doing this this project i had to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Demographics</ENAMEX> which you know i had never even knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> existed but it had some really neat stuff in it
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah that's um we did a lot of demographic stuff at school
 	
 	
 		huh i was amazed i did not know that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> was even out there
 	
 	
 		i know it's something you never thought you would care about there is perhaps a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> for every interest in the world
 	
 	
 		yeah cause even like in the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> you know i do not ever go over and look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> but i was getting some pictures developed at the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and it was taking longer so i was hanging out over there and i was amazed at the different kinds
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah there is it's a lot out there we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Maturity</ENAMEX> that was the worse mom and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad dad</ENAMEX> turned fifty so we got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Maturity</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		like this is not good
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it has all these like health tips and ways to fix prunes and
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh God
 	
 	
 		what a good magazine
 	
 	
 		oh that would be awful
 	
 	
 		so yeah and so we are
 	
 	
 		i do not know what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> get i think uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> so i know that they get something along those lines
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh and he is real big into genealogy but i don't know if there is any genealogy magazines
 	
 	
 		oh no doubt there is i am sure i'm sure of it
 	
 	
 		really yeah well that is probably true i had not thought about that
 	
 	
 		their's i never knew all the specific things they had in magazines
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah they are fun though i mean at least it kills time while you are at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s office
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know really all the try do the word find in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highlight</ENAMEX> magazine
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah i was real surprised though my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> carries tons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i mean he has like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennis World</ENAMEX> and i mean stuff that normally i mean a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s usually have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> magazine and that is about it
 	
 	
 		right my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> have the worst magazines i
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		have to change <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> but then i might need to get that
 	
 	
 		you want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s name  well i mean if you get that many at home you probably would not want them
 	
 	
 		i know um we're not at any loss for reading material here you you pretty much you can read like the table of contents before the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> comes and then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		i bet you are you're
 	
 	
 		that there is like a big pile these are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> we are going to read sometime and so it's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah your mailman is probably not real happy with y'all huh
 	
 	
 		no i uh no  get we have the jumbo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> that comes by our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to drop off the mail
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		it's a mess but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's okay we keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers  magazine publishers</ENAMEX> in business
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		in the midst of the recession we're
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s publishing economy
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine um was getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and she wasn't taking the time to read it so she just had this huge pile and we were like what are you doing saving up for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		really
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		line a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> cages
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		with that
 		okay well i guess that's about all on magazines nice talking with you have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> sorry to interrupt your dinner  bye
 	
 	
 		well
 		okay
 		well you too
 		thanks you too
 		that's fine bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	