
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn</ENAMEX> do you do you want to start
 	
 	
 		certainly um
 	
 	
 		okay
 		do you want to tell me about some of the vacations you've taken or
 	
 	
 		well i i tend to uh take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of vacations
 		the vacations to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and the vacations to just have a week being cultural and going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> and doing sightseeing and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		which is your favorite
 	
 	
 		oh well i couldn't live without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> vacations but uh my favorite is the the indulgent ones where we go off and and uh see places that have interested me since i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> for the most part
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> doesn't live close then
 	
 	
 		uh not anymore they uh they've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> and they're moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and that's one of those things you just have to go once a year
 	
 	
 		yep i understand
 	
 	
 		so uh basically it it sorts out into that and then once about once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years</TIMEX> i try to get over to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> because i lived there for a while
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years back</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've only only been there once
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i'd love to go back
 	
 	
 		beautiful  country
 		beautiful country beautiful people
 	
 	
 		it was
 		yeah it we had a great time
 	
 	
 		but uh and i'd real really like to go because um i'm fairly recently married and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has been hearing about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and uh but he's never met them so
 		uh i'd like i'd like to do that but anyway that's that's our typical vacation and uh we enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> vacations but the other ones are very special getaways  and we probably take one of each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well  we we as you do take family vacations uh sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a year
 		and but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we're not going to be taking one for several reasons but vacations we really enjoy i think we've been on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cruises
 	
 	
 		oh i've never been on a cruise
 	
 	
 		and we we really love cruises we've gone on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnival Cruise Lines</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we've gone fairly inexpensive from as most cruises go uh we usually book just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> before it's ready to go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we get upgraded last time last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times in fact we had an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and it was beautiful
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and we like not having to take our suitcase in and out of hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and drag it all around it's kind of
 	
 	
 		well what do you do on a cruise i've never been on a cruise
 	
 	
 		oh my God you do everything
 		you i mean you can be as busy as you want to be or as laid back as you want to be you can sit in the sun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> around the pool
 		or you can take part in the games that they have going on they always have bingo they have a casino uh they have a massage parlor they have exercise i mean you can do anything
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and that's just aboard <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> and then when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> docks you get to go sight seeing and shopping and that's quite fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and where have you been on these cruises
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">uh Nassau San</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Saint Thomas</ENAMEX> we've been there twice we went <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cruises that hit those islands but with different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we we've gone with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> each time
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and then we went to uh the western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> which is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port</ENAMEX> uh Cancun Cozumel
 	
 	
 		oh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> coast
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX> pardon me
 	
 	
 		i the that's all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh and but it was wonderful so we really like those and uh i guess we just like to go someplace someplace entirely different we've been to a few places in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we still have a lot to see though
 	
 	
 		where are you from originally
 	
 	
 		we're from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois</ENAMEX> originally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we've been down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years</TIMEX> and so like you we we always try to make it you know back home to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> we both still have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's fun it brings back a lot of memories
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		uh things are different there though they're uh i don't know it's just entirely different world
 		than this area
 	
 	
 		well i i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so i mean it's not it's not like i'm going home my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> retired <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> and they're going now to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and so they're going very nice places thank God
 	
 	
 		did you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that will be a pleasure to visit and get to know i really came to love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> and feel very comfortable there they've been there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i just grab the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and drive everywhere
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		so it it is it is nice but it's not home this is home and um and i've never thought about a cruise it's so funny
 	
 	
 		oh they they they really are we've
 		yeah as i said we've done them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times we'd be going again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this this year</TIMEX> if circumstances hadn't changed we we'd probably go my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> would you know the minute i said the word he he he's chomping at the bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he kind of likes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i like all of it and
 	
 	
 		what's the best part from your point of view
 	
 	
 		i like seeing other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and shopping in other places
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like shopping i can shop anyplace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and wherever now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> so we're going to be able to go up there
 	
 	
 		oh that'll be nice
 	
 	
 		so i'm kind of looking forward to that except i hate to see them go
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		sure well go in don't go in the winter
 	
 	
 		oh that's what everybody says and i i think it's i think i'll try to stay away except my my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grandchild will be born in
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so that will be hard to stay away from
 	
 	
 		well there there are exceptions made for special occasions like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but the ordinary thing is to stay out of the north in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> and get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		isn't that the truth uh-huh
 	
 	
 		hum
 		well that sounds wonderful well i i guess i i would contemplate going on a cruise uh oh all circumstances permitting it
 	
 	
 		well there's all age group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> too and that's that's kind of fun uh you if you sit at a table with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for your meals you meet different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you may meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> older than you or younger and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		everybody is really interesting and everybody is there to have a good time and
 	
 	
 		huh how long are the cruises
 	
 	
 		and
 		uh we've only gone on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> cruises
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they have shorter ones and then they have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten day</TIMEX> ones
 		but i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> is long enough for us by that time we're ready to get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and
 		get ba ck to our routine i think most vacations uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> is enough for us we've gone i think when we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> we were there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten twelve days</TIMEX> and that was pushing it a bit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		uh i tend when when i spend enough money to go overseas  i go for a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that that makes sense
 		it really does i mean oh we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh he we went with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> to visit his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who live there and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is a kindergarten <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and they took time off it was
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> and they were having a little break so they took some time off that uh they could show us around and it it is a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> it is beautiful they have mountains we were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an hour</NUMEX> away from the mountains or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an hour</NUMEX> away from the shore
 	
 	
 		huh
 		that's really nice
 	
 	
 		and it it is gorgeous they live in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David</ENAMEX> which is northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> up near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's it's just it's just a gorgeous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't realize it i think if they could get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> coming to their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> they'd improve the economy considerably
 	
 	
 		huh well may maybe now things are calming down again that will happen
 	
 	
 		yeah we really hope hope so
 	
 	
 		well that that's really great um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i mean as i said well well basically all i've done is go back and forth to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		well that that's that's pretty good that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and and uh we had  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had a conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> so we spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> and of course
 	
 	
 		oh do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i'm very i'm i'm very unusual i like
 		
 		
 	