
 
     		
 	
 		okay well what do you think
 	
 	
 		it um i'm trying to remember exactly how the question was worded what what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s roles and how they've changed
 	
 	
 		change
 		in the last generation or two
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well one thing and i don't know how how long a span a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> is considered whether we're talking you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> or or or whatever but it seems to me there are more and more women
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's obvious there are more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working outside the home some of them of course are finally climbing corporate ladders uh whereas when i was growing up it was either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> or teacher
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really are you working outside the home
 	
 	
 		yes i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah but i still notice a lot of not necessarily prejudice but i work with a um
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that are very chauvinistic still
 	
 	
 		so do i
 	
 	
 		yeah it is it's it's very hard to deal with because i mean they know that it offends me what the way they act but they do it anyway
 		so i don't know though it's really weird because my i came from a very my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has a lot of strong willed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in it and so i've i've never really
 		you know nobody ever said well you could only be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> to me i mean you know my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were very strong and said you can do whatever you want to do so i got really lucky there but it's real funny i have a niece and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> now and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years old</TIMEX> and something was said about my niece being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and he said well she can't be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> she can only be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>  i thought golly you're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years old</TIMEX> and you're already opinionated
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well and probably probably he hasn't seen any female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well yeah that's the only thing i could figure because i'm i'm sure that he didn't get that from my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> or his mother
 	
 	
 		probably not but but on if he watches television if he gets a coloring book the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> is is frequently
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh she portrayed as a male and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> well i'm just i'm just thinking of pictures that i've seen and and you know uh uh i i suspect no no message was ever intended to be while what you have to be this gender
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to do this job but it does sometimes come through and when i said um that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that those were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> professions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> seemed to do it wasn't necessarily that that was what i was told to do or or whatever it simply that's what i observed growing up was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um about the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> you know it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at that time could uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> in a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> or any other kind of store
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		be a teacher
 	
 	
 		yeah and i went into teaching that was uh what i had started out doing early on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and left that when i decided to get married and leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so and i've never gone back to it in the last in the intervening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen years</TIMEX> it's just uh
 		i i love to teach i don't want to have to deal with the discipline problems and so forth so that's a whole another story
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> was a that was his i guess second profession he was a teacher
 	
 	
 		uh okay undying admiration comes from me that's that's for sure
 	
 	
 		huh well that's neat well um it was real funny i went to a seminar that was just it was is a satellite seminar it was really neat and it was just for women
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they talked about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cindrella Cinderella</ENAMEX> syndrome and i had never heard about that had you
 	
 	
 		uh uh not by that term anyway
 	
 	
 		well it's about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or not necessarily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are taught that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> will come and he'll do everything and he'll make everything right
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and um it was really neat because she totally reworked this the story about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinderella</ENAMEX> um
 		networked her way to this ball and then  it was really neat it was great the way she turned the story around and said you know she left her calling card in the form of a glass slipper and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		very interesting
 		very creative
 	
 	
 		yeah it was really neat but you know i i hadn't even thought about about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tales that they really do leave that impression i'm sure with a lot of little girls
 	
 	
 		well i hadn't thought about it but but very likely i went to a seminar a conference just uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> uh
 		that was put on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">by by TI</ENAMEX> but it it dealt with um the minority issues of promotion within the business
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and they had had invited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> from uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsico</ENAMEX> and and another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> and the these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> were all uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> or higher
 		were were from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> but in addition they were also addressing um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in in the entire focus of
 	
 	
 		right
 		huh
 	
 	
 		the minority issues and so uh it was a very interesting discussion in the afternoon uh the questions and so forth that that their  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> uh uh speeches engendered uh just talking about well how
 		how does your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> deal with this and and and so forth and it was refreshing to hear that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are beginning to address the issue of of uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> beyond a certain level so few in the board room and and so forth and so they they shared some of the ideas they their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were had uh instituted as far as uh uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		giving a leg up mentoring processes and so forth that they had in place
 	
 	
 		right
 		well that's neat
 	
 	
 		and then one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VPs</ENAMEX> shared what what are some of the things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is doing to um come up with some similar results
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh well that's neat
 	
 	
 		i'm beginning to find more and more female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		although not um
 		not many of them yet have moved into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> positions that'll part of that's because so many of them are are still real young and they've got to learn the business <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and then they can move up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right
 		well i work in a computer industry also and um
 		i've found very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are higher up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIS</ENAMEX> departments
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i i can only think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i've talked to
 		so it's it's amazing that yeah they're out there but they're just slowly moving their way up
 		but hopefully it will all happen and by the time my little niece gets up there she can  yeah
 	
 	
 		she can pick whatever she wants to be and if she would like to be the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cinderella</ENAMEX> and find that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> that's okay too but there
 	
 	
 		right oh yeah yeah i don't want here to be neglected of anything like that but
 	
 	
 		yeah but there are other options that are available
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well um i lost my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> of thought  no that's okay um well i've lost it
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		hum oh well um yeah it's it's uh i think it's gotten a lot better over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> but like i said i i felt very fortunate that i grew up around strong willed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so because i i some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that i have worked with are so wimpy that you can understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> get frustrated with them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	