
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		are you a TIer
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		is somebody in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> a TIer
 	
 	
 		no uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> works for the computers for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and that's how he got it
 	
 	
 		oh okay so who do you work for
 	
 	
 		i just graduated from college
 	
 	
 		so you don't have any benefits at all to talk about
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you're just going to have to imagine what you would like as benefits
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		or what i'm looking for
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay well in in interviewing have you ever discussed benefits with some of the potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		didn't get that far you normally just try to sell them on your uh aptitude and not you know well how much vacation do i get oh well
 	
 	
 		no
 		um
 	
 	
 		well i'll tell you a little bit about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has as benefits we do have uh like most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> we have medical insurance
 		although they're tending to try to really cut costs more and more um what they started with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> is that they only would allow you to go to um
 		set <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> in the area they call it network <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> they're hospitals
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i've heard of that
 	
 	
 		yeah they're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> that they're uh agreeing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh TI</ENAMEX> that they'll be a certain rate you know for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and care and all that kind of stuff to keep costs you know costs down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now they're going to start to do the same kind of thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> so it's almost like a um uh an HMO
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know kind of thing that uh only certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are you going to be allowed to go to and get the full coverage if you go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who isn't in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> then it will be less benefits that you get
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have some dental coverage now um but you have to pay a little more to really get something worthwhile Like i've had a couple of crowns recently and
 		if you didn't have the extra dental plus um you only get like a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of your cost which can be kind of expensive with a crown so i i pay
 	
 	
 		yeah it can
 	
 	
 		yeah i pay for the extra dental plus so much more per month
 		because it always seems like if you're going to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX> or something major done it pays a little more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um we do have pension although i've realized recently that the pension doesn't seem to be too good and i know when you first start out working you're not thinking about that
 	
 	
 		oh i like to think about that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		after you've been working for a while and you look at your pension account and you go is that all that's in there i don't think's it's going to pay too long when i get out
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um we do have a new thing that they've started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> um
 		it's not an i <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> A it's called a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> plan it's kind of like pension you put in so much money and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI um</ENAMEX> meets you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> way up to a certain maximum so like i put in a dollar they put in fifty cents so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that grows pretty good and i think that will be more of something i can see of a pension than the regular pension plan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		course you can buy stock in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> but you know that's not always a real for sure kind of thing course
 	
 	
 		not always safe
 	
 	
 		yeah especially with this one you know it kind of goes up and down i don't know if it's any different than other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> but you hate to have it fluctuate and like
 		you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> a share and now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty six</TIMEX> dollars a share and you go gee i'm losing money  doesn't quite feel as good
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and we get you know vacation normally after you're here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> and you start to get like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days every six months</TIMEX> is kind of how they accrue it to you
 		and it's one nice thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is after you've been here uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> you get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		which
 		a lot of places make you work like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years or so</TIMEX> before you get that much
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and we get some we get uh decent holidays um we at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> we always get the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> off which is nice to make a nice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long weekend</TIMEX> and at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> we always get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmas</ENAMEX>
 		they float it around depending on which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day of the week Christmas</TIMEX> falls on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's nice so you always get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just take you know that week i normally take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that week</TIMEX> somehow you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you only have to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days of vacation</TIMEX> and you get the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yeah well um i can just tell you like you know from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> well there's twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in my family
 	
 	
 		whoa okay
 	
 	
 		so uh the the dental was very important you know to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>
 		but um i think they took the dental away now he worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Telephone System</ENAMEX> it's you know it's just another you know telephone network
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they took the dental away but now i think they're going to start getting into eye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh um i don't use the services but yeah i think sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> or just recently they started to give some kind of eye coverage you get discounts on uh glasses and
 		i'm not quite sure there's certain places you can go to that have uh discounts for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you can get glasses and contacts and stuff through those particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah and now for his pension he pretty much just has the stock
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> he's on that same kind of pension as what you said
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		only for everything he puts in they'll match it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		up to a certain amount
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like if he puts in a dollar they'll put in a dollar
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know and then he's only allowed i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know if it's maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent
 		or something like that that he's allowed to put in and they'll match it
 		so and um he works for the did you ever hear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Bureau of Standards</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well he works for them they changed their name now but that's that's where he works and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he his vacation is really nice he's going to be there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this month</TIMEX> and he'll be getting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		gee that's pretty decent
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah okay you know of course it's it's for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and he has all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> off
 	
 	
 		right and you get some extra ones federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> always seem to get you know you get <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Columbus Day</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Day</ENAMEX> and those ones that you couldn't really care about so much but you get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> off anyhow
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah uh-huh he has it really nice it's nice where he works and um he seems to be very happy you know
 		like his hospi talization and you know he has all that and with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and stuff they have um a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> can go to
 		and it only costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a dollar</NUMEX> as long as they go to that doctor
 		you know and i think it works the same way with his prescriptions and stuff if he needs any
 	
 	
 		oh yeah okay
 	
 	
 		but you have to go you know to certain ones but still that works out really nice you know
 	
 	
 		yeah we're doing an HMO right now um and when we go to get prescriptions it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX>
 		so but so you know sometime sometimes when you go you know the prescription like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> always takes  which is kind of like you know contact stuff only better um you that's like a buck a capsule
 	
 	
 		that's not bad either
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so if you've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> in there it normally comes out to about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four</TIMEX> dollars so when you pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> it's a pretty good savings then there's other times that you know maybe the prescription wouldn't cost more than like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight dollars</NUMEX> and you pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> anyhow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it isn't a percentage but sometimes you work you know you manage to make
 		
 		
 	