
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay uh do you work outside the home
 	
 	
 		no i do not
 	
 	
 		okay wow  have you yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		do you
 		have i
 		uh no not actually
 	
 	
 		okay well yes i do in fact i am at work right now uh and so let me take the lead uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX> uh i think
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what is really important uh  of course salary is very important because that's why you are working for your for the money but job satisfaction to me is also uh very important in having a job
 		and uh one of the things that uh she asked us to discuss was benefits uh i'm assuming that you are married and have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that supports you
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and so we could we could talk about uh that path you know how important you think his benefits are and and and uh how important you think they are and if what would you like to see increased
 		in his benefits like uh perhaps uh he has uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the benefit of having eyeglasses for the family uh uh and how much coverage uh it provides and also your hospital coverage and uh
 		um probably dental how important you think that would be
 	
 	
 		right i i think that
 		job wise benefits are important just as important as salary is
 	
 	
 		because they of course if you did not have them you would be pulling from your salary of course right right
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly especially when you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and you are always going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> for
 	
 	
 		and they always have surprises for you with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know and so it's it is uh
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		they always do
 	
 	
 		we could not do without the benefit package from from any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that we worked for whether they be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> or just a small uh uh business
 	
 	
 		yeah i think any any even if your insurance policy is not the greatest
 	
 	
 		you would still have something
 	
 	
 		exactly you  you would not be pulling it out of your account all of the time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		just by yourself also  for working women
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh i think a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> should start providing for day care in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the in the</TIMEX> in the building
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they are getting a handle on that in fact uh my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is uh is uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>
 		and she just received her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> degree and she is now into consulting and that's one of the areas that she is working on to have uh
 		uh a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for the individual the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> that are staffing the facility
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that is true in many many areas of you know uh job titles
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and professions
 	
 	
 		like in may case
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from ages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and it's just unfeasible for me to try to get a job because all the money that i would be making would be going to day care
 	
 	
 		sure
 		would
 		it would
 		it would be just futile
 	
 	
 		and it would be just basically be me working to pay for them to be at a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> exactly
 	
 	
 		and they would not have the quality
 		and they would be deprived of their mother
 		yeah no i understand that totally
 	
 	
 		besides which it would be easier uh there's a lot of single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> out there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> from divorces and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are starting to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and to go to work
 	
 	
 		oh i hear
 		yes that's true
 	
 	
 		you are worried about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> besides which you have to get up earlier to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to day care and if they were in the same building
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then you are going to the same place and you could go for your <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch hour</TIMEX> down and visit with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or you know and take your breaks with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yes do you
 		do you think that you should fund that if they have that as a benefit if you would fund that somewhat
 		from your salary that you are getting
 		do you think that would be
 	
 	
 		i think that i think it would be fair i think if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could not provide it all on their own for the for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that would be using it you know a certain amount of their salary would go to it but it would still probably be cheaper
 	
 	
 		acceptable
 		i do too
 		right that you
 		right
 		that's right
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> than than having to go
 	
 	
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> helping our if everybody you know pulled their own weight in it
 	
 	
 		that's correct that's right
 		yes
 		i agree with that
 	
 	
 		i think it would be really really great
 	
 	
 		that would be fair
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and how how do you feel about uh
 		let's see eye care
 	
 	
 		eye care is good i don't i'm not sure i don't think we have that on our policy
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but uh we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> i guess it's called vision care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it would be great i mean
 		uh the glasses that the exams themselves are not expensive it's the glasses
 	
 	
 		it depends on who has examines your eyes
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		if you have an an ah optometrist or an ophthalmologist there's a vast difference in those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh professionals
 	
 	
 		right now like my
 		right
 		well like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> she has to go for testing cause she has got
 	
 	
 		glaucoma
 	
 	
 		well she does not have it but she is like on the verge of it or something her eyes are changing and she has to be tested periodically and and those are expensive tests
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh okay so
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes they are
 	
 	
 		now i think your insurance covers her on that but you know for something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		it that's just as bad as a medical you know that's
 	
 	
 		right that's critical because she's in need of it so often yes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you know we have uh needs
 		in our life that are unique to us and uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have needs in their life that unique to us to them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean we are all different so
 	
 	
 		now i i would like to see bettle better dental insurance
 		to me was that our beep
 	
 	
 		well no that's my other phone
 	
 	
 		oh huh
 	
 	
 		so that's it that's okay my that phone is ringing to an empty desk and she's on vacation  so it's okay
 	
 	
 		okay but with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um orthopedic care um not orthopedic orthodontic ca re
 	
 	
 		that's very expensive
 	
 	
 		because on on a lot of the dental insurance they do not cover that well for the the orthodontal stuff
 	
 	
 		yes that's true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orthodontic</ENAMEX> work is terribly expensive especially when you have a lot of problems with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> teeth and
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you have to really get them when they are young in order to have uh not uh a decent smile when they are fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> had to have that and they started having extractions at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age eight</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because they just had too many teeth for their size mouth
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we footed the bill because there was not any such thing and when they were young
 	
 	
 		right my middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> needs to have uh orthodontic he's because his his pallet is
 		squared not rounded
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and it affects his speech a little bit not not anything you know
 	
 	
 		uh-huh major
 	
 	
 		right but just enough that his bite is off a little bit and it's like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollars</NUMEX> and my insurance is only going to cover like fifty of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i tell you i i just read an article in the paper about what they are doing i think it was an ad in in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> where they are breaking the jaw and
 		and lining the jaw up with the teeth it's it's less painful and less expensive
 	
 	
 		oh
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that sounds like it would hurt more
 	
 	
 		i i know but it it's it's uh easier on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in the long run
 		which amazed me
 	
 	
 		oh gosh i i would much rather that do that to myself than make my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year old</TIMEX>  go in and do it that would kill me
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 		
 	