
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hi Ed</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		uh
 		books uh i've actually i am reading a couple of different books uh uh
 		one was uh is uh
 		a story well it is not a story it is a collection of um
 		of memos supposedly written by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Hughes</ENAMEX> uh that was uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that was  it came out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and i have just now gotten around to reading it i have had it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> but uh just just
 	
 	
 		who wrote that
 	
 	
 		oh i do not remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s name he was used to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for uh i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Time</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and he supposedly got this this  story uh i mean this uh
 		was contacted by this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who had these these memos he wanted to sell and they were they were ones that had supposedly been stolen from the um corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		they on i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Romain Drive</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Romain Street</ENAMEX> or something there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> they used to have a or i guess they still do uh had a uh
 		uh big warehouse kind of thing which had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and it was sort of nondescript for a
 		you know for the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> which inside was basically a store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of a bunch of stuff he collected he he was uh a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX> of everything he he
 		he didn't he didn't throw anything away and uh supposedly this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had had been breaking there for awhile he was a like you know burglar had been breaking there awhile and uh and had ended up
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		he he had some accomplices that were kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> and they uh they broke in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one one night</TIMEX> and found a bunch of memos that were uh supposedly from
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> to uh to his main um
 		main assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant assistant assistant</ENAMEX> back uh in the fifties and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> well i guess in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> up until his death
 	
 	
 		well that is interesting
 		all right
 	
 	
 		so it's pretty interesting work so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that is an intriguing type of book to be reading and trying to keep up on things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a it's a little
 		it's a little hard it's a it's a you have to plod through it and you know it doesn't doesn't have a real story or any plot you just kind of have to read and understand what is going on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and they haven't made a movie of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> of it yet
 	
 	
 		no i have not seen it but it's but it is it is real interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i also reading uh the uh  it's a an old <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another old</TIMEX> book that i happen to have i am sort of rereading it it's um
 		a book about uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Triangle</ENAMEX> but it's uh it's about it's a real good book that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy um</ENAMEX> wrote who was uh a research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> he wrote um sort of
 		debunking many of the uh uh um
 		the stories about the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Triangle</ENAMEX> you know he he was saying many many of the
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		the myths many of the myths of the triangle were uh actually could be explained and and you know
 	
 	
 		explained like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the reason reason i was i hadn't picked it back up was in light of all the uh
 		the  well when they found the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> thinking they were Flight Nineteen and i don't know if you are familiar with that at all but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Flight Nineteen</ENAMEX> was one of the uh
 		a collection of a flight of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> adventures at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two Right</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War Two</ENAMEX> and they were they were lost and uh so
 	
 	
 		supposedly scooped up by the triangle yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah they were and so and in the book you know even  he wrote this book back in the seventies and even and even then he
 		he made had a very good case for the fact they probably just got lost and they ditched in the water and uh because he he
 		he mentions he he goes through and and brings out points from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>'s findings and so forth and uh it's probably you know real close to what you know everyone is thinking now that they just got turned around and couldn't find their way back
 	
 	
 		yeah on that same topic have you ever read anything about you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amelia Earhart</ENAMEX> story whatever happened with her
 	
 	
 		uh no i haven't
 	
 	
 		i i think that would be i am sure there is something out there uh that might a
 	
 	
 		yeah i would i would like to too because it's a lot of things coming up here lately about her you know possibilities of her of where she have might have been
 	
 	
 		i thought she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of war or something for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> well whatever this is one aspect of it of course you know it is so weird cause no one will ever really know it's it the
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so but it's entertaining and it makes you think about things that is for sure
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah so that is pretty much for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> that is what i have been reading i i kind of like to read different stuff and uh i like to read a novel every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> but um i am trying to get away from just reading novels all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right well i i guess i just have not read anything i mean usually i just if i find a good book i will sit you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> until it is finished if it's that good and i think the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i read like that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Thurow</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumed Innocent</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i just really really liked the way he writes it's just
 	
 	
 		yeah i read that too i got it um right after it came out my uh
 	
 	
 		incredible
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know he was an an assistant district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> at uh and while he was writing the book and uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and she had before it actually got big she sent me this book saying you might like this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is you know from here and
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh i i read it and really liked it and then about that is when it really got big and uh so i
 	
 	
 		that was good i think and and the other book i am trying to think you know like was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> and i think i did read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX> you know Bon yeah
 	
 	
 		i haven't read that although i have heard it is pretty good
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah i that was really really good the movie was nothing compared to the book and yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that is what i have heard i saw the movie and
 	
 	
 		oh the movie was a joke  compared to i mean because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX> is so perceptive when it comes to you know pinpointing um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>'s ills and things like that and just nailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the wall and exposing things and
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh it was it was a much more intense book than the sort of flimflam that they cast off in the movie
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		and anyway we are not talking about that but um gee i just i like to read gardening books and things like that just to tell me what to do with my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX> and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i have a lot of  computer books because i am i do computer work and so i have a lot of those so i spend a lot of time looking through those not necessarily reading them but uh looking through them so i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		interested in a lot of that but uh i have got a lot of books that i i intend to read but i have not been able to yet you know for one reason or another
 	
 	
 		like what is a book on your list you know i have a list too and  i have never gotten to it
 	
 	
 		oh gosh i don't i don't really have a list because i just kind of uh i just have all the books out you know i have book shelves and i have them all out and usually when i am through with one i will go in and uh uh
 		look look through uh i have one now and i i can't remember the name of it that i that i got is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> usually sends me for my birthday or or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> or something will send me another another good book and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> shit i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i can not remember the name of it uh it is supposed to be a mystery
 		
 		
 	