
 
     		
 	
 		i've uh
 		i've
 		well i've had i used to have the opinion that there was that there really wasn't any more crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> anyway than there was in previous centuries
 		uh before uh simply because the reason there seems to be so much was the fact that
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> now had advanced uh reporting methods with computers and other devices
 	
 	
 		compile more statistics
 	
 	
 		that's right and those statistics  in turn got them bigger budgets
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		however i have been persuaded lately i guess simply by the uh overwhelming data that seems to be available that there is indeed a lot more violent crime
 	
 	
 		more especially where you are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 		no i am in i am in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> D C
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i was going to say
 	
 	
 		actually it you know i do a lot of business here and i come here quite often and and that again is a is a sort of media perception there's some absolutely lovely and marvelous and peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		regardless of the racial makeup but it's it's these real uh there's pockets of violence that is so violent that they uh
 	
 	
 		it just really grabs your attention it just makes the whole place seem like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right now just to focus on that a minute i guess uh
 		um when um previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">educate Bennett</ENAMEX> i think his name was became the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX> uh for uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> he was going to focus on it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		on this area and do something about it and i see that even he was met without with with little success even though the entire
 		i guess a a quite a bit of money and and other uh planning efforts went into that
 	
 	
 		what do you what do you think is is causing all this because it seems that there there even though crime though though i think it is increasing in number it sure does seem to be increasing in intensity and violence too
 	
 	
 		well
 		yes
 		well i uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> theories about it you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things i have one theory and it's  by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things one i i believe that this is a function of uh the violence that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> see on television and in the movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i am not just talking about you know uh
 		role models of uh of tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> and things like that i'm i'm not even
 		i'm not even
 		convinced that maybe things like uh football hockey and the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the and</TIMEX> and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the</ENAMEX> and even <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> games now where the everything is settled with a fight you know the the immediate need to show some sort of violence to settle the uh the argument and
 		and then i i am an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of hand gun control to some degree so i think that particularly i i was reading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corpus Christi Texas</ENAMEX> which has the  highest
 		i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corpus  Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> that had the highest rates per hand gun death in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh per capita i mean the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> special stuff so that that's what i think about it that's some of the things i think about it plus uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i i haven't seen that but uh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know what are your views
 	
 	
 		well yeah i tend to agree with you with you know it seems anymore uh a movie can not be considered good unless there's just some
 		some sort of violence or something in it and and along with that you know and then you start making a movie and
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it it has no there's no call for something violent but so they just throw something in there just to say they have it
 	
 	
 		exactly well that's that's that's the impression i get yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i and i imagine it's it you know it just feeds upon itself when when we have this sort of violence in society <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to it conditions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to it and
 		uh you have to emphasize it has to be even uh magnified to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s attention i guess to have them spend money on something like that and i am sure that it does form role models for young for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah you become callous
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i mean i i read now where where
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are arrested young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are arrested fighting with knives over over
 		whatever  whatever reason which is kind of unheard of when i was young now i do not want to sound like an old fart but  but that that's what it seems that those things happened before
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it didn't happen in that manner before television and i i i i have to think that that it has some influence on it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i listening to a radio talk show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch time</TIMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX> i do not know if you listen to him or not he's on AM but uh there there's a fellow that had called in and was
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah
 		no
 	
 	
 		lamenting about the uh that there was a interview done on the assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of police</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and they were just really coming down on him because of
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		some of the things he was just some of the things that he believed in some of his morals for instance uh they asked him if he spanked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and he said you bet i believe in discipline and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i i i i guess they confuse confused discipline with punishment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and  just it seems anymore that uh if if you have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know this type of a moral stance
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come down on you it's like you know hey everybody has to be free to do their own thing and i disagree and i think that's really contributing to this high rate of crime
 	
 	
 		yes yes well i mean i i guess so what i wanted to say and i stopped uh i do not know i got diverted was uh that
 		uh there's so much there's so much of a return from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> that the rehabilitation programs seem to be a failure and
 		and that is not emphasized i recognize there's there's over crowding problems and and since we have decided to put everybody in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> that commits a crime now that that's complicated the entire process what i also think is that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i guess it's the reflection of of the society where where we have so much more mobility and less
 		attachment to
 		uh you know it does not seem to be any responsibility to the community
 		where you where you live or i do not mean responsibility attachment and responsibility i guess i mean
 		any sort of
 	
 	
 		well nobody feels responsibility to do something it's like oh boy i wish they would stop doing that yeah
 	
 	
 		yes that's right that yeah
 		i i do not know how that's i do not think it's done by uh the changes come simply by statutory nature i do not know what it really will take
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">huh</ENAMEX> and i do not know if i have solutions except except to you know i am sort of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of
 		of uh of letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of having free speech and i guess to curb
 		uh television uh the violence on television and in the movies would be contrary to my beliefs in that however there does seem to be a right now in verbalizing it does seem to be a higher need for something of that sort
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and then how many
 	
 	
 		and the sacrifice isn't that great
 	
 	
 		how how many studies have to be done to show that there is a link between you know what you see and how you i mean what you see affects how you think and therefore what you do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes yes i think i think that's correct
 	
 	
 		and  and yes but you know as soon as you
 		start uh
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has uh has always struck me i mean i i i have lived in and out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> both in the service and
 		and uh uh short business stints and it seems to me they are a pretty pretty tough law and order state but  but yet that does not seem to have effected the
 		amount of violent right in the state just citing that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah uh unfortunately you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> got a lot of the
 		uh some well a lot of it can be contributed to the the
 		the racial differences i mean just you know we are so close to the border with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> we've got a lot of that influence
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	