
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi um this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX> and i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nola</ENAMEX> and i'm in Plano
 	
 	
 		oh okay well here we go
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess we're going to have a lot of parades <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> in honor of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are that did some stuff over in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah no did you push one oh okay okay well then i think it i just started doing this so i don't know too much about it
 	
 	
 		yeah uh no i haven't pushed one yet i just
 		oh okay we're just sort of getting acquainted here
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		um you know i i just wanted to see if you know you had an opinion about this or you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um so if that's okay with you then i'll just press one okay
 	
 	
 		that'll be fine
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well hi  good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		i think i mean if if i start this i just wanted to say that um
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that i don't think we really understood about the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle eastern</TIMEX> situation is that they're a totally different type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than we are and i mean they think differently
 		and their idea of what is justice is totally different from ours and and right now i i think that that's been proven in the fact that um they have just
 		well anyway i just think that you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> policy over there i think we should just leave them alone i really do in in a major way because they just um
 		that whole region over there i think needs to settle it's own differences within itself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's the way the course that they should go i mean you know we can maybe help them a little bit prompt them but i don't think this intervention at such high levels
 		should be going on the the thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> i believe that should be settled between them and also um you know
 		the other thing is their idea or our idea idea of democracy has nothing to do with them
 		i mean that i mean i'm talking about the whole middle eastern and and maybe this is too general but i just believe that um they do not look at democracy the same way we do they don't understand it as we don't understand the way they live
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so you know trying to put like a square peg in a round hole is just you know it i don't think that that's the way to go in this and um you know it it
 		oh well that's that's a couple thoughts on it i i guess you know i'd like you to maybe express something here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i i think overall that's right i think it's kind of sad though that for generations they've been taught to hate each other
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's if you know if somewhere in there someone's going to have to learn a different way
 	
 	
 		that's yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and an i i think that um
 		true we do have completely different ways of looking at things at a lot of things
 		but uh at the same time i think there are a lot of there is a lot of good that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> can do as far as example and and um
 		i think some different things could come from what's happened than what we expect
 	
 	
 		well yeah well yeah um i i guess we could be a catalyst for their change i um the war has certainly sort of set things on end over there and i don't think we'd be talking about this
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> situation <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> situation um sort of came to a head um unless there had been a war i mean that was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		one thing that came out of it good or bad i i don't judge any war as good or bad it's just a war  and i don't see any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> or losers i just see dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> i'm sorry  you know but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i i just think you know you're right and i think maybe it's at a whole different level of them trying to cooperate and get along
 		it's not going to be that we're going to uh you know sort of tell them to go to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and that's going to solve the whole problem it's going to be them
 	
 	
 		yeah but that's the type of thing they understand they don't understand any other way and so at that at that you have to work at their level to an extent too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and you know
 		it's
 		yeah that that's true too i um
 	
 	
 		uh they wouldn't have understood anything else than what we did in the war there was nothing else yeah
 	
 	
 		oh well yeah they they understand violence  they love violent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to you know i mean look at you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> they had they they just adored him because he was so strict and cruel and you know for a while there he had them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i can't figure out why they adored him
 	
 	
 		well it has a lot to do with their religion i got to say that over there um and i know this
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		only because from personal experience that i'm speaking of this because i've i've you know traveled around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> with different <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> in a situation where i've done that and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of the kindest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've ever met in my whole life
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> is from that area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and i mean he is just
 		overly he he is abounding in kindness let's say and his life is so Godly i mean every thought they have a totally different life than we have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know and when you add the um commercialization of the western world it sort of screws everything up for them and they have very basic life um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well it's just a very basic life and they just really believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Allah</ENAMEX> or God or whatever and it's you know everything is to the glory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allah</ENAMEX> and and you know and it it's almost like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what's sad is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> that have control
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's see
 	
 	
 		are in
 	
 	
 		that using that yeah
 	
 	
 		power
 		yes and they abuse that
 	
 	
 		and it's always been military and it's always been and that's that's always been the way of the world don't you think
 	
 	
 		which i think that that's not the the way the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over there really are
 	
 	
 		yeah so it's really hard when you see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> compared to the people
 	
 	
 		but i think in a in a way the war uh i think in a way all uh the involvement over there too though has shown a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't
 		follow what those few are doing and there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are good people
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know there's and i i think we may not have ever have seen that without some of these uh newspeople being in there in the broadcasts and the the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> leaving
 		um you know surrendering and trying to get out of that situation and and the um uh you know
 	
 	
 		right and surrendering that was yeah
 		it just really comes down to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know you have to have some compassion some humanness doesn't matter where the boundaries are
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		um you know there are political boundaries and those are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> made boundaries but you know for heaven sakes that's something that's been going on for ages and
 	
 	
 		and i i think so much of it is what you're taught
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		you know they teach their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		uh in such a way that
 		
 		
 	