
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 		all right what type of things would you fix if you're having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> come over
 	
 	
 		well i have a really great one that i make in the summertime because it's cool and it's uh it's just really pretty easy it's pretty much dumping things in and stirring and i like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the only thing you have to do is cook the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> that goes in in it and then i you're supposed to do chicken but i just use those little cans of chicken
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it makes it so much easier and so you dump the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> you dump the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and then you put in fruit like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pineapple</ENAMEX> and mandarin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX> and grape now grapes are the ones that you have to pull all that off but i get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to do that so  i i don't have to do that
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and um and it really and you mix it all up with yeah there's a little dressing that goes in it that you have to stir up but it's so simple and it tastes really good because it's cool in the summertime uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you serve it cold oh yeah that sounds good
 	
 	
 		yeah it has to sit in the fridge over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> but but it's really good
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and i like that one
 	
 	
 		yeah usually when we entertain we do something really simple because i like to visit with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and not be scurrying around in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> so a lot of times we'll barbecue like that for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day</ENAMEX> we had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over and we
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		just bought a brisket and marinated it overnight in one of those like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adolph's Meat Marinate</ENAMEX> and put it on the smoker and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that sounds good
 	
 	
 		cooked it and that it was real good you can buy a fairly cheap piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> that way and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think they're eating steak or something
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> that helps doesn't it yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it really does
 	
 	
 		i know what you mean
 	
 	
 		i don't usually i just pass on any recipe that's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> steps to it because i just know i'll never take the time to do it
 	
 	
 		now spaghetti's such an easy one um i do that a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do spaghetti a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like spaghetti
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't like to do that if if it's hot real hot though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because um
 		i don't know i have a real thing about being hot in the in the summertime i guess
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i think when you heat your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> up it really makes a big difference
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in your whole house
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's right and um
 		we don't entertain that often but when we do i'm like you i like it to be fast and easy and something so that we can talk and not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and not have to worry about being in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		most we don't entertain like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from work or stuff even often usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and stuff and it's usually kind of like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you want to come over and they say well what can we bring and so it's real easy because you just make one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things and everybody else brings something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's exactly like us from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> we just do it yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah it's a lot more relaxing i don't know if i could take the pressure of having to make you know put on this really fancy dinner for someone
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well you see all that on TV  and i could never be that person
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it just uh i'm just not well i'm so i'm pretty laid back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and so i don't i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in a my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and uh she
 		like does her own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and does her own stuff and so when she um does food she really goes all out and i don't know how she can do it and be calm
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah do you work
 	
 	
 		i guess no i don't
 	
 	
 		do you stay home with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i i've been working we're going to have a baby <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> and i'm not going to work anymore yeah so hopefully i think i'll enjoy cooking more when i don't have to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> i don't like to come home and
 	
 	
 		oh how exciting
 	
 	
 		stand in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and spend an hour fixing something and then have to clean it up and by then it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight thirty</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine o'clock at night</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah well i usually start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six</TIMEX> and an and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and and then eat at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook cook</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and eat at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> rather
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		eat at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i we're a sit down together family
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i don't like the run in and out part and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i like to be able to sit down after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and have them talk with me and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> about what's happened and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's neat
 	
 	
 		i think i that was ingrained in me during my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> time at home and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know we could learn to talk about things and i think that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah that really is it keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in touch with what's going on with each other
 	
 	
 		yeah i think
 	
 	
 		right now we eat in front of the TV but since it's just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us it's
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well that happens to us sometimes too uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		sometimes if something uh is on that they want to watch i leave it on but we eat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and their heads are always poking past the door
 	
 	
 		uh-huh see what's happening
 	
 	
 		yeah anyway <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is is uh a real lifestyle kind of thing and i some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't like to do this but i like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook uh cook</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and if they're going to have other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> over then then they help and we make real simple things you know those oh i don't i don't know if you've ever made them maybe not since you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> yet but those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JELL-O</ENAMEX>
 		uh gelatin things you can pick up with your fingers i can't think of what they call it
 	
 	
 		oh i've seen those in the magazines
 	
 	
 		yeah they're so simple
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> love to do that uh finger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is is a biggie with them and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and like  now one thing i wish i could find a a better way to do are celery sticks and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carrot</ENAMEX> sticks because they love to do that and it's just really hard and if they have to work with a knife i don't like that so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's uh they like to eat it but it's a hard one to have to to prepare
 	
 	
 		yeah i'll bet
 	
 	
 		but they like that with the the cool ranch dressing that goes along with that so yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah we like that
 		that's good that that's a good way to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s getting to be a a real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> so uh
 	
 	
 		oh neat
 	
 	
 		sometimes he fixes me breakfast
 	
 	
 		oh wow that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah i like it i like it a lot
 	
 	
 		how old he
 	
 	
 		he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> wow that's good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah so he's
 	
 	
 		do you cook breakfast like you cook a breakfast every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		uh not every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> uh
 		mostly during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> it's hit and miss and we usually have like uh cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal</ENAMEX> or something like that um during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> during
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wintertime</ENAMEX> when they're in school um then i try to vary it so that we only eat that like a twice a twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or something and then have like when it's really cold
 		i even cook oatmeal because i like oatmeal and the look they like it all right and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then sometimes we do something it has to be fast because they're on their way to school we do like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eggo</ENAMEX> waffles and stuff like that but
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so i try to uh and sometimes we do <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> if i get up
 		early enough to do that i used to do them in the microwave but they don't like that
 	
 	
 		oh do they get rubbery or
 	
 	
 		uh um
 	
 	
 		i've never tried it
 	
 	
 		it depends it depends if you let them cook too long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then they'll turn a little bit gray you can tell if they've gone to long because they'll turn a little bit gray and they will be a little harder and i don't like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you have to just let it cook a little bit less than what it says in if you have a microwave book but uh you cook it a little bit less and then let it sit with a
 		like a plate over the top and let it steam and then and then stir it up
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		yeah an and that turns out okay and it's funny because if i turn them out on to a dish i on to like a plate for them to take what they want
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they don't know i've ever done it in a microwave
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's really funny it's very deceiving you know because if they see it with their eyes they go uh i don't like want that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and yet if they don't ever see it then then it's like oh this tastes okay you know so anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> used to do that to us with things like squash everybody would say we don't like squash we won't eat squash so she would make these fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casseroles</ENAMEX> and hide it in there you know and then we'd go oh this is really good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	