
 
     		
 	
 		there you go first question do you own your house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh right well we try  i mean it's a big mortgage in the sky and someday maybe we might even own it but um
 		for all practical purposes i guess we hold the mortgage
 	
 	
 		
 
 		our name is on the bill so that implies ownership
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah right no one else has offered to pay for it
 	
 	
 		that's right and i wouldn't object if anybody did
 	
 	
 		yeah really they could move right into the spare room
 	
 	
 		yeah well we've we had this one for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> now before that we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> uh
 		probably about you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> blocks away liked the area chose to stay inside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Park</ENAMEX> it's a uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you have been up here but it is a residential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> so there's a lot of you know activities a lot of pluses and common land
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh we thought we were buying at the bottom of the market you know it could not possibly have gone any lower and so we were wrong
 	
 	
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think what it bottom out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year year</TIMEX> later
 	
 	
 		yeah it well i mean just recently i would say i would give it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years back</TIMEX> when it was i think bottomed out
 	
 	
 		oddly enough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> you know i i think that
 	
 	
 		but maybe not in your area see it was just different areas
 	
 	
 		not in in in this area because this is about like the
 	
 	
 		that's a really nice area besides it's you know it's not it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> is it it's still considered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> and hold on a second  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> i can hear you perfectly perfectly well i don't want to hear you you are being rude whatever you ask or scream when i'm on the phone the answer is no do you understand
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah
 	
 	
 		how does that sound
 	
 	
 		there you go write that one down it sounded good to me
 	
 	
 		yeah there i go yeah yeah well i hate to say how long that will last too no this area up here is uh  all custom <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and it's
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i i don't think that many by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builder</ENAMEX> that we that built this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and we were not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> i think we are the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> it was built by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> for himself
 	
 	
 		uh okay
 	
 	
 		who never moved into it who sold it to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> who had no idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> ever needed upkeep
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		oh yeah caulking windows was a great mystery to them you know you know they just watched the water pour in on the carpet but it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sharif Myneer Homes</ENAMEX> if that means anything it did not really mean anything to me except i liked it
 	
 	
 		oh gee
 		i i i kept thinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Sharif</ENAMEX> every time i saw that name somewhere so
 	
 	
 		he builds <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight hundred thousand dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> now i think he got out of the lower end market and decided but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> here in in this class of housing never dropped to below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		yeah well  but still i know that this one was built for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two ninety nine</NUMEX> which is nowhere near what we paid for it and i think or somebody told me it's also on a creek side lot heavily wooded off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		yeah and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> around the corner is being transferred so he said uh well he did comparable that it's about eighty dollars
 		i think it was
 		i don't remember if he said it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> dollars a square foot off the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">creek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eighty on the creek</ENAMEX> or if it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty and a hundred</NUMEX> i think it was sixty eighty
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah
 		probably eighty sixty eighty
 	
 	
 		i think
 	
 	
 		well because i know our our little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> over here stuck in the middle of you know the subdivision is i think fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> so i think the high end is definitely you know somewhere around there
 	
 	
 		well try and think if it was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> a square foot
 		no it could not be because this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around thirty four hundred square feet</NUMEX> and it would never sell for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred forty thousand dollars</NUMEX> just never
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		now maybe you know that's that's pretty close to what it would have sold for uh brand new
 		or and that's pretty much what it was built for it's got an awful lot of nice things in it but you know i don't think i think it's going to be a long time if ever when nice things and really quality construction and all the other additional amenities
 		are really uh
 		desirable it's seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go for square footage only now
 		and uh because have you been back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Perry Homes</ENAMEX> back here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		um the ones that look like brick houses
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Monopoly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right yeah i think those are awful  i'm sorry i just don't see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>'s
 		i i just see him as trying to squish as much space you know as much <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> into the space as possible
 	
 	
 		they are huge when you are inside them they're very spacious they're you know i was i was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one today</TIMEX> it was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty two hundred square feet</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		well see that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that we got is small enough so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i because there's just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats um</ENAMEX> can yell at each other from one end to the other and be heard and we thought that was important instead of getting swallowed up in something that you know
 	
 	
 		see when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you like to be able to send them some place where they can yell and you won't hear them but i have been watching these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> go up and i i
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		don't well somebody was telling me i know somebody who lives back there i've always questioned the quality of construction and i i don't think they exceed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than twelve nails</NUMEX> per house
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		when you watch them go up you are just amazed that they do not fall over and it takes them something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX> to complete a house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that's amazing right now in fact even as we speak we are having a deck put on in back and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are phenomenal they just they they are doing such a
 		terrific job back there i mean you know you you pay for it too but it's it's like really worth it they are putting in a deck a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">redwood deck</ENAMEX> and it's just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they are doing such a fine fine job and i'm really excited about it
 	
 	
 		we've got
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different levels of decking because this lot slopes way back down and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is built around the trees
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and with these decking decking that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> and a large area for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> to come up so it's real real shady but that's one of the few things
 		that really uh immediately pays back on return but what i was going to tell you these <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry Homes</ENAMEX> back there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> come down and they are you know they're used to the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> area metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> my God they come down here and and those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that that look like to them the colonial look what the
 	
 	
 		oh
 		looks like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town Brownstone</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		right and the idea of ever owning anything that has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four thousand square feet</NUMEX> in it for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than two hundred twenty thousand dollars</NUMEX> which is probably about what their equity is that they got out of selling their house those things are selling like hot cakes
 	
 	
 		must be a dream come true yeah
 	
 	
 		but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that was living back there was telling me that there is his air conditioning bill per month <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> was in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month and i thought
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i can't
 	
 	
 		and he was talking he was talking about how you keep up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> here and i was thinking well you know i know why your God damn bill is so high it's because there's not a there's no insulation insulation in those things
 	
 	
 		he has no insulation probably
 		oh my gosh what a trap
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		any yet you know  they they show very well uh they show very well unless you have you know lived in a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> around here or
 	
 	
 		and you ask the right questions and can research yeah
 	
 	
 		or looked at a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> around here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think that makes a big difference but i like i like this area and everything that i've been saying says that it's
 	
 	
 		oh i do too
 	
 	
 		if i think if we had to sell now we could come close to breaking even
 	
 	
 		but still um it's worth it for the area and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		you're in you're in the
 		
 		
 	