
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		uh
 		wow i don't know what that was i don't know
 	
 	
 		what what was that
 		and uh to um
 		
 
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brazos River</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dinosaur Valley State Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes uh-huh um the we have not camped in any of those places in fact it has been a number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> since we have camped but we used to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyler State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> and um to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dangerfield</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that is where we camped basically um
 	
 	
 		what are they like
 	
 	
 		they're very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX> is really really a neat place to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> it has a nice a nice little lake and it has some really wonderful uh sights that are in the the wooded areas
 		um the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are quite nice and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> like liked it quite well uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are
 		well they were quite a bit younger then and uh you know it they we felt real um safe with their being able to do what they would like to do there in the area and uh it was just it was a really nice place to to camp
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um now Dangerfield</ENAMEX> is let's see i think that's a little bit more more east further east
 		and maybe south if i am remembering where that is no i think it's a little bit further north when i think about it at any rate it was it was very nice as well but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX> we sort of got spoiled with i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh we had lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> before we came here and um had done a lot of camping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> i think the upper peninsula of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> especially and then also we had done some camping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> in the mountains so uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were real avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campers</ENAMEX>  and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were really avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> as well so i guess we just kind of came by it naturally
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		do you um have a large tent or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it was a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a nine by twelve uh-huh</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and how how many does that sleep uh comfortably
 	
 	
 		well there well supposedly it it's they always say it sleeps more than it does
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it they it would have slept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> anyway yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well sort of early on especially as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> got a little bit bigger uh we invested in some stacking um cots you know that were like bunk bunk beds but they were cots fold up cots that really gave us a lot more space um floor space and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you didn't have to be constantly getting things off the floor in order to walk around and uh gave us a place to stack things during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> so that was real nice
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh we um
 		my my uh uh in-laws also had a camper um pop up tent tent you know one of those trailer pop ups and those are really nice too and the little more uh luxurious so to speak but not much
 	
 	
 		do do they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> in them
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh it's really nice in fact it even have a had a little refrigerator and and the whole business it was quite nice in that respect and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh everything was very convenient and you didn't have to to be hauling things out of your the trunk of you car so that was nice yeah
 	
 	
 		trunk of your car all time right
 	
 	
 		so um do you have plans for for any other camping trips in the near future
 	
 	
 		oh maybe uh maybe back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caddo</ENAMEX> or um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdis Creek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		or uh i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Sandlin</ENAMEX> too it's a new park
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there is um not really camping but
 		
 
 		um
 		what's it called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cedar Hill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Pool</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and sometime i like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> up on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> Texoma
 	
 	
 		yes yes i've been in that area that's a really pretty state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just we didn't camp there but we drove through it just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time when we were in that area and it's just real lovely it's close to the lake and close to the dam i think it's close to the dam up there so it's it's really quite pretty
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are you um let's see what was i was going to ask you something else oh do you have a favorite among all those that you have been to
 	
 	
 		oh from from those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> just just uh from when i have been an adult i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caddo</ENAMEX> the best
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		is uh is it true that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caddo Lake</ENAMEX> is the only natural lake in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		i i would i've never been there and i would love to see what it looks like
 	
 	
 		it's not it's not very deep and they did build a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX> on it but it was there before they built the dam it's been there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years</TIMEX> apparently an earth quake caused it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see
 		how interesting i guess i'd never heard the history of that huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that might be some place where we my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i can go we're talking about starting camping again in the fall
 		um our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are both grown and and so it's just pretty much the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us who do things and so uh we thought we might take some weekend trips then and maybe that would be a good place to to go to and see what it looks like
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really nice
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and it i don't know probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> is probably the busiest time anywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		is it uh yeah i think so especially with uh uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> start blossoming out and everything it is really very pretty especially in east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's really nice so
 	
 	
 		that's right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		well uh  i've enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		it's nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		and um have uh uh some happy camping trips  hope you get to those places you've talked about
 	
 	
 		yeah you too
 	
 	
 		well okay thanks uh-huh bye bye
 	
 	
 		bye bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	