
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans Americans</ENAMEX> like me and whether or not uh uh uh not i think that we're paying too much taxes um that including taxes in general or income tax
 		and um  the other thing was do we get what we pay for i mean what what is our what is our opinion on that so
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		are you prepared to talk  let me push
 	
 	
 		oh i guess so go by ear
 	
 	
 		let me push <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay um well i can just tell you a little bit about taxes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's most interesting because we're one of the few if i don't know of any other state
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> does not have a state and so we don't have a state income tax but we certainly make up for it in other ways here um for instance the local um sales tax is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight and a quarter</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		isn't that awful  how about you what do you have there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh we have a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">six percent</NUMEX> sales tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and you have state income tax also
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah well it's been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here have just have this um they've been really holding out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> and
 		it's starting to show um in a lot of ways as far as things that are just totally under funded and and i don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is ever going to be able to to um totally avoid having an income tax or not i think eventually they're going to have to do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um do you think you pay too much there or how do you feel about that
 	
 	
 		i don't mind my taxes as much as my social security
 	
 	
 		oh really interesting uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um the taxes i don't know i can deal with that because i know everyone else is paying in too i guess you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yes
 	
 	
 		but uh oh i don't know uh the one thing that we don't have uh tax on clothes do you
 	
 	
 		uh-huh um yes we do have tax on clothes
 	
 	
 		that's what i thought i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> has also has a sales tax on clothes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like going to college with me that lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or out of state and a lot of them would buy their clothes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> just for the simple sake of not paying that
 	
 	
 		how interesting i guess i didn't realize that um we don't have tax on groceries for instance um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no well we don't have it necessarily on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> but then there's other things that they nail you for it like health and beauty products you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right yes yes i should i should've um delineated yet your absolutely right it's the food the consumable food parts that you know we don't have to pay tax on yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and you really have to watch your your um bill sometimes i think um it's real interesting to look to see how many things that i buy in a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> which are not really edible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX>  and that's when it really starts to add on and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so um that's that is sort of a help but um i don't know it's just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight and a quarter</NUMEX> just seems like an awfully lot of of tax on uh any sale as far as i'm concerned um
 	
 	
 		yeah that would uh
 	
 	
 		it's real interesting this last um tax season i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and the last tax season i had a just a part time job helping out in a tax office
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that owned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was saying she'd had this business for oh probably seventeen or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years</TIMEX> and she was saying as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> have gone on there are fewer and fewer things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can uh take off of their income tax
 	
 	
 		deduct yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know if you're not a home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> it's or if you haven't sold property or uh have something major like that it's hardly you know it it's just not much else you can do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she said it's really taken the fun out of doing taxes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for her because she used to be real creative about helping them find ways of you know accumulating receipts can't do oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and see i take it she was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		can't do it any more  so
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh i know well i i i also was a student i just graduated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and um i graduated with a finance degree but that was the big joke the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who found ways to cheat on your income tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		how interesting
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that was the big joke
 	
 	
 		oh gosh where did you go to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarion University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh well you're you're the same age as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> because she just graduated from college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> too i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> having gone back after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> so um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		nevertheless i am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and poor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's uh um
 		you know it's been i i guess as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we can feel like sometimes we pay more than our share as middle class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with um college age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> you know and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i there just i don't know i guess as you say you just have to look around and decide that most of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know are paying about what you are and
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think they should go back i i realize you know that we have uh graduated tax brackets
 		but i think they should still go back and instead of putting the burden more on the middle class i think the burden should be put more on the wealthy
 	
 	
 		oh yes absolutely yeah because uh it seems like you they still come out okay um you know uh they
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you know they always have the argument well you know well who's to say we don't work harder to get that you know well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i kind of have my doubts
 	
 	
 		i don't care how much they take off of you you know you're still going to be above on top and i you know like you said i i've worked in different places and the ones that get the most pay do the least work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's
 		yes seems that way yeah that the higher they get the you know at least i don't know it seems like um they must feel like they're paid for all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of experience or um or something or just the title sometimes um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it it doesn't seem fair and i i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do make money um you know in in good investments and things like that
 		but i think that's a lot of luck and a lot of gambling and not a whole not a whole lot of work
 	
 	
 		i agree with you i do think it's a lot of luck and i don't like that part of the finance you know whatsoever
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know but like what i was saying about the social security that's real you know it never bothered me until we started talking about it in my classes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then the more i think about it the more i think i'm paying in to something that i granted you know i'm paying for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> but i'm never going to see that social security is going to be gone before i ever get any
 	
 	
 		right
 		probably not
 		yeah yes or what's left is not going to be worth anything um you know in terms of how you can actually use it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right they're going to pay me fifty dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> well
 	
 	
 		yeah right but that's well and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i 'm sorry i put in much more than that you know
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah yeah that's i haven't heard much um in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> um about social security i mean for a while there not too long ago they were they were saying that the whole system was going to be bankrupt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know before very long because so much was going out for programs that were it was that originally it was never intended to be used for or you know programs just weren't in existence and um
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then i it sort of calmed down i haven't heard much lately but if you have talked about that in your classes you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> i'm sure that you have heard
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah well um i don't know i guess we complain about taxes but i guess you know uh you have to be sort of
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you you got to look to what they put you know you have decent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> at least
 	
 	
 		yeah you have to appreciate yeah what what you do get for them sometimes and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess it's it's worse you know i'd rather see be able see to control my money as much as i do with what's left over taxes than to live in oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> or um some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where so much of it is socialized that you don't see any of that money at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and so you know i guess it's all relative
 	
 	
 		it's how you look at it too
 	
 	
 		yeah that's exactly right
 	
 	
 		i like to instead of thinking how much you know that i'm paying out i like to just look at it and say oh well everyone else is doing it too you know
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah and i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	