
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um well what's your favorite TV program
 	
 	
 		well i tape one soap opera everyday and i watch that i've been watching that since i was in college i mean we made our class schedules around it so we could watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Days of Our Lives</ENAMEX>  and then um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pretty much i like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> minute sitcoms in the evenings i mean i don't i don't get to watch them a lot but i do watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy Brown and Designing Women</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so what do you watch
 	
 	
 		uh well to the to the great chagrin of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i i love all forms of entertainment and so i i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Entertainment Tonight</ENAMEX> with regularity
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i love it but it comes on so late
 	
 	
 		i tape it and watch it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		oh you do  well that's a good idea yeah because i was real disappointed because on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> i used to especially try to watch it and because they kind of caught you up during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> and uh then they put on some other goofy show after that
 	
 	
 		right
 		well that they're doing it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> now um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh really what at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at ten thirty</TIMEX> oh well i'll have to watch that then
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten thirty</TIMEX>
 		hm for an hour i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm sure my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> doesn't care too much for that either
 	
 	
 		no  i just what can i say i just
 		matter of taste and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the time right now</TIMEX> there's not a TV series that i'm particularly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		glued to uh i watch some of the anthologies if they've got something interesting on like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masterpiece Theatre</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		Mystery or something like that yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah um channel thirteen had on a a thing about astronomy that was really neat but i didn't get to see all the parts
 	
 	
 		yes we saw we saw we saw several of those not all of them
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh so we're we're we're pretty eclectic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> we've i've been introduced to the joys of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> so we watch that with  with total total devotion
 	
 	
 		the old ones or the new ones
 		do you watch the new ones too
 	
 	
 		uh yes only the new one i i i i never really was interested in the old one and uh and so but i like i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of the new one so uh that's what we watch
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		well that's pretty neat yeah i don't even know when that comes on anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Saturdays</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really hm well we go to the lake a lot so when i don't get to see it that much TV in the summertime and plus everything is in reruns anyway so i guess it works out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		true that's true um i i'm a very selective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX> i i look at the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> and
 		decide what i'm going to watch and watch it but as a rule i don't sort of  stroll around the dial and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah without with the old remote control in hand
 	
 	
 		let things catch my eye
 		yes unlike certain parties
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got my niece and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> so i thought well i ought to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> because there's some fun stuff on there even for me to watch
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		oh yes and also i don't know how old they are but there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX> but they get that but where they live they live out in the boondocks of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and they don't get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> channel
 	
 	
 		oh well they would enjoy that
 	
 	
 		so yeah i think i might have to do that but i mean just some of the movies that they have on there i would love to see so i might have to do that
 	
 	
 		um-hum so would i
 		i wouldn't admit it to anybody normally
 	
 	
 		yeah i like the older movies better i think uh channel <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX> or somebody played uh Hello <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolly</ENAMEX> last night
 	
 	
 		oh well  yes you hit upon a a weak spot of mine i like i i have a thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius Hackel</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really yeah it was neat
 	
 	
 		no i mean forty here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years later</TIMEX> you understand yes because he's uh he plays the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Phantom of the Opera</ENAMEX> now and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i didn't realize that
 	
 	
 		oh yes and  his voice is somewhat developed to put it mildly and so uh but but i've already got that on tape so we didn't tape it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i like old movies i love musicals
 	
 	
 		oh i do too i mean i've got um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Society</ENAMEX> on tape that i taped and uh you know all the older ones
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum right
 	
 	
 		they were fun to watch  they were real good on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">rainy days</TIMEX> and there's nothing else on
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 	
 	
 		sit back and watch the old musicals
 	
 	
 		i know i keep a little a little a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and if i get stuck i can resort to my little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in all sorts of things
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah because that does happen a lot there is nothing on anywhere on cable or anything
 	
 	
 		it's surprising with all the choice we have sometimes there's no choice
 	
 	
 		yeah  it's strange  well um did i catch you in the middle of something
 	
 	
 		not really but uh  you know luckily i wasn't i hadn't i hadn't started dinner yet
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i've i've already finished mine i haven't done my dishes yet my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s on his way home so  well i do we have a time limit
 	
 	
 		hm
 		i don't know i got kicked off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> because they said the lines were busy
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but i think i uh  i don't i think that's unusual i don't think that's typical
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hm  well i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		me too me too and uh you keep you keep on watching for those old movies
 	
 	
 		oh i will got to tape them  thanks bye
 	
 	
 		all right all right bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	