
 
     		
 	
 		okay we can start
 	
 	
 		okay hi
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> okay okay well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		how many do you have
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stepdaughters  so we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> altogether too
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay
 	
 	
 		yeah are you are you running ragged these days
 	
 	
 		well no because <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> are all grown
 	
 	
 		oh they are oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so the topic for me i i can only rerate relate now to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well good impart me some wisdom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do keep my
 		uh i do take care of my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">granddaughter</ENAMEX> uh
 		most every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is uh
 		uh doing a schedule of uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> but she gets paid for forty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> is uh in supervisory work and he has to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every Saturday</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		how old is your granddaughter
 	
 	
 		she's three
 	
 	
 		oh so she's a little one yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yes she's she's little  she's says how are you doing grandma today
 	
 	
 		oh  are you surviving is she oldest your oldest granddaughter child
 	
 	
 		whoa
 		oh no no no no she's my baby
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		she's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> yeah she was a miracle baby
 	
 	
 		oh
 		was she yeah oh oh that's nice now do your other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area do you get to see them how nice what a treat you know being from Plano
 	
 	
 		yeah she really was uh-huh yeah
 		yes they do uh-huh they really do uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know i know so very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in town i'm real jealous when i hear that somebody has a grandma around because we don't and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's really that's really wonderful
 	
 	
 		it is it is and you know just so that they get to know their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> but also
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for help  we don't we don't have that luxury but we have lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and and everybody tends to be in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> so we trade we trade off a whole lot with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		run here and run there we're right smack dab in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of baseball season</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's marvelous well they keep you hopping i'm sure
 	
 	
 		so
 		they definitely do
 	
 	
 		well i know um that uh one of the ladies i know they are very involved with their little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and and i think it's excellent because she's getting qualified quality time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for um her musical uh talents her sports abilities
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think because she is um
 		the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that they concentrate uh
 		they would like to have more but that hasn't been um
 		possible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she's tried many uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so now it's just you know that she's kind of resolved herself that yes this is going to be the only one
 	
 	
 		yeah and she devotes yeah
 	
 	
 		and and they're focusing on all of her uh
 		welfare
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh yeah well our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know um
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> sings uh sings with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Younger Generation</ENAMEX> i don't know if you've ever heard of them there they're a singing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> here in Plano
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and they're part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plano Children's Civics Civic Chorus</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> next <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">to sing</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time isn't that neat yeah so so we have been really up to our eye balls in fund raising and trying to get uh
 	
 	
 		oh how wonderful that's wonderful
 		well that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah it is it is so you know and then she plays softball and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> plays baseball and my stepdaughter plays softball so we we tend to do a lot of running things are very different nowadays than when i grew up and i'm sure when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> grew up you didn't
 	
 	
 		oh they are
 	
 	
 		uh you know i don't remember doing all these things i certainly don't remember my parents
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		running me here and there and supporting me in all these things but we had more
 		i guess family time alone where we did nothing which was good
 	
 	
 		yeah you're now i think everything everything is doing doing doing out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> which can be very hectic
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		it can be and and sometimes i uh you know i kind of long for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the good old days</TIMEX> when  we didn't do all these running but on the other hand
 	
 	
 		yeah it wasn't so hectic
 	
 	
 		we just love watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play and getting to know the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and we've had a lot of fun with that too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you have to look on that on the uh positive side of that
 	
 	
 		it's just different
 	
 	
 		yes it is it's just a different lifestyle yes
 	
 	
 		yeah it's just very different
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		my my uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> is an a cappella and i know what you're talking about when he's involved
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are involved in that and he's been he has traveled and they have won awards so i know yes uh-huh and i know where you're coming from and it's it's very nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really yeah
 		yeah
 		it is very nice
 	
 	
 		i think um
 		uh those type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um that are involved in things like that their uh goals are going to be set higher than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that are not participating in things
 	
 	
 		well i think so and and i think they've learned a whole lot about
 		being part of a team whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is your singing group your band your your sports team
 	
 	
 		right
 		going to
 	
 	
 		you know you all have to pull together and uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 		on of a team effort yes to
 	
 	
 		yeah and so i've been real pleased with that too i think they've learned some real good life skills
 		um
 		you know being involved in all those things and uh yeah
 	
 	
 		that's
 		that's wonderful that's really is nice to have in your background that you know then you can you're you can be very flexible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		there's less uh friction involved in relationships when you add that skill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of teamwork and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> are having to go back and learn those basics when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are already learning that
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		and i think it's a step
 		uh a giant step of progress i really do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um i
 	
 	
 		give me some wonderful advice <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX> what is the best advice of mothering that you know  besides don't sweat the small stuff
 	
 	
 		the best of
 		well uh
 		Cathy i think if you look to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word of God</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh that's good that's real good advice
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		think on the things that are pure and lovely
 		and uh keep your mind
 		off of negative things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and keep your mind on positive things and and stress that to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even if they're even if they're discouraged tell them that that's just a passing moment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and to dwell on those things that are uh  not negative and that are positive things things in their life and i think you'll see a lot of growth in uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in their ability to uh control their thought pattern
 		and and when you employ the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word of God</ENAMEX> there's nothing as powerful as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word of God</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		absolutely well i would agree with that we're also real active in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		do an awful lot with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allyson</ENAMEX> sings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> i told her that's a gift from God and you need to return that back
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely that's right
 	
 	
 		and you owe you owe that back to God because he's given you that ability and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and and that's real nice i i'm real proud of her i'm equally proud of her when i see her in church as i am when i see her performing you know that's that's real neat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		well if she looks yeah if she looks at it as you suggest that that that's that she can give her her her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> for His glory and she can look at it that way and and uh that's beautiful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but there's nothing stronger than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word of God</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	