
 
     		
 	
 		okay do you like to listen to music
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i like to listen to music i just am not a very educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> when it comes to music
 	
 	
 		well i'm not either as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		what what do you like to listen to
 	
 	
 		well it's really strange i like country music and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes the older rock and roll stuff so we've had to kind of educate each other
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's been kind of strange
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure
 	
 	
 		yeah but being in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> you'd think you get a lot of good country music
 	
 	
 		well i'm not originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> so it took me moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> to start liking country music
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and now i really do i'm i'm really becoming Texanized
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well have you ever gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin City</ENAMEX> Limits
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i haven't but i watch it on i watch it on um television sometimes and and uh i've taken country western dance lessons oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh you have did you like that oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i love it i absolutely love it
 	
 	
 		yeah i took that in college <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time as an easy course
 	
 	
 		and uh oh yes i definitely am am much more into country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um so you you which uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> do you like i mean i can actually name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> i'm i'm not too bad
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		well naturally i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Strait</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Strait</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> went to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that i went to and he used to play in a little dive there in town  when
 	
 	
 		so you know him from
 	
 	
 		when he was a nobody no i don't know him personally but i do remember going to see him when he was a nobody
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah but i went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Strait</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Strait</ENAMEX> was a nobody too
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so yeah i've kind of followed them
 	
 	
 		well who are you going to go see now i mean who do you see now that's going to be somebody someday
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i really like um what's his name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> what's his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i can't think of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name he's a blonde <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and he sings um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Jackson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Jackson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		he has some kind of fun <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> tunes but you know it's really funny because country music has changed so much from when
 		like i remember in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s ed in high school that that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> always liked to listen to country music as we were  driving and i thought oh God this stuff is horrible
 	
 	
 		well okay well maybe it just has changed and maybe it's more accepted all over
 	
 	
 		it really has i mean country music is a lot easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to break into as opposed to other fields of music so i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and then try to
 	
 	
 		right and then you you know you kind of think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> you know that kind of brought everyone into a more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and and you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah definitely yeah i used to go see them they weren't nobodies then but i did go see them before they got to be major big stars
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so  it was fun but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenny Kenny Rogers</ENAMEX> he's kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i remember because when i was taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s ed is right when <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Picked a Fine Time to Leave Me Lucille</ENAMEX> came out and it seemed like every other song on the radio was that song
 	
 	
 		
 
 		had to listen to that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but it's fun i really i i enjoy listening to it i i keep my radio on at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> but i don't you know i don't have it turned up real loud unless it's a really good song
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and then you just you you pump up the volume yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah just a little see it's real funny because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that i work with is from um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and he is trying to learn now about country music he's gotten to where he really likes it but he doesn't know any of the names of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> yeah that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah  just yeah i was so amazed
 	
 	
 		that's like about the farthest call from country music you can get
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but he's got he's real funny because his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is across from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> and so he'll turn up the radio real loud and say who's this singing
 	
 	
 		oh that's great where do you work
 	
 	
 		i work for a computer company
 	
 	
 		oh that's super
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's fun because it's small enough that we can do stuff like that and get away with it
 	
 	
 		so you can do things like that yeah i'm i'm i'm being envious well one thing that i did in music that i mean was a big extravagance for me but
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> that are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitney Houston</ENAMEX> just came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and and she was coming to town <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was getting her braces off so i and i really like her so i thought well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		we'll we'll go buy tickets and this is how we'll celebrate getting braces off teeth
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and she really she really i i wouldn't say it was the a great concert
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not that i've had that many but i know it wasn't a great concert you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it wasn't a bad one either and the one thing that i really appreciated in going to hear her sing in person is
 		her extreme volume for that tiny little body you know and she really does have to work to get it all out
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and you'd you wouldn't catch that you know off of a  a CD or a cassette you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well did you happen to see her um welcome home show on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i did not no
 	
 	
 		she had so much energy i mean she danced and danced and danced  and i thought golly that's like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hour</TIMEX> aerobic class
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i know i know so that that was really really fun um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah that would be neat i didn't know she was going to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that was just last week
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh well that's neat
 	
 	
 		so we had a good time
 	
 	
 		yeah well are you familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Henley</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		i'm not
 	
 	
 		he um used to play with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Eagles</ENAMEX> have you do you know anything about them
 	
 	
 		i know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		okay well he was one of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> and he's broken off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and gone solo and he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and put on a wonderful concert he sang
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		for like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> and he sang a lot of old stuff and a lot of his new stuff so it was really exciting
 	
 	
 		well you know now that you mention it i probably had would know you know know a song of his
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm sure yo ur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		oh yes i well they're you know they know everything and then they always ask me if i know sport figures too so i'm a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flunky</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i in fact i had older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> so or older older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> older sisters
 	
 	
 		oh so they kind of
 	
 	
 		so i got to listen i got to listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermits</ENAMEX> and all that stuff so that was fun
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it's but it's really funny now because i'll i'm going to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and it's sad because i listen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oldies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and i know all the songs
 	
 	
 		i know i know
 	
 	
 		it's kind of depressing
 	
 	
 		it is it's it's sad when you reach that age
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		but you're not doing bad i have a a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that i mean she's much older than i am she's i think about fifty eight
 		and she's really up on all the new music even better than i am and and i mean she just likes music and she's just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's really with it so maybe you'll be like she is
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah
 		well i hope it's really funny though because i'll be at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> working out and i'll hear the aerobics music going and i'll think God that's a remake of an old song
 	
 	
 		right right  and it really gets bad when you can remember what you were doing oh i remember
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know  remember the original
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh and we're we're just getting to that age where we date ourselves all over the place
 	
 	
 		oh i know it's pretty sad but it's real funny with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> too because he really likes older rock and roll so
 	
 	
 		did he really like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah he i mean he's got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crosby Still</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> and you know all those songs that that my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> know i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> but not any of the other ones i mean like he likes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santana</ENAMEX> and some kind of off the wall ones so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm getting indoctrinated to a new a new uh line of music
 	
 	
 		you're picking up some new stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah it's fun though we have a good time because
 	
 	
 		oh it is
 		
 		
 	