
 
     		
 	
 		okay what do you think is the biggest problem
 	
 	
 		the biggest problem well like in this part of town seems to be the attitude and the atmosphere in the schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh you know you can throw money at it but it's i don't know to me it seems like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are reflecting society in a bigger way you know because i mean the general values that we're teaching
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of conflict with what we expect out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in school i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		is it the do you think it's the values that they're teaching in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or the the values they get from home
 	
 	
 		uh well the values more or less at home and the TV just a general i mean learning is not a a revered endeavor really i mean it's a lot more
 		it's socially well i won't say socially unacceptable but whereas like in uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that uh study they put a lot more emphasis on athletics and things like that are a lot more glorified generally in society and i think that carries over to school a lot so
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i i i i think that the biggest problem is uh with the uh with the the home environment being part of it you know if
 		i think too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> expect uh the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school</TIMEX> to teach uh the moral aspects of of things to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you know while we're not going to worry about uh
 		teaching you manners or teaching you respect for anyone or anything like that you know and then uh
 		expect them to to pick it up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and you're not going to do that you know you're going to carry carry with carry to school uh out into the world you know what you learned at home and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i think that that part of that's
 		showing up now you know with with things because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		i think have probably less respect than for for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than in in other things than
 		than uh we may have seen in the past uh
 		and uh part of it's the the family i think and part of it's uh
 		the living conditions of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are subjected too uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is a big problem now and i think that's that's that's another root problem
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you know i wonder if that's a a root problem or not because i think about that a lot and it's just like everybody likes to blame uh everything on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> now but i wonder
 		you know do you get the oh that's kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> tracked but uh i just remember seeing on the news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> they had the thing about how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are doing so much better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i thought well you know of course they're doing better and not so much when i was growing up uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are generally considered a little bit easier than the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but uh
 		they still had a a better success rate simply because they started with a lot better raw material i mean everybody that went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had uh
 		at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did at least had education as a priority like you said and kind of had a whole conducive atmosphere to it and i wonder if not so much that uh
 	
 	
 		right right
 		well i think it's like you say it's it's the socioeconomic mix there you know the they're uh the you you look at the if the if the
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> like that that where you got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who are basically uh
 		that might be more well to well off you know going to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or whatever uh and and they're not all that way but you know some that are um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that they're they're they're not quite the same as as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are going to the inner city uh you know public schools
 	
 	
 		yeah this is interesting because i in my mind i don't have the stereotype of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> being a suburban kind of environment but uh this this was actually inner city
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were sending i mean just because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had the ability and the and the drive to do try and get an education
 		they didn't send him to a public school you know you have like you said you have the drug problem and just the general atmosphere where you're pressured not to learn in instance
 	
 	
 		well you know in a lot of cases uh like that where you know if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are going to a public parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> like that it's it's because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are more interested in them receiving them
 		uh uh an education it shows i think it shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have some uh desire for for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to do do well you know and that may be
 		now passed on down to to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> as well and uh maybe they pick up on that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then and then from the other aspect um maybe the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> itself is is has more emphasis on uh
 		trying to do a good job because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> may be smaller uh they may be able to to give the resources that's needed to uh to do a good job
 	
 	
 		yeah i wondering what do you what would you do to fix the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh that's a tough question how to fix the school system uh with uh i would try to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess uh to see about getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> more involved  try to to come up with more ways to do that uh uh uh stress the importance of education to both both the parents and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
 		uh
 		more
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> classes that i think that are and i think this is is happening some around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in terms of um morals trying to teach the kinds of things that that aren't getting taught at home and
 		uh
 		and and respect for other people
 		uh i think that's a big part of it you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know if you don't care about property and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know
 		you're not going to care about uh
 		about learning i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know you're not going to really care about yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what i was going to say it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and the egg thing i wonder a lot of times
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean a lot of times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> literally tear apart their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know vandalism wise and you go to
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it's been a while since i been in high school they're even in grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> when they do that but i can't remember exactly what goes through their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> when they're doing that but you got to think in a way it's
 		kind of a outward showing of that they don't think they have a chance of doing anything and take it out on the school
 	
 	
 		well you know and i that's not an easy but that's not an easy task you know that's why i say it's it's a tough question what would you do because you know even
 		trying to instill those values is kind of hard when uh when when you're growing up in you know in a home which may be uh just the pits and uh
 		you know you don't have any any kind of a environment good environment to live in you know it's kind of hard to say well you need to take care of of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s stuff as well when you're when you
 		you barely have anything yourself so i could see where that would be a problem and i think that's i think it's there are others
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	