
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 		um
 		fringe benefits are very important in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i think to provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> with a sense of security
 		do you agree with that or
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely uh are you talking about benefits i can't think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more important then than the you know the medical
 	
 	
 		yes at the rising cost of health uh care now it's uh if you have to go out and buy your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> coverage you probably have to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three four hundred dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> to get anything that even came close to it
 	
 	
 		insurance right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right and uh
 		even have dental dental insurance now which is really good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		we uh we've just got dental insurance after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first of the year</TIMEX> it's been i think probably
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight or nine years</TIMEX> since we had dental coverage and it sure makes a difference and
 	
 	
 		it it really does and uh uh
 		well let's let's see insurance i i guess that would be one of the real biggies you know to a consideration
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think the in the insurance area one of the things that we also got that we didn't have before what we haven't had in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years</TIMEX> is the card for prescriptions where you go in and just pay a minimal amount for prescriptions
 		and uh we have some that are fairly expensive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty seventy</TIMEX> dollars well now we pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight dollars</NUMEX> for them
 	
 	
 		but with um paying twenty percent
 	
 	
 		uh no that's just all prescriptions uh
 	
 	
 		i know well see if you had a seventy dollar
 		yeah okay that would save you
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's a i think it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> on generic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight dollars</NUMEX> on a name brand <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> so no matter what they are in fact you have to pay the certain basic cost
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for them you don't have to meet any deductible or anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		how about paid time off
 	
 	
 		uh yeah that's uh just vacation and some sick leave not very much though
 	
 	
 		do uh do you have a certain number of sick leave to you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> that are available to you or or is it
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		pretty much just depends on your supervisor
 	
 	
 		uh really depending uh on what you need kind of it's a case that there if you need <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a couple weeks</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> or whatever it may be then they they will consider it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's been with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> i've been with generally at a a executive position they're a little more liberal even though they're not supposed to be supposed to treat everyone the same still leave hard you know rule more liberal with time off due to the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all the extra hours</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> put in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh the uh
 		i think pension costs are making it more and more difficult for them to provide per pension benefits too
 		it's uh
 	
 	
 		oh that's right
 	
 	
 		yes because it just keeps going an up up and up there too
 		but uh there's
 	
 	
 		yeah well do as you get closer to that time you start you know you start becoming
 	
 	
 		yeah the older you get the more you start thinking about the possibilty  pension
 	
 	
 		all of a sudden you know i can remember when that who cares  so now i think oh wait let's let's maybe we better start getting serious about that
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah
 		yeah uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has worked for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six year</TIMEX> he graduated from college what in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighty six so five years this fall</TIMEX>
 		and he started out with they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four O One K</ENAMEX> plan and he asked me if he should get into it and i said well very small amount uh you can put in there and you keep adding to it and they're going to match it or so and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all of a sudden at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of last year</TIMEX> he had a sizeable amount saved up in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four O One K</ENAMEX> plan just with the matching funds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is putting in and any earnings on investments
 		so
 	
 	
 		but he can't touch that though right
 	
 	
 		no no he can't but he's only uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven years old</TIMEX> and he's already got a good start
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even if he changes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> he can you know roll that over into another plan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah we had i had that too there's a certain percentage of your salary and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> matches it fifty percent not half not not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> i meant
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they don't match it exactly but fifty fifty percent which is good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um i wish i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that did that
 		but there's oh there's various intangibles also like uh you know
 		taking pride in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you work for being able to say i work for such and such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or i hold such and such position with this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and that's one of the intangible fringe benefits i guess a certain ego level there
 	
 	
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has a lot of prestige
 	
 	
 		well it not the one i'm working for now but one i did in the past did so
 	
 	
 		but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i just felt you know
 		at a i need to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> like that again
 	
 	
 		well another thing our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> does is as far as uh like uh taking classes either within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or them offering classes to us or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or or external you know they pay close pay yes
 	
 	
 		pay tuition and books or a portion thereof
 	
 	
 		and uh check they we i think we we have a mandatory we spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least ten days a year</TIMEX> not or not well yeah
 		about something like that uh in taking classes and they're offered within <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> but you we have training plans everybody does
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i mean they really
 		you know i i think uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> really has a lot of good really good benefits
 	
 	
 		oh what you can find there is so many of these things like uh working for a company some of the things they really enhance your experience in case you do have to change companies
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it's a just makes you that much more salable shall we say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you do have to go and search for another position
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's true everything you everything you learn you
 		its yours and you you it goes with you wherever you go so the more you learn the better off you are
 	
 	
 		it's right that's right
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i used to be with also took care of things like professional dues and subscriptions to like the Wall Street and other professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> in the financial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> so it uh
 		there are there are more than just insurance and pension there's lots of other things that come up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		back in the heyday of the economy before this recession then of course there were other things available to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i never even took advantage of them of uh like
 		memberships in clubs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh had to entertain and such
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there's all sorts of fringe benefits
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's true so salary salary is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		salary is what we do work for and what we have to have that's our initial motivation
 	
 	
 		eh that's right it
 		it keeps your mortgage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> happy
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it keeps your mortgage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> happy
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah having to salary again being uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> being able to acquire the the nicer things that you want not just have to live at a a certain level being able to do things or purchase things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that you want that aren't really necessary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so um  that's about all i have
 	
 	
 		well i guess that i guess we've pretty well exhausted that
 	
 	
 		okay fine it's been nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		well nice talking nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">good-bye</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	