
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well hi i guess uh
 		i'll just start by saying that we entertain with uh a gourmet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> here
 		um which means that we have like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> four couples
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> this is really peculiar
 		most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> cook
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> you know get i guess so burned out on cooking whatever they have to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> um you know they don't really care about gourmet stuff but it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that got together and did all this and um like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> just
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		he really really likes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> in terms of um
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">barbecue</ENAMEX> and i mean all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i think like to barbecue i think it's caveman mentality but um he really does <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and it's a good thing because you know you can't you can't knock that but all these other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> do too
 	
 	
 		right right
 		no
 	
 	
 		and so we've gotten together and we just do these really elaborate gourmet meals and it's really really kind of a neat thing to do you can
 	
 	
 		
 
 		how often do you meet
 	
 	
 		well we try i mean because you know everybody is so active with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and all that it's like
 		you know if we can do it once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> we are doing well yeah so i mean we originally started out you know when we were younger  and didn't have so much stuff going on with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um then we would
 		we tried to do it every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other month</TIMEX> but lately it's just been once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh well that's much more reasonable i was involved in a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> like that for um that you know where we tried to really do gourmet uh meals and uh we
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we were a little bit too frequent i think i don't remember if we were once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or anyway it was
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it was difficult by the time we went around it was uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> so uh by the time we got around uh to each of us and it was time again we were almost tired you know
 	
 	
 		really really
 	
 	
 		um partly because um  gourmet cooking is not particularly conducive for regular dining it's too rich
 	
 	
 		oh it is absolutely
 	
 	
 		and so i we found that while we enjoyed the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> we regretted it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um so uh we we kind of and then one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> uh moved and so we sort of didn't didn't continue it but um and i must admit that as you say when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> start taking up your time
 		then you you don't have as much time for uh regular entertaining but um
 		when when we entertain i usually try to find something that would be  um kind of good for everybody and that that sometimes means you can't do gourmet
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because depending on who your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well yeah that's true and we have a
 		gourmet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that
 		can't stand fish so mean and she can get with in
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> doesn't eat any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		uh so that's a real problem because so many dishes require <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> uh well i take that back uh she can't eat some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream cheese</ENAMEX> but that that really limits um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 		it sure did it makes you uh keep looking for recipes every time you have an eye out for something like right so we we try to keep all that in mind but otherwise um i guess you know entertaining um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		i i guess i have recipes i
 		um but that's that's basically what we do is the gourmet so you know they would be pretty elaborate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um but it's fun i mean it took us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> to cook a stock and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> to make this stuff and you know you get all prepared but you're right it's very very rich and i'm glad we don't have it every
 	
 	
 		oh wow yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because it is it's a quite a treat it really is um
 	
 	
 		yeah sounds wonderful
 	
 	
 		right but so you like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and i just love the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of food i just think it's neat i just love sharing meals and
 	
 	
 		oh sure i do too yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um and whatever you can do you know to do that i don't think you have to be you know more than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX> and hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> out in the backyard and the and the coleslaw and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato salad</ENAMEX> but but
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		sure well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um daughter</ENAMEX> is graduating uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and so we're having a uh few
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and i did a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> out on to it i'm
 		buying cold cuts  well i have to make a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> and i have to make hors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">d'oeuvres</ENAMEX> and i have to make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> so i figured for the main thing it's going to be sandwiches
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but you providing
 		so right
 		right there you go
 	
 	
 		uh so oh i'm buying the little tiny rolls and so on but i can't do it you know working full-time and it's just too much
 	
 	
 		i know we're all not built like uh what what the
 		oh
 	
 	
 		those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that try to do everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> you know we all aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> and have our coordinated glasses and tablecloths and and time to you know shoot yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		wouldn't that be nice
 	
 	
 		shoot a video of the whole thing i don't know but it's it's really kind of a neat thing i get a kick out of it i i really do everything all parts of the food i mean i love to make things from scratch you know making breads and
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really pretty much appreciate it and
 	
 	
 		oh they do it it's very difficult to purchase um  items that are as good as what you can make yourself
 	
 	
 		oh i think so
 	
 	
 		um in spite of uh or if you if you do buy it it's extremely expensive in fact uh i just got back from a shopping trip to purchase purchase them
 		cold cuts and i i bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> and pastrami and and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">barbecued ham</ENAMEX> at a an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amish</ENAMEX> market near here and i've never been there before and i found that there's uh individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> are wonderful and one of the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">um  vendors</ENAMEX> had
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		cakes all sorts of wonderful cakes uh they
 		fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberry strawberry cheesecake</ENAMEX> now and and so on and it's like thirteen fifty for a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberry</ENAMEX> cheesecake
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um which is really not such a bad price i decided i i i just couldn't quite make myself um  buy it because i do make cheesecake and somehow
 	
 	
 		there you go
 	
 	
 		i didn't want to do that because it but i was very tempted because it looked wonderful and they they had black forest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cherry cake</ENAMEX> and all those things that are but those are homemade they are not um
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX> made and in that they are made in their homes um so it it's kind of interesting um it's out there if you want to pay the price but
 	
 	
 		oh it is i mean we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bakeries</ENAMEX> around here that you know you you just gain weight going by the door you know just like that really but i don't know i guess some of the best things i've ever had um
 	
 	
 		right just smelling the air yeah
 	
 	
 		i some of them were just <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hors</ENAMEX> d'oeuvres you know doing little hors <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d'oeuvre</ENAMEX> things that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have a kick making that i mean you know  i get off on strange little details of food i guess but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		gee we have so much going on here because  you know this is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> this is the southwest this is you know chips and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Picante sauce</ENAMEX> and anything hot you know you can always make it hotter and and lots of stuff like that you know so that's um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		really good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> time eating all that hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they just love it you know down here it just just you know all the
 	
 	
 		we like hot food too so
 	
 	
 		stuff that goes with that so oh i'm not thank you for noticing  i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>  and how i got really and well how i got to
 	
 	
 		right you don't sound like you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> originally though
 		
 
 		i thought i thought that there was a slight difference in accent
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> by way of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> i'm and everything is a long story but yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh that did um do you have a favorite hors <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d'oeuvre</ENAMEX> recipe that's easy or is it always complicated
 	
 	
 		well absolutely i in fact it just came to mind um and this
 		
 		
 	