
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well i take it since you selected this topic that you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't but i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and sisters
 	
 	
 		you don't
 		my goodness
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and um
 		they're past this they've been latchkey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for a while and they're almost where i can start saying they're you know young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> so i don't have to worry about child care too much anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		we're supposed to discuss what criteria we would ask or expect
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i would assume it's you know if you were looking for a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		well if i were looking
 	
 	
 		or probably even babysitters would be the same thing
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly um i think my my top priority would be that it would be someone who would be responsible and someone that would actually like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i would think someone older and i would want to know if they've had any past experience with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that varies
 		i think a lot of your criteria vary with the age of your child
 	
 	
 		yes that's true also
 	
 	
 		um you know it's it's it's once they get to a certain age it's almost more important that it's someone that can entertain your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> as opposed to someone who's
 		you know really really qualified per se
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		but with a with a baby definitely have to be someone who knows how to handle a baby and would know how to respond to an emergency
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well um i did a lot of babysitting when i was younger i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two now</TIMEX> and i did most of my babysitting when i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages of thirteen</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX>
 		but um the only thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ever asked me well of course they knew i came from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but they really didn't ask me if i was used to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or not the only other thing they asked me is what i would expect in pay
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know and um i was pretty surprised because if i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and someone would you know i would want to know
 		i personally would ask for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has babysit for before
 	
 	
 		well i my experience i babysit a lot also at when i grew up and um
 		coming from you know that background and the background as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> now i think the reason that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't ask a whole lot of questions is
 		a a lot of times babysitters i know i did this with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> it's you get somebody where you kind of know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> already
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that gives you so much basic knowledge that you don't ask a whole lot of questions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because because i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> myself so they they thought okay she knows how to how to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes well see when um i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got my babysitting my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> babysitting job was pretty strange um this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> saw us at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and she was a you you know she was a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> she didn't really know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> she knew my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> by name and that was it
 		and um
 		she knew that i was one of the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so she just asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> if i could babysit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know she really didn't know my name or anything you know and i thought that was pretty strange
 		you know and she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was still in diapers when i started babysitting
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so um
 		she pretty much you know just assumed that i would know
 		you know how to handle them so i want you know i enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i get along with them very well so there's no problem but uh with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s world and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today
 		uh there's no way i can't say that i would just ask someone you know that i didn't know like that to babysit
 	
 	
 		oh i agree with you but there again she she you know she knew
 		knew of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and she and she met in a safe setting such as church
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so she was going on those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> instincts just the same i know myself i never and i was very very protective on who babysit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i would be too
 	
 	
 		and and in it it really shocked me because just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months ago</TIMEX> someone came to my front door rang the doorbell she had just moved in the neighborhood she had her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> with her and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was oh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about a second grader</TIMEX>
 		and she was actively looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would babysit her child
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		and i thought well she doesn't know me or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from anything and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was i was almost more reluctant of letting my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> go babysit for her because i didn't know her  then she was reluctant of letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> into her house
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so different
 	
 	
 		oh i know um well i really i obviously you've never had to look for a day care or anything
 	
 	
 		well i did i did have um
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> uh in a day care for just a short time and when my oldest was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two and a half</NUMEX> and i worked just a part-time job and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in in those situations um what i did is i'd
 		i went in and you know i made a few phone calls i went in and visited i asked questions such as how they would discipline a child um that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> with me um you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you learn a lot by going in there and they explain they explain to you you know what their day consists of and what their general rules are and um
 		that's you know
 		that's as much as i know you probably could get really good feedback from a lot of other working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that have done this over and over again but i
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		how did you stumble upon the day care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> did you just look it up in a phone book or what was it
 	
 	
 		um i think lots of people lot i think i went by location for one thing i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do that i think you start out with the criteria of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know do i know of anything or do i know anyone who has their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in a day care and
 	
 	
 		yeah most i would say most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would probably go by word of mouth
 	
 	
 		right
 		right and then you know i mean even at that you have to consider the logistics of it you know i mean you're not going to take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> south of town if you work north
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes exactly
 	
 	
 		you even if that's the best <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the whole wide world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there there are just so many considerations
 	
 	
 		um-hum then again did um money come into play with it at all
 	
 	
 		oh money is always a factor in my life definitely  i've never you know i've never had the luxury of not having that be a factor um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		even in something as important as day care i know if i didn't have that stipulation i would have done things differently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montessori</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> would be something that i would have pursued but that's always a little bit more expensive than what i could look at
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		and i was very very fortunate in that i didn't have to do that on a full-time basis
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so and and then when you get you know when you get into the full-time basis day care
 		
 		
 	