
 
     		
 	
 		uh we are to discuss air pollution and uh what we think the causes are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i probably would uh target uh industry as being number one polluter
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's probably a major one i think uh individually
 		uh
 		just by the vast number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are there's i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are also a major contributor to it
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and and yes and
 	
 	
 		yeah vehicles
 	
 	
 		but right because uh there's a lot of commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> out there especially those the big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rigs</ENAMEX> like the busses and um
 		the big uh eighteen wheelers and so forth
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they would generate probably uh one of them would probably generate enough for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but that's not and i think it can be resolved if uh if they really let go with the technology that they have at uh at their hand and they haven't released it yet
 	
 	
 		just a minute i'm on the phone
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think there's a lot of hold back uh because of uh
 		oh priorities that they have you know and um it's you have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah  well it
 		yes i have i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> at the moment  you need to shut the door please
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		shut the door right now
 		we have the air conditioner running
 		what do you need  hurry i'm on the phone
 		yes you may and they keep turning the tape recorder up besides
 	
 	
 		oh okay  do you have do you watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or do you
 	
 	
 		um i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of my own and i have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that i'm tending for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> off and on so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well well that's interesting
 		um
 		is there anything
 	
 	
 		they cause more noise pollution than air pollution
 	
 	
 		well temporarily they do  then we get out of that phase
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		soon enough
 	
 	
 		but um i think another  you can tell when you go around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> you can smell specific things from from uh specific industries
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		i remember being i i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i can remember the smell of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX> vividly  and it's the type of industry you know which obviously if you can smell it it's in the air
 	
 	
 		uh-huh sure
 		um-hum  well i know uh uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> uh the way they used to take care of the trash is they would incinerate it and the fumes from the incineration was a terrible pollutant to the air
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um of course now
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think you burn it it's gone but it's not gone
 	
 	
 		no and when they and you bury it and it's not gone either because it has untold ramifications
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		then it just gets into the soil and into the water
 	
 	
 		and it gets into into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know which is uh the the most important um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX> that we have is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they're and they're destroying us they really are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we really have to do more
 	
 	
 		so i think the cockroach will evolve uh safely safely
 	
 	
 		i think we've got to do more with the recycling that's i'm i'm really glad to see that there's more of that happening
 	
 	
 		so they say
 		yes but there's not enough
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> cooperation
 	
 	
 		well it's a we're getting at least they're starting you know so at least they're moving that direction
 	
 	
 		yeah education of the
 		education of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is primary i would think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and we're hard to teach
 	
 	
 		um-hum well it's going to it's probably going to be a generation or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> before
 	
 	
 		we are hard to teach
 		absolutely yeah
 	
 	
 		before it's really going very well because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> are more aware of it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are being taught in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> more
 		it'll be you know on down the road this is going to be passed on which is good
 	
 	
 		absolutely yes uh of course uh we would like to see it accelerated because uh of the critical nature of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the learning of it and the just to um think that way we have to be in that thought pattern and able to um motivate ourselves to um
 		uh do what is right for the atmosphere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think we're all contributors i mean every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> that lives is a contributor to pollution so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we just um
 	
 	
 		i think you're right education is a big thing you know and as we educate them individually what they can do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> become more aware of the things in industry too that that are causing problems and and i think that they'll gradually they'll work towards solving those problems more too
 		um
 	
 	
 		well hopefully it can be resolved within a shorter time frame than we have seen it done in the past
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that the time frame for cleaning up our air and our and our um  land you know which uh we get our nutrients from you know i mean everything goes back to the land
 	
 	
 		yeah  just a minute and i'll turn it up i'll turn it up in a minute honey when i'm done
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so  um it's just um very critical i think at this point to uh get that through to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and get us educated
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well i think science has come a long way to making it
 		so that it's possible to find ways to solve the problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i don't know if they offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> in uh the uh in the grade school uh uh subjecting
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think they teach it a lot in science
 	
 	
 		in science okay
 	
 	
 		yeah i would think that that's where it would come through
 	
 	
 		what grade level would that be would that be um
 		perhaps the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade level which would be
 	
 	
 		i
 		i think they're kind of getting it in all different grades
 	
 	
 		well i mean are they starting though at at with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are so their little minds are like sponges and they can really uh relate to that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think they are starting probably in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade they're you know they're hearing somewhat about it um
 		i know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX> has their program to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> more aware of it and
 	
 	
 		target stores
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		they've got if you go in the entrance they've got uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> usually where they have um
 		little uh kind of a little newspaper thing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can read and and they can form a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh i see
 		um
 		help fight the pollution oh that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		uh yeah yeah
 		so
 	
 	
 		well i'm sure that uh perhaps they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> you know and other will others will pick up on their example and carry it um  further
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because um
 		thoughts are
 	
 	
 		well i i know it's hard it's a hard problem to solve because you you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> has changed back and forth between paper and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foam</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they do all these studies on which ones pollute more and then there's the paper and plastic bag question
 		
 		
 	