
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we've talked a little bit about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> school system um i i really have been pleased with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano i</ENAMEX> have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is learning disabled
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i thank God <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> that i have the resources that we have tapped into
 	
 	
 		now is he the elementary school
 	
 	
 		he's in elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and he's not severely learning disabled i mean you know he just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh but he is being helped
 	
 	
 		he's being helped he he was in resource from <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade till <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade in math and they recently released him from resource which i'm i was thrilled i really was i i just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		thought that was so neat that they got him over that hump
 		and um he's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Method</ENAMEX> of Reading i don't know if you're familiar with that it is something new and basically what they do is they start right from the beginning relearning the sounds of letters
 	
 	
 		no that's something new to me i'm
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i think i read about that in the paper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haggard</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		it's wonderful
 	
 	
 		is heading that up
 	
 	
 		yes and it's wonderful he didn't have a problem with reading as a matter of fact he's reading on level the problem was his spelling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know in in watching the way he has struggled it's interesting because i'm convinced i have the same learning disability or had that was ignored and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right so you worked you learned how to solve your problems on your own
 	
 	
 		that's right and and so it's you know it's not an intelligence problem it's just a problem with learning
 	
 	
 		has has he had this since kindergarten or is this something that maybe learning phonetics and then he just didn't learn the right way
 	
 	
 		well you know it's funny when um when he was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade he had trouble with with spelling and i would say to the teacher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's amazing he will be able to you'll say to him spell <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 		and you know he'll say <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C A T</ENAMEX> and then he would go to write it and he would write <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C O T</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and i kept saying to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> something is wrong here something is wrong here and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> kept saying oh he has a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> birthday he's just immature
 	
 	
 		you're right right
 		right
 	
 	
 		well <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade it was i will these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> as far as i'm concerned are absolute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX> because in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade it was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second week</TIMEX> of school i went up there and i i requested a conference
 	
 	
 		good good that's great for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to be involved
 	
 	
 		and because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> long they kept telling me i was crazy
 		well i was and i and i went up there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second week</TIMEX> of school and i said you know something is wrong and thank God the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> the head <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> the team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> was a special education major
 	
 	
 		oh how great
 	
 	
 		it was it was and
 	
 	
 		so she she was able to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> in oh
 	
 	
 		she had picked it up yep she had already picked it up and she said you know we we were going to call you if you hadn't called us we think there's a learning disability and we think he needs to be tested immediately
 		because you know once the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> report card comes in they have all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being tested and she said i think we can get him real fast
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and sure enough they tested him and you know he qualified for for the help
 		and it's been great and i and i thank God i'm here because i i know i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who has the other extreme she has a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> who is extremely gifted
 		and because of the cutbacks in the economy they have nothing for her
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		and and to me that's the same thing it's it's like having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who has a learning disability that's being ignored this poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted child</ENAMEX> is being ignored
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right but that's something that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i think are able to help the gifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the home more than they could help the learning disabled child
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		so because that's something you can do by just enrichment types of things in the home
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but learning disability unless you are schooled in the types of things and ways to help a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> like that
 		then it makes it real difficult and this is this to me is the benefit i see in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is that that uh you do have government money to fund the kinds of programs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> need and i'm not sure that the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> address that problem they test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> before they take them
 	
 	
 		exactly and
 	
 	
 		and if they're a behavior problem they're out that and and uh
 	
 	
 		they don't take them that's right right
 	
 	
 		this is kind of a rejection type of thing and and we get it even at our level in in i work a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine ten</NUMEX> school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that come in that have been kicked out of the uh parochial and public and uh private schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they come in and their attitude is i'm a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and proceed to  prove it
 	
 	
 		really really
 	
 	
 		so i i really hate that for them i i would rather they not have that attitude but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well when comparing test scores i know recently i was in a discussion and they were comparing test scores between private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and that was one of the points that i made is that you're not comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> to apples
 	
 	
 		that's
 		right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you know you can't say um you know i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> probably would not be accepted because he has a learning disability and into a private school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		into a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and um which is which is too bad
 		but on the other hand i i can't necessarily blame them you know they they are a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and they can do whatever they want
 	
 	
 		no
 		that's right they can be selective right
 	
 	
 		and they can they that's right they have the ability to be selective but you can't say then well public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are
 		are not as good
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		perhaps they are because they're they're
 	
 	
 		if you choose the select
 		top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> out of the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and tested them and then compared them to the private to the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school group</ENAMEX> then i think you would have a more equitable
 	
 	
 		you're right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> and i have a problem when they compare the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> here in in in uh honesty honesty the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> are they have to try out to even get into to which kindergarten they're going to get into
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and then after uh and if if you only the in fact they've had cases in the past where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have committed suicide
 		because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> has not gotten into the top kindergarten which means they probably won't get into the top elementary and and high school and if they don't then after when they reach a certain age they just that's the end of their schooling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and uh they don't ever really go on it's only their top ones that go on like ours do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and uh so that that creates a problem and and you can't compare because they go so many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	

 	
 		the other thing is that the priority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s education and is that child
 	
 	
 		right well you see that with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> that come here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		um i i was talking to somebody recently or read somewhere where they where they said that
 		you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they they had to be the best and they put off all social life all everything you know well is that good yes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is very bright
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		bright but on the other hand i feel like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are kind of middle of the road
 		have are more rounded you know sure sure i think it's real important to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i think it's real important to play sports i think it's real important to be part of a team
 	
 	
 		better coping skills yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so that's why i said their childhood is extremely different from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> we didn't do all that you know  we certainly didn't carpool and run the way i do um
 	
 	
 		right
 		well and you don't you don't see the parents uh encouraging those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to get on athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> or drill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> or band
 	
 	
 		no right right
 	
 	
 		it's strictly stick to the educational and it's interesting to see them as they get older uh then that is the type of adult they are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 		
 	