
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah yes i talked with um i talked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three days</TIMEX> and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> i talked with someone with from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> so it's the
 	
 	
 		yeah because i've only been made this is only my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> call i i tried to make calls <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and i couldn't get through
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i know sometimes i just i'm in it just takes a very long time so
 	
 	
 		does it yeah i've been trying to you know do that and and sometimes i just can't wait that long so i just hang up because it keeps going through the thing over and over again
 	
 	
 		yeah i know well
 		this is hilarious  oh well tell me what books have you read lately
 	
 	
 		but i knew as soon as i heard your voice i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX>'s it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Kenser</ENAMEX>  well
 		well let's see i um  gosh i can't even think i haven't read any and you're such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> i know that and i
 	
 	
 		well i don't read all that much for enjoyment i mean i read a lot for school but gee i just don't have much time for enjoyment reading
 	
 	
 		yeah the the last book i picked up was a book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Bloom</ENAMEX> and it was um it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um  Smart Women</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		um or something like that and it was it was kind of i really didn't like it at all it was it was written back in the early eighties and it was all this this um divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> syndrome of the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um it was almost like a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">a pre AIDS</ENAMEX> scare kind of thing
 	
 	
 		interesting
 	
 	
 		it was really an interesting because i i right away looked at when it was copyrighted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i could tell by the theme of almost when it was written
 	
 	
 		yes yes yeah
 	
 	
 		and it was all about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> searching for themselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		you know a lot of  hanky-panky going on
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that kind of was um kind of a pop psychology time for when when a lot of books like that were coming out i think
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and so that makes real sense that that's um when it was written um i haven't wasn't really aware that she had written anything for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um adults</ENAMEX> i was always just more aware of her journal you know for her young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> her books uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and she's more famous for that but she has been writing
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> also and so i thought hey i'll just try this you know and see what it was like it was very um  the style was very conversational
 	
 	
 		i'll be darned
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you would have lots of conversations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> rather than any description
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know how that is and and um
 	
 	
 		yeah i wonder if she's written anything really recently if she's got anything printed in print
 	
 	
 		yeah she has because i i remember seeing a new book by her that was out and i think it was a it was an adult book
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		so anyway but that's the last thing i i've read and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well it's i'm trying to think the last actual book i read that wasn't let's see i think i read oh when i was on vacation um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between semester</TIMEX> break and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and you know on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester break between spring</TIMEX> and summer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i went to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s i read a book that i have should have read when i was probably in high school i read um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Eyre</ENAMEX>  no wait a minute wait a minute wait a minute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Eyre</ENAMEX> no no no no it wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Eyre</ENAMEX> no it was um
 	
 	
 		i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wuthering Heights</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Pride and Prejudice</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX> that's what it was yes and um you know i i didn't know what to expect except i had heard that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX> was such a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX> yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		she really was good i mean i was was very much impressed with the way her plot was put together so intricately and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know i just but i as i say i was pretty much ashamed that i hadn't read something before then
 	
 	
 		yeah because i i think i was i think i read it in college or had to write it read it in high school or college but i don't remember it and then when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennie</ENAMEX> had to read it at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> and i got her the i got her someone i think it was um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> reading it you know they had an abridged version of it on tape and so i got that for her and she loved doing that but i remember that was the book
 	
 	
 		oh how interesting
 		yes
 		oh i'll bet yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and now i i mean i think it's around here somewhere i'm just going to have to put it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> sometimes and listen to it
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right i wouldn't be surprised yeah
 		sure oh yeah well i read that and then i'm trying to think um usually i try to to find something long that i'm going to do
 	
 	
 		but um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when if if i have long periods of time like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas vacation</TIMEX> or you know when i know i'm not going to be doing anything for a while um
 	
 	
 		yeah oh that's what i do too
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's about it because otherwise i'm reading so much for school i'm um i have just started reading a book actually it's for school but it's for um there's a a literary journal well not a literary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> it's a
 		it's kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> of of the history of ideas that's that's starting to be published um from UTD the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue doesn't come out until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> but um i'm doing some reviews of books just to
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		what to sort of recommend to whether whether or not a full-scale review should be done for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> and i've yeah it's really neat because these are brand new books and i just got a i got a this this one
 	
 	
 		oh how neat
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		um most of the stuff is on uh literary criticism and philosophy and religion and all that this one is on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johann Sebastian Bach</ENAMEX> and it's a a biography a biography
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		that is really interesting i mean it it's fascinating it really is um but it's so long i i don't really have the time to read the whole thing but i think eventually i'll go back to it but it
 	
 	
 		oh that's fascinating oh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was written i mean the the copyright is nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX> so it's a brand new book yeah uh-huh yeah and he really this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> really shed some light on um
 	
 	
 		oh it's a brand new book oh that that would be wonderful to read something like that
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some aspects of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> and and and you know the and more sociological things you know like the the idea that um
 		that music to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> was as much um of a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> as anything i mean you know that was it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> had just loads of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>  yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah and they just went from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> probably to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> just with these with these all passing it from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to the other
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh and um
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the way it was i'm sure back then yeah oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so um it was just really interesting if that's
 		you know that's kind of what but i have to not only am am i reading reading it to decide whether or not it should be reviewed but also um because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> for this um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> doesn't have right now doesn't have a really respected name um who's a
 		um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> on on music um and i'm supposed to decide whether i think this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> might be a worthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to be a you know in that position on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know if i want to take that responsibility or not but  but at least i can tell them what i think so um it's real interesting
 	
 	
 		wow that's rough that's real rough
 		yeah well that's a neat thing to be involved in because i think our i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX> um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> i think they were just starting a magazine
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was similar to that i think that's probably a sort of a thing to do in small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yes
 		yeah that it you know you see you see a lot of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> doing things like that right uh-huh because it attracts really a a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s interest that's one way it's really good public relations for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i think so
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		oh yes yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh another one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> is actually it's part of my research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assistantship</ENAMEX> is um it's helping a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> uh compile a bunch of translations of of various poems for a book that he's writing
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so i'm learning the names if not the actual contents of a lot of different poems and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> people
 	
 	
 		now translations what do you mean translations of of
 	
 	
 		um well where where for instance um a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baudelaire</ENAMEX> poem that was written in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and then has been translated into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> by various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the translations are all so different from one another um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see
 		all different
 		oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		so it's multiple translations of single works and and that's right now right now pretty much what i'm doing as far as um my work is just kind of compiling all that for him so
 	
 	
 		gosh
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		it's real interesting
 	
 	
 		boy you really lift me up to a different i mean here i i'm dealing with uh cleaning the stove and you know i'm  i wish i were dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baudelaire</ENAMEX>  that would be nice  but i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh well let me tell you there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when i would be prefer really doing that  i don't know if i've told you but um this is not on the subject
 		
 		
 	