
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		first how much television watching do you do
 	
 	
 		so
 		i do a little bit more than i think usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do because i am here alone during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and i like it just for the noise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right but do you actually watch it and pay attention to it or is it more of a company
 	
 	
 		um
 		um it just depends on what it is i mean i have my favorite things that i do and that's a fun thing to do sometimes but um what about you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum okay
 		right
 		well actually i i work full time and when i'm not working i'm running and i don't watch a lot of television and i'm very selective in what i watch if there's something that i absolutely
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		want to watch i will turn it on and watch it and then turn it off i probably watch television <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		well see that's great yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">max</ENAMEX> and uh if if i don't find something that i really want or really want to watch well then i just do not turn it on i would rather listen to music
 	
 	
 		well
 		right
 	
 	
 		part of it is that uh i think we need to be very selective about the kinds of things that come to us on a subliminal basis and i think that if we're doing other things and these programs come in
 		sometimes they influence us and we don't know where that influence came from
 	
 	
 		well i think that well part i think that's partially true i think you have to have the will and the and the um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		anyway i think it you you could be susceptible to stuff and it has to be reinforced at another level too but anyway what would you watch if you had you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to watch i mean do you like specials
 	
 	
 		uh right right right of course i uh
 		that's right
 		i uh
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> for example i really would've liked to have watched <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unsolved Mysteries</ENAMEX> those are fascinating to me if i have the opportunity i watch it unfortunately i was with someone else who was flipping channels i hate that
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i do not care a whole lot for some of the contemporary humor
 	
 	
 		oh right yeah
 	
 	
 		in our comedy programs although nobody can appreciate comedy any more than i can but i would prefer to find a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> or one of the older comedians
 	
 	
 		well we have cable also and and sometimes you can um get the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> specials and sometimes those are really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right and some of those are fine programs uh-huh
 	
 	
 		pretty hysterical so i i like to watch comedy i mean you know that's something but i'm not real up to date on what's going on now i i guess i have my old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> that i
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i i enjoy comedy um-hum um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hooked into i mean you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Newhart</ENAMEX> still on on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> and uh you know something on that level i i also enjoy um i don't know its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum i enjoy that um-hum um-hum
 	
 	
 		it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> thirteen i watch a lot of thirteen uh The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> and i i just laugh i mean i think it's so hysterical these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> it's just so much fun it's just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's just a lot of fun watching that i mean i don't agree with a whole lot of stuff they say  but it's fun you know so yeah i watch to be entertained i really do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 		well
 		yeah i watch it for entertainment but i also watch it for uh cultural impact i do a lot of channel thirteen channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> some of the educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and i watch for special programs that have special
 		a special play a special concert uh i recently watched a tribute to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the finest opera stars
 	
 	
 		oh now that was fabulous and that you know yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it was fabulous i just absolutely you just held you breath in some of those uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patavani</ENAMEX> and uh  oh i was just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know so
 	
 	
 		makes chills all over you
 		so i i may or may not even look at the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> but if i have time i may flip through and say hey
 		this looks good if i finish this task i can watch that in an hour uh if the hour comes and i don't get a chance to watch it so what
 	
 	
 		you know well there's certain things i mean i've got um my TV in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> here and um you know if there's something like cooking shows i love to watch cooking shows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i do too it makes me want to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and then i eat and then i get fat so i just let other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> watch when i eat what they cook
 	
 	
 		i i really do
 		i know  i i yeah and and there's some um in fact one of the watercolor shows on now has inspired me to take watercolor lessons you know so
 	
 	
 		oh i think that's marvelous yeah oh yeah i took a lot of my college courses i took some of my college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> on television so that it's very successful for some of those things but i think i really got stung very badly
 	
 	
 		you know things like that you you get a whole whole lot of exposure
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		about having influence in your life or at least i've i saw a very bad example of having television influence your life uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> who was addicted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soaps</ENAMEX> and i want you to know that became the most suspicious cantankerous contrary old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that ever was i mean she
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		she thought she was
 	
 	
 		absolutely i don't know who she thought she was but she just got to the point where you could might near you could almost hear those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soaps</ENAMEX> being echoed in her voice and that attitude being demonstrated
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and for her to miss a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX> was was a big withdrawal and
 	
 	
 		oh well see that's you you you but she was probably depressed to begin with you know what i mean  yeah grumpy to begin with
 	
 	
 		well i don't know well she was grumpy to begin with there's no doubt about that but uh
 		but you could clearly see those influences and in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> i know that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> were watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Stooges</ENAMEX> and i always thought that was just casual slap stick comedy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i hate that show
 	
 	
 		but when one tried to lift the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX> wrench i decided that wasn't funny anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah i i good
 	
 	
 		and i really i really feel very strong about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bart Simpson Show</ENAMEX> i think that is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> watch that and that's absolutely the mouthiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that i ever saw and i just i do not like it uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		isn't that amazing how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> are grown but i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> around and uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a four year old</TIMEX> to think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bart Simpson</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> is tragic
 	
 	
 		oh okay so that's yeah
 		i had forgotten about that see it's just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i and so i don't have that you know i uh that constant influence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> shows and all that but um i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum um-hum yeah yeah
 		well i was very careful even when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were at home and when they were young i really did uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		watch what they watched i was cautious i sat down with them and i watched it and if i did not like it i changed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> for them you know i i you know i distracted them changed their interest
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because i just couldn't tolerate that kind of influence on my kiddos it just would
 	
 	
 		and and you know they get it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> too anyway so you might as well not reinforce it you know i
 	
 	
 		sure that's right that's right gosh they got they're mouthy enough anyway
 	
 	
 		i know i remember going to school my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were a lot like that too and of course we did not have any of the variety you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have but all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> used to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawhide</ENAMEX> and all those shows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> never let me watch anything like that i could watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yogi Bear</ENAMEX> you know what kind of culture was that  and i remember going to school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and everybody would be asking oh did you see that did you see how he did that and did you see and i could never participate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it always made me feel a little bit you know like a loner like i you know but um
 	
 	
 		sure i can understand how that would happen
 	
 	
 		but see then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i think then you have to replace it with other things you know to uh
 	
 	
 		absolutely well i did i ran my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to death  i said hey i think that's enough television for awhile maybe we need to go outside
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really yeah
 	
 	
 		and we need to go out and play and enjoy some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so i'd go out with them now see there's the problem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't do that they say you go outside and play
 	
 	
 		that's true or you go rent a video up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and come home and sit down and watch it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i said but but we went on field trips and we did other things and i think that was
 	
 	
 		well that's you know that's something <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't do that well here we are talking on that subject but that's that's an interesting concept i've got to stick in my  um you know work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on but um
 	
 	
 		of course
 		
 		
 	