
 
     		
 	
 		here we go <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> can you give me your ideas on uh what you think about the budget
 	
 	
 		well on the budget i'm not for sure i wouldn't um
 		start off <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all by putting a limit on the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of congress
 		and then maybe we could get some new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in there to work on it
 		but other than the budget i think they just have to uh
 		i don't know i think they have to just have uh maybe um
 		uh almost a like a constitutional convention and get sharp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to come together
 		try to decide what we're going to cut i think we cut the wrong areas and
 		and just maybe start all over again
 		almost like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> sometimes i have to do this call time out and then
 	
 	
 		yeah  i guess some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> had had started started out like uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i think i think they had is it proposition <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half</TIMEX> they had out there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> had the same type of of uh legislation you know they only can raise taxes so much there there's a cap on it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		see down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they just they don't state they we don't have a state income tax and so they never want to raise taxes so they just raise the fees they just call them fees and there's a fee for everything
 	
 	
 		you don't have a state income tax
 	
 	
 		we don't have a state income tax and uh there's no uh the sales tax isn't on food
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		or anything like that so we
 	
 	
 		yeah our sales tax isn't either uh it's a
 	
 	
 		yeah so we're not taxed very much uh but the fees are pretty pretty ridiculous
 		but i think we just may need to have uh you know get sharp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over the country
 		into some sort of a like a constitutional convention and then to say what's working in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place why wouldn't it work someplace else i noticed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bridgeport Connecticut</ENAMEX>'s declared bankruptcy
 	
 	
 		yeah isn't that something uh yeah it was just in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last day</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so
 		yeah and it happened i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> way back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late sixties</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soapie Williams</ENAMEX> was governor they declared bankruptcy the whole state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>
 		so it's
 	
 	
 		yeah it's just they're just running um
 		i i don't know about about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but i know up around here as soon as uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> too it doesn't make any difference which state when things get tight they always
 		threaten they're going to cut uh police fire uh they're going to layoff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> but they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's the rank and file they never talk about cutting at the top you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> and the assistant to the assistant to the assistant
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 		absolutely absolutely
 	
 	
 		and i think the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is the same way that it's it's just gotten so huge that i don't think anyone
 		has got a handle on it anymore
 	
 	
 		no by leaving
 	
 	
 		there's no
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah by leaving that particular group in there to make the decisions it's not going change
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so somebody has to get it to where that it's just a rank and file <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and and the and like a
 	
 	
 		that's right that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		like a huge convention you know if they'd send uh
 		so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from each uh um they could do them they could do them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> by state and then each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> could pick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> just like they do at uh political conventions
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		but you'd what what it would end up it would be the same old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going so
 	
 	
 		that's  probably there should be uh uh a mandatory limit on on how long you can serve like maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two</TIMEX> terms
 	
 	
 		yeah that's i've always thought that
 	
 	
 		and that's if we you know because some of these old boys have been in there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thousand years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		get in get in there forever and then that seniority system and then the
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creep</ENAMEX> in there and uh so um
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah it's probably going to have to start there and get some new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in there and then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um maybe they can look at it and they can you know each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them that's in there now have got their own favorite projects and all you know they're they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX> and
 		um but i don't think you can do anything i don't think they're i think the budget's out of hand until you can get in there and change the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> and i'm talking about right through from top to bottom
 	
 	
 		right i think uh well even at the beginning of the country <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Hamilton</ENAMEX> wanted to put a limit
 		on um
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> was only supposed to serve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and they didn't uh they didn't follow through on that but i i've i've thought about a twelve year cap for  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>
 		and maybe go back to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year</TIMEX> term for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
 		sort of you know
 	
 	
 		it so it would run
 	
 	
 		could you hold <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one second</TIMEX> just a second <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's all right my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> and i thought that might be somebody calling in for her
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		how are things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">um Massachusetts Massachusetts</ENAMEX> is in is in terrible terrible shape
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're uh uh they're still talking about uh
 		uh laying laying off a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know cutting cutting a lot of services um the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is not funding any of the any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> now are are forced to go out and uh raise capital uh it's it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is trying
 	
 	
 		it's just a bad situation and it's not only there but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> is the same it's just isn't there you know it's in the same boat
 	
 	
 		oh that's crazy because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh it looks like it's trying to bounce back a little bit but it's we've still got a ways to go
 		it's uh i teach in a college and i and i'm in a i'm in pretty good shape but some of these uh there's just a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of work lot of homeless
 		and the budget is just i don't we've got a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> democratic democratic governor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> and uh
 		she's trying to cutback but she has to be so careful and that's the problem is that you if you come in too fast
 		you can't get reelected
 	
 	
 		yeah you know um there's an awful lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that are idle uh when you say like the homeless and there's the prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is skyrocketing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		uh i think they should probably go back and borrow some of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s ideas you know uh set up some of these CCC <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> like they had way back
 	
 	
 		yes yes but
 	
 	
 		um that
 	
 	
 		you know give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a little uh dignity because i know a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would like to work they just don't know how uh to go out and get find a job or they're not skilled or or something and it  it doesn't take a lot of skill to rake leaves or
 		do some of those things like those
 	
 	
 		that's right they could they could uh they could build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads uh bridges uh uh canals uh</ENAMEX> there's there's a ton of things they can do we can take in uh they could stop start uh a rapid transit
 	
 	
 		right right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		movement like when they when they first broke into uh
 		uh the interstate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh we don't have a rapid transit system in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> though worth a worth a damn
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no we don't we don't  the um we and you mentioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison prison</ENAMEX> population another thing you can do in the budget we've got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't need to be in prison
 		i mean there's some of the lesser crimes anymore probably you don't need to put them away put them in some work program
 	
 	
 		that's true right
 		yep
 	
 	
 		you know a minimum very minimum security and this they've got a job and you you work uh
 		you know work this long some of them may find that they they like it and want to take it permanently then you could just switch them over in another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of that and pay them um
 		a decent wage you you'd whatever you'd pay them would be a lot better than having them in jail or having them out on the street
 	
 	
 		that's right because i don't know what what it costs per year per inmate
 	
 	
 		it's a it's a lot
 	
 	
 		but
 		if they just if they just like paid them a wage and let them perform something useful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	