
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what do you think about it
 	
 	
 		well i i feel in light of some of the accidents and so forth that have happened lately that i think there are some occupations that they should such as the health field the transportation field
 		uh they're already doing it in the armed forces where they handle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and so forth uh they do it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> so i i uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i feel like it should be mandatory in some professions and i think if if uh
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> feels that he wants to to drug test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and they don't like it then they should not be employed there  that was you know i would not mind it
 	
 	
 		yeah i i especially agree that if it's an area where they could cause somebody else you know harm or injury absolutely
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i don't have a problem at all with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> uh testing in the hiring process
 		but i i i don't
 		i don't have a problem with them too much testing even after the fact but i do a little bit where it where it wouldn't hurt anybody
 		i don't know sometimes i think they carry it a little bit too far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		well  unless an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> has a reason to believe that his uh the work competency of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee employee</ENAMEX> is is hurting the business i mean maybe it's uh number one because generally if if they are involved in that type of thing they are into theft
 	
 	
 		right and then it's not a problem
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> i would think that would be
 		and the first it's not going to be wholesale because of the cost there's no way but but my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is uh school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um i'm not even i'm in education i'm not even opposed to it for that
 	
 	
 		train the train drivers
 	
 	
 		uh i'm concerned in the medical field
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i i think they should screen for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> in these areas too because i consider that a drug
 	
 	
 		i wish they would
 		i i wish they would and that i think is even probably more widely abused by you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> than than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> so to speak
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		right but when you consider they could be driving an airplane or driving a bus or
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh i know it
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train um</ENAMEX> and it doesn't take that long uh they they don't have be totally roaring drunk just a little off on their timing could could mean life
 	
 	
 		and
 		no
 		just uh
 		
 
 		yeah and
 		now <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has the random testing policy and and you know our names or our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> numbers or whatever are in a in a pool
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so i've already been tested once when i was hired and and once since they initiated this random testing program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i work with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who was tested her name got got randomly selected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my word
 	
 	
 		and i think that's the only reason i have a problem with it when there's no you know there's no reason to suspect someone you know that that's getting a little bit that's enough to make anybody paranoid
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well as long as you accept that it is a random
 		a random testing uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know to to alleviate
 		that way you can't feel like somebody's out to get me if it's almost like being selected for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know so your name came out of pot when they spun the wheel that's that's just the way it is
 	
 	
 		you were just the lucky or the unlucky one depending on how you look at it
 	
 	
 		i would i would rather have it that way to know that i was chosen
 		at random by a computer than to think that somebody turned me in
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 	
 	
 		because i i think there's when you let other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> turn in people
 	
 	
 		there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with with their petty axes to grind it could really get out of hand and
 	
 	
 		right right
 		so i i i would really rather know however there's got to be some backup to say that if if somebody does observe you at say at a party
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i would think that it would be their obligation to report that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		to report it and i guess you'd report that to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> maybe anonymously or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> or something
 		right
 	
 	
 		because i i would feel very uncomfortable working with someone i knew was using either illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or abusing alcohol i'd just i'd feel really uncomfortable
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i don't know what kind of work you do but there there would be even be a situation where you were at a machine and working with somebody that was that way and
 	
 	
 		yeah we have we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who work on the line i'm in accounting so it wouldn't you know they they couldn't hurt me with their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> key or something but out on the line they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working some serious equipment
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		right
 		it's it's
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i i just think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> have to have especially given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the drug abuse that goes on i just think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> have to have some kind of way
 		to see that they're not being
 		put at
 		risk because they're the ones who are going to have the lawsuits the insurance claims <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera and and i'm not sure but what some of the insurance claims aren't due to
 	
 	
 		put at risk i agree totally
 	
 	
 		uh illnesses brought on by drug abuse or alcohol abuse
 	
 	
 		and in the long run we're all paying for that so it's i mean it it protects us in the long run hopefully when they do that
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		i i was trying to remember there was a court case
 		uh here here where i live just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> they wanted to um the city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wanted to institute the random drug testing
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> uh took them to court
 		to protest saying that it invaded their i guess first amendment the the search and seizure amendment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's still tied up in the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> they haven't ruled on whether they can test them or not
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so i'm curious especially since <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> a local you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> is also already doing it seeing what what they'll say about it especially since
 	
 	
 		to see how that's
 		is it is it uh just a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that are concerned
 	
 	
 		well it's the whole it's the whole city
 		seems like the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that's raising a stink over it
 	
 	
 		they they just don't want to be drug tested
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		you know we've never my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i have never been in a situation where somebody said you have to be drug tested
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">y</ENAMEX> eah
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s retired from i R S agents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		however this isn't a problem that we have and either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and so we we in our minds we're thinking what's the big deal
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah that's the way i looked at it if i had something to hide it's one thing but i'm you know you know you don't so it's not as big a deal and you sometimes wonder when these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> protest so much
 		whether they're really concerned about their rights or whether they're really concerned about something else
 	
 	
 		right
 		and and then they say well if you give them the right to do this then they're going to take some other right away from you but i i a firm
 	
 	
 		i don't believe that
 	
 	
 		i think that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> has the right to ask you to do anything and of course the big deal one of the big deals now too is to that when you
 		come into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as you sign a paper saying that i will go take a
 		
 		
 	