
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> have did you vote in the last election
 	
 	
 		most assuredly
 	
 	
 		oh you did
 	
 	
 		yes ma'am i've voted in every major election since i turned <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's great well why do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't
 	
 	
 		don't always vote for somebody i sometimes vote against somebody
 	
 	
 		that makes sense too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think that a lot of it is uh i know that my late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was simply indifferent he didn't feel like he had any say there was too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too many  other votes for example uh
 		you know he'd say well look you and i see different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of the fence if i go vote you'll cancel my vote
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i said i sure will he said so i just won't vote i said then mine counts because you could cancel mine too
 	
 	
 		and
 		then does
 		
 
 		yeah i think i think that's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just indifferent  i know that i've moved around a lot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past um three years</TIMEX> i've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different addresses each time i change jurisdictions or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		so i just haven't because i mean graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or whatever so i haven't kept track of it i did when i lived steadily in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> community i always i voted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but this past time i didn't well actually i voted it for the presidential election but then i didn't vote uh i guess in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two year</TIMEX> for uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> and things and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well characteristically in some in the local elections
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		typically those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who vote are those who feel very strongly about an issue
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		if i do not feel very strongly about an issue then i see no reason to go vote
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah and that's probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why i voted in the the last election but not really this one because this one really didn't matter that much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's probably true
 	
 	
 		well of course of course listening to government the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> you'll find out that everything matters but then you could go crazy worrying about everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you know they also say that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> vote their local politics that that local is far much more important than uh national issues
 	
 	
 		well that's the way you get to national and that's the way you make changes about your neighborhood
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right oh i definitely think so
 	
 	
 		uh i know that i have been involved in preparing and in in uh
 		carrying out a lot of the local petitions that take place even something so simple as getting a street light
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in between lights on the end of the block but it makes a big difference when it's the difference in having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> run over in the dark and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		it took a close call to wake us up and cause us to take that kind of action and that's completely unnecessary In another particular case they were trying to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		put in a um senior citizen's home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in an area very near our neighborhood but if you just cross that major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the neighborhood changes and it's less savory
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and that i was just very i felt very strongly about that those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> simply did not have access to safety to security and they were at risk
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> who lived alone and they were going to put a cluster of of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> there for them but even clustering together for the elderly does not ensure safety
 	
 	
 		no most now that's true
 	
 	
 		and all it all it did was to in my judgment make them easier targets uh-huh yeah easier targets and so we we did get a petition together and we very strongly resisted it and
 	
 	
 		prepare them to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> yes yeah
 	
 	
 		and it was placed in a actually it was placed clear closer to my neighborhood but it was on the right side of the street
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right side of the tracks yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh it it i think that they're they're much more comfortable there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> did they
 	
 	
 		uh i haven't seen too much crime in my neighborhood although we have a good crime watch program but it's it's very serious just across the street
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		did um did you think i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>'s last gubernatorial uh election probably brought out a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		did that did that seem to because that really that got national attention national attention i guess having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman governor</ENAMEX> running against a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and whatever
 	
 	
 		well
 		no i don't think it had to do to with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> running against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i think it had to do with dirt running against dirtier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's it it was a dirty election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were calling each other uh names and every bit of the trash it was a it was a dirty campaign
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was a dirty mud slinging campaign
 	
 	
 		well you know what's funny up here uh i live i see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> news and i guess uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilder</ENAMEX> are active right here and they have some type of wire tapping problem going on and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> are complaining see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robb</ENAMEX> is married to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynda Bird Johnson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> are complaining that he is he's using <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> politics in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and they're really complaining big time because they said that we don't have that type of trashy politics up here like they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were getting
 	
 	
 		well of course now that's not all the time we've had some pretty
 	
 	
 		yeah you were getting slandered i think
 	
 	
 		we were having some pretty healthy uh campaigns that were based on issues there for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> of the gubernatorial races but i historically <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX> and muddier campaigns i mean it's just i think that eventually you know the better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have sensibilities and they vote on those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are least likely to do damage unfortunately that's not always the way it should be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't want to vote for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who is least likely to do damage you want to do the one who can do the most good
 	
 	
 		do the most good yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		i guess that's why i know that um
 		i'm previously from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Thornburg</ENAMEX> who's now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> is going to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> because uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Heinz</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> died in an airplane crash
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i know that they're expecting a gigantic turn out to landslide <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Thornburg</ENAMEX> into as into the senate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they don't like  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> or whatever and they're almost expecting landslide
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		out uh turn out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> for  for that election
 	
 	
 		okay so you
 		so you see that's very negative motivation isn't it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		isn't that too bad
 		we really could use a little positive motivation hey we think this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> can really make some changes and we're going to support him that was true in a lot of cases in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">in a couple of the older sixties</TIMEX> campaigns
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		what in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> was that when you
 	
 	
 		no i'm talking about national campaigns yeah uh even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> was elected there were so many strikes against him but there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who believed he could make a difference now
 	
 	
 		that's that's true yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's not to say what has transpired or what really was i'm saying that's how it was perceived
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's right that's perception that's true
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		because the those were big political that was a big um turn out election
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		absolutely and and it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going to vote for i think more than those who voted against
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know i know that in my own uh
 		area of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whom i knew and how they were going to vote they didn't go to vote against uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> as they did
 		a little bit later when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> was running they went to vote against the less of lesser of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> evils in certain cases
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think that one was one that you had some very strong feelings among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they voted their convictions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh well i think that also happened with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		absolutely you're right
 	
 	
 		he was he was landslided in and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really saw that was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	