
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay  so what books do you like to read
 	
 	
 		well all kinds to tell you the truth uh  mostly i like uh  um science fiction science fantasy type books
 	
 	
 		like what what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well let me see uh well the most my favorite ones are kind of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Rice Burroughs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he had a uh series of uh called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carter</ENAMEX> Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> i don't know if you're familiar with it or not but uh he's the one that wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tarzan Of The Apes</ENAMEX> and all that too and uh and uh
 	
 	
 		no i'm not
 		okay yeah heard of that
 	
 	
 		and uh he uh he had one where this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> and and uh made some trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> and stuff i thought it was really interesting  plus i i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce Anthony</ENAMEX> uh the one about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zanth i</ENAMEX> don't know if you're familiar with that
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting
 		no i really i have never really never never read science fiction much
 	
 	
 		and well that was more fantasy i guess and uh because it's kind of neat because it has a lot of puns and stuff you know in it and so it's kind of funny too and then uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then i like uh what else do i have there oh it's a series of another fantasy but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Saberhagen Saberhagen</ENAMEX> and it's the it's uh The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sword Series</ENAMEX> which i liked and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> i like too it's another fantasy one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh starting i think i'm going to start pick up a few uh more science fiction as far as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Asimov</ENAMEX> have a number of his books too and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H G Wells</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's older stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah uh but but i think they're pretty good and uh and then i'm i think i'm going to start picking up some of the newer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Star Treks</ENAMEX> because i hear they're pretty good too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> wrote a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> episode wrote one of those novels that yeah as under this fake name she wrote it in  she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and it was
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		kind of a hush hush thing that she'd written this book so we all had to read it for a sociology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> so um no i don't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> was like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madge Larson</ENAMEX> or something like that it was a kind of feminist
 	
 	
 		do you know which which one was it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Trek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on a  it's the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had been a POW in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> who wrote it and so she she's one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> female POW's and so she had um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of paralleled that with kind of a space version of it and it was kind of it was interesting i don't know if it was interesting just because i knew the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who'd written it or if it was actually a good book
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i've never really read a lot of science fiction it's
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i sort of read mostly in high school and uh you know and i and i like it you know as as kind as the light reading and everything and uh i recently uh completed graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and i've really kind of got interested
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		through a number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple of</NUMEX> classes that i took there on on history and stuff and i've gotten a number of history books but i haven't read any yet you know uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh  but you've got them so that
 	
 	
 		yeah but i've got them and they're ready to go  that's right but uh i was kind of getting into you know like uh you know like medieval times and stuff like that and just as to just to do some reading about what went on and everything
 	
 	
 		halfway there so that's good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i've i've read a lot of medieval literature <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> in school a lot of like took a class in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chaucer</ENAMEX> so we were reading in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle English</ENAMEX> and all that and that was a lot of fun kind of weird but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and what what which ones do you like
 	
 	
 		um well i'm uh i like a lot of contemporary short stories um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors authors</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobbie Ann Mason</ENAMEX> she's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and writes a lot of just kind of contemporary realism sort of stuff um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Barthelme</ENAMEX> who wrote he just died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and he wrote kind of weird avant-garde
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		short fiction and then like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> through the late eighties and he was kind of responsible for turning around the short story movement so that was  kind of neat um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if i'm reading kind of trashy stuff i like um i guess kind of mystery books and then stuff that's funny i like pretty much any humor book
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and gosh oh
 	
 	
 		well i've got those as far as humor i've got a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irma Bombecks</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh that's fun
 	
 	
 		yeah and then also there there's another one i don't know you might have read it <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hitchhiker's Guide To The Galaxy</ENAMEX> yeah there's a series well it was a trilogy with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> books  and uh have you read those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		no i i i have one of them sitting on my bookshelf and i just never picked it up
 	
 	
 		do you
 		yeah they're they're pretty funny because it's really kind of interesting and uh uh those are are kind of neat too and i've read uh i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> well i like some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i i like him
 	
 	
 		i i'm not really too i don't really like his endings so much but uh i think some of his books are pretty good and then there the other one that i've read a little bit is uh  um oh God let me go look at his name here it's the one that wrote uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i used to
 	
 	
 		um i can't even think of his
 		see oh here oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clive</ENAMEX> Barker
 	
 	
 		oh what have you read by him
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Books Of Blood</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable Cable</ENAMEX> i guess how you say just you know some paperbacks and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i've never read anything i got a book of his out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> to try it out i'd been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and thought you know he's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> so oh really i'll have to
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 		uh-huh well i like him better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> yeah he he he's pretty he's pretty good
 	
 	
 		oh well he's next on my list to read i'm reading a little private eye book now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and then of course i've read the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clancy</ENAMEX> books
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hunt For Red October and Red Storm Riding Rising</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh those are the ones my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> keeps trying to get me to read but i
 	
 	
 		well actually you know <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Storm i</ENAMEX> haven't i've started <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Storm Rising</ENAMEX> but uh i really recommend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red October</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because it really it's good and and it keeps going pretty quick but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Storm Rising</ENAMEX> i've heard and then it's been apparent the first you know few pages or whatever it's kind of slow in starting and everything
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it's not a bad book at all
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting i read i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moby Dick</ENAMEX> that's a  that's my big book that i like
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah actually i i i got an old copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moby Dick</ENAMEX> that i like too i read a while back
 	
 	
 		that's one i just my very very favorite book so if i had to go read something again i'd probably read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moby Dick</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarlet Letter i</ENAMEX> also like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah oh probably liked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek Two</ENAMEX> didn't you
 	
 	
 		no i actually have never seen any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> movies was that oh well that's interesting i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> who did a did you ever see the movie Heathers
 	
 	
 		oh you hadn't Two was really good because he quoted a lot from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moby Dick</ENAMEX>
 		no i didn't
 	
 	
 		oh it's it's kind of this sort of black comedy movie about this these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in high school who
 		are not real popular and they kill all the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the class it's it's kind of bleak but it's sort of fun and they do a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moby Dick i</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> who wrote a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moby Dick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heathers</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and well i  i thought it was a little much but it was kind of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Irving</ENAMEX> that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Irving</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		he hasn't written much in a while but
 		when he does i'm pretty happy with it
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm trying to think what else i've read that i've really just loved
 		i don't know how i it's hard to read when you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it's like you just read those textbooks and that's it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i know and that will have to do
 	
 	
 		but i guess maybe in the real world too you just don't have time to read but
 	
 	
 		yeah that's pretty much the way it is usually i try to i have some a book or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> by the bed and then maybe like i get to read for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> before i go to sleep or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and then you fall asleep and have to reread it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next night</TIMEX> because you forgot what you've read yeah i i do that too oh i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry McMurtry</ENAMEX> he's good and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">like Lonesome Dove</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		yep  that's right yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was a long book but it was really good
 	
 	
 		well i understand that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Benchley</ENAMEX> is coming out with a new one yeah i just read an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> you know uh because i have this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaws</ENAMEX> book here and i think he's going to call it The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beast</ENAMEX> or something like that it's about a squid
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so you know whether or not it will be as good as you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaws</ENAMEX> was i don't i don't know
 	
 	
 		i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jaws and The Deep and The Island</ENAMEX> those were pretty good so i would read that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaws</ENAMEX> actually have have you read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the book
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	