
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about uh drug testing Bob
 	
 	
 		well i guess  uh i really don't have a lot of contact with uh with the business world i'm self employed work in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> office
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and so my my my my contacts with the with the drug testing possibilities are pretty limited uh
 	
 	
 		um how do you feel about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are subjected to having to have the drug testing done
 	
 	
 		well i
 		i i you know i understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can  in some cases would feel a need
 		uh i have some reservations about it because i i do believe that i believe in individual rights
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and i think that uh that that does at least borderline on an invasion of privacy or you know or violation of you know personal rights
 	
 	
 		oh uh what recourse do you think a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would have then if they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and were jeopardizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> structure
 	
 	
 		yeah well i guess i'd i'm uh i'm not sure that uh
 		
 
 		uh you know you'd have to prove somehow
 		show that there's a reason for you know for suspecting that person
 		as you know as being a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> or you know whatever and i mean you wouldn't uh you wouldn't you're not allowed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s not allowed anymore to give uh uh
 		what is it uh
 	
 	
 		protection
 	
 	
 		the no the the test uh now i've drawn a blank
 	
 	
 		um you mean uh uh the test to oh the polygraph
 	
 	
 		polygraph test
 		yeah you're not allowed to use polygraph test in pre screening you know for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> anymore uh so you know you don't have any any proof or any way to check on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as to their honesty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 		the only way that you you know the only alternative you have if you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> suspect a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is uh is stealing from you is to get evidence
 	
 	
 		correct
 	
 	
 		uh to that effect you know and i kind of feel like uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		drug testing should fall into that into that same category or potentially anyway that if you suspect it that you should have some kind of proof not
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		not come up with a method to to have the employee furnish the furnish the proof against themselves you know in effect you know that's that's kind of uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of  defeating some of the purposes i think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> which you know which says you know you don't have to give
 		self incriminating evidence course we're talking about you know criminal cases in that in that case but i still i think it still fits you know the same uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		somewhat anyway the the same area
 	
 	
 		i guess uh they feel because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use is so widespread
 		and there's not any um
 		deviation so to speak
 		between an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and a lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use goes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i feel and just looking at it on the surface
 		um
 		that they wouldn't have much of a choice um
 		in picking somebody uh sometimes drugs don't uh the results of taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> don't come out until after something tragic has happened
 		and in order to uh resolve it before it happens that they feel that this is most the most direct way and
 		painless way of uh
 		scanning their uh employees
 		i know that in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i have not known a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to have the drug test yet
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		but of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> i guess it's more popular and i don't know if this is true if it's more popular between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> drug use than it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> because i know there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that do use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum  yeah there's not uh from my from my own personal uh knowledge not experience but knowledge
 	
 	
 		but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there are i would say there are as many women drug users
 	
 	
 		as there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		as there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> uh in most you know most of the cases that i know of you know
 		from
 		personal conversations uh
 	
 	
 		i don't know anybody
 		uh in even a random um friendship that uses drugs
 	
 	
 		yeah well i've known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the in the past</TIMEX> that have you know that uh and in in almost all of those cases it was you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend girlfriend</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that kind of a situation
 	
 	
 		a casual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		do what a casual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> uh yeah pretty much uh right social social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> say uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		just to try and see what it was like and then
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and and in in you know in some cases it would be
 		uh a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that you know that i would know about that you know i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> i have not ever been and will not ever be but i you know i've known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have talked about it you know and uh
 	
 	
 		that were experiencing different things
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was you know it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and
 		you know male and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it was not limited to
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i i would be um i don't have any desire to but i would be awfully fearful because of all the uh
 		um  illicit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that are around and the methods by which they're made
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and some of them are very deadly  and it's kind of playing <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian Roulette</ENAMEX> with drugs
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah so but yeah i i understand the  you know the idea i'm i'm all in favor of getting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> out of the you know out of the the system completely
 	
 	
 		so it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it doesn't bring anything but chaos
 	
 	
 		yeah right but uh you know i i think that uh i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that that have started
 		the the the non voluntary drug testing and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> in particular or is you know is one that i know of anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they uh
 		i think they're asking for for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> to be interpreted  to say hey you can't do this it's you know it's a violation from my point of view it's a violation of you know of of  a person
 	
 	
 		do you think a rule against a certain uh um
 		substance is in violation of their civil rights
 	
 	
 		uh not a rule against it but a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a non voluntary testing for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is i think that's you know it's it's like you're telling if they're telling a person you don't have any alternative but to uh accept uh accept this test  go through this testing
 	
 	
 		i wonder if uh now in their applications when they hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know it wasn't in the application that i filled out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> but
 		if now they um are very up front with saying we are going to test you for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and if it's then knowledgeable to the uh applicant
 	
 	
 		well  yeah
 		you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s under <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s current policy uh new hire new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are tested
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know so it's it is a part of the you know it's a part of the test a part of the part of the employment employing procedure now is is to test
 	
 	
 		so they know that it's not a
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		and and there's there's no problem with
 		you know with pre employment testing that i guess that's a little a little unusual that they can test test for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but they can't test for honesty
 		and uh
 		you know so that's uh but that is you know that is a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		we live in a in
 		
 		
 	