
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> i went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifty million</NUMEX> other people
 	
 	
 		hi
 		bet you stood in a long line didn't you
 	
 	
 		no we got really lucky the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> that we went to was sold out so we ran down the road to another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and it wasn't too bad it was pretty crowded once we got in there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you've seen the more recent one than i have then i have we don't usually go out to movies we usually wait until we can watch them at home
 	
 	
 		yeah that's really a lot of fun too
 	
 	
 		right uh we have been trying to get out to go but it just seems like with working and
 	
 	
 		well and it's so expensive unless you go yeah i mean
 	
 	
 		and
 		it is getting that way isn't it
 		well did you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i did um i hadn't seen any of the earlier ones so i really didn't know what to expect but they had injected a lot of humor into it which i really liked
 	
 	
 		yes
 		the previews look like that that's the way it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and so and there was a lot of action lot of swashbuckling type of things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um i really liked the humor of course i love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> so that helped
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well that's needless to say really did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves Dancing</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it doesn't hurt to sit and watch him for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>
 		
 
 		no i never went to see that one
 	
 	
 		i haven't either we want too uh because everyone tells us that we'd better go see it on a wide screen so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's definitely what i want to do but i think by then that might even be at the dollar movies
 	
 	
 		so
 		well uh maybe so i'll have to check that out  but uh i think that some of the most recent ones we've gotten and rented have been Ghost and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really did you like that
 	
 	
 		yes did you
 	
 	
 		yes very much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		in fact uh you know it's one of those things that i want to see more than once
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		yes and uh oh we got <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis Belle</ENAMEX> and all the things that are out at the current time
 	
 	
 		now is that the one is that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with uh who's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis Belle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's about the airplane the old airplane
 	
 	
 		the airplane yeah was that good
 	
 	
 		yes it's good
 	
 	
 		huh i didn't realize that was already on video
 	
 	
 		it is it's been out about the same time Ghost came out
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah so we we uh we'll i watch and grab the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one that comes out
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and of course we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> so we're taping or or watching as many of the  cartoon types as we can get and get them and uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well my cable had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> preview on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> and so i taped a bunch of shows off of that
 	
 	
 		yeah right yes well we've gotten our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are still small so uh we just they like the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pans</ENAMEX> and all that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah i have a niece that is just in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Littlest</ENAMEX> Mermaid she just thinks that's the best show in the world
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well they have a a movie out now and i saw it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster's</ENAMEX> and it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby Talk Baby Songs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and our little <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> granddaughter just loves it and it's real  down to her level it's songs about getting up and getting dressed and getting dressed on your own by yourself and
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		that'd be neat
 	
 	
 		it tells you that you're a miracle and there's nobody like you and  it's very uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 		i'll have to go get that my little <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> niece is coming to see me for her vacation so i guess i'll go see if i can get that
 	
 	
 		you would she would really love it and we're even thinking about uh
 		buying a copy of it of the tape to put in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church library</ENAMEX> because i think it's a it's a real excellent movie to sort of build <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' egos up and tell them that they can
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and they can do what they want to on their own and and it's it's a real real nice little movie
 	
 	
 		huh well that would be neat
 		yeah i was a when i was growing up i was the victim of that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cinderella</ENAMEX> movie because they say that now girls my age have the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cinderella</ENAMEX> syndrome where they think that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> is going to come and solve all their problems
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh  that doesn't happen doesn't not in real life yeah so
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		well i think that uh i think that it sounds like that our lives run along the same path  as far as movies go we kind of like the same thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i really enjoy comedies and then
 	
 	
 		i do too and and love stories i'm not for much into Silence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> or anything like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no i wouldn't go see that if i had to i don't think i'd i'd have nightmares
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i would too i just i'm not interested at all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no there're have been a few they're not really spy movies i guess they're suspenseful movies that yeah that don't have a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and gore because i just can't deal with that but i do kind of like the suspense
 	
 	
 		well now that's that's not bad
 		no who wants to
 		yes exactly
 	
 	
 		i mean you know i i love old old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchclock Hitchcock</ENAMEX> classics things like that but some of the rest yeah i wouldn't go see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silence of The Lambs</ENAMEX> if i had to
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i like those too yeah right
 		no no that'd be the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on our list
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh shoot
 	
 	
 		but um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Backdraft</ENAMEX> is supposed to be really good
 	
 	
 		yes oh i want to see that one too
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> said she just really enjoyed that that had been one of the better ones she had seen all summer
 	
 	
 		well good
 	
 	
 		so i guess i'll have to eventually get to that one
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		huh well do you tape movies off the TV
 	
 	
 		well
 		yes yes in fact a lot of times i'll scan through the program to see if i can find something that we'd like to tape to watch during our during the week
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah  well especially right now because there're all reruns just on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">regular</TIMEX> TV
 	
 	
 		but i don't find many
 		yeah exactly
 		and i don't find too many
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of difficult well like i said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Singing in the Rain</ENAMEX> on and so i taped it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 		yeah we've we've got that on tape too from once before channel thirteen
 		uh put that on because oh somehow or other they had interrupted it
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so they put it on straight through without any commercials in it and so we got it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> and i've got all the old musicals like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um Hello</ENAMEX> Dolly
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		that's like watching that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> preview they're going to have <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> on and i mean just all these great old classic musicals and i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i think i'm going to have to trade in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> and get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		oh that's wonderful
 		yeah  you know well i was just thinking about  maybe we ought to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well oh i would love to have it but you know it's kind of hard to justify when you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		that's true but you know looking through the program as i do i see a lot of things on there that are not just for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> yeah so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well especially with all those old musicals because i just love them
 	
 	
 		i do too i love all the old musicals and all the like you said the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Hitchcock</ENAMEX> and uh just old movies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i taped uh Funny <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX> so i taped that one
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah um i guess i missed that
 	
 	
 		yeah there's a lot of fun ones that was like on channel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one</TIMEX> so it it had the commercials in between it but you can fast forward through those
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		well that's okay yes exactly  oh well uh you sound like that you like are like us you don't go out too much to the movies but
 	
 	
 		no we really don't i mean we we both work and so we're exhausted when we get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and then the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> there's always so much to do to catch up from what you didn't do all week
 	
 	
 		we do too
 		isn't that the truth  that's exactly the truth
 	
 	
 		so really i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> going to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i had gone with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to the show in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> probably
 	
 	
 		well i have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> still at home and they went to see that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> too liked it real well
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh he goes to movies but and he'll come home and he'll say well you'll like this and you'll like that so or he he and i pretty well like the same thing so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it really has gotten outrageous though with the prices because i mean if you are a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> trying to go on a date it'd cost you a fortune
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they pretty well have to go <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>  they really do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		or go to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> cheap show
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly oh shoot
 		well i say it was nice talking to you about it
 	
 	
 		well
 		you too and maybe i'll get you
 		
 		
 	