
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay what uh TV shows do you like and what do you watch
 	
 	
 		well i i tend to be a a uh sports news and uh not very many of the modern sitcoms
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what about what about yourself
 	
 	
 		well uh i like a variety of things you know uh the like the sitcom wise i like uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Major Dad</ENAMEX> i'm in the i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> so i kind of you know can associate even though he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> i uh i you know i kind of associate with that a little bit and i kind of like the way it's done
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um i like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX> i don't get to see it as often as as i'd like to though uh
 		uh let me see what else oh there's some on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> that i've uh i like it's a Tales from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crypt</ENAMEX> they're kind of like those you know those <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Alfred Hitchcock Tales from His Crypt</ENAMEX> type of things i like watching that too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i just uh i like you know enjoy the horror or the mystery or whatever just kind of seeing you know what the twist would be and uh
 		same thing i like if i catch old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twilight Zone</ENAMEX> and stuff i like those
 		so
 	
 	
 		well what i find is that outside of uh well sports because i'm a sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> is the the ones that i do watch is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		except i i wish they didn't have so many reruns
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and otherwise we're caught up with uh because we are pretty good at sitting down to dinner in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock</TIMEX> period uh good ole <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wheel of Fortune</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is uh an interesting combination of a a lot of luck and uh
 		the it's probably as good a program as any for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> to play along and see if you think you're smart or smarter then then those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that is very much into sitcoms and and i have to at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> uh fight getting the news on versus uh having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> changed on me because they want to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby</ENAMEX> or one of the other ones that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right right
 	
 	
 		running on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the uh the off channels
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's uh i don't do it so much now i guess in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year or so</TIMEX> but before that i would at the same time thing were happening to me in front of the TV at a certain time i was watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jeopardy uh Jeopardy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i thought that was kind of interesting you know trying to answer the questions and you uh you learn some good things i thought you know pick up some interesting facts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		certainly more educational than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wheel of Fortune</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right  but the one uh that slipped my mind but the one that i my favorite TV show right now i would say is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek uh The New Generation</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really enjoy it it's uh it's uh you know i thought that i really liked the old <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek and this Star Trek uh</ENAMEX> is so much better you know of course the uh special effects are better and the the story lines just seem to be really good and it's it's uh i really like it enjoy it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i but i always you know i i got to start getting into the habit of trying to record it on the VCR because i always forget you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> bedtime is a little after it starts so i kind of lose track of time putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to bed and uh so i always end up missing it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i do like that show a lot because it follows uh follows a good story line
 	
 	
 		yeah i find that it seems to me and uh maybe this is as you get older i'm in my mid forties now but uh uh i guess from my vantage point i think the quality of TV has gone down or else my interests have changed because there were
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there were various series over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that i would always make sure i watched and yet i find that now i'm
 		there's hardly anything that that except <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> that draws me to say i want to try to watch that i may watch something just because it's on but i uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i tend to go more to the educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> if there's uh something that seems interesting there i just uh as i say don't find the modern sitcom very uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well just very appealing to my interests
 	
 	
 		well there is a lot of things that interest me too that i catch catch you know as i'm i flip through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery Channel</ENAMEX> and i do like a lot of shows on that yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah do you get A&E
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		because that's one  we don't have cable so
 		uh there's a few things i miss because i don't have cable and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&E</ENAMEX> is one whenever i'm on a business trip
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have it i find that it has things that are uh that interest me they have a lot of series uh i guess i'm into uh
 		i'm a history buff so with all their reruns of uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aviators</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> and uh who built what <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and all that was uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that type of stuff interests me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's uh one of the things here is we we we kind of have to have cable here with the reception in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Beach</ENAMEX> area you you maybe if you're lucky get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> channels okay
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and uh otherwise uh if you want anything more than that you need to get it you need to get uh cable TV
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess that varies from place to place being in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area because we have
 		we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX> without uh cable and then with cable who knows how many you can get
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> seems enough
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah that sure is plenty
 		but uh let me see what other oh there's a new TV show out called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinosaurs</ENAMEX> did you catch any of that
 	
 	
 		uh i've read a little bit about it but uh i haven't i don't even know if it's running here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> It kind of shows the level of interest i have in looking at the TV schedule what time's it on there
 	
 	
 		well i i don't know that it's showing anymore i thought i saw it show once or twice i saw the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one you know because i was interested in seeing what it looked like and it wasn't really that good i mean you know the muppet stuff was really was was okay but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the comedy on it wasn't wasn't very very funny or anything and uh i think it might have been cut already because uh same with you i haven't really paid attention but i hadn't seen it you know just glancing through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it might've been cut and uh i thought that was surprising being a new show and i'm sure it cost a lot of money to make
 	
 	
 		well they do but it it's amazing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> if something isn't making it the word of mouth uh
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talking to each other can cause a program which gets bad reviews to uh to uh not last for very long and even though they did invest money in it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that they uh it's i think the comparison is like baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they seem to uh say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> in uh you've had your chance time to uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		since you aren't making it we're going to find somebody else
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true how about any of the other shows like uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thirty Something or LA Law</ENAMEX> or or uh what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon</ENAMEX>'s Deal i guess is another one
 	
 	
 		well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX> seems to be real hot and in fact because of the particular business i'm in i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> but i work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> seem to be very much into watching it and yet i again i have to say because of uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i have not watched very many episodes of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh again it's
 		i don't know what i do with my time but i certainly don't spend it watching uh TV in the evenings
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right right well same here usually it's already by the time we get everything done it's uh time to go to bed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i've caught that a few times you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirty Something</ENAMEX> and all and uh and even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX> and usually the episodes that i watch you know i'm not a fan of it or anyt hing
 		
 		
 	