
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so where was your last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh actually my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last vacation</TIMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> um we went home to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> before that we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i i'd well actually i did visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> once but i never made it off of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu</ENAMEX> which i've heard is not the nicest of the islands
 	
 	
 		oh
 		it wasn't actually it when when we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oahu Oahu</ENAMEX> uh
 		i couldn't wait to get off  we we took a cruise and we went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different islands and it was a really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kauai</ENAMEX> was nice and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maui</ENAMEX> was nice we had we had a great time we were there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's wow yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yes so where have you been
 	
 	
 		oh i've been  i've been lots of places my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last vacation</TIMEX> was actually in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX> i guess we that one would count uh that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half ago</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morocco</ENAMEX> really
 		no kidding and what what did you just decide to go there or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and we were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> at the time and we decided that i i've never been to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and i needed to get that continent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hadn't been there yet and it it's actually it's a fairly common vacation place for
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go and they speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">French</ENAMEX> and so uh you know in that sense is just a little bit easier and it just seemed like it would be a fun place to go and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah oh i'm sure it was wonderful
 	
 	
 		so we we didn't really have enough time we had about a little bit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two weeks</TIMEX> and as always it don't it seems a bit uh rushed we do a lot of traveling around we rented a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and drove pretty much everywhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		was it hot
 	
 	
 		no in fact some of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> we froze it was well we were there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> i don't remember which uh-huh
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> and uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> worked there we they used to travel quite a bit all around you know in in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and whatnot but i was very young so i don't remember that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		at what at  excuse me at what age did you
 	
 	
 		i was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> when we moved back here so i don't remember but we have all these wonderful pictures of all these great places that they have been  and that i was when i was a baby but so <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX> i think would be wonderful because that's you know that's
 	
 	
 		oh that's too bad because
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that area of the world i think would be great
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a very interesting vacation the only thing i didn't like was in some of the more touristy areas uh um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the it would just be besieged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wanting to be your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> and you there were some places where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> definite there would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> there that were excellent at ripping you off
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we had nothing taken because we knew and we had things in inside pockets and in you know in jacket underneath a coat type of thing but
 	
 	
 		really we we found that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> it was the same way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would come up and try and sell you well try and sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and things like that but they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they were so destitute and i guess they they make all their money on tourism and and they would come up and ask you
 		you know if if you want to buy different things and really after awhile it really gets annoying you know it it's a little scary too when they're coming up and they're all over you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the worst</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> was in Marrakech
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> it wasn't nearly as bad and a couple of them it was what we did in some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and they tell you to do that is to hire a local guide
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it doesn't matter who it is and they keep everyone else away from you and it's worth it and it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars a day or something and its worth it just to keep everyone else away from badgering you
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		really
 	
 	
 		and you feel stupid doing that but we did it and we were much happier and you also get in to see things that you might not get into if you were alone uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's great where else have you been
 	
 	
 		uh  yes no actually i haven't been all through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> like i haven't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> yet uh we're going to go for a conference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> and so
 	
 	
 		well you lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> so you've been all through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> no
 		really
 	
 	
 		hopefully we'll get to travel a little bit too uh my more exciting spots have been i've been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Galapagos Islands</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that was one of the most wonderful vacations i've ever had yes if you like wildlife it's a fabulous vacation
 	
 	
 		lots of wildlife huh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you don't like wildlife it's probably not of interest  but it that was really really fabulous and just the photos i have of it and gosh incredible and be so close um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> eighty eight
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when was that when were you there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then actually after there i went to um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> a lot of my travel has been sort of based around conferences or business meetings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and then to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did you go on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Barrier Reef</ENAMEX> did you see the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Barrier Reef</ENAMEX> and and go snorkeling
 	
 	
 		i i actually i didn't go diving i i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diver</ENAMEX> and so that's that's actually been another of my
 	
 	
 		oh diving
 	
 	
 		favorite vacations has been taking little diving trips
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh no i didn't get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Barrier Reef</ENAMEX> i drove from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney</ENAMEX> down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> and over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adelaide Adelaide</ENAMEX> it's gorgeous absolutely gorgeous the coastline was just incredible it's huge
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		is it really yeah yeah did you have shrimp i've seen in you know they they show all this wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> and and great big prawns you know the big shrimp and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> yeah uh but
 		i don't remember if i had shrimp
 	
 	
 		no didn't have shrimp there huh  i remember food
 	
 	
 		i don't think so
 		oh i like that too but uh in fact i didn't eat out that much there because i was traveling by myself in a car it would have been i think much more fun to do it like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> with a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh oh you're adventurous you went by yourself really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and i was by myself in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> too yeah
 	
 	
 		really oh wow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> was a little bit more uh of a challenge but it it wasn't more of a challenge in a sense because i hired a guide all the time and so i never you know got out by myself or not much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> was it very expensive
 	
 	
 		no actually i paid about
 		either a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> or a little bit
 		no maybe it was about a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> maybe a little bit less i don't really remember for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX> including all my meals a guide a car the airfare and sorry but this is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're kidding no kidding uh-huh
 	
 	
 		because i was already in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and um but it only cost you about a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> to go there and i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai Chengdu</ENAMEX> and actually then i too k a train up from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> to a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quingdao i</ENAMEX> think is the name of it it's a little
 		uh sort of getaway retreat village not far from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> it's just a train ride and that i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> internal one yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> internal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> flights
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a couple of other things
 	
 	
 		all for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> wow that really surprises me i guess i relate it to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> where things are very expensive aren't they yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan Japan</ENAMEX>'s ridiculous
 		and i stayed i didn't stay in t he top of the line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> but i stayed in they were all completely clean and you know they were newly built and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they were sort of the lower end of the top of the line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> because they said you can't stay in the cheap stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah and you don't want to stay in the very very very exclusive because you don't really even get a flavor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> if you're yeah yeah wow
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		uh but yeah that was that i highly recommend that way to go if you're ever interested in going the route i dealt with this woman her name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">China Tours</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah um and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who had gone for a business trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and she just gave me this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s name to contact and it would really be fun i think ideally with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> because you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a guide and then
 		
 		
 	