
 
     		
 	
 		uh
 		national health insurance i think is a problem
 		in as much as the quality of health care that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will receive
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah because uh the articles that i've read regarding national health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> has indicated that uh what
 		stay stay in line for uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> to get an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX> from a doctor
 	
 	
 		right yeah i'm  i'm sort of mixed on this i think that the the answer  may lie in uh not in so much a uh
 		national
 		kind of medical thing that like like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> has but more of a um  national insurance uh sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clearinghouse</ENAMEX> or whatever i think that uh
 		too many the problem with with right now is  that we've got too many different health insurances that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to go through and and i think that i think you you mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> i think that they have a system where uh
 		they the government
 		deals with the with i mean you you go to whoever you want but file through one one's particular uh setup and that way
 	
 	
 		um i see
 	
 	
 		they they are able to reduce prices because they've you know it's it's all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> centralized thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		like i think that uh again having gone through a period when i was out of work and had to buy health insurance on my own if you don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> supporting you
 		in the uh picking up the major portion of your health insurance the cost is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		almost prohibitive
 	
 	
 		right uh  i i was listening uh on the radio <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and they were talking
 		something something something like this i think they were talking about the fact that um the money that could be saved
 		um  in administrative costs and so forth nationwide by consolidating into sort of a national insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider um</ENAMEX> could uh could
 		they could make they could it i i provide health insurance to to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who couldn't afford it just by the money they would save
 	
 	
 		yeah uh we're currently where i'm working now under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Cross</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know what the total cost of the program is
 		but for dependent coverage i'm paying a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and</NUMEX>
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy</TIMEX> dollars a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or something like that so i assume that probably the total coverage cost is probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fifty to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> they're probably picking up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of it and that's a pretty good policy
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		right
 		
   
 	
 	
 		but if you had something like one of these uh
 		health maintenance programs or one of whatever the type name is HMO uh where the
 	
 	
 		yeah HMO
 	
 	
 		uh where you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and it only costs you ten dollars and the insurance picks up the rest if you tried to buy something like that i'm probable it would probably be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		yeah is they're  they're fairly expensive i i um
 	
 	
 		for just the cost of something
 	
 	
 		i had was on an HMO up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and uh through through work and it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i forget how much i paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> but it was much you know is at least twice if not more expensive than  the regular health care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh the reason i i quite was because of uh not because i didn't like it i i really kind of did
 		uh the reason i quite was just because the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> a a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that we enjoyed
 		enjoyed going to was no longer associated with that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> so we my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> decided she wanted to to stay with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> so  we went to the to the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the medical insurance that we have at here at work and uh i uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i like the i like the convenience of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> in in a certain respect because it uh even though you're once you find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that you like it's not a problem you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> complain saying well i don't want to uh
 		be have to be told who i need to go to but you know  if you don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> anyway normally it doesn't really make much difference
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		because you can you know if if you find someone you really like and then we did find several good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and um
 		like you say it's uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> an office visit and um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> had our had our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and i think her total bill was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around three hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		for everything uh that included uh
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> the time the hospital  everything
 	
 	
 		delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and everything include including a private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> because there was a little extra that she had to pay but that was that was still included in that price that cost so  it's really nice because they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know their their attitude is different than than a regular uh insurance uh health insurance uh the
 		in in a HMO you know they're trying to prevent a problem by by keeping the cost down at the front end
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and have you come in you know they they charge <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know pop you're more willing to go in and try to take care of a problem before it grows big
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		as to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s benefit to have a program like that because it keeps their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> healthy and on the job
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because they don't have to worry about going in and and paying
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh seventy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> look at you for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i i uh i i really liked it we both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i both did you you don't have to worry about filling out forms uh you know for reimbursement and all or you know getting paid <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> of of whatever you just pay the
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> right then and then you're done with it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but here again the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s practices in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> have gone become fairly sizeable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> under themselves now uh you take a hospital uh the physical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> itself you have to pay your share of the operating of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> story building uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are empty so they spread the costs out over uh all the patient costs and uh that's how you come up with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX> that costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX> apiece and things like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		the horror stories that you hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and uh it being a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four thousand dollar</NUMEX> bill
 	
 	
 		well they and then again they're also  they're taking up the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can't pay you know they they get a lot of uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are just just have to be there and can't afford it and so they they know they're not going to get paid you know get money from them so they
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		will have to absorb it somewhere else
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> here about uh what he he'll be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and uh their insurance plan that they're under
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		encourages you to shorten your stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and like she went in she had the baby and she was out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it was treated almost like it was an outpatient visit to the hospital the deductibles didn't apply
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rig</ENAMEX> ht
 	
 	
 		and so that's one way one way the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are trying to hold costs down is by uh okay if you'll shorten your stay then we will uh waive the deductible
 	
 	
 		right our our insurance is uh is doing something similar where they're also going  to more
 		
 		
 	