
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> did you go to college
 	
 	
 		yeah in fact i'm still going
 	
 	
 		oh that's good so you probably could give some great advice
 	
 	
 		uh well i don't know about that but i in fact i'm in the process of trying to choose a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PhD</ENAMEX> school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well what's your career what's your interest your uh
 	
 	
 		uh well computer science and cognitive science so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that that's similar to what i'm in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> program right now
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and uh my area of expertise it's information systems which is a little bit less technical i think than uh than computer science but my area of expertise is uh uh human computer interaction
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why i'm part of this study uh because it's of i'm working with voice systems
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so so good luck i guess we should talk about giving advice though what what what what type of advice do you think you'd give to a a parent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> well you know the thing is when you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> at that age especially if they're going into undergraduate it seems like they think they know what they want an and i mean choosing from my experience you know my i thought you know my i know what i want a lot more than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> know what i want
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i don't know at the same time you have to decide what is important about the school you know the size of it or
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's more important probably than even the career vocation because most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> change
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i know i know very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh started in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> field and stayed with it
 		you know they i think that's what you just said you know having to do more with the size of the school the environment of the school uh
 		i think that's much more important i i think i'd i'd advise a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> to send a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to a school though that has a number of different types of programs you know that uh
 		some of the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> might be very limited in what they can offer but some of the
 		uh small some of the larger small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know i guess around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have a can offer a broader range of curriculums and things so if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> does change they don't have to transfer or they don't have to uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know they don't have to give up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of you know of credit transfer and things
 	
 	
 		yeah that's disruptive
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i normally and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> hate to hear this you know because i i actually teach college i i hate to uh
 		i hate to talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> because um
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the reasons is because you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> doesn't know exactly what they want and i always say make sure you major in something that you like even if it's not going to be your career vocation
 		because you'll get better grades i i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> would probably rather hire you know a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a three six</NUMEX> in um  in history uh to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> than someone with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> oh in business administration
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah well yeah i see what you're saying
 	
 	
 		that make sense
 		yeah i always you know tell them that you should major in something you you're going to get good grades in because that that's always i think more important
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know overall
 	
 	
 		uh  give me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		yeah oh you you're at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> now you are at work yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i'm just getting ready to go to lunch  uh yeah that's like what we were saying though would you uh advise a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or a public school you know what's the trade off there what
 	
 	
 		i would i would it would i i tell you i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		could you get me those
 	
 	
 		and the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> here are pretty good i teach at a public school actually and i know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores for our admitting
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX> are higher than a lot of the public school a lot of the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and um i actually i would full time at a at a public school and then right now i'm teaching part time at a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> institution
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and um  and i really think i i think i'm getting a better caliber of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at the private school
 		because i think their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> pay more and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are a little bit more challenged because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are probably college educated
 		where at the public school i don't think as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> are are college educated and i don't i think because it costs less the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> doesn't take it quite as serious
 		you know they're not  it it's the minimal cost but i think you can get a good education at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> or private
 		uh but i think you can also get a bad education at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> or private you know i you have to really you have to look around at the school i i think the bad part is that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't know what to look for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah i think uh i would agree with that in fact the thing that i'm going through the same thing where in graduate school i was trying to choose you know a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> might be better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		for my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like say you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Small</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> or something might have some top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> yet if i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> of I or CMU or you know some you know any big name school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		my quality of education might not be that much better but it's the same thing as you know what will the name recognition get me kind of thing
 	
 	
 		right yeah does it have a big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> or is it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's that's usually the basic criteria
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean uh yeah is it a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> school you know but i think yeah see i'm i'm at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX> so in this this region
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um though i go to a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX> my diploma will still say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know it doesn't doesn't differentiate on my diploma though i would put it on my resume what program i went to but i i think you know i'm actually at a smaller program i'm not at the college the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">College Park</ENAMEX> campus you know that's the big one with the football team
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i i think um  i think you're right that there's a lot of there's difficult decisions there based on name recognition um
 		you know when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was applying for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> schools i applied to some big programs you know in this area like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevens Institute of Technology</ENAMEX> which is recognized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> as as
 		you know one step below <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> in a since you know so it's got big name recognition in this area a big science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> no football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but a big science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't yeah i think you're right you really have to think about that for the job i went to a very small state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> when i got my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s
 		and when i now i was in education at first when i was looking for jobs i was going to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> i was just a high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> so
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> recognized that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> because it was a teaching school sort of you know but then when i went um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> work you know or for a new job <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said to me you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shippensburg State</ENAMEX> where is that you know and you know when i went into higher education even at other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> they weren't aware of it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think yeah that's important um  i think it depends on if you want to be a if you want a regional job or a national job you need that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> job or so out of school too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i i guess another thing that concerns me is uh so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it seems like everybody <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is still in that  job market  and uh
 		um where was i at oh going in going to school you get taught
 		the things you learn in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but there is also a whole other dimension i mean the growing up while you're going to school part
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh actually in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> especially a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Missouri</ENAMEX> will have a main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> which is big multi disciplinary and they'll have a satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> in a usually in a smaller town
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that specializes in the technical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> so you've really uh
 		i guess sacrificed some social exposure to different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah depending on your technical areas yeah i could see that but you know at some of the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i know that at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX> where i am you know in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> program i i haven't even met uh someone outside of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my area of information systems except for
 		
 		
 	