



<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO s Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20548</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 3, 2000</TIMEX>
This document contains the protocols governing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>) work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The need for these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protocols</ENAMEX> was consistently voiced to me by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> since my nomination as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX>. I
firmly believe they will enable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to better serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
improve satisfaction with our work, and ensure equitable treatment
of all requesters.
These protocols are intended to provide clearly defined and
transparent policies and practices relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work. They
also provide a means of holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> accountable for commitments
made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and ensuring that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is consistent in dealing
with all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX>. They reflect a number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">refinements</ENAMEX> made on the basis of feedback from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> and staff
during our trial implementation phase (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000 to September</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>).
Along with all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, I look forward to using
these protocols to continue to serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for the benefit
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. We will continue to monitor the application
of these protocols and will consider what, if any, changes should
be made in the future. Any changes will be made in consultation
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. I encourage you to contact our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
Congressional Relations on (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-4400</TIMEX> if you have any questions
or comments on these protocols.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David M. Walker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
Contents

Letter


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Approach
The following protocols are general principles governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> involving audits, program reviews and
evaluations, analyses, and investigations.
To effectively support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> must be professional,
objective, fact-based, nonpartisan, nonideological, fair, and
balanced in all its work. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> products and services should
conform to generally accepted and applicable auditing, accounting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">investigative</ENAMEX>, and evaluation principles and standards. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will
only undertake work that is within its scope of authority and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competency</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will strive to meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' needs within
available resources and exercise the independence necessary to
guarantee that its products and work conform to professional
standards and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s core values of accountability,
integrity, and reliability.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO GAO</ENAMEX> undertakes work through
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> primary means:
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) congressional mandates, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) congressional requests,


Work
and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) legal authority allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to undertake work intended
to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.


Setting Priorities
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has a statutory obligation to fulfill requests from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>. To effectively accomplish this
obligation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> consult regularly with committee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work is prioritized
in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>' needs and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s resources by
subject matter. To ensure adherence to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s core values, effective
management practices, and efficient use of available resources, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
will prioritize its work in the following order.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
Congressional mandates, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> requests, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> requests


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee Member</ENAMEX> requests


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
Individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> requests


Congressional mandates include requirements specifically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> by statutes, conference reports, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> reports.
Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> requests include requests from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro</ENAMEX>
Tempore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> requests are those from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subcommittee Chair, Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranking Member</ENAMEX>), or
both, on a program or activity within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s jurisdiction.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee Member</ENAMEX> requests are those involving a program or activity
within the jurisdiction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>'s assigned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>.
Individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> requests are those for work where the program or
activity is not within the jurisdiction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>'s assigned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX>.
With respect to setting priorities, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> considers the nature of
the requested work in light of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> rules governing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX>, including their appropriation, authorization,
budgetary, and oversight jurisdiction over a program or activity.
When jurisdictional issues arise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> and
staff to consult with each other to resolve any related disputes.
In doing so, they may seek a resolution through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parliamentarian</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> devotes a limited portion of its resources for research and
development that enables <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) invest in issues the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may need to address in the
future and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) provide products of broad institutional interest to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. This work includes compendiums such as periodic
reports on highrisk areas and other governmentwide major management
challenges.


Congressional Mandates
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> treats work that is directed by congressional mandates
differently from congressional requests. Because congressional
mandates are established by either the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or
more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s policy that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> prepared in
response to congressional mandates are issued without any
restrictions (i.e., immediately available to the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
and the public). When mandates direct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to report to a specific
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will work with the majority and minority of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">designated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to clarify our reporting objectives and time
frames. If the mandate does not specify a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will work
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> of jurisdiction (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> and minority) as set
forth in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> rules and any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and/or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> identified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> of jurisdiction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will meet
with designated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> regarding the scope and
timing of work. While the work is ongoing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide them
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) periodic status reports on the work, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) briefings on the
preliminary and final results of the work, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) notification
before the draft product is sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for comment and
offer a copy of the draft for informational purposes.


Congressional Requests
Congressional requests for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> work must be made in writing by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> and addressed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> or their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> are encouraged to consult informally with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> in developing requests for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> work. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will do
work without a written request only if the work involves limited
technical assistance that can be completed within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> staff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>,
such as providing briefings on prior work or readily available
information. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will refer any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who wants a copy of a
request letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> who submitted it.
For requests that involve work on programs or activities
relating to the internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>-the


Commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX>
Requesters
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, or both--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will work with the requester to seek
bipartisan support for such requests. If the request affects both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houses of Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will work with the requester to seek
bicameral support for the request <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from either</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chairs and Ranking</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> of jurisdiction over the
congressional program or activity. If the request affects only one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will work with the requester to seek support for the
request <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from either</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the affected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
or
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chair and Ranking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>(s) of
jurisdiction over the congressional program or activity. When it is
not possible to obtain bicameral or bipartisan support, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will
work with the requester to notify the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of the
request before 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> commits itself to do the work. (See
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">03</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">198G</NUMEX>.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> who request work, within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>
business <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of receipt, a letter acknowledging the receipt of the
request and either accepting or declining it. This letter may be
augmented by a verbal communication. When a request is accepted,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide the requester an estimate of when the job is
likely to be staffed (e.g., immediately, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a few weeks</TIMEX>, within
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX>, or at a future date to be determined). When a
request is declined, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide the requester the rationale
for declining the work (e.g., the requested work is outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
scope of authority, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> already has ongoing work addressing the
issue, or resource constraints limit our ability to respond to a
Member request). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will, where appropriate, suggest alternatives
to meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">requester</ENAMEX>'s needs. In consideration of its past
practice for requests from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s oversight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmental Affairs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Government Reform-GAO</ENAMEX> will send a
copy of our letter to either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chair</ENAMEX> (if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranking Member</ENAMEX>
submitted the request) or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ranking Member</ENAMEX> (if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chair</ENAMEX>
submitted the request) of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>.
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requesters</ENAMEX> should not expect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to proceed with
the request or provide additional services until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has informed
each requester that it will accept the request. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> submit
independent requests on the same issue and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has not formally
accepted the requests, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will consult with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> and will merge requests only if the requesters agree.
Otherwise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will issue separate products. In limited
circumstances, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will work with the requesters to merge
multiple requests it receives relating to a major event, such as a
natural disaster or accident.
After accepting the request, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will initiate a meeting with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">requester</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 business days</TIMEX> of receiving the
request to gain a better understanding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">requester</ENAMEX>'s need for
information and the nature of the research questions. During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this</TIMEX>
meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will also (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s ability to respond within
the desired time frame, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) provide a verbal estimate of the level
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO resources</ENAMEX> required, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) advise the requester that, as
the original requester, only he or she can approve co-requesters.
If this option is exercised, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will send a letter to the original
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">requester</ENAMEX> and each co-requester documenting this agreement.
Once the requester and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> have agreed to proceed with the
request, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide the following to the requester:


•
A letter confirming the agreements reached within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>
business days after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the requester agree on the terms,
including the need for a job design phase and a preliminary
expected completion date.


•
Periodic status reports; notification of any significant
changed circumstances affecting the scope of work or related time
frames for completing the work (e.g., availability, reliability, or
access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> records,




Commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-Requesters
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of information); and briefing(s) on the
preliminary and final results of the work.



•
The option to withdraw at any time sponsorship of work
that is not intended to result in a written product (e.g., a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>).

If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has agreed to produce a written product, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will:


•
Notify the requester before a draft product is sent to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for comment and offer the requester a copy of the draft.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide the draft, for informational purposes, when it is
sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for comment. By law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Governmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Government Reform</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> may request a copy
of any draft product generated under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s legislative authority
(research and development work) when it is sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for
comment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will advise these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> when such drafts are sent
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for comment.


•
Allow the requester an option to restrict the release of
a product for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 30 calendar days</TIMEX> after the date the product is
issued. This restriction does not preclude the requester from
sharing the product with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX>.


•
Inform the requester of the option to withdraw
sponsorship at any time before the product is submitted for
printing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reserves the right to issue the product without
reference to the requester when sponsorship is
withdrawn.


If any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> is interested in becoming a co-requester of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will explain its policy on co-requests and refer the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> to the original requester. If the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requester</ENAMEX> agrees,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> can become a co-requester any time before a product is
submitted for printing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will extend the same commitments to
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-145G <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX>


Supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional</ENAMEX>
Interests
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-requesters as to the original requester (see Commitment to
Congressional Requesters). However, co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requesters</ENAMEX> cannot approve
additional co-requesters or restrict the timing of the release of
the product after it is issued.
In limited circumstances, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> may be unable to do the requested
work on behalf of a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>. These
circumstances involve situations in which the request (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) addresses
an important issue of broad interest to multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> as a whole, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) involves an issue that is a legislative
priority or is on a fast legislative track, or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) asks for a
compilation of information which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has developed from a
substantial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of prior work and/or work originally requested by
others. In such cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will advise the requester that it cannot
do the work as a request but will instead address the issue as part
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s research and development work.
On rare occasions, the results of ongoing congressionally
requested work may be important and relevant to pending legislation
(e.g., when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has information which could inform the legislative
debate on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor) or other institutional
interests. In such cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reserves the right, after
consultation with the requester, to make the information or product
generally available regardless of a restriction placed on its
release. In these cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will promptly notify the requesters
why, when, and to whom the information or product will be
released.


Notification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ongoing Work</ENAMEX>
For ongoing work--except for classified work and
investigations--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will disclose, if asked (e.g., by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX>,
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, or the press), the source of the
request and the project's objectives, scope, and methodology.
Additionally, all congressional
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-145G <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obtaining Agency</ENAMEX> Comments
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> have, through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> intranet connections to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, access to the objectives, scope, and methodology of active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assignments</ENAMEX>, except for those cases where the reporting of such
work would result in disclosing classified or other sensitive
information. Active assignments are those that have been
staffed.
As required by generally accepted government auditing standards,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will hold an exit conference with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> at the end
of the data collection and analysis phase to (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) validate the
factual accuracy of data gathered and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) discuss the implications
that flow from them. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and other
directly affected parties the opportunity to officially comment on
a draft report to which they are a party (other than reports that
largely reflect prior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> work). The substance of those comments
will be published in the report along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s assessment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> prefers written comments but will accept oral comments.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> may give an agency <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 30 calendar days</TIMEX> to comment,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> may attempt to obtain comments in shorter time frames,
depending on the product timing needs of the requester and the
complexity of the issues involved. In rare cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> may grant an extension beyond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 calendar days</TIMEX> if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> shows that an extension is necessary and will likely result
in a more accurate product.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will not provide an opportunity to comment in cases where
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) disclosure of an investigation's results could pose risks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and their confidentiality or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) premature disclosure
of information could compromise the results of the work.


Termination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Work</ENAMEX>
If requesters or co-requesters decide to withdraw their support
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> work that will not result in a written product (e.g., a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>), they may do so at any time. If a written product has been
planned, the requesters or co-requesters must advise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> of their
withdrawal before the product is submitted for printing. Their
withdrawal will not result in the termination of a product if
significant resources have been expended and/or the product is in
the public interest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will, under these circumstances, issue a
product as if it were undertaken on its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>. The product
may be addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> of jurisdiction or the affected
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>. Copies of such products will be sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> of
jurisdiction and will be available to other interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>.


Product Release
All congressionally requested products will have a targeted
issuance date. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will notify requesters <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 30</NUMEX> calendar
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> before they are to receive a product and accommodate their
requests for restrictions on the release of the product of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 30</NUMEX>
calendar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> after the issuance date. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will grant extensions
beyond the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 calendar days</TIMEX> only in limited cases (e.g., a change
in the date of a hearing related to the report). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reserves the
right to release any product that has been issued but is under
restriction if it is leaked or otherwise made publicly available.
In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reserves the right to release drafts of products
that have been leaked or made publicly available. In such cases,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requesters</ENAMEX> prior to the release.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workpaper Access GAO</ENAMEX> will grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX>,
upon their written request, access to its workpapers at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
site or will provide copies of selected workpapers only after a
product has been made publicly available. This is subject to legal
and privacy considerations, such as those concerning
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-145G <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX>


Requests for Testimony
taxpayer return information, protected banking information,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand jury</ENAMEX> information, and credit card accounts listed in travel
vouchers.
Requests for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> testimony should be made by a committee Chair
in writing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will strive to respond to all congressional
requests for testimony. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will decline an invitation to
testify when (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> cannot produce a testimony that conforms to
its core values and standards or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the substance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
testimony would be new information developed for another committee
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> who wants to restrict the information until its public
release. In cases of multiple requests for testimony involving the
same subject matter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will testify on the date of the first
hearing held and will be available to testify at any subsequent
hearings. For testimony based on new work, regardless of whether it
is a preliminary or final product, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will, consistent with
professional auditing standards, hold an exit conference with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> before the written testimony is completed to (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
validate the accuracy of data gathered and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) discuss the
implications that flow from the data. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will distribute its
written testimony in accordance with the rules of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>' rules, and be available to brief
the majority and the minority on material facts, major findings,
and recommendations relating to any new work.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detailees</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
By law, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> can be assigned on detail only to
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> or personal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> may not engage in partisan activities or discussions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> requests for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detailees</ENAMEX> should be in writing and be
for specific purposes for a period not to exceed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 year</TIMEX>. All
detailees must be approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> in a
manner


Press <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy</ENAMEX>
consistent with the applicable rules and policies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>.
In response to media inquiries about ongoing work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will
provide information only about the objectives, scope, and
methodology of an assignment; the names of the requesters; and the
expected completion date. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will refer inquiries for any
additional information to the requesters. As a professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courtesy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requesters</ENAMEX> of substantive media inquiries
during an ongoing assignment. Once a product is publicly released,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with expertise in the subject matter will answer
questions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> when asked. On-camera interviews for
television news programs are done only on request and only when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
deems them appropriate for public understanding of the facts,
findings, conclusions, and recommendations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> products. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
policy is that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> with the broadest knowledge of a
completed assignment do such interviews. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> agrees to do an
on-camera interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will advise the requesters of the media
source and the expected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> and time. If asked to participate in
press briefings sponsored by requesters, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide support
if the press briefing is held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> In such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instances</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with the
understanding that they are present only to answer questions about
the specifics of released <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> products. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> does not hold press
conferences or issue press releases about products, but it does
advise the media and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> of the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> products via
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX> and other venues.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investigations GAO</ENAMEX> has an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Special</ENAMEX>
Investigations that


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
investigates referrals concerning specific allegations of
federal fraud, waste, abuse, or misconduct and


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
conducts specific projects that require special
investigative tactics. It is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s policy to conduct


Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-145G <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX>
investigations according to standards established by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council on Integrity</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Efficiency</ENAMEX> (PCIE) as adapted
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PCIE</ENAMEX> standards place upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
the responsibility to ensure that (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) investigations are conducted
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who collectively possess the required knowledge,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skills</ENAMEX>, and abilities to perform the investigations, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) judgments
made in collecting and analyzing evidence and communicating results
are impartial, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) due professional care (e.g., thoroughness,
appropriate use of investigative techniques, impartiality,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objectivity</ENAMEX>, protection of individual rights, and timeliness) is
exercised. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s congressional policies and protocols apply to all
investigative work conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Special</ENAMEX>
Investigations unless an exception is specified herein or noted in
advance.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ordering Information</ENAMEX>
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> copy of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report is free. Additional copies of
reports are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> each. A check or money order should be made out to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Superintendent of Documents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VISA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> credit cards
are accepted, also.
Orders for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> or more copies to be mailed to a single address
are discounted <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX>.

Orders by mail:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.O. Box 37050</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC 20013</ENAMEX>
Orders by visiting: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Room 1100 700 4th St.</ENAMEX> NW (corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">4th</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G Sts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NW</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>


Orders by phone:
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6000</ENAMEX> fax: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-6061</TIMEX> TDD (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2537</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> issues a list of newly available reports and
testimony. To receive facsimile copies of the daily list or any
list from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 days</TIMEX>, please call (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-6000</TIMEX> using a
touchtone phone. A recorded menu will provide information on how to
obtain these lists.


Orders by Internet:
For information on how to access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reports on the Internet,
send an e-mail message with "info" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to:

info@<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

or visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX> home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> at:

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>




To Report <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fraud</ENAMEX>, Contact one: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste</ENAMEX>, or Abuse in

• 
Web site: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/fraudnet/fraudnet.</ENAMEX>htm•
e-mail: fraudnet@<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gao</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">• 1-800-424-5454</ENAMEX> (automated answering system)







