



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>


<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2001</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATIONAL SAVING</ENAMEX>


Answers to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Key Questions</ENAMEX>



Contents


Preface


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summary of Major</ENAMEX>



Personal Saving and Retirement Security9 
National Saving Overview11 
National Saving and the Economy12 
National Saving and the Government13

18



<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 1</ENAMEX>


Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>. What is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Rate and What Does it</ENAMEX>
Mean?18 
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>. Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Measure Personal Saving</ENAMEX>?20 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retirement Security</ENAMEX>
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>. How Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Rate Changed Over</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>?21 
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>. Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do People Save</ENAMEX>?22 
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>. Why Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Rate Declined</ENAMEX>?25 
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is the Relationship Between Personal Saving and</ENAMEX>
Wealth?27 
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Household Wealth Has Increased, Does It Matter</ENAMEX> if
the
Personal Saving Rate Has Declined?31 
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>. How Do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Compare</ENAMEX>
as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Retirement Income</ENAMEX>?34 
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>. What Are the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Implications of a Growing Elderly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Population</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retirement Security</ENAMEX>?39

47



<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 2</ENAMEX>


Q2<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is National Saving and How Is It Measured</ENAMEX>?
Q2<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>. How Has <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">U.S. National Saving Changed Over</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>-Both47 Overview 
Overall and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Component</ENAMEX>?49 
Q2<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>. How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Does U.S. National Saving Compare to Other</ENAMEX>
Major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrialized Nations</ENAMEX>?53 
Q2<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are Other Ways of Defining Saving and</ENAMEX>
Investment?55



<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 3 National Saving</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economy</ENAMEX>


58
Q3<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>. How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Does National Saving Contribute to Investment</ENAMEX>
and
Ultimately Economic Growth?58 
Q3<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>. Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Relatively Low National Saving Rate Affected</ENAMEX>
Investment and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Growth</ENAMEX>? What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Factors Have Fostered</ENAMEX>
Economic Growth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Recent Years</TIMEX>?62 
Q3<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>. To What Extent Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> Supplemented Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving and Investment by Borrowing Saving From Abroad</ENAMEX>? How
Does
Such <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Borrowing Affect the Economy</ENAMEX>?65 
Q3<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>. What Is the Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term Economic Outlook</ENAMEX>
for




<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 4 National Saving</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Saving and Investment</ENAMEX>? How Would the
Long-Term
Economic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook Change With Higher Levels of National</ENAMEX>
Saving?70

77
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>. How Has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Fiscal Policy Affected U.S. National</ENAMEX>
Saving?77 
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>. Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do Government and Private Saving Tend to Move</ENAMEX>
in

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opposite Directions</ENAMEX>?81 
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>. What Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term Outlook</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Government

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saving/Dissaving</ENAMEX>?82 
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>. How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Does Saving Affect Future Budgetary</ENAMEX>
Flexibility?87 
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>. What are the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Implications of Current Fiscal Policy</ENAMEX>
Choices

for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future Living Standards</ENAMEX>?90 
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX>. How Does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Investment Affect National Saving</ENAMEX>
and

Economic Growth?93 
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>. What Policies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> Government <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have Been Aimed</ENAMEX>
at


Encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonfederal Saving and Investment</ENAMEX>?<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX> Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>.
Given <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Experts Disagree About Whether Retirement</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Tax Incentives Are Effective In Increasing Personal</ENAMEX>
Saving


Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Do These Tax Incentives Affect National</ENAMEX>
Saving?99 
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>. What Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Government Doing to Educate the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>

About Why Saving Matters? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX>
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX>. How Would <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Reform Affect National</ENAMEX>
Saving? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106</NUMEX>
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX>. How Would Establishing Individual Accounts
Affect


National Saving? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">112</NUMEX>
Q4<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX>. How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Would Medicare Reform Affect National Saving</ENAMEX>?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX>


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 5</ENAMEX>


Q5<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are Key Issues in Evaluating National Saving</ENAMEX>?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>

Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy</ENAMEX> Issues


Appendixes
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Appendix I: Objectives, Scope</ENAMEX>, and Methodolog
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">122</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Appendix II</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Economic Model</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Key Assumptions</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">127</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appendix III</ENAMEX>: Glossary
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appendix IV</ENAMEX>: Bibliography
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">142</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appendix V</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Related GAO Products</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">153</NUMEX>


Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Selected Federal Income Tax Provisions That</ENAMEX>
Influence

Tables

Personal Saving


Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2</NUMEX>:Change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Saving Resulting</ENAMEX>
From a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> Tax-Deductible IRA Contribution Under
Alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Assumptions 100</ENAMEX> 
Table II.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Key Assumptions</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Model</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX>



Figure <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S.1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Rate</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2000</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S.2</NUMEX>:Net National Saving as a Share of GDP (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2000</TIMEX>)
12
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Rate</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2000</TIMEX>) 22Figure
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comparison of the Personal Saving Rate and the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Wealth-Income Ratio</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2000</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Net Worth</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Income Level</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 33</TIMEX>
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX>:Share of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Elderly Households</ENAMEX>' Income by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Source</ENAMEX>
of



Income, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 35</TIMEX> Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pensions</ENAMEX>, Income from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accumulated</ENAMEX>
Assets, and Earnings
Determine <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Had Highest Retirement Incomes</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 37</TIMEX> Figure
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aged Population Nearly Doubles From Today</ENAMEX> as a Share

of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total U.S. Population</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2075</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Relatively Fewer Workers Will Support More</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Retirees</ENAMEX>

(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2075</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Trust Fund Faces Insolvency</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2038</TIMEX>


(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2050</TIMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.9</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare's Hospital Insurance Trust</ENAMEX>
Fund Faces
Insolvency in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2029</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2050</TIMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.10</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare HI Cost and Income</ENAMEX> as a

Percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxable Payroll</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2075</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross</ENAMEX> National Saving as a Share of GDP
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2000</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Composition of Net National Saving</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2000</TIMEX>)
51
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Trends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gross National Saving</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-1997</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Overview of Saving</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Output</ENAMEX>, and
Income

Flows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.2</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Saving</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domestic Investment</ENAMEX>, and Net
Foreign
Investment (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2000</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX>:Net <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Holdings of Foreign Assets</ENAMEX> and Net Income
From

Abroad (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977-1999</TIMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX> Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross</ENAMEX> National Saving as a
Share of GDP Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Save</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Surpluses Simulation</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-2075</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX>:GDP <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Per Capita Under Alternative Gross</ENAMEX>
National

Saving Rates (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2075</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.1</NUMEX>:The Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Surpluses</ENAMEX> and Deficits on
Net

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Saving</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-2000</TIMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX> Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unified Surpluses</ENAMEX> and
Deficits as a Share of GDP Under
Alternative Fiscal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Simulations</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2075</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">86</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Composition of Federal</ENAMEX> Spending as a Share of
GDP

Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Save the Social Security Surpluses</ENAMEX> Simulation <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.4</NUMEX>:GDP <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Per Capita Under Alternative Fiscal Policy</ENAMEX>
Simulations
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2075</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX> 
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare HI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMI</ENAMEX> Spending as a Share of
GDP
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2075</TIMEX>) 116


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Text Box</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross Domestic Product</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross</ENAMEX> National
Product 48Text <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box 4.1</ENAMEX>: How do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> and federal unified
budget concepts of
federal surpluses and deficits differ? 78 
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Text Box</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Government Saving When Reducing Publicly</ENAMEX>
Held

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Debt</ENAMEX> is Not an Option <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84</TIMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Text Box</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individual Development</ENAMEX> Accounts for
Low-Income
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Savers 102</ENAMEX>
Abbreviations

Preface
The term "saving" is used both when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> discuss their own
finances and when policymakers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> discuss "national
saving." For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, saving means forgoing
consumption <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> so they can enjoy a better standard of living in
the future. National saving-the portion of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s current
income not consumed-is the sum of saving by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>,
and all levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. National saving represents resources
available for investment to replace old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> and equipment and
to buy more and better capital goods. Higher saving and investment
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital stock contribute to increased productivity
and stronger economic growth over the long term. Saving today
increases a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capacity to produce goods and services in the
future and, therefore, helps to increase the standard of living for
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, combined saving by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and business has
declined. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">much of that time</TIMEX>, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> did not
contribute to saving; instead it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrower</ENAMEX>, its deficits
absorbing a share of the saving pool available for investment. For
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> as a whole, saving has rebounded somewhat from its low
point in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX> but remains relatively low by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
historical standards. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1998</TIMEX>, the federal government
began to contribute to the pool of saving by running its first
surplus since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> budget surpluses now are projected for
at least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>. But even with the advent of federal
government saving in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX>, national saving available for
new investment remains relatively low, in large part because
personal saving has dramatically declined. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has been able
to invest more than it saves by borrowing from abroad, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> question whether this is a viable strategy for the long
term.
Personal saving plays a dual role, ensuring both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>'
retirement security and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s economic security. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> provides a foundation for retirement income, saving
through pensions and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> on their own behalf contribute
substantially to retirement income. Even as more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
accumulating balances through employer-sponsored 401(k) saving
plans and individual retirement accounts, personal saving-which
does not reflect gains on existing assets-has declined. The
personal saving rate has plunged, with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> households spending
virtually all of their current income. Although aggregate household
wealth has risen in part as a result of the stock market boom over
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1990s</NUMEX>, many individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> have accumulated little, if
any, wealth.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> faces a demographic tidal wave that poses significant
challenges for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>' retirement security and our economy as
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a whole</TIMEX>. More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are living longer in retirement, and there
will be relatively fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> supporting each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retiree</ENAMEX> in the
future. Without meaningful reform, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
programs face long-term financing problems. Although public
attention usually focuses on the dates by which the trust funds are
projected to become insolvent, the effects associated with
financing cash deficits for these programs will be felt sooner as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> boom generation begins to retire. As the population ages,
spending for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and federal health programs will leave
increasingly less room for spending on other national
priorities.
Increasing national saving is an important way to bolster
retirement security for current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and to allow future workers
to more easily bear the costs of financing federal retirement and
health programs while maintaining their standard of living. As we
have reported in the past, the surest way for the federal
government to affect national saving is through federal fiscal
policy, particularly in what it chooses to do with the budget
surpluses projected over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policymakers</ENAMEX> appear to
have agreed to save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> surpluses, and the fiscal
policy debate has centered on what to do with the balance of the
anticipated surpluses. To the extent that they are used to reduce
federal debt held by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, surpluses represent an opportunity
to increase national saving. In addition, how surpluses are used
has long-term implications for future economic growth. Policy
debates surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> reform also have
implications for all levels of saving-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, personal, and,
ultimately, national.
This report is designed to present information about national
saving-as measured in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Income</ENAMEX> and Product Accounts-and
its implications for economic growth and retirement security in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concise</ENAMEX> and easily understandable manner. In general, this report
is based on widely accepted economic principles, and we identify
those areas where many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> do not agree. Although many
excellent studies and books have been written on national saving
and long-term economic growth, these discussions tend to be complex
and technical. Also, most discussion of the decline in personal
saving focuses on the adequacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>' retirement saving
rather than on the significance of personal saving for the economy
as a whole. For example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point that is sometimes overlooked is
that low personal saving has consequences for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> reliance on
foreign borrowing, long-term economic growth, and standards of
living for future generations.
This report addresses the following questions: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) What is
personal saving, how is it related to national saving, and what are
the implications of low personal saving for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' retirement
security? (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) What is national saving and how does current saving
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> compare to historical trends and saving in
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) How does national saving affect the economy
and how would higher saving affect the longterm outlook? (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) How
does federal fiscal policy affect national saving, what federal
policies have been aimed at increasing private saving, and how
would <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> reform affect national saving?
And, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) what are key issues in evaluating national saving? For a
quick overview of the topics discussed in this report, see the
summary section.
For easy access to definitions of key terms, we include a
glossary at the end of this report. Terms contained in the glossary
appear in bold type in the text the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time they are used in the
major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who are interested in more detailed
information on the topics covered here, we also include a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bibliography</ENAMEX>.
This report was prepared under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul L. Posner</ENAMEX>,
Managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Budget Analysis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan J. Irving</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Budget Analysis</ENAMEX>, who may be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-9573</ENAMEX> if there are any questions.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul L. Posner Susan J. Irving Managing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> Budget
Analysis Strategic Issues <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Budget Analysis</ENAMEX>
Strategic Issues
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summary of Major Sections</ENAMEX>
Personal Saving and Retirement
Security
The personal saving rate-as measured in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Income</ENAMEX> and
Product Accounts (NIPA)-reflects how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> in aggregate
are saving from their current disposable income. In evaluating
personal saving, it is important to distinguish between saving as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> for an individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household</ENAMEX> to finance future consumption and
saving as a way to finance the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital formation. Strange
as it may seem to the typical household, capital gains on its
existing assets do not contribute to saving as measured in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX>.
That is because capital gains reflect a revaluation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
existing capital stock and do not provide resources for financing
investment that adds to the capital stock. Whereas employer
contributions to pension funds as well as pension funds' interest
and dividend income are part of personal income and contribute to
personal saving, increases in the market value of assets held by
pension funds, for example, are not counted as personal income and
saving. Although an individual household can tap its wealth by
selling assets to finance consumption or accumulate other assets,
the sale of an existing asset merely transfers ownership; it does
not generate new economic output.
The personal saving rate has largely declined since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>,
plummeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> to levels not seen since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Depression</ENAMEX>, as shown in figure S.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. A low personal saving rate
raises questions about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> have adequate resources
to sustain their rate of spending. A negative saving rate means
that, in aggregate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are spending more than their current
income by drawing down past saving, selling existing assets, or
borrowing.

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1960 1965 1970 1975 1980 1985 1990 1995 2000</ENAMEX>
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Economic Analysis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Commerce</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> use several theories to explain what motivates people
to save. Despite a great deal of study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have found no
single reason that convincingly explains the decline in the
personal saving rate. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possible explanation is that surging
household wealth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> contributed to the virtual
disappearance of personal saving. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1990s</TIMEX>, aggregate
household wealth has swelled relative to disposable personal
income, largely due to increases in the market value of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>'
existing assets (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>). Yet, despite the stock market
boom of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> have accumulated little, if any,
wealth (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> did not
own stocks as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> provides a foundation for retirement
income, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits replace <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 40 percent</NUMEX> of
pre-retirement income for the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> benefits must be supplemented by private pensions,
accumulated assets, or other resources in order for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to
maintain a reasonable standard of living in retirement compared to
their final working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pensions</ENAMEX>, income from accumulated
assets, and earnings from continued employment largely determine
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> will have the highest retirement income (see
figures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>). Pensions are not a universal source of
retirement income, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of those working in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
lacked a pension plan. While most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> say they recognize the
need to save for retirement,
National Saving Overview
fewer than half of those surveyed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2001</TIMEX> had tried to
calculate how much they need to save.
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 75 years</TIMEX>, the elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> will nearly
double as a share of the total <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX>). As
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live longer, there will be relatively fewer workers
supporting each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retiree</ENAMEX> unless retirement patterns change. While
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX>,
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2030</TIMEX>, there will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> paying taxes to support
each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX>). Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> face long-term financing problems, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare's Hospital Insurance</ENAMEX> trust funds eventually will be
exhausted as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> draw their benefits (see figures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.9</NUMEX>). Absent reform, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> costs would
constitute a substantial drain on the earnings of future workers
(see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.10</NUMEX>). Anticipating potential benefit cuts, people
could choose to save more now, work longer to delay retirement, or
experience a lower standard of living in retirement. With an aging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and a slowly growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>, saving more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and
increasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s future economic capacity is critical to
ensuring retirement security in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX>, national saving is the sum of saving by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, and all levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Gross national
saving-which reflects resources available both to replace old, worn
out capital goods and to expand the capital stock-has rebounded as
a share of gross domestic product (GDP) from its low in the 1990s
but remains below the level of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX>).
Depreciation as a share of GDP has increased slightly over the past
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, and net national saving-which excludes
depreciation-remains well below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> average, as shown in
figure
S.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Through much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX>, federal deficits
absorbed funds saved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and reduced
overall national saving available to finance private investment
(see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>). Even as federal surpluses have contributed to
national saving in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, personal saving has steadily
declined as a share of GDP, and personal dissaving in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> absorbed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> that otherwise would have been available for investment.
Although gross national saving in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> was low by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> historical standards, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> gross national saving has
generally been lower than other major industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> over
the past <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX>).
National Saving and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economy</ENAMEX>
14
12
10
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1960 1965 1970 1975 1980 1985 1990 1995 2000</ENAMEX>
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Economic</ENAMEX>
Analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Commerce</ENAMEX>.
National saving represents resources available for investment in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s stock of capital goods, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plant</ENAMEX>, equipment, and
housing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s human capital and knowledge-forms of
intangible capital-are not part of the NIPA definitions of saving
and investment. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> focuses on the incomes arising from
current production of goods and services and, thus, does not count
revaluation of existing assets in national saving. Changes in the
market value of existing tangible and financial assets, such as
land and stocks, reflect expectations about the productive
potential of the underlying capital, but fluctuations in asset
values may not represent real, permanent changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
productive capacity.
National saving together with borrowing from abroad provides the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> for investment that can boost productivity and lead to
higher economic growth and future living standards (see figure
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.1</NUMEX>). Investment in new capital is an important way to raise the
productivity of the slowly growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> as the population
ages. Greater economic growth from saving more now would make it
easier for future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to achieve a rising standard of living
for themselves while also paying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s commitments
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>. Economic growth also depends on education to
enhance the knowledge and skills of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s work
National Saving and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
force-the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s human capital-as well as research and
development to spur technological advances.
Even though national saving remains relatively low by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
historical standards, economic growth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> has been high
because more and better investments were made. Each dollar saved
bought more investment goods, and a greater share of saving was
invested in highly productive information technology. Also, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> was able to invest more than it saved by borrowing
from abroad (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.2</NUMEX>). Persistent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> current account
deficits have translated into a rising level of indebtedness to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, i.e., net <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> holdings of foreign assets (see
figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX>). Many other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> currently financing investment in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> also will face aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> and declining
national saving, so relying on foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savers</ENAMEX> to finance a large
share of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> domestic investment is not a viable strategy for the
long run.
Current saving and investment decisions have profound
implications for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s level of well-being in the future.
Our simulations using a longterm economic growth model show that,
even assuming the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> could maintain national saving
constant at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> share of GDP, future incomes would fall short
of the rise in living standards enjoyed by prior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> whose
income generally doubled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 35 years</TIMEX> (see figures
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.4 and 3.5</NUMEX>). Saving more would improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s long-term
economic outlook, but this requires consuming less now.
Federal fiscal policy affects the amount of federal government
saving and this in turn directly affects national saving. From the
1970s through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1990s</TIMEX>, federal deficits absorbed a large
share of private saving and reduced the amount of national saving
available for investment (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.1</NUMEX>). Borrowing to finance
these deficits added to the federal debt held by the public. In
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, federal surpluses added to national saving and
increased funds available for investment. So far, the federal
government has used surplus funds to reduce its debt held by the
public. Accumulating nonfederal financial assets, such as stocks,
could be another way that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> saving could translate into
resources available for investment, but this idea is controversial.
An additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> of government saving and debt reduction does
not automatically increase national saving and investment by a
dollar because changes in saving by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> will
tend to offset some of the change in government saving.
While attention has focused on budget surpluses projected over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next decade</TIMEX>, the federal budget will increasingly be driven by
one certainty-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is aging and there will be fewer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> supporting each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retiree</ENAMEX>. In our simulations, saving only
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> surpluses will not be sufficient to accommodate
both the projected growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and health
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entitlements</ENAMEX> as well as other important national priorities in the
long term (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2</NUMEX>). Absent program changes, saving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> surpluses-and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> surpluses-is not
enough to ensure retirement security for the aging population
without placing a heavy burden on future generations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> and health spending alone eventually would exceed total
federal revenue and squeeze out most or all other spending (see
figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX>). Even if the entire unified surplus were saved, our
simulations show that the rise in living standards- measured in
terms of GDP per capita-would fall short of the rise enjoyed by
prior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> whose income generally doubled every 35 years
(see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.4</NUMEX>). Reforming retirement and health entitlement
programs is critical to putting the federal budget on a more
sustainable footing for the long term and to freeing up future
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> for other competing needs.
Although increasing government saving is the most direct way for
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to increase national saving, budget
surpluses also could be used to finance federal investment intended
to promote long-term economic growth or to encourage personal
saving. Whereas unified budget surpluses increase national saving
available for private investment, increasing federal spending on
national infrastructure, if properly designed and administered, can
be another way to increase the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital stock. In addition,
not counting as investment in NIPA-can, if properly designed and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">administered</ENAMEX>, promote the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s long-term productivity and
economic growth. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> also has sought to
encourage personal saving both to enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> and to boost national saving. But, developing policies
that have the desired effect is difficult. Tax incentives affect
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> save for retirement but do not necessarily increase the
overall level of personal saving. Even with preferential tax
treatment for employer-sponsored retirement saving plans and
individual retirement accounts, the personal saving rate has
steadily declined. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> disagree about whether tax incentives
are effective in increasing the overall level of personal saving.
The net effect of a tax incentive on national saving depends on
whether the tax incentive induces enough additional saving by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to make up for the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> saving resulting
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s revenue loss. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, policymakers
have explored using government matching or creating new individual
accounts to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to save more.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> found that a leading obstacle to expanding retirement
saving has been that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do not know how to save for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retirement</ENAMEX>, let alone how much. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Labor</ENAMEX> maintains
an outreach program to raise public awareness about the advantages
of saving and to help educate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> about how much they need to
save for retirement. Other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> also play a role in
educating the public about saving. Individualized statements now
sent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Administration</ENAMEX> to most workers
aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 and older</TIMEX> provide important information for personal
retirement planning, but knowing more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s
financial status would help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to understand how to view their
personal benefit estimates.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoring Social Security</ENAMEX> to sustainable solvency and increasing
saving are intertwined national goals. Saving for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
retirement costs is analogous to an individual's retirement
planning in that the sooner we increase saving, the greater our
benefit from compounding growth. The way in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
is reformed will influence both the magnitude and timing of any
increase in national saving. The ultimate effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
reform on national saving depends on complex interactions between
government saving and personal saving-both through pension funds
and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> on their own behalf. Various proposals would
create new individual accounts as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> reform or
in addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. The extent to which individual
accounts would affect national saving depends on how the accounts
are funded, how the account program is structured, and how people
adjust their own saving behavior in response to the new
accounts.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program is fiscally burdensome in its current form,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> spending (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX>) is expected to drive federal
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissaving</ENAMEX> over the long run. Given the aging of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and the increasing cost of modern medical technology, it
is inevitable that demands on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program will grow. The
current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program lacks incentives to control health care
consumption, and the cost of health care decisions is not
transparent to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. Although future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> costs are
expected to consume a growing share of the federal budget and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, pressure is mounting to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>'s benefit package
to cover prescription drugs, which will add billions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
program costs. In balancing health care spending with other
societal priorities, it is important to distinguish between health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> wants, which are virtually unlimited; needs, which should be
defined and addressed; and overall affordability, which has a
limit. Reducing federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> spending would improve future
levels of government saving, but the ultimate effect on national
saving depends on how the private sector responds to the
reductions.
Key Issues In light of the virtual
disappearance of personal saving, concerns about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> reliance on
borrowing from abroad to finance domestic investment, and the
looming fiscal pressures of an aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, federal
decisionmakers must consider how much of the anticipated budget
surpluses to save, spend, or use for tax reductions. Economic
growth will help society bear the burden of financing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, but it alone will not solve our long-term
fiscal challenge. To participate in the debate over how to reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, the public needs to understand the
difficult choices the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> faces.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 1</ENAMEX>
Personal Saving and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retirement Security</ENAMEX>
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>. What is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Rate and</ENAMEX>
What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Does it Mean</ENAMEX>?
A1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>. The personal saving rate is the most widely cited
statistic about how much households save, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do not
know what the rate measures or what it means. First, it is
necessary to distinguish "saving" from "savings." In everyday
terms, "saving" means spending less than your income and "savings"
are the assets accumulated over time. To better distinguish between
these concepts in this report, the term "saving" means the money
set aside from current income for future consumption-i.e., how much
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each period</TIMEX>'s income is saved rather than spent. The terms
"assets accumulated" and "wealth" are used for the cumulative stock
of resources built over time-what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> commonly think of as
"savings."
The personal saving rate, as measured in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Income</ENAMEX> and
Product Accounts (NIPA)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,1</NUMEX> reflects how much <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are
setting aside from current income. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">NIPA</ENAMEX>, personal saving is
what is left over from personal income after taxes and personal
spending for goods and services. Disposable personal income is the
income available for personal spending and saving after federal,
state, and local taxes as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
payroll taxes are paid. The NIPA personal saving rate is calculated
as the ratio of personal saving to disposable personal income.
To understand what the personal saving rate means, it is helpful
to understand the NIPA definitions of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>," personal income,
and personal spending. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> purposes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>" include not
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> but also nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> primarily serving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, pension funds, and private trust funds. NIPA personal
income includes wages and salaries; interest and dividend income;
rental income;<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietors</ENAMEX>' income; government transfer payments,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, and unemployment benefits; and
employer contributions to pension plans as well as group health and
life insurance plans. Contributions to traditional defined benefit
pension plans and defined contribution plans-such as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">401</NUMEX>(k)
plans-together with pension
1The national income and product accounts (NIPA) are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> set of accounts that show the composition of
production and the distribution of incomes earned in production.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> data reflect production in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
transactions with the rest of the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> data are prepared by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Economic Analysis of the Department of Commerce</ENAMEX>. For
more information, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene P. Seskin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Parker</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
Guide to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX>'s," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Survey of Current Business</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vol.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>, No. 3
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1998</TIMEX>), pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26-68</NUMEX>.
2NIPA treats the net rental value on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>-occupied housing as
personal income.
funds' interest and dividend income represent an important
component of NIPA personal income and saving<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> Benefits paid by
pension plans are not a component of NIPA personal income, although
pension benefits represent an important means for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> consumption (see Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>). NIPA personal spending includes,
for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, clothing, rent, utilities, and medical care;
consumer interest payments; and consumer durables, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and
major appliances<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>
Strange as it may seem to the average household, changes in the
value of existing assets, such as stocks, bonds, or real estate, do
not contribute to NIPA personal income and saving. That is because
capital gains reflect a revaluation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s existing
capital stock and do not provide resources for financing investment
that adds to the capital stock. Under the current NIPA methodology,
realized gains do not count as personal income, but any taxes paid
on such gains reduce disposable personal income and thus personal
saving.
Although the NIPA personal saving rate is the measure most
frequently cited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, an alternative
macroeconomic measure of personal saving is available from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flow of Funds Accounts</ENAMEX> (FFA)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Whereas</ENAMEX> NIPA
measures saving as what is left over from personal income after
taxes and personal spending, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> measures saving as the net
increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' financial and tangible assets less the net
increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' liabilities. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> measures
count household purchases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> as saving. The FFA personal
saving rate also counts household purchases of consumer durables as
saving and, thus, is somewhat higher than the NIPA personal saving
rate. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> macroeconomic measures focus on saving
from the economy's current production and do not include changes in
the market value of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' existing portfolios. In this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, we use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> measure of
3A defined benefit pension plan generally provides benefits
based on a specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formula</ENAMEX> linked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>'s earnings and
tenure. Typically, a defined benefit plan is funded completely by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, who bears the investment risk of such as arrangement.
Under a defined contribution plan, a percentage of pay is
contributed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> to an account for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, with the
worker bearing the investment risk. The increasingly popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">401</ENAMEX>(k)
plans also allow contributions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
4This refers to spending by "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> and not just by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
5The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flow of Funds Accounts</ENAMEX> (FFA) measure the acquisition of
physical and financial assets throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of funds used to acquire the assets. For more information,
see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guide to the Flow of Funds Accounts, Vol. 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Governors</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve System</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>).
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>. Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Measure Personal Saving</ENAMEX>?
personal saving because it more closely represents the resources
available from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital formation.
For the economy as a whole, the personal saving rate provides a
measure of how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are saving compared to current
disposable personal income. A positive saving rate means that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> in aggregate are saving. A low personal saving
rate means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> in aggregate are spending virtually all
of their current income. A negative personal saving rate means
that, in aggregate, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are spending more than
their current income-or "dissaving." Given that the personal saving
rate is an aggregate measure, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> might be saving a
lot even while others are drawing down past saving, selling
existing assets, or borrowing to finance their current
consumption.
A1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>. For the economy as a whole, personal saving can be a vital
source of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s saving available to finance private and
government investment. NIPA personal saving is widely recognized by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> as the key measure of the resources that households
contribute to national saving. A low personal saving rate-unless
offset by relatively higher saving by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and/or government
or by borrowing from abroad-limits how much the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> can invest
and so ultimately limits future economic growth. A low personal
saving rate can raise questions about whether current generations
are setting aside enough to sustain the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s productive
capacity, especially if the other components of national saving are
not correspondingly higher. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> are concerned that the
demand for household consumption is in part fueling the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trade
deficit. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 2</ENAMEX> discusses the trend and the components of
national saving, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 3</ENAMEX> explains how saving affects
long-term economic growth and living standards.
The personal saving rate also has implications for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>'
ability to sustain their current rate of spending. Personal
spending represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. A low
personal saving rate raises questions about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have
adequate resources to withstand a financial emergency such as
unemployment in the event of an economic downturn. In addition,
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policymakers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> have questioned whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are saving enough to ensure their retirement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>.
Having said this, it is important to recognize that
macroeconomic measures such as the NIPA personal saving rate do not
provide a complete picture of
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>. How Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Rate</ENAMEX>
Changed Over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>?
the finances of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household</ENAMEX>'s capacity to
consume depends on both its current income and its wealth. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way
to measure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' wealth is net worth, or the difference
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' assets and their liabilities<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX> The change in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' net worth is broader than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIPA</ENAMEX> or FFA measures of
personal saving and includes both the flow of saving from current
income plus any increase (or decrease) in the market value of
existing assets such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and stocks. For the economy as a
whole, however, the change in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' net worth due to
revaluation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' existing assets does not represent
resources available to invest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital stock.7
A1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX> shows the personal saving rate-expressed as a
percentage of disposable personal income-over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 4 decades</TIMEX>.
The personal saving rate averaged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.3 percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> and
increased to an average of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.6 percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each</TIMEX>
of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, annual saving rates were relatively steady,
although they ranged from a low of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.2</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> to a high of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.7</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, the personal saving rate was
slightly lower than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. After peaking at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10.9 percent</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, the rate generally declined over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, dropping as low
as to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.3 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>; for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>, the rate averaged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.1</NUMEX>
percent. The personal saving rate rebounded from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987 to 1992</TIMEX> when
it reached <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.7 percent</NUMEX>. Since then, the personal saving rate has
steadily declined and averaged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5.9 percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. In
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX>, the personal saving rate dropped below the postwar
low of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.7 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the personal saving rate
plunged to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.2 percent</NUMEX>-an annual rate not seen since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Depression</ENAMEX>. As shown in figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>, the personal saving rate in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> was estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-0.1 percent</NUMEX>.8 With the personal saving
rate around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> or negative, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have questioned how to
interpret the decline; see question <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX>.
6Households' aggregate net worth is available from the Flow of
Funds Accounts' balance sheet for the household sector.
7For further discussion of whether revaluation of existing
assets counts as saving, see questions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4</NUMEX>.
8The last time the personal saving rate was negative was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>
(-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.8 percent</NUMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX> (-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5 percent</NUMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-591SP <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Saving</ENAMEX>
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>. Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do People Save</ENAMEX>?
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Rate</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-2000</TIMEX>) Percent of
disposable personal income <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">12 10 8 6 4 2 0 -2 1960 1965 1970 1975</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1980 1985 1990 1995 2000</ENAMEX>

Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Economic Analysis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Commerce</ENAMEX>.
A1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>. Before trying to answer why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are saving less, let's
start with the question of what motivates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to save. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
save for a variety of reasons such as buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, taking a
vacation, providing a college education for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, or
preparing for their own retirement. They may also save for general
reasons such as for a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">rainy day</TIMEX>" or to leave money to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> with seemingly identical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and income situations may
make different saving choices-some may save a great deal while
others save little, if anything. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> use
several theories in analyzing how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> decide
how much of their current income to save for the future.
The standard theory for explaining personal saving is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">life-cycle</ENAMEX> model<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX> The basic hypothesis is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> save and
accumulate assets to smooth out their consumption and standard of
living over their lifetimes.
9A complementary theory of personal saving is the
permanent-income hypothesis. Generally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> save a greater share
of income when their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> income is higher than their expected
long-run permanent income and save a smaller share when their
income is lower than the expected long-run level.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-591SP <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Saving</ENAMEX>
Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>, anticipating that their
incomes will increase over their careers, save little and may
borrow to finance current spending. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> in their peak earning
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> save to repay past borrowing and to accumulate assets for
retirement. The life-cycle model predicts that saving is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hump</ENAMEX>-shaped by age so that wealth accumulation peaks just before
retirement. Upon leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>, the elderly run down their
wealth-or "dissave." In saving for retirement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
theoretically take into account not only their expected retirement
age and the number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they expect to live in retirement but
also project their expected income, real returns on assets
accumulated, and inflation over their lifetime.
Although providing for retirement is a powerful motive for
saving, the life-cycle model in its simplest form cannot fully
explain how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> decide to save. Faced with the difficulty of
reconciling the standard life-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> with available empirical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have examined other motives that may help explain
saving behavior. While some evidence supports each motive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> do not have a unified theory that fully explains how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose to save<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.10</NUMEX> In general, the other major incentives or
reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> save are categorized as follows:



Precautionary saving motive. This is saving to protect
against unexpected expenses or possible emergencies, such as
unemployment or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>. In particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who face
greater uncertainty about their income and those who are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">risk-averse</ENAMEX> may tend to save more for a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">rainy day</TIMEX>." Precautionary
saving may be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over-and-</NUMEX>above basic life-cycle saving for
retirement. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may choose to save enough to maintain a
buffer-stock or contingency reserve during their early working
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and defer retirement saving until their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">40s</NUMEX> or
50s.11



Bequest saving motive. This is saving beyond basic
life-cycle saving for retirement. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may choose to save
more in order to bequeath the accumulated wealth to future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>. The desire to leave a bequest may explain why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> do not fully deplete their wealth and some even continue to
save during retirement. To some


10For a comprehensive review of personal saving literature, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Browning</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annamaria Lusardi</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Household Saving: Micro</ENAMEX>
Theories and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro Facts</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Economic Literature</ENAMEX>, Vol.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXXIV</ENAMEX>, No. 4 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1797-1855</TIMEX>.
11Christopher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Carroll</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Buffer-Stock Saving and the Life</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cycle/Permanent Income Hypothesis</ENAMEX>," Quarterly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Economics</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vol. CXII</ENAMEX>, No. 1 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1-56</NUMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-591SP <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Saving</ENAMEX>
extent, bequests may be unplanned and thus reflect unspent
retirement and precautionary saving.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON"></ENAMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big</ENAMEX> ticket" saving motive. This is relatively short-term
saving to accommodate a mismatch between current income and
expenses during the life-cycle. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> save to pay for
big-ticket items such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, other consumer durables, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vacations</ENAMEX>. Some must save in advance because they cannot borrow,
while others may prefer to save and avoid borrowing. Another big
ticket is the down payment to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> largely borrow
to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and later save by repaying their mortgages. Paying for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postsecondary</ENAMEX> education is a big ticket above and beyond life-cycle
saving for retirement.
Given that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> save for different purposes, increasing the
rate of return on saving does not necessarily motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
save more. A higher rate of return has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> opposing effects on
personal saving. On the one hand, a higher rate of return may
encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to save more because future spending becomes less
costly relative to spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>-the substitution effect. On the
other hand, given a higher rate of return, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to save less
now to finance a given level of future consumption. This reduced
incentive to save as real rates of return increase is called the
income effect<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> How <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> react to an increase in the rate of
return depends not only on their preferences about spending today
versus spending in the future but also on the real after-tax rate
of return-that is, the rate expected after taking into account
inflation and taxes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX>
Not everyone behaves like a life-cycle saver. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> plan
over shorter horizons-a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">few years</TIMEX> or even paycheck-to-paycheck.
Instead of trying to forecast lifetime income and economic
conditions in the distant future, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may use simple rules of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thumb</ENAMEX>, such as saving a fixed share of their income or avoiding
debt<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX> Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are "target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savers</ENAMEX>" who aim for a fixed level
of wealth or ratio of wealth to income in order to achieve
12Textbooks in microeconomics discuss these effects in detail.
For a brief summary of substitution and income effects, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Mankiw</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macroeconomics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4th Edition</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Worth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">446-447</ENAMEX>.

13See <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 4</ENAMEX> for a discussion of federal tax incentives for
personal saving.
14People can save for retirement using rules of thumb, such as
saving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a fixed</NUMEX> percentage of income in an employer-sponsored
retirement saving plan or saving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> each year in an individual
retirement account (IRA).
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>. Why Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Rate</ENAMEX>
Declined?
specific goals such as retirement, college education, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>,
or a vacation. Once target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savers</ENAMEX> reach their wealth target, they
may feel no need to save more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> may use mental
accounts-and even separate bank accounts-to earmark the money saved
for different uses. To ensure saving discipline, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may use
"contractual" or automatic mechanisms, such as payroll deductions,
to save. A mortgage is a key form of contractual saving in which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowner</ENAMEX>'s commitment to repay the principal borrowed compels
future saving.
Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have various theories to explain why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose to save, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do not save at all<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Low-income</ENAMEX>
and even some moderate-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> may feel that they are
unable to save. Others may be unwilling to save. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may be
impatient and they may discount the future so heavily that
retirement saving seems irrelevant compared to current
spending.
A1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>. No one is sure why the personal saving rate has declined.
Despite a great deal of study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have found no single
reason that convincingly explains the decline. Instead, research
points to a combination of factors that influence the personal
saving rate. These include-but are not limited to-demographics,
government programs for the elderly, credit availability, and
expectations about future income and wealth<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON"> Demographics</ENAMEX>. Under the basic life-cycle model, one would
expect that an increase in the elderly as a percentage of the total
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> would reduce the aggregate saving rate. However,
empirical research has found that saving has declined across most
age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. There is no
15For more information, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annamaria Lusardi</ENAMEX>, "Explaining Why
So Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Households</ENAMEX> Do Not Save," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working Paper</ENAMEX> Series <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00.1</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth College</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The University of Chicago</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>); and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annamaria Lusardi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Skinner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Venti</ENAMEX>, "Saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Puzzles and Saving Policies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working Paper</ENAMEX>
No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8237</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Bureau of Economic Research</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2001</TIMEX>).
16Martin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annamaria Lusardi</ENAMEX>, in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Household Saving:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro Theories and Micro Facts</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Economic Literature</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vol. XXXIV</ENAMEX>, No. 4 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1797-1855</TIMEX>, identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> possible
explanations offered for the decline in personal saving. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX>, in "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spendthrift</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>? On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two Decades</TIMEX> of Decline in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Saving Rate," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working Paper</ENAMEX> No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7238</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Bureau of Economic Research</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX>), examined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
possible explanations for the decline.
consensus that the aging of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> caused the
decline in the personal saving rate.



Programs for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare and Social Security</ENAMEX>
affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s incentives to save for their old age<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
may reduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>'s perceived needs for precautionary saving
to cover medical expenses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> can have opposing
effects on personal saving<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.18</NUMEX> On the one hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
benefits reduce the amount <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to save on their own for
retirement. On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> may induce personal
saving by encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to save for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> retirement-the
retirement effect. In a sense, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> makes retirement an
attainable goal and thus can prompt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to plan for
retirement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> may save more than they would have otherwise to
supplement their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits with additional
retirement income or because they want to retire before they are
eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> benefits. Nevertheless,
some evidence suggests that the existence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> may
have reduced personal saving, and numerous studies have attempted
to estimate the saving offset<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.19</NUMEX> However, given that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> was established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, it seems
unlikely that these programs were major contributors to the decline
in the personal saving rate over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s and 1990s</TIMEX>.



Credit availability. Improved access to credit reduces
the need to save before big-ticket purchases. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 20</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, credit cards have become widely available, and a smaller
down payment is needed to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. Easier access to credit may
have contributed somewhat to the saving decline. The ability to
borrow together with a rise in the number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-earner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
may have reduced the perceived need for precautionary
saving.


17Means-tested government programs, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, also may
affect the incentive to save. For example, requirements specifying
low levels of financial assets in order to qualify for government
benefits may discourage personal saving.
18Employer-sponsored pension plans also affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>'
incentives to save for retirement on their own. As noted above,
employer pension contributions as well as pension funds' interest
and dividend income are part of NIPA personal income and
saving.
19For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX>
Memorandum, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Private Saving: A Review of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Empirical Evidence</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1998</TIMEX>).
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is the Relationship Between</ENAMEX>
Personal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving and Wealth</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON"> Expectations</ENAMEX> about future income and wealth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> decide how
much to save based not only on their current income but also on
their expectations about their future lifetime income and wealth.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1991</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has enjoyed its longest postwar
economic expansion-unemployment and inflation have remained
relatively low and stable, and the stock market has achieved record
highs. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, the booming economy and stock market may
have lulled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into a sense of complacency that good times were
here to stay. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> may have saved less because they were
confident about future income prospects, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> were
wealthier because of gains on their existing assets. As discussed
below in question <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX>, increased household wealth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>
appears to have contributed to the plunge in the personal saving
rate over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX>.
A1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> save little but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are wealthier is
a paradox that can be confusing. It is widely known that saving
from current income is the way to accumulate assets and repay past
borrowing, thus increasing net worth. The flow of saving is
essential to accumulating a stock of wealth-as a general rule
someone who never saves will have no wealth<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conversely</ENAMEX>,
dissaving-spending more than current income-reduces the stock of
wealth because amounts saved in the past must be drawn down,
existing assets sold, or borrowing increased. Not only does saving
affect the stock of wealth, but wealth in turn influences the
choice to save.
Under the life-cycle model, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> save to accumulate assets to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> future consumption, and attaining their wealth-to-income
target depends in part on the rate of return anticipated. Assets
accumulated can generate income in the form of interest and
dividends that in turn may be saved. Moreover, the change in net
worth not only includes the saving flow from current income but
also reflects changes in the market value of assets accumulated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> generally agree that saving and wealth are
inversely related: increased wealth increases an individual's
ability to consume in the future and thus reduces the incentive to
save from current income. In other words, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' existing
assets increase in value, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less</NUMEX> from current income
and still achieve their wealth-income target. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>'
existing assets lose value, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to save more to attain
their wealth-income target. While the idea of wealth
20A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonsaver</ENAMEX> could get lucky and receive an inheritance or win
the lottery.
targets may seem abstract to the average household, increased
wealth clearly influences personal saving through traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defined-benefit</ENAMEX> pension plans. For example, gains on existing
assets reduce the amount of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s contribution necessary to
fund its pension liability.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> shows that even as the personal saving rate has
fallen, the ratio of aggregate household net worth to disposable
personal income ("the wealth-income ratio") has risen in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Over most of the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' wealth-income
ratio did not fluctuate widely from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year to year</TIMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1990s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' aggregate wealth ranged from a
high of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.3</NUMEX> times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' disposable income in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961 and 1996</TIMEX> to
a low of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.3</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' wealthincome ratio
has increased rapidly-peaking at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.4</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Although the surge in
household wealth contributed to the plunge in the personal saving
rate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> agree that increased wealth does
not fully explain the timing or magnitude of the decline over the
1980s and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990s</TIMEX>.
Personal saving percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household</ENAMEX> wealth to disposable
disposable personal income personal income ratio

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1960 1965 1970 1975 1980 1985 1990 1995 2000</ENAMEX>
Personal saving rate Household wealth-to-income ratio
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Economic Analysis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Commerce</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> analysis of Flow of Funds Accounts data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Board of Governors</ENAMEX>.
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, aggregate household net worth doubled in nominal
terms. Moreover, the mix of assets held by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> has
changed dramatically. Traditionally, real estate has represented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' largest asset; while the total value of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>'
real estate holdings grew by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, real estate
steadily declined as a share of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' total assets from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, the total value
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' stock holdings grew more than fourfold over the
1990s, and stocks as a share of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' total assets increased
from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28 percent</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1999.21</NUMEX>
As figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> shows, household wealth accumulation has swelled
relative to disposable personal income even as the flow of saving
from current income has dwindled. Recent research estimated that
the growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' aggregate net worth over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> and
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX> was roughly equally divided between
traditional saving and the increase in the nominal value of
existing assets. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s and 1980s</TIMEX>, the increase in the
nominal value of existing assets was estimated to be about twice as
large as the flow from saving<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.22</NUMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, nominal gains on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' assets-particularly financial assets-have dwarfed the
saving flow. For example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, even though personal saving was
less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 billion</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' wealth still grew by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trillion</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX>).
As <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> learned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> when the stock market declined from
its peak value, what goes up can come down. Aggregate household
wealth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> declined for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since data were
available in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. According to the latest estimates, personal
saving in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> was -<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.5 billion</NUMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' wealth declined
by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $842 billion</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>) largely as a result of the drop
in the market value of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' stock holdings. The total value
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' stock holdings declined by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 18 percent</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, and stocks as a share of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' total assets declined to
less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Households</ENAMEX>' wealth-income ratio dropped from
its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> peak of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.4</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5.9</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> but remains relatively high compared to the
1960s through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1990s</TIMEX>.
The basic life-cycle model of saving holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
trying to smooth their standard of living over their lifetime.
Therefore, life-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savers</ENAMEX>
21Households hold stocks directly as well as indirectly through
mutual funds, pension funds, life <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>, and trusts.
22William <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Gale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sabelhaus</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perspectives</ENAMEX> on the
Household Saving Rate," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Papers</ENAMEX> on Economic Activity
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1999</ENAMEX>), pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">181-224</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-591SP <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Saving</ENAMEX>
would not treat gains on existing assets as a windfall to spend
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The theory predicts that anticipated wealth changes would
not affect planned lifetime spending. Likewise, changes in wealth
perceived to be temporary due to fluctuating market values of
assets would not affect planned spending. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can
respond to an unexpected increase in wealth that they think will be
permanent by spending more of their current income. This change in
spending in response to a change in wealth is called the wealth
effect. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may tap their wealth by selling stocks or
borrowing against their home equity to boost current consumption.
The wealth effect can also work in the opposite direction. A
dramatic drop in household wealth-for example, due to an extended
downturn in the stock market-could eventually dampen household
consumption and lead to an increase in saving.
The increase in spending at any one time due to the wealth
effect would be expected to be small, given a life-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">saver</ENAMEX>'s
tendency to spread consumption of a significant change in wealth
over time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> estimate that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">each dollar</NUMEX> in increased
wealth increases consumption by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few cents</NUMEX>. Estimates of the
wealth effect range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 to 7 cents</NUMEX>, and the typical estimate is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 3</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 cents</NUMEX>. A recent study estimated that a wealth effect
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3 to 4 cents</NUMEX> could explain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fifths to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of the
decline in the personal saving rate since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1988.23</NUMEX>
23Annamaria <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lusardi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Skinner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Venti</ENAMEX>, "Saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Puzzles and Saving Policies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working Paper</ENAMEX>
No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8237</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Bureau of Economic Research</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2001</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-591SP <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Saving</ENAMEX>
Q1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Household Wealth Has Increased</ENAMEX>,
Does It Matter if the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Saving Rate Has Declined</ENAMEX>?
A1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>. With the personal saving rate around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> or negative,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have questioned the relevance of the NIPA personal
saving measure<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.24</NUMEX> Wealth measures, which reflect the value of
existing assets based on current market conditions, show a
fundamentally different trend, as illustrated in figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2.25</NUMEX>
Although these supplementary measures may explain why individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> may choose to save less, the NIPA personal saving rate
shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are consuming virtually all of their current
income and saving little for the future.
In evaluating the level of personal saving, it is important to
distinguish between saving as a source to finance the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
capital formation and saving as a way for individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> future consumption. A key difference between measuring the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s saving and gauging a household's finances is the treatment
of changes in the market value of existing assets. As discussed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 2</ENAMEX>, it is saving from current income-not gains on existing
assets-that is key to financing capital investment and increasing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capacity to produce goods and services. Although an
individual household can tap the increased value of its assets to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> additional consumption or accumulate other assets by
selling an asset to another household, the transaction itself
shifts ownership of the existing asset and does not generate new
economic output. Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> as a whole may not be able to
consume and invest more<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moreover</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> may not be able
to simultaneously tap their apparent wealth to finance consumption
because large-scale asset sales could tend to depress market
values.
24To some extent, spending wealth-like spending income-drives
down the reported personal saving rate. As discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Q1.1</ENAMEX>,
realized gains do not count as personal income, but any taxes paid
on such gains reduce disposable personal income and thus saving. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> then spend a portion of their realized gains, this
spending further reduces the saving residual and the saving
rate.
25For alternative measures including changes in the market value
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' existing assets, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William G. Gale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Sabelhaus, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perspectives on the Household Saving Rate</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX>
