



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2001</TIMEX>
STRATEGIES TO MANAGE IMPROPER PAYMENTS



Learning From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public and Private Sector Organizations</ENAMEX>
a

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-69G
Preface
complex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the world-expended <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $1.8</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion dollars</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>. As the steward of taxpayer
dollars, it is accountable for how its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and grantees spend
those funds, and is responsible for safeguarding against improper
payments-payments that should not have been made or that were made
for incorrect amounts.
Despite the amount of funds involved and the impact improper
payments can have on a program's ability to achieve its intended
outcome, most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have not yet estimated the magnitude of
improper payments in their programs. Without a systematic
measurement of the extent of the problem, agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> cannot
determine (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) if the problem is significant enough to require
corrective action, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) how much to costeffectively invest in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> control systems to correct the problem, or
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the impact of the actions already taken to reduce improper
payments or additional corrective actions needed.
This executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> is intended to identify effective practices
and provide case illustrations and other information for federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' consideration when developing strategies and planning and
implementing actions to manage improper payments in their programs.
It was prepared at the request of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph I. Lieberman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Committee on Governmental Affairs</ENAMEX>. This is one in
a series of projects we are undertaking for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Committee on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmental Affairs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Committee on Government Reform</ENAMEX>
concerning the issue of improper payments involving federal
programs.
In producing this guide, we contacted a number of private and
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector organizations</ENAMEX>, which we identified primarily through
extensive research on financial management practices, and obtained
information on actions that they took and considered effective in
reducing improper payments. 
1The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Services</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Financing Administration</ENAMEX>; 
2the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Administration</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>; the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> private sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. 
3We thank them for their willingness to participate
and for the valuable information and insights they provided.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
For a more detailed discussion of our objectives, scope, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">methodology</ENAMEX>, see appendix <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
For a description of each of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, see appendix
II.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Page 1 GAO-02-69G Improper Payments</ENAMEX>
This executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> was prepared under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
Calbom, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Management and Assurance</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
contacts and key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> are listed in appendix <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>. Questions
can be directed to Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calbom</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-9508,</ENAMEX> 
calboml@<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gao</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>,or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Broderick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Director</ENAMEX>,
by phone, e-mail, or regular mail at the following:
Phone: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8705</ENAMEX>
E-mail: 
broderickt@<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gao</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>
Mail: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Broderick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Director</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">441</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">G Street</ENAMEX>, NW <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20548</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey C. Steinhoff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Management</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assurance</ENAMEX>
Contents
Preface
Introduction

Observations

Abbreviations





Introduction
Improper payments are a widespread and significant problem
receiving increased attention not only in the federal government
but also among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, and private sector
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Improper payments include inadvertent errors, such as
duplicate payments and miscalculations; payments for unsupported or
inadequately supported claims; payments for services not rendered;
payments to ineligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>; and payments resulting from
outright fraud and abuse by program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> and/or federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. In the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, for example, they occur in a
variety of programs and activities, including those related to
contractors and contract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>; health care programs, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>; financial assistance benefits, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>
Stamps and housing subsidies; and tax refunds.
While in the private sector improper payments most often present
an internal problem that threatens profitability, in the public
sector they can translate into serving fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> or
represent wasteful spending or a higher relative tax burden that
prompts questions and criticism from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. For federal programs with legislative or regulatory
eligibility criteria, improper payments indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are
spending more than necessary to meet program goals. Conversely, for
programs with fixed funds, any waste of federal funds translates
into serving fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> or accomplishing less
programmatically than could be expected.
Despite a climate of increased scrutiny, most improper payments
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with federal programs continue to go unidentified as
they drain taxpayer resources away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> and goals of
our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. They occur for many reasons including insufficient
oversight or monitoring, inadequate eligibility controls, and
automated system deficiencies. However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point is clear based on
our study-the basic or root causes of improper payments can
typically be traced to a lack of or breakdown in internal control.
Collectively, internal controls are an integral component of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>'s management that provides reasonable assurance that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> achieves its objectives of


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
effective and efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) reliable
financial reporting, and


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
compliance with laws and regulations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal</ENAMEX> controls
are not one event, but a series of actions and activities that
occur throughout an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>'s operations and on an ongoing basis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> make internal controls work, and responsibility for good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> controls rests with all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>.


The risk of improper payments increases in programs with (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
complex criteria for computing payments, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a significant volume
of transactions, or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) emphasis on expediting payments. Since
these factors apply to a number of government programs that
collectively disburse <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>, there is clearly a need
for federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to be ever more vigilant in the design,
implementation, and maintenance of proper controls for safeguarding
assets and preventing and detecting fraud and errors.
The risk of improper payments and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s ability to
prevent them will continue to be of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> in the future. Under
current federal budget policies, as the baby boom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> leaves
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>, spending pressures will grow rapidly due to
increased costs of programs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>. Other federal expenditures are also likely to increase.
The increased size of federal programs, spending pressures,
implementation of new programs, and changes in existing programs
all but guarantee that, absent improvements in internal controls
and other proactive actions, the potential for additional or larger
volumes of improper payments will be present. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> illustrates
the reported and projected trends in certain federal expenditures,
excluding interest on the public debt, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal years 1980</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trends in Certain Actual</ENAMEX> and Projected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Expenditures: Fiscal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years 1980 Through 2006</TIMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1980 1982 1984 1986 1988 1990 1992 1994 1996 1998 2000 2002</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004 2006 Fiscal year</TIMEX>

Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Medicare Medicaid</ENAMEX>
Source: Actual and projected amounts are from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Government</ENAMEX>, Fiscal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year 2002, Historical Tables</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Management</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Agenda</ENAMEX>, Fiscal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2002</TIMEX>, includes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governmentwide</ENAMEX> initiative for improved financial performance. Under
this initiative, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> will establish a baseline of
the extent of erroneous payments and require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to include,
in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2003</TIMEX> budget submissions, information on
erroneous payment rates, including actual and target rates, where
available, for benefit and assistance programs over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX>.
Using this information, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> will
work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to establish goals to reduce erroneous payments
for each program.
Few would argue that the goal of reducing improper payments is
not a worthy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. But attacking the problem requires a strategy
appropriate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> involved and its particular risks,
including a consideration of the legal requirements surrounding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> and privacy issues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that participated in
our study have taken actions that they consider to be effective in
reducing potential as well as actual improper payments.
All of these actions shared a common focus of improving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> control systems over the problem area. This focus on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> controls does not necessarily mean that the programs
lacked controls but that the existing controls needed to be updated
or policies and procedures added to strengthen the overall control
system.
In this executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>, we highlight many of the strategic
actions taken by the study participants 
4to reduce improper payments. We categorize these
actions into the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> components of internal control-control
environment, risk assessment, control activities, information and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX>, and monitoring-outlined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General's Standards</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Control</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Government</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-AIMD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21.3.1</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>). 
5For purposes of this study, we define these
components as follows.


●
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> environment-creating a culture of accountability
by establishing a positive and supportive attitude toward
improvement and the achievement of established program
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX>.


●
Risk assessment-performing comprehensive reviews and
analyses of program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> to determine if risks exist and the
nature and extent of the risks identified.


●
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> activities-taking actions to address identified
risk areas and help ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s decisions and plans
are carried out and program objectives are met.


●
Information and communications-using and sharing
relevant, reliable, and timely financial and nonfinancial
information in managing improper payment related
activities.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
The examples we have included from these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are meant
only to illustrate the range and variety of internal controls that
may be useful to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. They are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">all-inclusive</ENAMEX> and may not include the specific controls that a
particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> may need.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Managers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Financial Integrity Act of 1982</ENAMEX> required
that we issue standards for internal control in the federal
government.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">● Monitoring</ENAMEX>-tracking improvement initiatives, over time, and
identifying additional actions needed to further improve program
efficiency and effectiveness.
Although these internal control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> are applicable to the
entirety of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s operations, 
6this executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> focuses on internal controls as
they relate to reducing improper payments. The following graphic
represents the interrelationship between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> and efforts
to manage improper payments.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Managing Improper Payments Through Internal</ENAMEX>
Controls

While this guide discusses each of these control areas
separately, actions to manage improper payments would typically
require a continual interaction between these areas. As depicted in
the figure, the control environment surrounds and reinforces the
other components, but all components work in concert toward a
central objective, which, in this case, is managing improper
payments.
We conclude our discussion of the actions taken to address
improper payments with observations about key factors necessary for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>. We have included descriptions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> we visited
in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">appendix</ENAMEX> II. Also, appendix <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> identifies other sources of
information that may be useful to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in their efforts
to address improper payments in their programs.
6See also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Control Management and Evaluation Tool</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1008G</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>). The purpose of this tool is to assist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in maintaining or implementing effective internal control
and, as needed, to help determine what, where, and how improvements
can be implemented.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Environment</ENAMEX>: Instilling a Culture
of Accountability
-Changes madein <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> might not have happened if the legislature
hadn't become involved. Regulations should not be seen as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roadblocks</ENAMEX>, but as support orbacking to achieve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Holcomb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems Resources</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Investigations and Enforcement</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>
Commission
Of the elements that are critical to the identification,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, and implementation of activities to reduce improper
payments, perhaps the most significant is the control environment.
By focusing their attention on and communicating their intent to
reduce improper payments throughout an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and to all
affected organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, top-level
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>-whether in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or within private sector
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>-and legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> set the stage for change. They
instill a culture of accountability by adopting a positive and
supportive attitude toward improvement and the achievement of
established program outcomes. They also establish a transparent
environment in which their expectations for program improvement are
clearly defined and accountability for achieving these improvements
is set. The actions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in our study in areas including
passing legislation, setting and maintaining the ethical tone,
delegating roles and responsibilities, and implementing human
capital initiatives clearly communicated the need for change.

We were told by many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> we met in the course of
our work that, without the clearly established expectations and
demands for improvement by top management and legislative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, little would have happened to effectively reduce fraud
and errors in their programs. However, it is important to note
that, while top management sets the tone for cultural change,
everyone from program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> performing day-to-day
operational activities must buy into this change and work to
achieve its overall goals. The cultural change fostered by an
effective control environment stresses the importance of
improvement and efficient and effective program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, while
maintaining a balance with concerns raised regarding privacy and
information security in a world where computers and electronic data
are indispensable for making payments. In the legislative arena, it
involved passing laws requiring certain actions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, the use of various prevention and/or detection
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">methodologies</ENAMEX>, and periodic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> reporting on the status of
improvement efforts. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or program level, it included
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s public commitment to reduce fraud and errors, as
-There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways to stop fraud-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> is to lock up
everythingaround you, andthe other is to surround yourself with
ethical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Linton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Certified Fraud Examiner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Advisor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fraud</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention and Investigation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland Revenue</ENAMEX>
Department
well as annual performance reporting and follow-up actions based
on performance results.
Top-level interest in the amount of improper payments at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> that participated in our study often resulted from
program, audit, and/or media reports of misspent funds or
fraudulent activities. As the magnitude of these improper payments
became known, pressures increased on government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and
legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> to reduce them.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> was instrumental in effecting changes
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s benefit programs through provisions in several
pieces of legislation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>'s involvement was
precipitated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> by the reported amounts of improper payments
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> program (estimated to range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$365 million</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$730 million</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 to 8 percent</NUMEX> of total expenditures) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</ENAMEX> (TANF) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Stamp</ENAMEX>
programs (estimated at a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$222.4 million</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 8</NUMEX>
percent of total expenditures for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> sought to reduce improper payments by mandating specific
actions by responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, including the use of computer
technology to identify and deter fraud and abuse in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> program. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> called for publicizing
successful fraud prosecutions and fraud prevention programs to
deter benefit fraud.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Zealand</ENAMEX> prepared and adopted a joint standard 
7on "risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>," to provide a cultural framework
for managing risk. Risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> is the term applied to a logical
and systematic method of managing risks associated with any
activity, function, or process in a way that will enable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> to minimize losses and maximize opportunities. The
philosophy makes risk management a part of its organizational
culture and integrates risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> into its day-to-day
practices and business activities. When this is achieved, risk
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> becomes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of everyone in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are what make internal controls work, and the integrity
and ethical values maintained and demonstrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> play a
key role in the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s ethical tone. After the
identification of significant internal fraud, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland</ENAMEX>
Revenue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> (IRD) created the position of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Advisor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraud Prevention and Investigation</ENAMEX>, and adopted a fraud control
strategy. The primary aim of the strategy is to enable responsible
conduct, where the need to obey the law and to behave ethically is
part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s ethos. Accordingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRD</ENAMEX> has adopted a
code of conduct applicable to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that explains the
standards of integrity and behavior expected.
In the experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Advisor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraud Prevention</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investigation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are often provided a copy of the code
of conduct
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Australian/New Zealand Standard</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4360</TIMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> was prepared by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Technical Committee</ENAMEX> OB<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/7</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risk Management</ENAMEX>. It was approved
on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Standards Australia</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2, 1999</TIMEX>,
and on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Standards New Zealand</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. It was published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12, 1999</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Referenced</ENAMEX> material is
from pages iii and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of the standard.
-Good customer service is accurate customer service. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">timeliness</ENAMEX> is important, quality and accuracy aremore important and
will ultimately improve timeliness anyway."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Vardon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Executive Officer</ENAMEX>, Centrelink
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their first day</TIMEX> of work, along with a large volume of other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paperwork</ENAMEX>, and never actually read the code unless the code is
breached. To heighten employee awareness, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRD</ENAMEX> holds roundtable
discussions with new and seasoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, which bring the code
to life in terms of everyday business activity.
While many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have programs to deter and detect
fraudulent payments, improper payments resulting from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miscalculation</ENAMEX> and other errors often receive inadequate attention.
Centrelink, a "one-stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>" that pays a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
government benefits, has recently made it its business to improve
payment accuracy. Centrelink was established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> with a strong
focus on customer service and the goal of paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>
promptly. However, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, internal and external audit
reports showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centrelink</ENAMEX> had, to some extent, traded quality
for timeliness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centrelink</ENAMEX>'s own internal review showed that up to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> of all work was rework because it was not done correctly
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> responded by
implementing a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Getting it Right</ENAMEX>" strategy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, which
established a tone for change by setting out


●
the roles and responsibilities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and team
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, including setting clear and measurable goals in line with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centrelink</ENAMEX>'s strategic framework and meeting performance measures,
and


●
minimum standards to be applied by all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in
establishing proof of identity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, managing records,
keeping technical knowledge and skills current, recording reasons
for payment decisions, and checking work
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comprehensively</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centrelink</ENAMEX> has distributed posters and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> pads to reinforce
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Getting it Right</ENAMEX>" message and has provided resources to staff
on how to reach minimum standards. Through implementation of the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Getting it Right</ENAMEX>" strategy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centrelink</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Executive Officer</ENAMEX>
has stated that she expects a reduction in improper payments as
well as continued timeliness in payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>.
Activities that must be undertaken for each program, to ensure the
quality of assessment and services provided, are being developed. A
number have already been released for implementation in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centrelink's Customer Service Centre</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2001</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Social Security</ENAMEX> was renamed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Work and Pensions</ENAMEX> (DWP).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
Amounts included in this report have been converted to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
dollars using the following exchange rates, effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one U.S. dollar</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.697064</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> pounds, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.95665</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> dollars, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.43533 New Zealand dollars</NUMEX>.


●
Putting it Right-detecting when payments go wrong and
taking prompt action to correct them with appropriate penalties to
prevent recurrence, and


●
Making Sure Our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Strategy Works-</ENAMEX>monitoring progress,
evaluating the strength of controls, and making adjustments where
needed.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWP</ENAMEX>'s strategy also established performance measures for the
reduction of the amount of losses from fraud and error in the
Income Support and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Jobseeker's Allowance</ENAMEX> benefit programs.
To kick off its new program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWP</ENAMEX> launched a publicity campaign
against "benefit cheats" to shift public attitude and promote
intolerance toward those who defraud the benefit system.
Additionally, television commercials, billboards, newspaper
articles, and an antifraud Web site ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">targetingfraud</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gov.uk</ENAMEX>)communicated the
government's message to the public that fraud and abuse of the
benefits system would not be tolerated.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> has also stayed actively involved in benefit payment
reform and improper payment reductions. For example, it enacted
legislation authorizing data sharing activities within and between
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>. Also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> requires
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX> to disclose instances of irregular expenditures arising
from erroneous benefit awards and fraud by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX>. Further, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller and Auditor General</ENAMEX> has qualified his opinion on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWP</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1995 through fiscal year 2000</TIMEX> financial statements
because of the level of fraud and error identified in the benefit
programs. This served to reinforce the message that high levels of
improper payments are unacceptable in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>.
Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> we studied, the pressures applied by
oversight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> and top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> were instrumental as change
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. They not only defined and communicated a need for improved
program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> but, most important, they redefined the
organizational culture. Further, by being transparent in redefining
the culture, oversight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> and top management set expectations
and obtained buy-in on the need for and importance of change from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. This was critical for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> since these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> managed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> program
activities. Further, a culture of accountability was essential to
begin the critical next step in managing improper payments, the
risk assessment process.

Strategies to Consider-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Environment</ENAMEX>
To create a control environment that instills a culture of
accountability over improper payments, the following strategies
should be considered:


●
provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in setting and maintaining the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s ethical code of conduct and in ensuring proper behavior
under the code;


●
provide a cultural framework for managing risk by
engaging everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the risk management
process;


●
increase accountability by establishing goals for
reducing improper payments for major programs; and


●
foster an atmosphere that regards improper payments as
unacceptable.





Risk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Determining the Nature</ENAMEX>
and Extent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Problem</ENAMEX>
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the worst problems an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> confronts is the
problem of institutional denial. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> should not simply
say, "We know we have a problem, but we don't want to know how big
it is.'"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurora LeBrun</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate Commissioner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Investigations</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enforcement</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services Commission</ENAMEX>
Strong systems of internal control provide reasonable assurance
that programs are operating as intended and are achieving expected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX>. A key step in the process of gaining this assurance is
conducting a risk assessment, an activity that entails a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> review and analysis of program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> to
determine where risks exist and what those risks are, and then
measuring the potential or actual impact of those risks on program
operations. In performing a risk assessment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> should
consider all significant interactions between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, as well as all internal factors at both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizationwide</ENAMEX> and program levels. Once risk areas are
identified, their potential impact on programs and activities
should be measured and additional controls should be considered. As
risks are addressed and controls are changed, they should
occasionally be revisited to determine where the risks have
decreased and where new areas of risk may exist. As such, the risk
assessment process should be iterative.

The information developed during a risk assessment forms the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> or basis upon which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> can determine the nature
and type of corrective actions needed, and it gives management
baseline information for measuring progress in reducing improper
payments. The specific risk analysis methodology used can vary by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> because of differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> and the difficulty
in qualitatively and quantitatively assigning risk levels. In
addition, because governmental, economic, industry, regulatory, and
operating conditions continually change, risk assessments should be
periodically updated to identify and deal with any special risks
prompted by such changes.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that participated in our study found that
conducting risk assessments, to determine the nature and extent of
their improper payments, was an essential step in helping them
focus on the most significant problem areas and determine what
needed to be done to address the identified risks in those
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>.
Many federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, even those with recognized weaknesses
that result in improper payments, do not perform risk assessments
to identify and estimate the magnitude of improper payments within
their programs.
However, some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> do perform risk assessments. For example,
an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> estimate of improper payments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
Fee-for-Service program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, it reported
estimated improper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Fee-for-Service</ENAMEX> payments of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.9</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 7 percent</NUMEX> of such benefits. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>' reporting and
analysis of improper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> payments has helped lead to the
implementation of several initiatives to identify and reduce such
payments. These initiatives include working with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> to
ensure that medical records support billed services.
A thorough risk assessment also allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> to target
high-risk areas and, therefore, to focus often limited resources
where the greatest exposure exists. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Aid</ENAMEX> (IDPA) conducted a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> comparison of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> payments made with information and documentation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the claims to determine if the payments were
accurate. From this information, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA</ENAMEX> calculated that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s payment accuracy rate was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 95 percent</NUMEX>. The review
identified errors and their causes and provided IDPA with
information that allowed it to focus attention on the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of
inaccurate payments and target strategies to improve the accuracy
of these payments. For example, of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37.2 million</NUMEX> spent for
nonemergency transportation services included in the study, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.55</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 percent</NUMEX>) were estimated to be in error. The payment
accuracy review and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other studies led to a series of actions
that included assuring that transportation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> actually
existed and were providing services, assuring that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> billed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> correctly, and sending notices to let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> know what
is expected of them.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two</TIMEX> reviews of the accuracy of its health
care payments-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1998</TIMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>.
Both reviews of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> program were designed to measure the
incidence of potential overpayments that could be due to fraud and
abuse. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> study used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different types of analyses-client
telephone interviews, data analysis (identifying billing trends
that are known to result in overpayments), and medical record
review. Documentation errors, clerical errors, and potential fraud
and abuse were identified. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> used the results to improve its
fraud and abuse detection process by considering certain high-risk
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> in the development of data analysis techniques in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid Fraud</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Abuse Detection System</ENAMEX> (MFADS). For example, it
recommended an increase in analyses targeted at medical supplies
and durable medical equipment and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> who bill higher cost
procedure codes to maximize their reimbursement.
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> found the first-time payment accuracy
review to be expensive-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000 and $400,000</NUMEX> in direct costs,
respectively. However, both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> recognized that the cost of risk
assessments would decrease after the baseline measurement had been
determined, and found them to be cost-beneficial in light of the
ability to focus on high-risk areas. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources</ENAMEX> are maximized when
strategically aimed at the areas that need the most improvement.
Thus, they regarded the payment accuracy review as an effective and
cost-beneficial way to combat improper payments.
Government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> also use payment accuracy
reviews to identify risk areas. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> uses the results of a rolling
program of reviews to determine the levels of fraud and error in
its Income Support and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Jobseeker's Allowance</ENAMEX> benefit programs.
Specifically, these reviews quantify the amount of fraud, customer
error, and official error (error by government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>) affecting
benefit claims. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uses the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1997</TIMEX> through
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1998</TIMEX> review results as a baseline against which the
results of subsequent reviews are measured. Further, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWP</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> plans to use this information to target areas for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prevention</ENAMEX> and detection in the benefit programs, to identify
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> who are at risk for higher levels of error in their
claims, and to facilitate case interventions.


"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> activities will not be fully effective until everyone,
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on the counter through to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>,
takes responsibility for managing risk from the perspective of
their respective positions."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Watzlaff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Review Division</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Insurance Commission</ENAMEX>
In our study of activities to reduce improper payments, risk
assessments identified problem areas and resulted in estimates of
monetary values associated with the problems. Thus, the process of
doing risk assessments was essential for evaluating the feasibility
and cost-effectiveness of the various corrective actions
considered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> viewed risk assessments as
opportunity, and identified risk areas were communicated throughout
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.
Assessing its risks allows an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to set goals and
target its efforts to reduce improper payments. Having developed
such a framework, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is well positioned to determine
which control activities to implement to reduce risks and
ultimately reduce fraud and errors.

Strategies to Consider-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risk Assessment</ENAMEX>
To assess risk by determining the nature and extent of improper
payments, the following strategies should be considered:


●
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institute</ENAMEX> a systematic process to estimate the level of
improper payments being made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>;


●
based on this process, determine where risks exist, what
those risks are, and the potential or actual impact of those risks
on program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>;


●
use risk assessment results to target high-risk areas and
focus resources where the greatest exposure exists; and


●
reassess risks on a recurring basis to evaluate the
impact of changing conditions, both external and internal, on
program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>.





<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Activities</ENAMEX>: Taking Action to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Address Identified Risk Areas</ENAMEX>
-There are no brownie points for just talking about the
problem."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan McQuay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Benefit Control</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Debt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Work</ENAMEX> and
Income <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>
Once an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has identified areas of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> that
are at risk and quantified the possible extent of the risk, and its
management and other key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are committed to and have set a
goal for reducing the risk, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> must take action to
achieve that goal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> activities are the policies, procedures,
techniques, and mechanisms that are designed to help ensure that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s decisions and plans are carried out. They include
activities designed to address risks that lead to fraud and error.
They are an integral part of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s actions in planning,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">implementing</ENAMEX>, reviewing, and achieving effective results.

The control activities used by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to address
improper payments vary according to the specific threats faced and
risks incurred; differences in objectives; managerial judgment;
size and complexity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>; operational environment;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensitivity</ENAMEX> and value of data; and requirements for system
comply with all relevant laws and help strike a balance between the
sometimes competing goals of privacy and program integrity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>
activities can include both prepayment and postpayment mechanisms
to manage improper payments. Given the large volume and complexity
of federal payments and historically low recovery rates for certain
programs, it is generally most efficient to pay bills and provide
benefits properly in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. Aside from minimizing
overpayments, proactively preventing improper payments increases
public confidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of benefit programs and
avoids the difficulties associated with the "pay and chase" 
10aspects of recovering improper payments. However,
recognizing that some overpayments are inevitable, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> also
need to adopt effective detection techniques to quickly identify
and recover them. Detection activities play a significant role not
only in identifying improper payments, but also in providing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10"Pay and chase</ENAMEX>" refers to the labor-intensive and
time-consuming practice of trying to recover overpayments once they
have already been made rather than preventing improper payments in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.
on why these payments were made and, in turn, highlighting areas
that need strengthened prevention controls.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in our study used many different prevention
and detection control activities to manage improper payments. The
nature of these activities ranged from sophisticated computer
analyses of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> and program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> data to postaward
contract audits. The kinds of activities pursued were dictated by
the types of payment activities each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> had identified as
presenting the most significant risk of improper payments as well
as the kind of data and other resources that were available to the
entity in this effort. This guide discusses the following <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> kinds
of control activities:


●
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> sharing,


●
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> mining,


●
neural networking,


●
recovery auditing,


●
contract audits, and


●
prepayment investigations.


The data sharing, data mining, and neural networking techniques
discussed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> are powerful internal control tools that
provide more useful and timely access to information. The use of
these techniques can achieve potentially significant savings by
identifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>-related reporting errors and misinformation
during the eligibility determination process-before payments are
made-or by detecting improper payments that have been made.
However, the more extensive use of personal information in an
evolving technological environment raises new questions about
privacy and how it should be protected. In the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>, such
activities must be implemented consistent with all protections of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Privacy Act of 1974</ENAMEX>, as amended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Matching</ENAMEX> and
Privacy <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Protection Act of 1988</ENAMEX>, and other privacy statutes.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> sharing allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that make payments-to
contractors, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in benefit programs-to
compare information from different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to help ensure that
payments are appropriate. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government agencies</ENAMEX>, data sharing can
be particularly useful in confirming initial or continuing
eligibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in benefit programs and in identifying
improper payments that have already been made. 
11
A form of data sharing that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has found to be effective for
determining the initial eligibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Stamp</ENAMEX>
benefits puts information from several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
in
11See also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benefit and Loan Programs</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Improved Data Sharing</ENAMEX>
Could <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enhance Program Integrity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/HEHS-00-119</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 13</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>).
the hands of state caseworkers by means of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX>-provided
software program. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> maintains public information, such as
that recorded by local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> or municipal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, where it can be easily searched by caseworkers to evaluate
information provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> applying for benefits. Using
the software, caseworkers can target questions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> when
there are discrepancies between information provided by the clients
and that recorded elsewhere. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caseworkers</ENAMEX> can search the database
for data such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license information, records showing the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' reported
addresses, telephone numbers, vehicle values, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and motor files,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> convictions, marriage/divorce records, and consumer credit
reports. Then, for example, if the data search shows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> at an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applicant</ENAMEX>'s address when the benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> has reported only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, the caseworker can, at the time of the benefit application,
question the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> concerning this discrepancy. Generally, this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">query</ENAMEX> information is treated only as a "case clue" and must be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">verified</ENAMEX>. The database contains reporting options that allow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supervisors</ENAMEX> to monitor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' use of the system to ensure that
all queries are appropriate-in addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s internal
auditor monitors the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>'s use of the database.
Beyond determining initial eligibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in
benefit programs, data sharing can also be used to identify
improper payments that have already been made. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> sharing allows
a flow of information in two directions, which is particularly
helpful to some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in managing improper payments. For
example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Administration</ENAMEX> (SSA) obtains death
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to determine if deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are
receiving benefit checks. At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> provides data to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Among the data it shares is notification
of whether there is a valid social security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> to confirm the
eligibility of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> for various state or federal benefit
programs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of information allows data matches to take
place, a process in which information from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> is compared
with information from another to identify any inconsistencies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>
matches of social security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers</ENAMEX> and other data can help
determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> are receiving payments
inappropriately or under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> name or address.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> performs over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> data matches with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 10</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 3,500</NUMEX> state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> using incoming
information. Additionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> shares outgoing information with
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 15</NUMEX> matches. For example, SSA
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>) so it can perform a match to verify the identity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of housing benefits and identify potentially fraudulent
claims. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> uses data matches to prevent and detect improper
payments in its programs. It estimates that it saves <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350 million</NUMEX>
annually for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Age</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Survivors Insurance and Disability</ENAMEX>
Insurance, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$325 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental Security</ENAMEX>
Income through the use of data matching. Further, the savings are
not limited to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> data matches save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX> for other governmentagencies
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>.
those realized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX>, its matches save
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX> each year for other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. 
12
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> matches to identify improper payments can be performed
periodically (i.e., <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX>) or on an ad hoc
basis, using various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of data to reconfirm eligibility of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> and accuracy of payments. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> conducts both
periodic and ad hoc matches using data including


●
prisoner information obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Department</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminal Justice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prisoner Verification System</ENAMEX> (to
determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> are receiving benefits to which they
are not entitled),


●
deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> lists obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Bureau of Vital Statistics</ENAMEX> (to determine
whether benefits are being paid to such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>),
and


●
income information obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Employees</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retirement System</ENAMEX> (to check retiree income for amounts that affect
the level of benefit eligibility).


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> also shares data with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of its bordering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to
determine duplicity of benefits, which, for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, has
resulted in an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">337</NUMEX> potential duplicates per <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> per
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, after researching potential duplicate
payments, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> denied or decreased benefits in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">656</NUMEX> cases,
resulting in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $578,000</NUMEX> in benefits saved.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> performs data matches to determine eligibility for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stamps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> benefits using an integrated automated
system that lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caseworkers</ENAMEX> determine eligibility for the three
programs simultaneously. At the time the application is entered
into the system, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> performs several matches to obtain
additional information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> and prevent duplicate
participation. These matches are made through its income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eligibility</ENAMEX> and verification system using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>'s social
security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX>, name, date of birth, any previous disqualification
record from assistance programs, and income. In addition, on a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> basis, other matches are conducted. The state matches data
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Crime Information Center</ENAMEX> to check for fleeing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">felons</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> to determine if any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> or have
died, and with assistance programs in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to check for
client disqualification. In addition, matches with unemployment and
state wages records are done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>. When these matches result in
information that could require changes in benefits, the matches
appear on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> case status reports, alerting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caseworkers</ENAMEX> to
potential changes in benefits.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> formalized data matching between government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, and it reported that, through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX>, it
had realized benefit savings of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $450 million</NUMEX>. From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1999</TIMEX>
through
12
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SSA</ENAMEX> calculates the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> savings based on a compilation of
cost-benefit analyses performed by the matching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> under the
terms of their matching agreements with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX>, matches identified about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217,000</NUMEX> inconsistencies for further investigation, and resulted in
an overall benefit saving of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $53 million</NUMEX>. Additionally,
legislation has now been passed to enable the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to obtain
financial information from the private sector in certain
circumstances.
The prevalence of data sharing is evidence of the value provided
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> when they can obtain and use data from sources external
to an individual program's systems. Having the two streams of data
allows for matches to occur and inconsistencies or anomalies to be
flagged for further research. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> contemplating data
Computer <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Matching and Privacy Protection Act</ENAMEX>, which requires that
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the privacy of data used in computer matches be protected, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> complete cost-benefit analyses on all computer matches and
report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> on their findings, unless the matches are exempted
by law, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) data integrity boards be established to approve and
review the data matches.

While data sharing gives an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> the means to
compare data from different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, data mining offers a tool to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> and analyze diverse data. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> mining analyzes data for
relationships that have not previously been discovered. For
example, the incidence of improper payments among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> claims
might, if sufficiently analyzed and related to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> data,
reveal a correlation with a certain health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>.
The central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">repository</ENAMEX> of data commonly used to perform data
mining is called a data warehouse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> store historical
and current data and consist of tables of information that are
logically grouped together. The warehouse allows program and
financial data from different nonintegrated systems throughout an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> to be captured and placed in a single database where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> can query the system for information. The information can
then be "mined" or searched according to specific criteria to
identify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, sequences, patterns, and clusters between
different pieces of information-relationships that are often hidden
in separated databases.
As a tool in managing improper payments, applying data mining to
a data warehouse allows an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to efficiently query the
system to identify questionable activities, such as multiple
payments for an individual invoice or to an individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> on
a certain date. This technique allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who are not
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>, but who may have useful program or financial
expertise, to directly access data, target queries, and analyze
results. Queries can also be made through data mining software,
which includes prepared queries that can be used in the system on a
regular basis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA</ENAMEX> began data mining in an effort to improve a system that was
too slow to provide the timely information needed for a wide range
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> functions, including the prevention and detection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overpayments</ENAMEX>. As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> had spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29 million</NUMEX>
to create a data warehouse to supplement the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid Management</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information System</ENAMEX> (MMIS), which maintains data on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> as well as claims and payments. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> warehouse includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 2,000</NUMEX> different fields/elements. The
results of data queries are particularly useful because the data
warehouse is able to store more current data than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMIS</ENAMEX>. At present,
there is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-month</TIMEX> lag in current information, compared to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-month</TIMEX> lag that existed before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA</ENAMEX> began using data mining. In
addition, the data warehouse can now store <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 5 years</TIMEX> of data,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA</ENAMEX> is currently weighing the costs and benefits of increasing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this to 10 years</TIMEX> of data.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> noted that using data mining allows them to
analyze large amounts of data. Because the large number of
transactions in the system precludes manually examining each
transaction for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and patterns with other transactions,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> mining is an effective and efficient alternative. The IDPA
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> (OIG) also uses data mining to quickly
respond to requests for information for ongoing investigations from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Bureau of Investigation</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA OIG</ENAMEX> created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraud Science Team</ENAMEX> (FST), an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interdisciplinary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that includes an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>, program and
policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, and information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FST</ENAMEX> maximizes the
value of the data warehouse by performing data mining activities
and providing a research-based approach to fraud prevention and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">detection</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FST</ENAMEX> has produced documentation on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over 800</NUMEX> fraud
schemes, which it has categorized into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> different types, such as
billing for services not rendered and kickback schemes. The
information on these schemes is used in the development and
implementation of targeted analyses that are run against the data
warehouse information to identify data relationships and anomalies,
which are often signs of fraud. This information can also be used
to implement specific controls in the system intended to prevent
the identified types of fraud.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our</TIMEX> visit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA OIG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> ran several queries and
analyses. For example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> risk area identified was health care
providers that were billing for services provided in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a single day</TIMEX>. With the capabilities of the data warehouse,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> developed an analysis that identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> that
had billed over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 1 day</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 6 months</TIMEX>
ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31, 1999</TIMEX>. A number of the identified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> were
already under investigation for other program violations. As a
result of this analysis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIG</ENAMEX> plans to refer serious cases to
appropriate law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and take administrative action
against the less serious violators.
An early effort at using data mining software in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> has
identified <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 million</NUMEX> in potential overpayments.
Before the data warehouse was available, obtaining responses to
queries of this kind would have required obtaining separate reports
from different systems and could have taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 2 months</TIMEX>.
However, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our</TIMEX> visit querying the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> took from several
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds to a few minutes</TIMEX> per query.
New initiatives that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois</ENAMEX> expects will further improve data
mining at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA</ENAMEX> are the development of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 3-day</TIMEX> training course to
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> properly structure queries and the use of data mining
software. In an early effort using data mining software, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA OIG</ENAMEX>,
as part of a partnership audit with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS OIG</ENAMEX>, identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">232</NUMEX>
hospital transfers that are believed to have been miscoded as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discharges</ENAMEX>, creating a potential overpayment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 million</NUMEX>.
The large number of computerized claims processed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
also lends itself to the application of data mining techniques.
Claims administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Medicare</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> Services (formerly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Financing</ENAMEX>
Administration) use data mining and statistical analysis as part of
their postpayment review activities. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX> also has
contracted with a specialized statistical analysis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> to
perform large-scale analysis of durable medical equipment claims.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> mining can identify many potentially inappropriate payments,
but determining which ones are actual overpayments takes additional
investigation. Currently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> only have the resources
to investigate situations in which the data indicate potential
large-scale abusive practices.

Neural networking is a technique for extracting and
analyzing data. In this case, the system analyzes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and
patterns among data elements, which allows it to find relationships
that can result in new queries.
A neural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> is intended to simulate the way in which a
brain processes information, learns, and remembers. A neural
network is initially "trained" or fed large amounts of data and
rules about data relationships (for example, "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandfather</ENAMEX> is older than that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>"). Neural networks
"learn" by comparing new data with historical data and can be used
to detect patterns that are difficult, and sometimes impossible, to
detect without computer intervention in large volumes of data. The
more data a neural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> processes the better it performs (i.e.,
the better it identifies the characteristics of potentially
fraudulent payments). Based upon this knowledge, neural networks
automatically alter their analytical processes to produce more
accurate detection results.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> mandated the use of neural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> program. After examining the results of a
pilot test
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas' Medicaid Fraud and Abuse Detection System</ENAMEX> used neural
networking to recover <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.4 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>.
of neural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller's Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services Commission</ENAMEX> (HHSC) responded to the
legislation and implemented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFADS</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFADS</ENAMEX> project was
operational in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1998</TIMEX> and combines both data mining and
neural network capabilities.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> used with the neural network technology
identify fraudulent patterns from large volumes of medical claims
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> history data. For example, they can help
identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> of both known and unknown fraud schemes
through the analysis of utilization trends, patterns, and complex
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interrelationships</ENAMEX> in the data. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> currently has models for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> and dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and plans to initiate a model for
pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHSC</ENAMEX> awarded a contract for the development and operational
support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFADS</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> contract costs range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.6 million</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.1 million</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor operations</ENAMEX> that include the development
and ongoing support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are composed of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500 to 600</TIMEX> variables and generate an annual report that identifies
the potential unscrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and ranks the providers
according to how questionable their billing patterns appear to be.
The models detail the variances through graphs that compare amounts
billed and services rendered (among others items) by the identified
provider with the average of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. For example, one
dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> was ranked <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> on a dental model listing due to
unusual activity in areas such as multisurface restoration and root
canal activities. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>, using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFADS</ENAMEX>, was able to run
detailed reports on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>'s activity in the identified
high-risk areas and determined that the combination of services
provided, volume of services provided, and the recurring pattern of
the services provided were indeed suspicious. Additionally, a
dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> reviewed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>'s dental charts and
determined that many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> claimed were unnecessary. As a
result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> agreed to a settlement and has repaid the
identified overpayments of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$162,000</NUMEX> plus other penalties.
Additionally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> was excluded from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> program
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX>.
The results from both the data mining activities and the neural
network reports are reviewed and possibly investigated to determine
if the claims are fraudulent or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> are unscrupulous.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, medical judgment is important when
considering the accuracy of claims, and, as such, medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> assist in reviewing medical claims.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas' HHSC</ENAMEX> prepares <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> reports for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>'s
review. The Second <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quarter Fiscal Year 2001 Contract Performance</ENAMEX>
Report for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid Fraud and Abuse Detection System</ENAMEX> reported
that it had identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,567</NUMEX> cases (representing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $6 million</NUMEX>)
for investigation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>. As a result of investigating
these cases, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $3.4 million</NUMEX> has been recovered. These
reports also show how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHSC</ENAMEX> is performing in relation to its
performance measures. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, one of the performance
measures was that total dollars identified for recoveries equal or
exceed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">139 percent</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.7 million</NUMEX>) of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fiscal year</TIMEX> contract cost
amount. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HHSC</ENAMEX> exceeded its goal by identifying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.1 million</NUMEX> for
recovery.

Recovery auditing is the practice of identifying and
recovering overpayments that examines payment file information to
identify possible duplicate or erroneous payments. For instance,
vendors make pricing errors on their invoices, forget to include
discounts that have been publicized to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, neglect
to offer allowances and rebates, miscalculate freight charges, and
so forth. In addition, the same invoices, or portions thereof,
could be paid more than once. These mistakes, when not caught,
result in overpayments. Recovery auditing can incorporate data
mining techniques.
While traditionally used as a technique to identify improper
payments already made, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have also experienced success
in using recovery auditing to analyze records prior to payment.
Because it helps to prevent improper payments before they occur,
this use of recovery auditing eliminates the costs associated with
obtaining reimbursements for the erroneous payments or taking other
actions needed to offset future payments by the amount of the
improper payment.
Recovery auditing started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 30 years ago</TIMEX>, and it is used in
several industries, including the automobile, retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, and
food service industries, and, to some extent, within the federal
government. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> use their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to analyze their
payment records while others contract with recovery audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> for
the work. Contract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> often perform this work on a contingency
fee basis, that is, they only receive compensation if they identify
and recover amounts determined to be improper payments. As
discussed below, recovery auditing, which has a long-standing track
record in the private sector, offers an opportunity to identify
improper payments before they occur and to identify and recover
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overpayments</ENAMEX> if they do occur.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">● One</ENAMEX> private sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> contracted, on a contingency fee
basis, with a recovery audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> for a review of its accounts
payable files- files in which its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>' controls had not found
errors. The review resulted in the recovery of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> in
improper payments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> recently began using recovery
auditing techniques on accounts payable information to prevent
improper payments before they occurred. It expected that this
activity would identify possible duplicate payments, and the test
verified the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s expectations. For example, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our</TIMEX> visit,
it identified and avoided a duplicate payment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$136,000</NUMEX> from the
reports generated by the recovery audit
A private sector companyrecovered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> in improper
payments as a result of a recovery audit.
software. In addition, as a result of using recovery auditing
before payments are made, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> identified and stopped the
processing of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$41 million</NUMEX> in wire payments that had already been
processed. Another advantage of the recovery audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> used by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is that the software identifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who are
making processing errors so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can take appropriate
counseling and training action.
● Another private sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> contracted with a recovery
audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, on a contingency fee basis, to perform two separate
reviews of its disbursements-the first review was for disbursements
made from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992 through 1995</TIMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> for disbursements made
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1996 through 1998</TIMEX>. Both reviews identified duplicate payments
and resulted in recovery actions and in changes to the payment
system to help reduce future overpayments. For example, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> processed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 9 million invoices</NUMEX>. The
recovery audit review of these invoices identified <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $5 million</NUMEX>
in potential overpayments and resulted in actions to recover these
funds, where appropriate. Further, based on an analysis of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overpayments</ENAMEX> identified, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has implemented procedures
that have reduced its dollar error rate per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one million dollars</NUMEX> of
transactions from a reported <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992 through 1995</TIMEX> to a reported
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34 dollars</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996 through 1998</TIMEX>. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is now
preparing to enter an agreement with the recovery audit contractor
under which the recovery auditing software will be installed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s system, allowing its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to perform the recovery audit
function-even as part of the prepayment process.
Recovery auditing is also being used to some extent in the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Veterans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX>' (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Services Center</ENAMEX> (FSC) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, had
contracted with recovery audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in the past, but now performs
recovery auditing in-house using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to
administer the program and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> for software development.
If a duplicate payment is identified, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of several
actions, including canceling the transaction prior to payment,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">notifying Treasury</ENAMEX> to stop issuance of a check, or issuing a bill
of collection. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSC</ENAMEX> has identified over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overpayments</ENAMEX> and has collected, by either offsetting future
payments or cash collection, nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 6 months</TIMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> noted that recovery auditing
could be beneficial to almost any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that makes
payments.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postaward</ENAMEX> audits of contracts are another technique that can
help to combat improper payments and are used, to some degree,
within the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. These audits verify that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> reported recoveries of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$119 million</NUMEX> from contract audits.
payments are being made in accordance with contract terms and
applicable regulations. They can detect improper payments that have
been made, help avoid future payments of the same kind, and provide
oversight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> conducting business with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. For
example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA Office of Acquisition</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Materiel Management</ENAMEX> partnered with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA OIG</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX> to establish the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA Procurement Working Group</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PWG</ENAMEX>). As a result, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contract Review</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evaluation Division</ENAMEX> was
established to provide audit and advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> related to
contracts awarded by contracting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA's Office of</ENAMEX>
Acquisition and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Materiel Management</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1993 through September</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PWG</ENAMEX> reported recoveries resulting from postaward audits of
contracts totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $119 million</NUMEX>. This represents a reported
return of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18</NUMEX> for every dollar spent in support of these audits.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PWG</ENAMEX> attributes its success to the establishment of a knowledgeable
and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of contract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> in the pharmaceutical
and medical/surgical supply industries. As a result of the audits
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PWG</ENAMEX>'s efforts, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> have voluntarily elected to
perform internal reviews and have submitted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX> voluntary
disclosures and refund offers to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VA.</ENAMEX> Prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> received
almost no voluntary disclosures. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> have also
developed and implemented corporate responsibility plans to ensure
compliance with acquisition regulations and statutes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> reports saving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX> for every dollar spent on fraud
prevention investigations.

In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA</ENAMEX> established a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraud Prevention Investigations</ENAMEX>
Program (FPI) to prevent ineligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> from receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stamps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>. Under this program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">case managers</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Department of Human Services</ENAMEX> (IDHS) refer applications
that contain suspicious or conflicting information to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDPA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Investigations</ENAMEX> (BOI) for action before benefit payments begin.
Case <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> use certain referral criteria, such as applications
that contain contradictory information about household composition
or employment, to identify these applications. BOI submits referred
cases to a private investigation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, under contract with the IDPA
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIG</ENAMEX>, which investigates the information on the application. This
investigation may consist of interviews; contacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landlords</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>; or a visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>'s home. The
results are reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOI</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8 business days</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> business days
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> stamps) and then to the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDHS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for appropriate
action- approval, denial, or reduction of benefits.
The program was piloted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and was implemented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook County</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDHS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> participating.
Currently, all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDHS</ENAMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook County</ENAMEX> participate in
the program. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPI</ENAMEX> reports total savings, since program inception, of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $12</NUMEX> for every dollar spent.
Specifically, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FPI</ENAMEX> prevented <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.5 million</NUMEX> in
improper payments from being issued at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$823,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savings</ENAMEX>
are calculated based on the administrative and contract costs of
the program as a percentage of gross savings and cost avoidance for
cases that resulted in denied or reduced benefits.
The preceding examples of control activities are meant to
illustrate a sample of the type of activities that may be useful to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s internal control activities should be
flexible, weighing costs and benefits, to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to tailor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> activities to fit their special needs. Once control
activities are in place, the internal control cycle continues with
the prompt communication of information that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> need to help
them carry out these activities and run their operations
efficiently and effectively.

Strategies to Consider-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Activities</ENAMEX>
In taking action to address identified risks, the following
strategies should be considered:

