



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>

Report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on Readiness</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Support, Committee on Armed Services</ENAMEX>,


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2002</TIMEX>
BEST PRACTICES



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capturing Design and Manufacturing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knowledge Early Improves Acquisition Outcomes</ENAMEX>
a


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-701

Contents


Letter


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>




Executive Summary


Purpose2 
Background3 
Results in Brief4 
Principal Findings6 
Recommendations for Executive Action9 
Agency Comments10

11


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 1</ENAMEX>


Best Practices of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading Commercial</ENAMEX> Companies12 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional Approach</ENAMEX> to Product Development15 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adoption of Best</ENAMEX> Practices16 
Objectives, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scope</ENAMEX>, and Methodology17


22

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 2</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DOD Programs Had Better Outcomes When Design and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manufacturing Knowledge Was Captured</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Key</ENAMEX> Program
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturing</ENAMEX> 
Junctures22 <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knowledge Is Critical to Program</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 3 Best Practices Enable Timely Capture</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturing Knowledge</ENAMEX>


29
Leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial Companies Use Evolutionary Product</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Development Framework</ENAMEX> to Reduce Development Risks30 
Leading Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> Use a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Product Development</ENAMEX>
Process to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capture Design and Manufacturing Knowledge</ENAMEX> for
Decision Making32 
When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DOD Programs More Closely Approximated Best</ENAMEX>
Practices,
Outcomes Were Better43

<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 4</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Match of Policy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Incentives Is Needed</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ensure Capture of Design and Manufacturing Knowledge</ENAMEX>



52
Acquisition <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Policy Lacks Specific Implementation</ENAMEX>
Criteria53 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incentives</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD Acquisition Environment</ENAMEX> Do
Not Favor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capture of Design</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manufacturing Knowledge Early</ENAMEX> 
Enough57



Related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Products</ENAMEX>


Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:
Figures
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>: Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>: Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>: Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>:
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>: Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>:

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procurement Funding</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fiscal Years 1995 to 200712</TIMEX> 
Knowledge-based <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Process for Applying Best Practices to</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development of New</ENAMEX> Products13 
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Notional Illustration Showing the Different Paths That</ENAMEX>
a
Product's Development Can Take15 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Concurrent Approach to Weapon System</ENAMEX>
Development16 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notional Single-Step</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evolutionary Approaches</ENAMEX> to
Developing New Products31 
Achieving Stability on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-9X Missile</ENAMEX> Program by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knowledge Point</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">244</NUMEX> 
History of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drawing Completion</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> Program46 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PAC-3 Design Knowledge</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Critical Design</ENAMEX> Review49 
Illustration to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show How the Best Practice Model Would</ENAMEX>
Apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acquisition</ENAMEX> Process56
A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20548</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 2002</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honorable Daniel Akaka</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable James Inhofe</ENAMEX>
Ranking Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on Readiness and Management</ENAMEX>
Support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Armed Services United States Senate</ENAMEX>
As you requested, this report examines how best practices offer
improvements to the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> develops new
weapon systems, primarily the design and manufacturing aspects of
the acquisition process. It examines the attainment of design and
manufacturing knowledge and its use at critical junctures to make
decisions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX>' readiness to move forward in the
acquisition process. We make recommendations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
Defense for improvements to weapon system acquisition policy to
better align design and manufacturing activities with best
practices that have shown that the capture and use of key knowledge
can result in better cost, schedule, and performance outcomes.
We are sending copies of this report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
Defense; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missile Defense Agency</ENAMEX>; and
interested congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>. We will also make copies
available to others upon request. In addition, the report will be
available at no charge on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> Web site at 
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.gov.
If you have any questions regarding this report, please call me
at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-4841</TIMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> are listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">appendix</ENAMEX> II.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine V. Schinasi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acquisition</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sourcing</ENAMEX>
Management
Executive Summary
Historically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>) has taken much longer and
Purpose
spent much more than originally planned to develop and acquire
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX>, significantly reducing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s buying
power over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. Clearly, it is critical to find better ways
of doing business and, in particular, to make sure that weapon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> are delivered on time and cost-effectively. This is
especially true given the vast sums <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> is spending and is expected
to spend on weapons acquisition-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 billion</NUMEX> alone in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> and an
anticipated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 5 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> has recognized
the nature of this problem and has taken steps to address it,
including advocating the use of best practices for product
development from commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
have achieved more predictable outcomes from their product
development processes because they identify and control design and
manufacturing risks early and manage them effectively. While DOD
has made some progress in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recent weapon system
reviews show that persistent problems continue to hinder
acquisition cost, schedule, and performance outcomes. For this
reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has continued a body of work to identify the lessons
learned by best commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to see if they apply to weapon
system acquisitions.
This report addresses how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> can manage its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon system</ENAMEX>
acquisition process to ensure important knowledge about a system's
design, critical manufacturing processes, and reliability is
captured and used to make informed and timely decisions before
committing to substantial development and production investments.
It identifies best practices to facilitate this decision making at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> critical junctures-transition from system integration to system
demonstration during product development and then transition into
production. Ultimately, this should improve cost, schedule, and
quality outcomes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> major weapon system acquisitions. In
response to a request from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on Readiness and Management Support</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Armed Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) assessed the impact of design
and manufacturing knowledge on DOD program outcomes, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) compared
best practices to those used in DOD programs, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) analyzed
current weapon system acquisition guidance for applicability of
best practices to obtain better program outcomes.
Background
Executive Summary
In any new product development program there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> critical
points that require the capture of specific knowledge to achieve
successful outcomes. The first knowledge point occurs when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>'s requirements are clearly defined and resources-proven
technology, design, time, and money-exist to satisfy them.
Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> insist that technology be mature at the outset
of a product development program and, therefore, separate
technology development from product development. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
knowledge point is achieved when the product's design is determined
to be capable of meeting product requirements-the design is stable
and ready to begin initial manufacturing of prototypes. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
knowledge point is achieved when a reliable product can be produced
repeatedly within established cost, schedule, and quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s prior work on best practices covers achieving the first
knowledge point<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> This report examines best practices for achieving
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> knowledge points.
Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> understand the importance of capturing
design and manufacturing knowledge early in product development,
when costs to identify problems and make design changes to the
product are significantly cheaper. In a knowledge-based process,
the achievement of each successive knowledge point builds on the
preceding one, giving decision <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> the knowledge they need-when
they need it-to make decisions about whether to invest significant
additional funds to move forward with product development. Programs
that follow a knowledge-based approach typically have a higher
probability of successful cost and schedule outcomes. Problems
occur in programs when knowledge builds more slowly than
commitments to enter product development or production. The effects
of this delay in capturing knowledge can be debilitating. If a
decision is made to commit to develop and produce a design before
the critical technology, design, or manufacturing knowledge is
captured, problems will cascade and become magnified through the
product development and production phases. Outcomes from these
problems include increases in cost and schedule and degradations in
performance and quality.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best Practices</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX>
Matching of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Needs and Resources Will Lead to Better Weapon System</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outcomes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-288 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 2001</TIMEX>) and Best
Practices: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Management of Technology Development Can Improve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weapon System Outcomes</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/NSIAD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX>-162(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 30, 1999</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-701</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Practices</ENAMEX>
The success of any effort to develop a new
product hinges on having the
Results in Brief
right knowledge at the right time. Knowledge about a product's
design and producibility facilitates informed decisions about
whether to significantly increase investments and reduces the risk
of costly design changes later in the program. Every program
eventually achieves this knowledge; however, leading commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> visited have found that there is a much better
opportunity to meet predicted cost, schedule, and quality targets
when it is captured early, in preparation for critical investment
decisions. A product development process includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> phases
followed by production-integration phase and demonstration phase.
The commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> visited achieved success in product
development by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> achieving a mature, stable design supported by
completed engineering drawings during an integration phase and then
by demonstrating that the product's design was reliable and
critical manufacturing processes required to build it were in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> before committing to full production. The more successful
DOD programs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reviewed-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIM-9X</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FA-18-E/F</ENAMEX> programs-had
achieved similar knowledge as the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, resulting
in good cost and schedule outcomes. In contrast, the DOD programs,
which had completed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-quarter</NUMEX> of their drawings when they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transitioned</ENAMEX> to the demonstration phase and had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> of
their manufacturing processes in control when entering production,
experienced poor cost and schedule outcomes.
Leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> employed practices to capture
design and manufacturing knowledge in time for making key decisions
during product development. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> were most prominent. First, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> kept the degree of the design challenge manageable before
starting a new product development program by using an evolutionary
approach to develop a product. This minimized the amount of new
content and technologies on a product, making it easier to capture
the requisite knowledge about a product's design before investing
in manufacturing processes, tooling, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> captured design and manufacturing knowledge before the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> critical decision points in product development: when the
design was demonstrated to be stable-the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> knowledge point-and
when the product was demonstrated to be producible at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an affordable</NUMEX>
cost-the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> knowledge point. A key measure of design stability
was stakeholders' agreements that engineering drawings were
complete and supported by testing and prototyping when necessary. A
key measure of producibility was whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' critical
manufacturing processes were in control and product reliability was
demonstrated. Most DOD programs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reviewed did not complete
engineering drawings prior to entering the demonstration phase, nor
did they bring critical manufacturing processes in control or
demonstrate reliability prior to making a production decision.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> has made changes to its acquisition <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">policy2</TIMEX> in an attempt to
improve its framework for developing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX>, but the policy
does not require the capture of design or manufacturing knowledge
or sufficient criteria to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration and
production phases. In addition, it does not require a decision
review to enter the demonstration phase of product development.
Further, there is little incentive for DOD program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to
capture knowledge early in the development process. Instead, the
acquisition environment emphasizes delaying knowledge capture and
problem identification since these events can have a negative
influence on obtaining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> program funding-a key to success for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. In contrast, commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> encourage their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to capture product design and manufacturing knowledge to
identify and resolve problems early in development, before making
significant increases in their investment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is making recommendations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to improve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s acquisition process to achieve better
outcomes by incorporating best practices to capture design and
manufacturing knowledge and then use this knowledge as a basis for
decisions to commit significant additional time and money as an
acquisition program progresses through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration and
into production.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 DOD Directive 5000.1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Defense Acquisition System</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 23</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DOD Instruction 5000.2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation of the Defense Acquisition</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">System</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 2002</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD Regulation</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5000.2</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, Mandatory
Procedures for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major Defense Acquisition Programs</ENAMEX> (MDAPS) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major</ENAMEX>
Automated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information System</ENAMEX> (MAIS) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acquisition Programs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Apr. 5,</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-701</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Practices</ENAMEX>
Principal Findings
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timely Design and Manufacturing Knowledge</ENAMEX>
Is Critical to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Success</ENAMEX>
Knowledge that a product's design is stable early in the program
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilitates</ENAMEX> informed decisions about whether to significantly
increase investments and reduces the risk of costly design changes
that can result from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unknowns</ENAMEX> after initial manufacturing begins.
Likewise, later knowledge that the design can be manufactured
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affordably</ENAMEX> and with consistent high quality prior to making a
production decision ensures that targets for cost and schedule
during production will be met. Leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do not
make significant investments to continue a product development or
its production until they have knowledge that the product's design
works and it can be manufactured efficiently within cost and
schedule expectations.
DOD programs that captured knowledge similar to commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> had more successful outcomes. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIM-9X</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/A-18E/F</ENAMEX> captured design and manufacturing knowledge by key
decision points and limited cost increases to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> or less and
schedule growth to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 months</TIMEX> or less. In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIM-9X</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>
percent of its drawings completed at its critical design review.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/A-18E/F</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX> of its drawings completed and also had
over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of its higher level interface drawings completed,
adding confidence in the system design. Both took steps to ensure
that manufacturing processes were capable of producing an
affordable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> by the time the programs made production
decisions.
On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Threat Infrared</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Countermeasures/Common Missile Warning System</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATIRCM/CMWS</ENAMEX>)
programs did not capture sufficient knowledge before significant
investments to continue the programs and experienced cost growth
that ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 to 182 percent</NUMEX> and schedule delays that ranged
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months to over 3 years</TIMEX>. None of these programs had
completed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 26 percent</NUMEX> of their engineering drawings for
their critical design reviews, and only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PAC-3</ENAMEX> programs
attempted to track the capability of their critical manufacturing
processes prior to production.
Best <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Practices Enable Timely Capture</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design and Manufacturing Knowledge</ENAMEX>
Leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> developed practices that enabled
the timely capture of design and manufacturing knowledge. First,
they used an evolutionary approach to product development by
establishing timephased plans to develop a new product in
increments based on technologies and resources achievable now and
later. This approach reduced the amount of risk in the development
of each increment, facilitating greater success in meeting cost,
schedule, and performance requirements. The commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> visited used the evolutionary approach as their method for
product development. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had a plan for eventually
achieving a quantum leap in the performance of its products and had
established an orderly, phased process for getting there, by
undertaking continuous product improvements as resources became
available. For the most part, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> programs try to achieve the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leap</ENAMEX> in performance but in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> step, contributing to
development times that can take over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> to deliver a new
capability to the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, each leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had a product
development process that was prominent and central to its success.
The process was championed by executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and embraced by
product <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> as an effective way to do
business. Critical to the product development process were
activities that enabled the capture of specific design and
manufacturing knowledge and decision reviews to determine if the
knowledge captured would support the increased investment necessary
to move to the next development phase or into production. These
activities provided knowledge that the product design was stable at
the decision point to start initial manufacturing (exiting the
integration phase) as demonstrated by the completion of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>
of the engineering drawings. They also captured knowledge that a
product was ready to begin production (exiting the demonstration
phase) as demonstrated by proof that critical processes were in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and product reliability was achievable. The activities that
enabled the capture and use of this knowledge to make decisions are
listed in table 1.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Activities That Enable the Capture</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturing Knowledge</ENAMEX>
Design is stable Product can be produced


•
Limit the design challenge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">• Identify</ENAMEX> key system
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">characteristics</ENAMEX> and critical manufacturing processes.


•
Demonstrate, through prototyping or other means, that
product <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">• Determine</ENAMEX> that processes are in control and stable.
works.


•
Complete design reviews of system and subsystems. •
Analyze potential failure modes and their effects on
performance.


•
Obtain stakeholder concurrence that the design is
complete and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• Set</ENAMEX> reliability goals and growth plan and conduct
reliability producible. testing.


DOD programs that had more successful outcomes used key best
practices to a greater degree than others. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX>-9X
missile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> completed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of its engineering drawings at
the critical design review because it made extensive use of
prototype testing to demonstrate the design met requirements
coupled with design reviews that included program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/A-18-E/F</ENAMEX> program eliminated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 40 percent</NUMEX> of the parts used to
build predecessor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to make the design more robust for
manufacturing and identified critical manufacturing processes,
bringing them under control before the start of production. Both
programs developed products that evolved from existing versions,
making the design challenge more manageable.
On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> programs with less successful outcomes
did not apply best practices to a great extent. At their initial
manufacturing decision reviews, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATIRCM/CMWS</ENAMEX>
had less than onethird of their engineering drawings, in part,
because they did not use prototypes to demonstrate the design met
requirements before starting initial manufacturing. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX>
program, it was almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 years</TIMEX> after this review before <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>
of the drawings needed to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> were completed. Likewise,
at their production decision reviews, these programs did not
capture manufacturing and product reliability knowledge consistent
with best practices. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PAC-3</ENAMEX> missile program had
less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of its processes in control and, as a result,
the missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> had to be built, tested, and reworked on
average <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> times before they were acceptable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> entered
production despite being substantially behind its plan to achieve
reliability goals. As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> is requiring significantly
more maintenance actions than planned.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Match of Policy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Incentives Is</ENAMEX>
Needed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ensure Capture of Design and Manufacturing Knowledge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s acquisition policy establishes a good framework for
developing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX>; however, more specific criteria,
disciplined adherence, and stronger acquisition incentives are
needed to ensure the timely capture and use of knowledge and
decision making. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> recently changed its acquisition policy to
emphasize evolutionary acquisition and establish separate
integration and demonstration phases in the product development
process. Its goal was to develop higher quality systems in less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> and for less cost. While similar to the leading commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' approach, the policy lacks detailed criteria for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capturing</ENAMEX> and using design and manufacturing knowledge to
facilitate better decisions and more successful acquisition program
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX>. It also lacks a decision review to proceed from the
integration phase to the demonstration phase of product
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>.
While the right policy and criteria are necessary to ensure a
disciplined, knowledge-based product development process, the
incentives that influence the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the acquisition
process will ultimately determine whether they will be used
effectively. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>, current incentives are geared toward delaying
knowledge so as not to jeopardize program funding. This undermines
a knowledge-based process for making product development decisions.
Instead, program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> push the capture of
design and manufacturing knowledge to later in the development
program to avoid the identification of problems that might stop or
limit funding. They focus more on meeting schedules than capturing
knowledge. On the other hand, commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> must develop
high-quality products quickly or they may not survive in the
marketplace. Because of this, they encourage their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to
capture product design and manufacturing knowledge to identify and
resolve problems early in development, before making significant
increases in their investment. Instead of a schedule-driven
process, their process is driven by events that bring them
knowledge: critical design reviews that are supported by completed
engineering drawings and production decisions supported by
not move forward without the design and manufacturing knowledge
needed to make informed decisions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> recommends that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
Defense revise policy and guidance
Recommendations for

on the operation of the defense
acquisition system to include (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a requirement to capture specific
design knowledge to be used as exit criteria for transitioning from
system integration to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration
and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a requirement that the current optional interim progress
review between system integration and demonstration be a mandatory
decision review requiring the program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> to verify that design
is stable and that this be reported in the program's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
Acquisition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Summary and Selected Acquisition Report</ENAMEX>. The
policy and guidance should also be revised to include (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a
requirement to capture and use specific manufacturing knowledge at
the production commitment point as exit criteria to transition from
system demonstration into production and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a requirement to
structure major <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon system</ENAMEX> contracts to ensure the capture and
use of knowledge for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> to make investment decisions at critical
junctures when transitioning from system integration to system
demonstration and then into production.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> generally agreed with the report and
its recommendations. A detailed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> Comments
discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s comments appears in appendix <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 1</ENAMEX>
Introduction
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> (DOD) spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close to $100 billion</NUMEX>
annually to research, develop, and acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX>, and this
investment is expected to grow substantially. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 5</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2003</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s request for weapon
system development and acquisition funds is estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> (see fig. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
How effectively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> manages these funds will determine whether
it receives a good return on its investment. Our reviews over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 20 years</TIMEX> have consistently found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s weapon system
acquisitions take much longer and cost much more than originally
anticipated, causing disruptions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s overall
investment strategy and significantly reducing its buying power.
Because such disruptions can limit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s ability to effectively
execute war-fighting operations, it is critical to find better ways
of doing business.
In view of the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX>,
we have undertaken an extensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of work that examines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s
acquisition issues from a different, more cross-cutting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that draws lessons learned from the best commercial
product development efforts to see if they apply to weapon system
acquisitions. This report looks at the core of the acquisition
process, specifically product development and ways to successfully
design and manufacture the product. Our previous reports looked at
such issues as how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> matched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> needs and resources,
tested products, assured quality, and managed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> and are
listed in related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> products at the end of the report.
Best Practices of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading Commercial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procurement Funding</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fiscal Years 1995 to 2007</TIMEX>

Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>.
Leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> expect their program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to
deliver high-quality products on time and within budget. Doing
otherwise could result in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> walking away. Thus, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have created an environment and adopted practices that
put their program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> in a good position to succeed in meeting
these expectations. Collectively, these practices ensure that a
high level of knowledge exists about critical facets of the product
at key junctures during development. Such a knowledgebased process
enables decision <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to be reasonably certain about critical
facets of the product under development when they need this
knowledge.
To ensure the right level of knowledge at each key decision
point in product development, leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> separate
technology from product development and take steps to ensure the
product design is stabilized early so product performance and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">producibility</ENAMEX> can be demonstrated before production. The process
followed by leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, illustrated in figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, can be
broken down into the following <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> knowledge points.


•
Knowledge point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> occurs when a match is made between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>'s needs and the available resources-technology, design,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, and funding. To achieve this match, technologies needed to
meet essential product requirements must be demonstrated to work in
their intended environment. In addition, the product <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> must
complete a preliminary product design using systems engineering to
balance customer desires with available resources.


•
Knowledge point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> occurs when the product's design
demonstrates its ability to meet performance requirements. Program
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are confident that the design is stable and will perform
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptably</ENAMEX> when <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 90 percent</NUMEX> of engineering drawings are
complete. Engineering drawings reflect the results of testing and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simulation</ENAMEX> and describe how the product should be built.


•
Knowledge point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> occurs when the product can be
manufactured within cost, schedule, and quality targets and is
reliable. An important indicator of this is when critical
manufacturing processes are in control and consistently producing
items within quality standards and tolerances. Another indicator is
when a product's reliability is demonstrated through iterative
testing that identifies and corrects design problems.


Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knowledge-based Process for Applying Best Practices to</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development of New Products</ENAMEX>

Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s analysis.
This report focuses on best practices for achieving knowledge
points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 and 3</TIMEX>, particularly at how successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> design and
manufacture a product within established cost, schedule, and
quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. The concepts discussed build on our previous
reports, which looked at the earlier phases of an acquisition,
including matching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> needs and available resources.
A key success factor evident in all our work is the ability to
obtain the right knowledge at the right time and to build knowledge
to the point that decision <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> can make informed decisions about
moving ahead to the next phase. Programs that do this typically
have successful cost and schedule outcomes. Programs that do not
typically encounter problems that eventually cascade and become
magnified through the product development and production phases. As
shown in figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, the effects of not following a knowledge-based
process can be debilitating.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional Approach</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Product</ENAMEX>
Development
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Notional Illustration Showing the Different Paths That</ENAMEX>
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Product's Development Can Take</ENAMEX>
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s analysis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> has historically developed new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX> in a highly
concurrent environment that usually forces acquisition programs to
manage technology, design, and manufacturing risk at the same time.
This environment has made it difficult for either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DOD</ENAMEX> or
congressional decision <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to make informed decisions because
appropriate knowledge has not been available at key decision points
in product development. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s common practice for managing this
environment has been to create aggressive risk reduction efforts in
its programs. Cost reduction initiatives that typically arise after
a program is experiencing problems are common tools used to manage
these risks. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> shows the overlapping and concurrent approach
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> uses to develop its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX>. This figure shows that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> continues to capture technology, design, and manufacturing
knowledge long after a program passes through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each of the three</TIMEX>
knowledge points when this knowledge should have been available for
program decisions.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Concurrent Approach to Weapon System</ENAMEX>
Development

Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s analysis.
More important, the problems created by this concurrent approach
on individual programs can profoundly affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s overall
modernization plans. It is difficult to prioritize and allocate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX> budgets among needed requirements when acquisition
programs' cost and schedule are always in question. Programs that
are managed without the knowledge-based process are more likely to
have surprises in the form of cost and schedule increases that are
accommodated by disrupting the funding of other programs. Because
of these disruptions, decision <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> are not able to focus on a
balanced investment strategy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> is taking steps to change the culture
of the acquisition community
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s Adoption of

with actions aimed at reducing
product development cycle times and improving the predictability of
cost and schedule outcomes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> recently made constructive changes
to its acquisition policy that embrace best
Objectives, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scope</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodology</ENAMEX>
practices. These changes focused primarily on (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) ensuring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> are demonstrated to a high level of maturity before
beginning a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon system</ENAMEX> program and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) taking an evolutionary,
or phased, approach to developing new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX>. Because these
changes occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000 and 2001</TIMEX>, it is too early to determine how
effectively they will be put into practice. While these are good
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> steps, further use of best practices in product development
would provide a greater opportunity to improve weapon system cost
and schedule outcomes.
Our overall objective was to determine whether best practices
offer methods to improve the way DOD ensures that the design is
stable early in the development process and whether having
manufacturing processes in control before production results in
better cost, schedule, and quality outcomes in DOD major
acquisition programs. Specifically, we identified best practices
that have led to more successful product development and production
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX>, compared the best practices to those used in DOD
programs, and analyzed current weapon system acquisition guidance
for applicability of best practices.
To determine the best practices for ensuring product design and
manufacturing maturity from the commercial sector, we conducted
general literature searches. On the basis of our literature
searches and discussions with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, we identified a number of
commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> as having innovative development processes and
practices that resulted in successful product development. We
visited the following commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>:


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX> designs and manufactures construction and
mining equipment, diesel and natural gas engines, and industrial
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> turbines. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, it reported sales and revenues totaling
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20.45 billion</NUMEX>. We visited its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peoria</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cummins Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engine Business group</ENAMEX>) designs and
manufactures diesel and natural gas engines ranging in size from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,500</NUMEX> horsepower for mining, construction, agriculture, rail,
oil and gas, heavy and mediumduty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motor homes</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engine Business Group</ENAMEX> reported sales of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.1 billion</NUMEX>.
We visited its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric Aircraft Engines</ENAMEX> designs and
manufactures jet engines for civil and military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> and gas
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">turbines</ENAMEX>, derived from its successful jet engine programs, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marine</ENAMEX> and industrial applications.


In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, it reported earnings totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.4 billion</NUMEX>. We visited
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Evendale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX> designs and manufactures computing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> and imaging and printing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> for individual and
business use. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, it reported revenues totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45.2 billion</NUMEX>.
We visited its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> involved in the design and manufacturing of
complex ink jet imaging equipment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Corvallis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox Corporation</ENAMEX> designs and manufactures office
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>, including color and black and white printers, digital
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presses</ENAMEX>, multifunction devices, and digital copiers designed for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and production-printing environments. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, it reported
revenues totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.5 billion</NUMEX>. We visited its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.


At each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, we conducted structured
interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> to gather uniform and consistent
information about each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s new product development processes
and best practices. During meetings with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>, we
obtained a detailed description of the processes and practices they
believed necessary and vital to mature a product design and get
manufacturing processes under control. We met with design
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, manufacturing and quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> of the knowledge-based processes and policies.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 5 years</TIMEX>, we have gathered information on product
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> practices from such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing Commercial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airplane Group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bombardier Aerospace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motor Company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes Space and Communications</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>. This information enabled us to develop an overall
model to describe the general approach leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
take to develop new products.
Our report highlights several best practices in product
development based on our fieldwork. As such, they are not intended
to describe all practices or suggest that commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are
without flaws. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> from the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visited</ENAMEX> told us that the development of their best practices has
evolved over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> and that the practices continue to be
improved based on lessons learned and new ideas and information.
They admit that the application and use of these have not always
been consistent or without error. However, they strongly suggested
that the probability of success in developing new products is
greatly enhanced by the use of these practices. Further, because of
the sensitivity to how data that would show the actual outcomes of
new product development efforts might affect their competitive
standing, we did not obtain specific cost, schedule, and
performance data. Most examples provided by these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were
anecdotal. However, the continued success of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in a competitive marketplace indicated that their practices
were important and key to their operations. Furthermore, based on
our observations during meetings at these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, it was
apparent that because of the level of detailed process tools
developed for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> these best
practices were a centerpiece of their operations.
Next, we compared and contrasted the best practices with product
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> practices used in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> major acquisition programs.
Below is a brief description of each program we examined:


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter aircraft</ENAMEX> program. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> is
designed with advanced features to allow it to be less detectable
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX>, capable of high speeds for long ranges, and able to
provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> with improved awareness of the surrounding
situation through the use of integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">avionics</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> program
began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> and entered limited production in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
expects to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">341</NUMEX> at a total acquisition cost (development and
procurement) estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$69.7 billion</NUMEX>.


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Patriot Advanced Capability</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) missile program.
This program is intended to enhance the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Patriot system</ENAMEX>, an
air-defense, guided missile system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PAC-3</ENAMEX> is designed to enhance
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patriot</ENAMEX> radar's ability to detect and identify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>,
increase system computer capabilities, improve communications,
increase the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> in each launcher, and incorporate a
new "hit-to-kill" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>. The "hit-to-kill" missile capabilities
represent a major part of the development program, as these are not
capabilities included in prior versions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Patriot</ENAMEX> system. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">missile</ENAMEX> program began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> and entered limited production in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> plans to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,159</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> at a total acquisition
cost estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.5 billion</NUMEX>.


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Threat Infrared Countermeasures/Common</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Missile Warning System</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATIRCM/CMWS</ENAMEX>) program. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATIRCM/CMWS</ENAMEX> is a
defensive countermeasure system for protection against infrared
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">guided</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. The common missile warning system <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">detects missiles</ENAMEX>
in flight, and the advanced threat infrared countermeasure defeats
the missile


with the use of a laser. The combined system is designed for
helicopter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX>. The common missile warning system is also designed
for
tactical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>. The program began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
and is
expected to start limited production in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> and the
Special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations Command</ENAMEX> plan to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,078</NUMEX> systems at a total
acquisition
cost estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.9 billion</NUMEX>.


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIM-9X</ENAMEX> missile program. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-9X</ENAMEX> is an infrared, short
range, air-to-air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> carried by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> fighter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIM-9X</ENAMEX> is an extensive upgrade of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9M</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-9X</ENAMEX> is planned to have increased resistance to countermeasures
and improved target acquisition capability. A key feature is that
it will have the ability to acquire, track, and fire on targets
over a wider area than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9M</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIM-9X</ENAMEX> program began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
and entered limited production in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> plans to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,142</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> at a total acquisition cost estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>.


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/A-18 E/F</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter aircraft</ENAMEX> program. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> is
intended to complement and eventually replace the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/A-18</ENAMEX>
C/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> and perform <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Navy</ENAMEX> fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX>, strike, fleet air
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>, and close air support missions. It is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> major
model upgrade since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/A-18</ENAMEX> inception. The development program
began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> entered limited production in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> rate production in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> plans to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">548</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> at
a total acquisition cost estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48.8 billion</NUMEX>.


We selected these programs for review based on cost, schedule,
and performance data presented in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selected Acquisition</ENAMEX> Reports3
for each program. We also selected these programs because we
considered them to be in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic categories-successful and
unsuccessful cost and schedule performance outcomes. This basis for
selection was to compare and contrast the development practices
used on each with best practices used by the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
For each program, we interviewed key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and design and
manufacturing engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>. In some cases, we
discussed design and manufacturing issues with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of
the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> for the specific program to obtain
information on the practices and procedures used by the program to
ready
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Selected Acquisition Report</ENAMEX> provides standard,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> summary reporting of cost, schedule, and performance
information for major defense acquisition programs to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-701</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Practices</ENAMEX>
the product design for initial manufacturing and testing as well
as for production. We also discussed the use and potential
application of best practices that we identified. In addition to
discussions, we analyzed significant amounts of data on engineering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drawings</ENAMEX>, design changes, labor efficiencies, manufacturing
processes, quality indicators, testing, and schedules. We did not
verify the accuracy of the data but did correlate it to other
program indicators for reasonableness. Our analysis of the data was
used as a basis to develop indicators of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX>'s development
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">efficiencies</ENAMEX> and detailed questions to discuss product design and
manufacturing practices.
We conducted our review <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between May 2001 and April 2002</TIMEX> in
accordance with generally accepted government auditing
standards.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 2</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timely Design</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manufacturing Knowledge Is Critical to Program</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DOD Programs Had Better Outcomes When</ENAMEX>
Design and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manufacturing Knowledge Was Captured</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Key</ENAMEX> Program
Junctures
The success of any effort to develop a new product hinges on
having the right knowledge at the right time. Every program
eventually achieves this knowledge; however, leading commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> we visited have found that there is a much better
opportunity to meet predicted cost, schedule, and quality targets
when it is captured early, in preparation for critical decisions.
Specifically, knowledge that a product's design is stable early in
the program facilitates informed decisions about whether to
significantly increase investments and reduces the risk of costly
design changes that can result from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unknowns</ENAMEX> after initial
manufacturing begins. This knowledge comes in the form of completed
engineering drawings before transitioning from the system
integration phase to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration phase of product
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. Best practices suggest that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 90 percent</NUMEX> of the
drawings for a product's design be completed before a decision to
commit additional resources is made. Likewise, later knowledge that
the design can be manufactured <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">affordably</ENAMEX> and with consistent high
quality prior to making a production decision ensures that cost and
schedule <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> will be met. This knowledge comes in the form of
evidence from data that shows manufacturing processes are in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and system reliability is achievable. Leading commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> rely on knowledge obtained about critical manufacturing
processes and product reliability to make their production
decisions.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> (DOD) programs we reviewed captured
varying amounts of design and manufacturing knowledge in the form
of completed engineering drawings and statistical process control
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>. We found a correlation between the amount of knowledge each
captured and their cost and schedule outcomes. Programs that were
able to complete more engineering drawings and control their
critical manufacturing processes had more success in meeting cost
and schedule targets established when they began.
Conceptually, the product development process has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> phases: a
system integration phase to stabilize the product's design and a
system demonstration phase to demonstrate the product can be
manufactured affordably and work reliably. The system integration
phase is used to stabilize the overall system design by integrating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">components</ENAMEX> and subsystems into a product and by showing that the
design can meet product requirements. When this knowledge is
captured, knowledge point 2 has been achieved. It should be
demonstrated by the completion of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 90 percent</NUMEX> of
engineering drawings, which both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> and leading commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> consider to be the point when a product's design is
essentially complete. In the DOD process, this knowledge point
should happen by the critical design review, before system
demonstration and the initial manufacturing of production
representative products begins. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration phase is
then used to demonstrate that the product will work as required and
can be manufactured within targets. When this knowledge is
captured, knowledge point 3 has been achieved. Critical
manufacturing processes are in control and consistently producing
items within quality standards and tolerances for the overall
product. Also, product reliability has been demonstrated. In the
DOD process, like with the commercial process, this knowledge point
should happen by the production commitment milestone. Bypassing
critical knowledge at either knowledge point will usually result in
cost, schedule, and performance problems later in product
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> and production.
We found that the most successful programs had taken steps to
gather knowledge that confirmed the product's design was stable
before the design was released to manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to
build products for demonstration. They had most of the detailed
design complete, supported by the completion of a large percentage
of engineering drawings to manufacturing. Again, engineering
drawings are critical because they include details on the parts and
work instructions needed to make the product and reflect the
results of testing. These drawings allowed manufacturing personnel
to effectively plan the fabrication process and efficiently build
production representative prototypes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> so
manufacturing processes and the product's performance could be
validated before committing to production. The most successful DOD
programs also captured the knowledge that manufacturing processes
needed to build the product would consistently produce a reliable
product by the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration, before making a
production decision. On these programs, the initial phase of
production-sometimes known as low-rate initial production-was able
to focus on building operational test articles and improving the
production processes, instead of continuing the product's design
and development.
Problematic programs moved forward into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration
without the same knowledge from engineering drawings that
successful cases had captured. They increased investments in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tooling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and materials before the design was stable. In
these programs, only a small percentage of the drawings needed to
make the products had been completed at the time the designs were
released to manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> for building production
representative prototypes. In doing so, these programs undertook
the difficult challenge of stabilizing the designs at the same time
they were trying to build and test the products. This design
immaturity caused costly design changes and parts shortages that,
in turn, caused labor inefficiencies, schedule delays, and quality
problems. Consequently, these programs required significant
increases in resources--time and money-over what was estimated at
the point each program began the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration phase.
The most problematic programs also started production before
design and manufacturing development work was concluded. In these
cases, programs were producing items for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> while making
major product design and tooling changes, still establishing
manufacturing processes, and conducting development testing. These
programs encountered significant cost increases, schedule delays,
and performance problems during production.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> shows the relationship between design stability and
manufacturing knowledge at key junctures and the outcomes for the
DOD programs we reviewed. To measure design stability at the start
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration phase, knowledge point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, we determined
the percentage of the product's engineering drawings that had been
completed by the critical design review. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> programs, after the
critical design review, the system design is released to
manufacturing to begin building the production representative
prototypes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration phase. To measure
producibility at the production decision, knowledge point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, we
determined whether the critical manufacturing processes were in
statistical control at that time. We compared this information with
best practices. The cost and schedule experiences of the program
since the start of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration are also shown.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attainment of Design and Manufacturing Knowledge</ENAMEX> in DOD
Programs and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Outcomes</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">aWhile AIM-9X</ENAMEX> used statistical process control on a limited
basis, we believe other factors contributed to a successful
production outcome to date. Other factors included early
achievement of design stability, early identification of key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">characteristics</ENAMEX> and critical manufacturing processes, use of
established manufacturing processes for components common to other
weapon systems, design trade-offs to enhance manufacturing
capability, and a product design less vulnerable to variations in
manufacturing processes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bF/A-18 E/F</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX> of drawings completed but also had
completed most of the higher-level assembly drawings. The
combination of these drawings with the fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was a
variant of previously fielded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-18</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft models</ENAMEX> provided the
program a significant amount of knowledge that the design was
stable at the start of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration.
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selected Acquisition</ENAMEX>
Reports.
As shown in the table, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIM-9X</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FA-18 E/F</ENAMEX> programs had
captured a significant amount of design knowledge at the start of
system demonstration and manufacturing knowledge by the start of
production. In each of those programs, product <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> had the
advantage of prior versions of the systems. These programs came
very close to meeting their original cost and schedule estimates
for product development. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATIRCM/CMWS</ENAMEX>, had less knowledge at each key junctures. Their
development cost and schedule results significantly exceeded
estimates. Specific details on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9X</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATIRCM/CMWS</ENAMEX>
program experiences follow.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX>-9X Program Experience
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIM-9X</ENAMEX> program began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, continuing the long-term
evolution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM-9</ENAMEX> series of short-range air-to-air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, after developing and testing a number of engineering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">prototype</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, the program held a critical design review to
determine if the program was ready to begin initial manufacturing
of a production representative prototype for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration.
At this review, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 95 percent</NUMEX> of the eventual engineering
drawings were completed-a stable design by best practices. Because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-9X</ENAMEX> was the next generation in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, the
program had significant knowledge on how to produce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>. At
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> critical design review, the estimated development and
production costs totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.82 billion</NUMEX>. As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2001</TIMEX>, the
estimate was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.96 billion</NUMEX>, less than a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> increase.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22 Program Experience The F-22</ENAMEX> program
began detailed design efforts in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> when it entered a planned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year</TIMEX> product development phase. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, about the expected
midpoint of the phase, the program held its critical design review
to determine if the design was stable and complete. Despite having
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about a quarter</NUMEX> of the eventual design drawings completed for
the system, the program declared the design to be stable and ready
to begin initial manufacturing. At that time, the program office
had estimated the cost to complete the development program at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>. However, the program did not complete <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of its
drawings for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998, 3 years</TIMEX> into the system
demonstration phase. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of the initial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>,
several design and manufacturing problems surfaced that affected
the deliveries of major sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. Large sections
were delivered incomplete to final assembly and had to be built out
of the planned assembly sequence.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review team</ENAMEX> examined the program and
determined the product development effort was underestimated. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> found that building the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was taking
substantially <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more labor hours</TIMEX> than planned. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1995 and 1998</TIMEX>,
the development estimate for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> increased by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $3.3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> and the schedule slipped by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Achieving design
stability late has contributed to further cost increases. As of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2001</TIMEX>, the estimated development cost was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26.1 billion</NUMEX>, a
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX> increase since the critical design review was held in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> attributes some production cost increases to a
reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> quantities, it has been significantly affected by
design and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATIRCM/CMWS</ENAMEX> Program Experience
manufacturing problems that started during development. The
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review team</ENAMEX> evaluated the cost impact on the production
aircraft that would likely occur because of cost and schedule
problems in development and found that production <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> would
have to begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, at a slower pace, and cost more than expected.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> estimated that production costs could increase by as much
as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 billion</NUMEX> if savings were not found. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
subsequently increased the estimate to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $19 billion</NUMEX> in
cost savings required to avoid cost increases. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, when the
F-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> limited production decision was made, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> had less
knowledge about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>'s reliability and manufacturing
processes than more successful cases. For example, at its limited
production decision, it had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 44 percent</NUMEX> of its critical
manufacturing processes in control. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2001</TIMEX>, the program
reported that overall production cost would likely increase by more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.4 billion</NUMEX>. This estimate was based on the effort needed so
far to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> during product development.
Since it began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATIRCM/CMWS</ENAMEX> program has had
significant cost growth and schedule delays during product
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. The product <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> held a major design review in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX>, the review demanded less proof about the
product's design in the form of engineering drawings before
deciding to begin initial manufacturing. At that time, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 21</NUMEX>
percent of the engineering drawings had been completed, and it was
still unknown whether the design would meet the requirements. In
fact, the program knew that a major redesign of a critical
component was needed. Despite this, the program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> deemed the
risk acceptable for moving the program forward to begin
manufacturing prototypes. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 2 years</TIMEX>, the program
encountered numerous design and manufacturing problems. It was not
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 2 years</TIMEX> after the critical design review, that
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> felt that the design had stabilized; however, by
this time, the product development cost had increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">160 percent</NUMEX>
and production had been delayed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 3 years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATIRCM/CMWS</ENAMEX> is scheduled to begin limited production in early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, but without the same degree of assurance as the more
successful programs that the product can be manufactured within
cost, schedule, and quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. The program has not yet
determined if manufacturing processes needed to build the product
are in control. Many of the development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> were built by hand,
in different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, and with different processes and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. Program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> stated that because they did not
stabilize the design until late in development, manufacturing
issues were not adequately addressed. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the estimated
unit cost for the system has increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">182 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 3</ENAMEX>
Best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Practices Enable Timely Capture of Design and Manufacturing</ENAMEX>
Knowledge
Leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have been successful in achieving
product development goals because they have found ways to enable
the capture of design and manufacturing knowledge about the
products they are developing in a timely way. We found two
practices that allowed leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to capture
necessary knowledge for product development. First, they
established a framework of evolutionary product development that
limited the amount of design and manufacturing knowledge that had
to be captured. This framework limited the design challenge for any
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> new product development by requiring risky technology, design,
or manufacturing requirements to be deferred until a future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of the product. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) employed a
disciplined product development process that brought together and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> all of the technologies, components, and subsystems
required for the product to ensure the design was stable before
entering product demonstration and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) demonstrated the product was
reliable and producible using proven manufacturing processes before
entering production.
The product development process includes tools that both capture
knowledge and tie this knowledge to decisions about the product's
design and manufacturing processes before making commitments that
would significantly affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> resources. For example, during
system integration, each leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> used various
forms of prototypes and information from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX> products to
stabilize the product's design and identify critical processes,
then used a decision review that required agreements from key
stakeholders that the requisite design knowledge was captured in
making a decision to move into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> demonstration. During system
demonstration, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> used statistical process control and
reliability testing to ensure the product could be produced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affordably</ENAMEX> and would be reliable, then used a similar decision
review that required agreements from key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> that the
requisite knowledge was captured when deciding to move into
production.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> (DOD) programs that we reviewed used
some of these practices to varying degrees and experienced
predictable outcomes. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIM-9X</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/A-18 E/F</ENAMEX>
programs were evolutionary in nature, modifications of existing
products with a manageable amount of new technological or design
challenges. They also gathered design and manufacturing knowledge,
although not to the extent we found at commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
Finally, they held program reviews and ensured that the design and
manufacturing knowledge was captured before moving forward. They
had relatively successful outcomes. The other DOD
Leading Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> Use
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evolutionary Product Development</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Framework</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reduce Development</ENAMEX>
Risks
programs-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATIRCMS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-did not closely
approximate best practices in capturing design or manufacturing
knowledge during product development. They took on greater design
challenges, had program reviews that were not supported by critical
design and manufacturing knowledge, and made decisions to advance
to the next phases of development without sufficient design and
manufacturing knowledge.
A key to the success of commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> was using an
evolutionary approach to develop a product. This approach permitted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to focus more on design and development with a limited
array of new content and technologies in a program. It also ensured
that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had the requisite knowledge for a product's
design before investing in the development of manufacturing
processes and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> have found that trying to
capture the knowledge required to stabilize the design of a product
that requires significant amounts of new content is an unmanageable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">task</ENAMEX>, especially if the goal is to reduce cycle times and get the
product into the marketplace as quickly as possible. Design
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> not achievable in the initial development were planned for
subsequent development efforts in future generations of the
product, but only when technologies were proven to be mature and
other resources were available.
Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have implemented the evolutionary approach
by establishing time-phased plans to develop new products in
increments based on technologies and resources achievable now and
later. This approach reduces the amount of risk in the development
of each increment, facilitating greater success in meeting cost,
schedule, and performance requirements. In effect, these companies
evolve products, continuously improving their performance as new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> and methods allow. These evolutionary improvements to
products eventually result in the full desired capability, but in
multiple steps, delivering a series of enhanced interim
capabilities to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> more quickly.
Historically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s approach has been to develop new weapon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> that often attempt to satisfy the full requirement in a
single step, regardless of the design challenge or the maturity of
technologies necessary to achieve the full capability. Under this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">single-step</ENAMEX> approach, a war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> can wait over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> to
receive any improved capability. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> shows a notional
comparison between the single-step and evolutionary approaches.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Notional Single-Step and Evolutionary Approaches to</ENAMEX>
Developing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Products</ENAMEX>

Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s analysis and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> acquisition guidance.
Each commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> we visited used the evolutionary
approach as the primary method of product development. General
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric</ENAMEX> builds on the basic capability of a fielded product by
introducing proven improvements in capability from its advanced
engineering development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX> considers the
introduction of immature technologies into fielded products or new
engine development programs as a significant cost and schedule
risk. Its new product development process is primarily focused on
reducing and managing risk for design changes and product
Leading Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> Use a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Product</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development Process</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capture Design and Manufacturing Knowledge</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Decision Making</ENAMEX>
introductions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cummins and Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> indicated
that, in the past, their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> learned the hard way by trying
to make quantum leaps in product performance and by including
immature technologies. Now, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have new product
development processes that actively manage the amount of new
content that can be placed on a new product development effort.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterpillar</ENAMEX> also limits new content on its new products as a way to
more successfully and cost-effectively develop new, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evolutionary</ENAMEX>, products. Even during the development of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">797</NUMEX>
mining truck, which it considered a major design challenge, it did
not require the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> to achieve capabilities-such as prognostics
for better maintenance-that it could not demonstrate or validate in
the design in a timely manner.
Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> DOD programs we reviewed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-the F/A-18-E/F</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9X</NUMEX>-were variations of existing products-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/A-18</ENAMEX>-C/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIM</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9M</NUMEX>-and the programs made a commitment to use existing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> and processes as much as possible. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs
had relatively successful cost and schedule outcomes. They
represented an exception to the usual practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>. The
overwhelming majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s major acquisitions today require
major leaps in capability over their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> or any other
competing weapon systems, with little knowledge about the resources
that will be required to design and manufacture the systems.
Decisions are continually made throughout product development
without knowing the cost and schedule ramifications.
Leading commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> we visited had spent significant
amounts of time and resources to develop and evolve new product
development processes that ensured design and manufacturing
knowledge was captured at the two critical decision points in
product development: when the product's design was demonstrated to
be stable-knowledge point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-and</TIMEX> when the product was demonstrated
to be producible at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an affordable</NUMEX> cost-knowledge point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The
process established a disciplined framework to capture specific
design and manufacturing knowledge about new products. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX>
then used that knowledge to make informed decisions about moving
forward in a new product development program. Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
tied this knowledge to decisions about the products' design and
manufacturing processes before making commitments that would
significantly impact company resources. Each commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> we
visited had a new product development process that was prominent
and central to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s successes. It included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Design Knowledge Should Be Captured</ENAMEX> before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entering Product Demonstration</ENAMEX>
aspects: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) activities that led to the capture of specific
design knowledge,
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) activities that led to the capture of specific manufacturing
and product reliability knowledge, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) decision reviews to
determine if the appropriate knowledge was captured to move to the
next phase.
To ensure that the product's design was stable before deciding
to commit additional resources to product demonstration, commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> demanded knowledge, either from existing product
information or by building engineering prototypes. They also used a
disciplined design review process to examine and verify the
knowledge that had culminated at the end of product integration,
This design review process required agreement from stakeholders
that the product design could be produced and would satisfy the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>'s requirements. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stakeholders</ENAMEX> included design <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>,
manufacturing or production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">supplier</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> who used engineering drawings, supported by test
results and engineering data, as a key indicator of the design's
stability. Once the program achieved a stable design, the certainty
of their cost and schedule estimates was substantially increased,
allowing them to plan the balance of the product development
program with high confidence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX> shows the activities required
to capture design knowledge that leads to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> decisions about
whether to transition to the next phase of development.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Activities to Capture Design Knowledge and Make</ENAMEX>
Decisions

Activities to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Achieve Stable Design Knowledge</ENAMEX>


•
Limit design challenge - The initial design challenge is
limited to a product that can be developed and delivered quickly
and provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> with an improved capability. A time-phased
plan is used to develop improved products-future generations-in
increments as technologies and other resources become
available.


•
Demonstrate design meets requirements -The product's
design is demonstrated to meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>'s requirements. For a new
product that is not based on an existing product, prototypes are
built and tested. If the product is a variant of an existing
product, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> often used modeling and simulation or prototypes
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component</ENAMEX> or subsystem level to demonstrate the new
product's design.


•
Complete critical design reviews - Critical design
reviews are used to assess whether a product's design meets
requirements and is ready to start initial manufacturing. They are
conducted for the system, subsystems, and components to assess
design maturity and technical risk.


•
Stakeholders agree drawings complete and producible - The
agreement by stakeholders (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>) is used to signify confidence that the design will
work and the product can be built.


•
Executive level review to begin initial manufacturing -
Corporate stakeholders meet and review relevant product knowledge,
including design stability, to determine whether a product is ready
to initiate manufacturing of production representative prototypes
used during system demonstrations. The decision is tied to the
capture of knowledge.

