



<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Protocols</ENAMEX>
lmno
A

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">03</NUMEX>-232SP <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> 20548

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2, 2002</TIMEX>
This document contains <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Protocols</ENAMEX> that we are
launching in a pilot phase starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2002</TIMEX>. These
protocols are intended to govern the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>) work with executive branch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and to provide
clearly defined and transparent policies and practices on how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
will interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in the performance of its work. As you
know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in meeting its constitutional
responsibilities and strives to help improve the performance and
accountability of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the benefit of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, we
seek to maintain constructive working relationships with the
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>; conduct our work in a professional, objective,
and nonpartisan manner; and help improve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In fact, the
vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recommendations are addressed to executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> for action. I firmly believe these protocols will
help to ensure the consistency, fairness, and effectiveness of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s interactions with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and thereby enable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to
better serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
We provided an opportunity for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> (subsequently referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>), including all
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with presidentially appointed chief financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Council on Integrity</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Efficiency</ENAMEX>,
to comment on a draft of the protocols. The majority of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that responded appreciated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s initiative to develop the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protocols</ENAMEX> and said that they were comprehensive and provided a
framework for meaningful communication. We received and considered
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> comments, the majority of which we addressed. Many of
the comments sought clarification of what we expected of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> and what they could expect from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. For example, we were
asked to clarify communication procedures between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> associated with meetings, agency comments, and
recommendation follow-up. The protocols have been revised in those
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> to reflect the following:


â€¢
For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that designate a central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> liaison, we
will communicate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> liaison when executive-level
meetings are scheduled; provide the liaison with a notification
letter; and coordinate the entrance, exit, and agency comment
meetings with the liaison.


â€¢
To the extent possible, at the entrance conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
will provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> with an estimate of how long the work will
take.


â€¢
To the extent appropriate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> will hold a closeout
meeting at field locations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who are
responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of the field location and the work's
objectives.


â€¢
The purpose of the exit conference is to confirm that the
critical facts and key information used to formulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s analyses
and findings are current, correct, and complete. This information
may be provided in writing. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> did not revise the
protocols to require that such written material be provided. A
draft of the written report is provided subsequent to the exit
conference when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> comments are solicited.


â€¢
In keeping with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s values of being fair and balanced
in its work with all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has articulated its criteria for
determining the amount of time available for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> comments on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s products. In addition, the protocols have been revised to
recognize that in using these criteria, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will generally give an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 to 30 calendar days</TIMEX> to comment on a report. The exact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> will vary, depending on the nature of the engagement and the
needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">â€¢ Recommendation</ENAMEX> follow-up is a shared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and agency
responsibility. The revised protocols describe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s implementation
of this process in further detail, including how toward the end of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>, special attention is directed to the
identification of recommendations that are still open.
In addition to seeking clarification of various operational
issues, some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> raised questions concerning the statements of
our audit and access <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> cited in the protocols. We
provided additional references in some areas to clarify our
position. However, a few of the issues raised by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are
the subject of litigation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>, No. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:02CV00340</TIMEX>,
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 22, 2002</TIMEX>)); therefore, we made no changes
pending the outcome of that litigation.
I look forward to pilot testing these protocols from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> and lasting through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30, 2003</TIMEX>. After this phase, we will
make any needed refinements based on feedback received and finalize
the protocols. I, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, look forward
to using these protocols to continue to serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> while maintaining a professional, constructive
working relationship with the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that are stakeholders in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work. Questions or
comments about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Protocols</ENAMEX> may be directed to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. Dodaro</ENAMEX>, Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Operating Officer</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-5600</ENAMEX> or via e-mail
at AgencyProtocols@<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gao</TIMEX>.gov.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David M. Walker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
Contents
Letter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Protocols</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Protocols</ENAMEX>

Preface
This document contains the protocols governing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>) work at federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> (subsequently referred to in
this document as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>). The protocols are the general
principles governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s relationships with federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> conducts its work (e.g., financial audits, program reviews,
evaluations, analyses, and investigations) at these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. They
are intended to enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s working relationships with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
by building on practices that have proved successful in the past
and by establishing a framework that will supersede prior
arrangements with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
The purpose of these protocols is to set forth clearly defined
and transparent policies and practices on how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> carries out its
work at these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The protocols identify what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
can expect from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> expects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. They are
expected to cover most situations that arise during the course of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work. Furthermore, the protocols will help to ensure the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consistency</ENAMEX>, fairness, and effectiveness of interactions between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with which it works. The protocols reflect the
framework of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s engagement and audit activities. These
activities include communication between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>,
interactions during the course of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work, and follow-up on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recommendations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> follows modified protocols in work
leading up to congressional testimony and during investigations of
fraud, abuse, or misconduct conducted by its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Special</ENAMEX>
Investigations. These modified protocols are articulated in the
sections of this document entitled Testimony and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Special</ENAMEX>
Investigations.
These protocols are not applicable to the work <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> conducts in
support of its legal opinions and decisions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
issues legal opinions in response to requests from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> also has statutory authority to render
decisions on matters such as bid protests and the availability and
use of appropriated funds. Further information about this work can
be found in Bid Protests at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Descriptive Guide</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Principles</ENAMEX>

of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Appropriations Law</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Volumes I, II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>, which are
available on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Web site <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.gov.
In addition, these protocols are not meant to govern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
relationship with the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspectors General</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IG</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGs</ENAMEX> are all part of the accountability <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>;
therefore, the relationships between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGs</ENAMEX> are
considered additional to and separate from these protocols. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IG</ENAMEX> interactions are intended to underscore a constructive working
relationship that effectively leverages resources; builds a mutual
knowledge base; and maximizes the oversight of federal programs,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, and activities. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> relies on the work of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGs</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> to meet the requirements of the Chief
Financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX> (CFO) Act for audited financial statements.
Through successful working relationships between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGs</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have consistently met the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CFO</ENAMEX> requirements. Also, through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IG</ENAMEX>'s active participation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller General's Advisory</ENAMEX>
Council on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Auditing Standards</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domestic Working</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX>, and the activities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intergovernmental Audit Forums</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGs</ENAMEX> share information, identify emerging issues, and
achieve broad coordination. Furthermore, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has
a substantial ongoing audit presence, as a professional courtesy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> meets periodically with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> to (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) coordinate work between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) achieve efficiencies and minimize
duplication, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) identify specific issues that might benefit
from a collaborative effort between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Inspector</ENAMEX>
General.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission GAO</ENAMEX> examines the use of public funds; evaluates
federal programs and activities; and provides analyses, options,
recommendations, and other assistance to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> make
effective oversight, policy, and funding decisions. In this
context, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> works to continuously improve the economy, efficiency,
and effectiveness of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> through the conduct of
financial audits, program reviews, evaluations, analyses, legal
opinions, investigations, and other services. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s activities are
designed to ensure the executive branch's accountability to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Constitution</ENAMEX> and the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
accountability to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> supports congressional oversight in several ways. For
example it
â€¢ oversees government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> through financial and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">management</ENAMEX> audits to determine whether public funds are being spent
efficiently, effectively, and in accordance with applicable
laws;


â€¢
evaluates federal policies and the performance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> and programs to determine how well they are
working;


â€¢
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analyzes</ENAMEX> financing for government activities;


â€¢
conducts analyses to assess needed actions and the
implications of proposed actions;


â€¢
conducts investigations to assess whether illegal or
improper activities are occurring; and


â€¢
provides legal opinions to determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are
in compliance with laws and regulations.


Further information about the general principles governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s operating plan can be found in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Strategic Plan, both of
which are posted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Web site <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> undertakes work through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> primary
means:
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) congressional mandates, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) congressional requests,


Work
and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) legal authority allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to undertake work on its
own initiative that is intended to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> (research
and development work).


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Approach
To effectively support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> must be professional,
objective, fact-based, nonpartisan, nonideological, fair, and
balanced in all its work. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is committed to meeting the highest
level of professional standards while conducting audits,
evaluations, and investigations reflective of its core values of
accountability, integrity, and reliability. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> performs its audit
and analytical work in accordance with generally accepted
government auditing standards (GAGAS or the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yellow Book</ENAMEX>" standards
which can be found at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> conducts its
investigations-which involve allegations of serious wrongdoing that
may involve potential violations of criminal law-and its testing of
the security of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' systems, controls, and property in
accordance with standards established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Council on</ENAMEX>
Integrity and Efficiency as adapted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work.


Statutory Responsibilities
Through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Budget and Accounting Act of 1921</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">established GAO</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislative branch</ENAMEX> with the broad role of
investigating "all matters relating to the receipt, disbursement,
and application of public funds" and to "make recommendations
looking to greater economy or efficiency in public expenditures."
Since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has clarified and expanded that
original charter:


Communication between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies</ENAMEX>


â€¢
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Government Corporation Control Act of 1945</ENAMEX> provides
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> with the authority to audit the financial transactions of
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>.


â€¢
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Budget and Accounting Procedures Act of 1950</ENAMEX> assigns
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> the responsibility for establishing accounting standards for
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and for carrying out audits of internal
controls and financial management.


â€¢
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Legislative Reorganization Act of 1970</ENAMEX> and the
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974</ENAMEX> authorize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to conduct program evaluations and analyses of a broad range of
federal activities.


â€¢
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Financial Officers</ENAMEX> (CFO) <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1990</ENAMEX> and the
Government <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Management Reform Act of 1994</ENAMEX> authorize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to audit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' financial statements and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> audit the consolidated
financial statements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.


â€¢
Numerous other laws complement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s basic audit and
evaluation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> Act of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, providing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-established standards for the audit of
federal programs and activities, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Competition</ENAMEX> in Contracting
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1984</ENAMEX>, providing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s review of protested federal
contracting actions.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is committed to maintaining constructive and continuing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and major components within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
These communications will take several forms, including, as facts
and circumstances warrant, meetings between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Comptroller
General or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Operating Officer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designees</ENAMEX> at the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
confirmation (PAS) level to discuss areas of mutual interest and
concern.
Other forms of communication include periodic meetings with an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and specific communications with
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> pertaining to planned and ongoing work. Specifically:


â€¢
At least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has a
substantial ongoing audit presence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> responsible for managing and coordinating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work,
generally known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> executive liaisons, will meet with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencydesignated</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, such as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Secretary</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate Administrator</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems</ENAMEX>, or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Secretary</ENAMEX> for a particular program. These
executive-level meetings will help build an understanding of key
and emerging issues; provide an opportunity to discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s short-
and long-term work plans, as well as the general working
relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s use
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work; and facilitate the discussion of issues associated
with particular work. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that designate a central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liaison</ENAMEX>, once an executive-level meeting has been scheduled, as a
professional courtesy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will notify the liaison that the meeting
has been scheduled.


â€¢
When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> initiates work at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> can
expect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to designate a primary point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> who will be
available throughout the engagement to respond to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
requests for information on the status of work and to any concerns
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the work</TIMEX>'s scope or approach. In turn, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> expects the agency
to designate a point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> who is knowledgeable about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s relevant programs and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and is able to
facilitate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s ability to complete its work in a timely manner.
Furthermore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>-designated central liaison or point of
contact should be able to, among other things, set up necessary
meetings (such


as entrance, exit, and agency comment meetings),
identify and ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> meets with the
appropriate agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>, help resolve
problems, and coordinate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> comments on any
draft product that may result from the work.
In response to inquiries from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> not involved in a
particular ongoing review, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide information only about
the objectives, scope, and methodology of the review; the source of
the work (i.e., mandate, name of the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requester</ENAMEX>(s), or
legal authority allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to undertake work on its own
initiative that is intended to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>); and the
expected completion date, when known. For congressionally requested
work, further information may be shared after consultation with the
congressional requester(s).
Notification of Before beginning any new engagement that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">requires GAO</ENAMEX> to seek information, data, or both, from an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>,


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Work</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> generally notifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> of the work to be undertaken.
However, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> conducts an investigation it does not notify the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> of the work because to do so might jeopardize the
investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s modified protocols for investigations are
described in detail in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Special Investigations</ENAMEX> section
of this document. To the extent practical, the notice to an agency
will identify the


â€¢
engagement subject;


â€¢
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">engagement</ENAMEX>'s unique identification number (i.e.,
engagement code);


â€¢
source of the work; â€¢ objectives or key questions of the
work;


â€¢
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>(ies) and, when possible, anticipated location(s)
to be contacted;


â€¢
estimated start date for the work;




â€¢
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> frame for holding entrance conference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>;


â€¢
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> performing the engagement; and


â€¢
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> points of contact (name, telephone number, fax
number, and e-mail address).


If the objectives of the work to be performed change
significantly or if the location of the work needs to be modified,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will notify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>-designated central liaison or primary
point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> of these changes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will generally provide written notification to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
involved in the work electronically in an agreed-upon format that
protects the files from alteration. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide the
notification to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>-designated liaison or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>-designated
point of contact. If an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has not designated a central
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liaison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide the notification to the responsible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. In some instances, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> may ask an
agency liaison to distribute the notification to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
respective major components. In addition, if applicable, the
notification letter will be accompanied or followed by a notice of
visit form that includes the appropriate security clearance
information.
For certain types of work to be performed at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> may
initially provide only telephone or e-mail message notification.
Such work includes
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) congressional requests for quickly developed testimony based
on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">new work</TIMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) work that is to be completed within a short time
frame, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) requests for information on the implementation
status of recommendations made in issued reports. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
recommendation follow-up process is discussed in detail in the
Follow-up on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Recommendations</ENAMEX> section of this document. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
notifies an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> of work by telephone or e-mail message, it will
subsequently provide a notification letter in instances


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entrance Conference</ENAMEX>
when the work is on an issue with widespread national
implication or is resource intensive.
An entrance conference is a meeting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> holds with agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> at the start of an engagement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> anticipates that an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> will attempt to arrange for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to be available
for an entrance conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">no later than 14 calendar days</TIMEX> after
receiving a request for a meeting. At the entrance conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
will discuss the (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) source of the work; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) roles and
responsibilities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) information needs (e.g.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> and access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>); (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) key objectives (research
questions); (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> expects to conduct its work, when
known; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) need for any precautions to protect the data and
information, such as special clearances. To the extent possible,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> also will provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> with an estimate of how long the
work will take. During the entrance conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will also ask
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to designate a key contact to assist, as
applicable, in obtaining temporary office space in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> does not already have office space as well as fax and telephone
equipment needed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to complete its work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. In
addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> will request that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> identify
knowledgeable agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and discuss the kinds of information
that would be useful to carry out the work's objectives, such as
available studies or electronic files.
The attendance of key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>-those responsible for
work related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s key objectives- at the entrance conference
enhances the opportunity for a substantive exchange of information.
If the review includes work at separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> field locations, or
if requested by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will consider holding additional
entrance conferences when work is begun at field locations.


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Closeout Meeting at Field Locations</ENAMEX>
In certain cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work involves crosscutting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governmentwide</ENAMEX> reviews at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, including reviews
on such issues as performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and budgeting. For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work on how well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are incorporating a
results orientation into their budget decisions and resource
allocation process involves all major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. For such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governmentwide</ENAMEX> review, an entrance conference is generally held
with applicable central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Personnel Management</ENAMEX>. If
requested, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will consider either including all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
under the review at a single entrance conference or holding a
separate entrance conference with specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
Generally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will not hold an entrance conference in those
instances when it is (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) responding to congressional requests for
testimony based on ongoing or recently completed work, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
performing work that is to be completed within a short time frame
and is closely related to ongoing work, or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) updating the
implementation status of recommendations made in issued
reports.
After conducting work at a field location, to the extent
appropriate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> will hold a closeout meeting with agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who are responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of the field
location and have oversight for issues related to the work's
objectives. The purpose of the closeout meeting is to ensure that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> have been provided with a full understanding of the
information they have gathered at a field location and its
relevance to the engagement's objectives. In deciding on whether or
not a closeout meeting will be held, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will consider the
preferences of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and whether the work has
involved interviews with numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, over a significant period
of time, at that particular location.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exit Conference</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>
At the closeout meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> may discuss the implications
of the information gathered at that field location. Such
discussions may identify additional relevant information and thus
lead to further data gathering at the location. In addition, as
appropriate, the closeout meeting may cover the extent to which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> and documents were made available and access to relevant field
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> was provided. Generally, work undertaken at individual
field locations provides only location-specific information that
needs to be evaluated in the context of findings from other
locations. Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s preliminary conclusions or
recommendations are not discussed at the closeout meeting.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> holds an exit conference with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> after completing its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> collection and analysis. The purpose of the exit conference is
to confirm that the critical facts and key information used to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">formulate GAO</ENAMEX>'s analyses and findings are current, correct, and
complete. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> responsible for the completion of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">engagement</ENAMEX> will participate in the meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who
have oversight of the issues related to the engagement's objectives
are also expected to attend the meeting. Written material, if
provided, will be used to confirm that the critical facts and key
information used to formulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s analyses and findings are
current, correct, and complete. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Observations</ENAMEX>, preliminary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conclusions</ENAMEX>, and potential recommendations that flow from the
factual information collected may be discussed but are not provided
in writing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> Comments As required by generally accepted government
auditing standards, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> provides responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and
other directly affected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> with an opportunity to review and
provide comments on a draft of a report before it is issued. The
amount of time available for the
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">03</NUMEX>-232SP <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Protocols</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> to comment is determined on a facts-and-circumstances
basis. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will not seek comments from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or
affected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> when


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
disclosure of an investigation's results could pose risks
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and their confidentiality or



(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
premature disclosure of information could compromise the
results of the work. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> follows modified protocols for work
undertaken by its criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. These modified protocols
are described in the section of this document entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
Special Investigations.

In keeping with its values of being fair and balanced in all
its work with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> it reviews, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, when determining
the amount of time available for comment, will consider (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the
timing needs of the requester,


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
the extent to which substantive discussions have already
been held between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the length of time spent
on the engagement, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) the amount of resources <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> have expended to answer the engagement's objectives. Using
these criteria, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will generally give an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 to 30</NUMEX>
calendar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> to comment on a report unless otherwise required by
law. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§718(a) for a list of financial institutions
that by law must receive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> for comment. The exact time will
vary depending on the nature of the engagement and the needs of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. In rare cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> may grant an
extension beyond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 calendar days</TIMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> shows that an
extension is necessary and will likely result in a more accurate
report. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§718(b).


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reserves the right to issue the report to the congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">requester</ENAMEX>(s) if the comments are not received within the time
allotted. In such cases, the reason for not including the agency
comments will be stated in the report. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will usually not solicit
agency comments if a report summarizes information from a recently
issued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report. In addition, testimony statements generally are
not provided to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> for comment. As previously noted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
follows modified protocols for testimonies, which are described
separately in the section of this document entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Testimony</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> prefers that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> provide written comments, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is
requesting that the written comments be provided electronically.
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will accept comments provided in hard copy, orally, or
in an unsigned e-mail message. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is requesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
provide their written comments electronically in order to comply
with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act</ENAMEX>. This act requires that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> with disabilities have access to and use of information and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> that are comparable to the access and use provided to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>
without disabilities. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">§794d</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s goal is to provide
its products in a format that is compatible with assistive
technologies such as text-to-sound screen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> software.
Submitting an electronic file ensures that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s comments are
accurately reproduced in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s accessible product format. Contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publications</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissemination</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7055</ENAMEX>, for specific information about how to electronically
transmit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> comments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. Comments on classified or
restricted reports should be transmitted in the manner agreed to by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> expects an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to provide (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a single position on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
findings, conclusions, and recommendations-including a resolution
of disparate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> views if necessary-and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the rationale for
any disagreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s draft report. When an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
designated senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> provides oral comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will
summarize these comments and give the designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> an
opportunity to respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s characterization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
position. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> senior executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for the
completion of the engagement, along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> that
performed

Procedures for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soliciting Agency</ENAMEX> Comments
the work, will participate in this meeting. In addition, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governmentwide</ENAMEX> work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will generally request that comments be
provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>(ies) with whom the entrance conference was
held.
Consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX>, the congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">requester</ENAMEX>(s) will be notified before a draft report is provided to
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for comment and will be offered a copy of the draft for
informational purposes when the draft report is provided to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> for comment. Furthermore, under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§718(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Governmental Affairs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Government Reform</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>
may request copies of any draft report generated under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> to undertake work on its own initiative (research and
development work) when the draft report is sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for
comment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will advise these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> when such a draft is sent
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for comment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> does not have classification authority for its products.
Therefore, for those products that contain national security or
sensitive information, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will request that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> perform a
review for this type of information and that the review's results
be communicated in writing to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. When a product requires a
classification review, upon written receipt of the results of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s review, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will notify the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requester</ENAMEX>(s)
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has completed its classification review. Consistent
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will then offer the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">requester</ENAMEX>(s) a draft of the product that is with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for
comment. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s classification review and comments on
the product must be completed within the time frame identified in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s letter transmitting the draft product.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> transmits most draft reports for comment to agencies
electronically in an agreed-upon format that protects the files
from alteration. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide the draft report to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>-designated liaison or agencydesignated point of contact. If
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has not designated a central liaison, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide
the notification to the responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>.
Classified or otherwise sensitive draft reports are transmitted
through other means. A transmittal letter accompanies each draft
report to inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s request for written or oral
comments and the time frame within which the comments are due. The
transmittal letter also states that the draft report is not final;
is therefore subject to change; and must be safeguarded to prevent
its transmittal to unauthorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, alteration, or premature
release.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Draft GAO</ENAMEX> products are at risk of being prematurely released
once they leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s control. In some limited circumstances, when
there is concern that a draft product may be prematurely released,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will take extra precautions in obtaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> comments. For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> may decide not to transmit a draft report
electronically and instead provide limited printed copies of the
draft to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> may determine that the
particular sensitivity of a draft report's information or
recommendations requires restrictive comment procedures. In these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instances</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> may request that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> review the draft
report in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and that these officials
provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s consolidated comments at that time. In such
cases, the draft report will be available for review only at a
meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> may take notes as
they review the draft, at the conclusion of the meeting, all copies
of the draft report will be returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disposition of Agency</ENAMEX> Comments
After receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> considers their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>,
revises the draft report as appropriate, and indicates in the
issued report whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> agreed or disagreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
findings, conclusions, and recommendations. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> disagrees
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s findings, conclusions, and recommendations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will
accept further explanations from agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in support of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s position. However, any available documented evidence
supporting this explanation must be provided simultaneously to
allow for verification if it materially affects the content of the
report. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> disagrees with a finding, conclusion, or
recommendation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> identifies the disagreement and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> its own
position in the issued report. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s electronic or hard-copy
written comments are typically reproduced in an appendix to the
issued report. Unsigned e-mail describing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s comments will
not be printed in the issued report. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> identifies the
disposition of this e-mail message in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> Comments section
of the report, just as it does for oral comments.
On occasion, the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>(s) who requested the work
may ask to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s comments before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s final report is
issued. Copies of written comments on a draft <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> with the requester(s) if the requester(s) specifically
ask(s) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> for the comments and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has evaluated the comments and
developed its position on them. Comments will not be shared with
anyone else, including congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> not associated with the
request, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, or other external <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, until the report is
released and posted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Web site <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.gov.
Testimony Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> Chairs
frequently request that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> prepare testimony statements and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> appear at hearings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is required to follow the
rules of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and the
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">03</NUMEX>-232SP <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Protocols</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittees</ENAMEX> in connection
with any such testimonies. Accordingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Protocols</ENAMEX> are
modified for these requirements as described in this section. For
example, because most hearing appearances are requested and
statements are delivered within short time frames or are based on
work that is new and quickly developed, ongoing or already
completed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> generally does not hold an entrance conference with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> need to be contacted for
information that was not previously obtained or was not part of a
previous review, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will notify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>-designated central
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liaison</ENAMEX>, generally by telephone or e-mail message. If the agency
has not designated a liaison, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide notification to the
responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>.
For testimony based on new or ongoing work, regardless of
whether it is a preliminary or a final product, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will obtain the
views of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> on the information collected from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> to


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
validate the accuracy of the data gathered and


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
discuss the implications that flow from the data
gathered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s views are generally obtained through a
meeting with the official designated to speak for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or
through other means, such as a telephone conference call. The views
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> will be considered in the development of the
testimony statement. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is unable to schedule a meeting
to provide its views within the time frame specified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, the
testimony statement will reflect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> was unable to obtain the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s views. Generally, when the testimony statement is based on
recently reported work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will not seek agency views.
Additionally, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> testifies on investigations it conducts, it
does not obtain testimony statement views because such actions
could jeopardize future proceedings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s modified protocols
related to investigations are explained in greater detail in the
separate section of this document entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>





<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disposition of Work</ENAMEX>
Special Investigations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will distribute its written
testimony statement in accordance with the rules of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, including the applicable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>' or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittees</ENAMEX>'
rules.
Consistent with generally accepted government auditing
standards, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> prefers using published products to communicate the
final results of its work because they
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) communicate the results consistently to all interested
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) make the results available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) build a
readily available subject-matter record for future use, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
facilitate follow-up to determine whether appropriate corrective
measures have been taken when needed. However, an oral briefing may
be used, for example, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) determines that further work is
not warranted; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) provides information that is readily available
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, such as that in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> reports; or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
develops a summary of previously issued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> products that does not
contain any new findings, conclusions, or recommendations. In these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instances</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will notify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>-designated central liaison or
point of contact that the engagement has been terminated without a
written product.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide electronic copies of reports to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> upon
issuance or release. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> responsible for the engagement will
provide to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> contact via e-mail the final electronic
version of the report and the transmittal letter. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will
provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with hard copies of the report, if requested.
In addition to providing copies of the product to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
involved, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s goal is to post written products on its Web site
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> of release. All congressionally
requested products will have a targeted issue date that is
determined through negotiations between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the requester(s).
However, the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requester</ENAMEX>(s)


Follow-up on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Recommendations</ENAMEX>
may ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to restrict the release of a product for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 30</NUMEX>
calendar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> beyond the targeted issuance date. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reserves the
right to release any product that has been issued to the
congressional requester but is under restriction if the product's
contents are made public prior to the expiration of the restriction
date. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> products that contain classified or restricted data are
not posted on the Web site. Classified products are distributed
only to those with the appropriate security clearances and a need
to know. Restricted versions of products that contain sensitive
information are distributed only to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> who are authorized
by statute or regulation to receive the products, have a need to
know, or both.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recommendations are intended to improve the economy,
efficiency, and effectiveness of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s operations and to
improve the accountability of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the
benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Consequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> monitors
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' progress in implementing these recommendations. To
accomplish this monitoring, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> maintains a database of open
recommendations. As new products with recommendations are released,
their recommendations are incorporated into the database. This
database serves both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> by helping them meet
their record maintenance and monitoring responsibilities.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s goal is to remove all closed recommendations from the
database on an ongoing basis. However, toward the end of each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>, special attention is directed to this effort. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
removes a recommendation from its database after determining that
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has implemented the recommendation or has taken
action that in substance meets the intent of the recommendation or
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) circumstances have changed and the recommendation is no longer
relevant. The open recommendations database is available to the
public on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Web site <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specific</ENAMEX> recommendations can
be identified because the database is searchable by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>,
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, and key words. Congressional oversight and
authorization <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appropriations Committees</ENAMEX>,
can use the database to prepare for hearings and budget
deliberations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies</ENAMEX> also have a responsibility to monitor and maintain
accurate records on the status of recommendations. These
requirements are detailed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB Circulars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB Circular</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
provides the policies and procedures for use by executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
when considering reports issued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspectors General</ENAMEX>,
other executive branch audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and nonfederal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>
where follow-up is necessary; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Circular A-123</ENAMEX> addresses
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> management control systems. Among the requirements
included are that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) appoint a top-level audit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">follow-up</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) maintain accurate records on the status of
recommendations, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) assign a high priority to following up on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">audit</ENAMEX> recommendations.
Additionally, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> issues a report containing
recommendations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§720</ENAMEX> requires
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> head submit a written statement of the actions
taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recommendations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Governmental Affairs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Committee on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Reform</ENAMEX> not later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX> after the date of the
report. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s statement of action shall also be submitted to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Committees on Appropriations</ENAMEX> with the first
request for appropriations that is submitted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 60 days</TIMEX>
after the date of the report. If the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requester</ENAMEX> has
asked that the distribution of the report be restricted, as
provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Protocols</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> period will
begin on the date the report is released.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Investigations</ENAMEX>
Because agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> serve as the primary source of
information on the status of recommendations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> requests that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> also provide it with a copy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s statement of
action to serve as preliminary information on the status of open
recommendations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will follow up by discussing the status of
recommendations with cognizant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>; obtaining copies
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> documents supporting the recommendations' implementation;
and performing sufficient work to verify that the recommended
actions are being taken and, to the extent possible, that the
desired results are being achieved.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Special Investigations</ENAMEX> (OSI) is a specialized unit
within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> that is staffed by criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX>'s mission
is to improve the performance and ensure the accountability of
government by conducting oversight investigations concerning
allegations of serious wrongdoing that may involve potential
violations of criminal law. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> investigations disclose
potential violations of law, the information is referred to the
appropriate law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Inspector</ENAMEX>
General or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> investigations typically
focus on allegations of corruption, fraud, misconduct, contract and
procurement improprieties, conflicts of interest, and ethics
violations in federal programs or activities.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> also engages in proactive operations that test the security
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' systems, controls, and property. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> are
coordinated with appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> will inform the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> of any serious security issues
discovered during these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> shortly after the operations
have been completed and before any of the related findings are made
public. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX>'s work involves law enforcement-related
issues or programs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> also utilizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FraudNET</ENAMEX>, an automated system that
affords the public an opportunity to report allegations of fraud,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waste</ENAMEX>, abuse, and mismanagement of federal funds. Typically, OSI
refers this information to the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> or another law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for action. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
expects to receive a report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> on the results of the
action.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> conducts its investigations and other work in accordance
with the standards established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Council on</ENAMEX>
Integrity and Efficiency as adapted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work. In accordance
with these standards, all OSI work is conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who
collectively possess the required knowledge, skills, and abilities
to perform it and who exercise due professional care (e.g.,
thoroughness, appropriate use of investigative techniques,
impartiality, objectivity, protection of individual rights, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">timeliness</ENAMEX>) in the performance of their work. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> seeks evidence of
wrongdoing either in conjunction with or independently of audits
and evaluations. It focuses on physical, testimonial, documentary,
and analytical evidence that is relevant, material, and admissible
in criminal and civil proceedings. To ensure admissibility in
subsequent judicial proceedings, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> performs its work in
accordance with the requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">U.S. Constitution</ENAMEX>,
statutes, and court decisions applicable to obtaining evidence in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> and civil cases.
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> expects that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> will promptly
comply with requests for access to its records and to agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> directly involved with the matter under investigation.
Furthermore, there should be no interference with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>'s
ability to obtain relevant information concerning an investigative
matter. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> becomes aware of an ongoing executive branch
investigation pertaining to a matter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> is currently
investigating, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> will coordinate its work with the law
enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> involved.


Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Information</ENAMEX>
Investigations by their very nature do not support the use of
entrance or exit conferences. Nor do the standards of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council on Integrity</ENAMEX> and Efficiency require these
conferences. Revealing information at the start of an investigation
may lead to the destruction or concealment of evidence, thus
jeopardizing the investigation. However, in investigations that
will result in a public report or testimony, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> will brief agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> after the investigation has been completed and before the
information is made public. On occasion, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> works jointly with
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> or independently on compliance or evaluation
issues. In those cases, the provisions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s standard agency
protocols are applicable.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> relies on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to examine virtually every federal
program, activity, and policy, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> that rely on
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funds</ENAMEX>. Generally accepted government auditing standards
make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> responsible for planning,
conducting, and reporting their work in a timely manner without
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> or external impairments to the work. These standards
require that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> promptly obtain
sufficient, competent, and relevant evidence to afford a reasonable
basis for any related findings and conclusions. Therefore, prompt
access to all records and other information associated with these
activities is needed for the effective and efficient performance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work. While for the most part, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have provided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
with requested information within agreed-upon time frames, the
following sections describe the steps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is authorized to follow
if it believes it is experiencing unreasonable delays in obtaining
the requested access.

Handling and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disclosing Information</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> broad statutory rights of access to a
wide range of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> documents. The basic access authority
is established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§716(a), which requires each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to
give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> "information the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> requires about the
duties, powers, activities, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, and financial
transactions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is also authorized to inspect an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency's</ENAMEX> records to secure the required information. This authority
includes access to inter- and intra-agency memorandums and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electronic</ENAMEX> files as well as sensitive information, including
business-confidential or proprietary data. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom of</ENAMEX>
Information Act, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Trade Secrets Act</ENAMEX>, and other statutes may
generally protect certain categories of information from disclosure
by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, this protection does not justify
withholding the information from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has a statutory right to
access predecisional and deliberative documents unless the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> certifies that certain standards
are met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 31</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§716(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(C), as added by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Office Act of 1980</ENAMEX>. (For further information see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
Report No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-570</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 8, 1980</TIMEX>, pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6-8</ENAMEX>.) Aside from the general
access statute, various forms of special legislation govern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
access to certain types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> records and information, such as
tax, social security, financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, and employee benefit
plan records and information. In addition, under certain
circumstances, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has the authority to access information from
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> receiving federal funds, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, and private sector
contractors.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> secures all information obtained during the course of its
work. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> needs access to classified, proprietary, or
otherwise sensitive information, it will comply with all applicable
statutory requirements, including obtaining the necessary security
and other clearances for assigned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. Under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Â</ENAMEX>§716(e), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is obligated to give the information the


Obtaining Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>
same level of confidentiality and protection required of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>. Because of its statutory access authority, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> generally
does not sign a nondisclosure or other agreement as a condition of
gaining access to sensitive or proprietary data to which it is
entitled.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is not subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Freedom of Information Act</ENAMEX>, its
disclosure policy follows the spirit of the act consistent with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s duties and responsibilities to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. It is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
policy not to provide records to the public that originated in
another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or a nonfederal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> refers
those who request such records to the originating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.
Further information on the public availability of the documents and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> that form <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s workpapers can be found in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R. part</ENAMEX>
81.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will grant congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX>, upon their written
request, access to its workpapers at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> site or will provide
copies of selected workpapers only after a product that results
from the workpapers in question has been made publicly available.
This access is subject to legal and privacy considerations, such as
those concerning taxpayer return information, protected banking
information, grand jury information, and credit card account
information listed in travel vouchers.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work involves different collection approaches to meet the
evidence requirements of the generally accepted government auditing
standards. Such evidence falls into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> categories:


â€¢
physical evidence (e.g., the results of direct inspection
or observation);


â€¢
documentary evidence (e.g., information created by and
for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, such as letters, memorandums, contracts, management
and accounting records, and




<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Resolving Disputes Over Access</ENAMEX>
other documents in various formats, including
electronic databases);


â€¢
testimonial evidence (e.g., the results of face-to-face,
telephone, or written inquiries, interviews, and questionnaires);
and


â€¢
analytical evidence (developed by or for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> through
computations, data comparisons, and other analyses).


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> expects that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> will promptly comply with its
requests for access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s records so that it can obtain
all categories of needed evidence. Such access generally includes
the ability to make and retain copies of the evidence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> also
expects that it will receive full and timely access to agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who have stewardship over the requested records; to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who are responsible for the programs, issues,
events, operations, and other factors covered by such records; and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor personnel</ENAMEX> supporting such programs, issues, events, and
operations. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> expects that it will have access to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and other relevant locations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will
endeavor to conduct work related to requests for information with
minimal interruption to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s operations.
Timely access to information is in the best interests of both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> needs to efficiently use the time
available to complete its work to minimize the impact on the agency
being reviewed and to meet the time frames of the congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">requester</ENAMEX>(s). Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> expects that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s leadership
and internal procedures will recognize the importance of and
support prompt responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s requests for information. For the
most part, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have provided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> with requested information
within agreed-upon time frames. However, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> believes it is
experiencing unreasonable delays in obtaining requested access, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> will contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> for resolution and
notify the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requester</ENAMEX>(s) of the work affected, as
appropriate. Consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s reporting standards, when there
is difficulty in obtaining timely access to information that
adversely affects either the completion of an engagement, its
scope, or both, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s product will reflect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> had this
difficulty. In addition, unreasonable delays in gaining access to
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s information can reduce the time available for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> to provide its views or comments on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work.
To ensure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s access to information maintained by federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> provided in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§716(b) for
enforcement actions to compel the production of a record. First,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> sends a written request to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> head
for the record that has not been made available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> within a
reasonable time after an initial request. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> head then has
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 calendar days</TIMEX> to respond, either by providing the record for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX> or by explaining why it is being withheld. If the agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> does not provide the record, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> may file
a report describing the access issues with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> head, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> head does not provide the record within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>
calendar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the report's filing, the statute authorizes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> to bring a civil action in federal district
court to enforce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s access rights. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> is
successful in this action, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> will issue an order directing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> head to produce the record.
Extremely limited exceptions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> are established in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§716(b) for a civil enforcement action to compel access
to a record. The most notable exception is if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> certifies that (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the record could be withheld
under either of two <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Freedom of Information Act</ENAMEX> exemptions in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§552(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) (deliberative process) and (b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) (law
enforcement records) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) disclosure could reasonably be
expected to impair substantially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>-a
requirement that, as the legislative history of Section 716 makes
clear, presents a very high standard for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to meet. As
previously noted, the fact that materials may be exempt from public
disclosure does not justify withholding them from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. Moreover,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s statutory right of access to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s records is not
diminished by the certification provisions of the legislation.
Rather, the certification simply allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> to preclude the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> from seeking a
judicial remedy in certain limited situations. In the event there
is a certification, generally accepted government auditing
standards require that the limitations to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s access to records
be identified in the product and that the audit findings be
adjusted accordingly.
Press <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy GAO</ENAMEX> does not initiate press conferences, but senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> may participate in press conferences held by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, if requested. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> generally does not issue
press statements about products, it does advise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> of the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> products via its
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Web site www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX> and other venues. In response to inquiries
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> about ongoing work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide information
only about the objectives, scope, and methodology of a review; the
source of the work (mandate, name of congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requester</ENAMEX>(s), or
legal authority allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to undertake work on its own
initiative that is intended to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>); and the
expected completion date. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will refer inquiries for any
additional information to the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requester</ENAMEX>(s). However,
in response to media inquiries about ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSI</ENAMEX> investigations,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will neither confirm nor deny the existence of such an
investigation. As a professional courtesy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will inform the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">requester</ENAMEX>(s) of substantive media inquiries during an ongoing
review. As appropriate, such courtesy will be extended by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> staff
conducting the work to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>-designated central liaison or
point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> for the work. Once a product is publicly released,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with expertise in the subject matter will answer
questions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> when asked. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reporter's Guide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is
available on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Web site <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.gov.
Broadcast interviews-radio, television, and Internet-are done
only on request and only when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> deems them appropriate for public
understanding of the facts, findings, conclusions, and
recommendations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s products. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s policy is that senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> with the broadest knowledge of a completed engagement do
such interviews. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> agrees to a broadcast interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
will advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">requester</ENAMEX>(s) of the media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> and the expected date
and time. If asked to participate in press briefings sponsored by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">requester</ENAMEX>(s), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide support if the press briefing is
held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> In such instances, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will provide
knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with the understanding that they are present
only to answer questions about the specifics of released <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
products.



Ordering and Comment Information

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obtaining Copies</ENAMEX>:
The fastest and easiest way to obtain copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> documents is
through the Internet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Web site (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>) contains
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abstracts</ENAMEX> and full-text files of current reports and testimony and
an expanding archive of older products. The Web site features a
search engine to help you locate documents using key words and
phrases. You can print these documents in their entirety, including
charts and other graphics.

To order by Phone: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX>: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-6000</TIMEX> TDD: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2537</ENAMEX>
Fax: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6061</ENAMEX>
Comments: Comments on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Protocols</ENAMEX> can be provided by
e-mail to AgencyProtocols@<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gao</TIMEX>.gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presorted Standard Postage & Fees Paid GAO Permit No.</ENAMEX>
GI00
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">20548-0001</ENAMEX>
Official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Penalty</ENAMEX> for Private Use <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Address Service Requested</ENAMEX>






