



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>


<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2003</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO FORUM ON GOVERNANCE AND ACCOUNTABILITY</ENAMEX>
Challenges to Restore Public Confidence in


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Corporate Governance and Accountability Systems</ENAMEX>
a


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">03</NUMEX>-419SP





<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Governance</ENAMEX> and Accountability

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum Discussion</ENAMEX>
There was general agreement among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> that the root
causes of the accountability breakdowns are systemic in nature,
complex, and will require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and alterations to the current
models in each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> interrelated areas to transition to an
overall system that is more focused on protecting the public
interest and, in that regard, accountability. They also agreed that
considerable actions have been taken and/or proposed towards
achieving those objectives, but that having the "right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" and
"stakeholders" involved was critical to successfully achieve and
effectively maintain the necessary reforms. Several other key
observations follow:


•
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> are reassessing their roles and
responsibilities and currently it is difficult to determine what is
working and what is not working.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> agreed there is no "silver bullet" to
enhancing the effectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> in their role of
overseeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and protecting the public interest. However,
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to effectively perform its responsibilities, it must
have the "right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" who possess an "independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>" and are
"knowledgeable" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>/industry and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX>.


•
Little progress has been made moving toward a more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> financial reporting model that would include such
information as operating and performance measures and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forward-looking</ENAMEX> information about opportunities, risks, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s plans.


•
The impetus for changing the financial reporting model
needs more involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of financial
information as the current model is too driven by those who have
historically focused more on the technical aspects of financial
reporting, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of directors.


•
An "artful blend" of principle-based and rule-based
accounting standards, as well as a financial reporting model with
different tiers of reporting that provides full disclosure, are
fundamental changes needed to improve the financial reporting
model.


•
An "expectation gap" of what an audit is and what users
expect continues to exist, especially with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX>'s
responsibility for fraud detection.


•
Supplementing the traditional financial statement audit
with a "forensic audit" as well as with a more informative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">auditor</ENAMEX>'s report could help to narrow the "expectation
gap."


•
A strong, viable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> is
needed to maintain investor confidence. Concern was raised that the
Commission is not fully at that status and that funding issues need
to be resolved.


•
The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Company Accounting Oversight Board</ENAMEX> needs
to officially get up and running with immediate priorities focusing
on establishing policies and procedures for performing its
disciplinary, inspection, and standardsetting functions.


Contents

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller General Aof the United States</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20548</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 24, 2003</TIMEX>
The last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 years</TIMEX> witnessed major accountability breakdowns at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldCom</ENAMEX> leading to significant restatements of financial
statements and bankruptcy adversely affecting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, such failures were not
isolated instances as other accountability breakdowns in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qwest, Tyco, Adelphia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Crossing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro Strategy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Federal Savings Banks</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX>. Although stakeholders of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were directly
affected by the accountability breakdowns, these failures have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cumulatively</ENAMEX> contributed to the general shaking of investor
confidence in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> capital markets.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 25, 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> held a forum to discuss
systemic issues related to these accountability failures, such as
corporate governance, accounting and reporting, and auditing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>
Since that time, major reform legislation has been enacted-the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX>-and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> have proposed and/or
finalized a number of new requirements to address issues related to
the failures. However, much of the regulatory reform action is in
process and experience will be needed to evaluate the effectiveness
of the changes. Moreover, the changes to date do not address all
the issues raised by the accountability breakdowns.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 9, 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> convened a governance and
accountability <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> for the purpose of identifying past, pending,
and proposed actions designed to protect the public interest by


•
identifying challenges to improving public confidence in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> corporate governance and accountability systems to assist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, the accounting profession, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to effectively implement the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX> and other related regulatory actions
and


•
placing special interest on steps designed to enhance
independence of the corporate governance system and enhancing the
accounting/auditing and attest/assurance models for the 21st
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>.


1U.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Highlights</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Governance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transparency and Accountability Forum</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-494SP(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2002</TIMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Page 1 GAO-03-419SP Governance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accountability Forum</ENAMEX>
Specifically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> focused on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> interrelated
areas-corporate governance, the financial reporting model, the
accounting profession, and regulation and enforcement.
The invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, private, and
not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> having extensive experience and subject
matter expertise in the accounting profession, corporate governance
issues, financial reporting and disclosure models, auditing,
accounting, and related regulatory issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> also extended
invitations to chairs and ranking minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of relevant
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> invites attended. As agreed with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, the purpose of the discussion was not to reach a
consensus, but rather to engage in an open, no attribution-based
dialogue. Therefore, this report summarizes the collective
discussion and does not necessarily represent the views of any
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> acknowledged that recent legislative and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regulatory</ENAMEX>



Corporate Governance
reforms in response to issues raised by significant restatements
of financial statements and corporate failures were placing greater
emphasis on the roles and responsibilities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of directors.
They noted that many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> are reassessing their roles and
responsibilities and, at this time, it is difficult to determine
what is working and what is not working. Information on best
practices of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> would be useful to help improve board
operations, for example in areas of improving communications with
management and using external <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
generally agreed that there is no "silver bullet" for enhancing the
effectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> in their role of oversight of
management and protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>.
In discussing the role and responsibilities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> stated that it starts with having the right
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> who are independent, knowledgeable, and ethical
and whose integrity is unquestionable. The basic roles and
responsibilities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> were defined as enhancing shareholder
value, assessing and monitoring risk, and ensuring management
accountability. It was noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> need to do a better job of
identifying their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> and understanding and addressing
their concerns. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have a responsibility to
educate themselves about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s operations and plans and to
seek advice of external <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, when and as appropriate.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also focused on the roles of the nominating,
compensation, and audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> noting that (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) nominating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX> need to independently identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for board
membership rather than "rubber stamp" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
compensation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> need to focus more on achievements related
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s long-term strategic objectives and less on
short-term accomplishments, such as meeting earnings projections,
and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> need to work more effectively with the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> as defined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX>,
and not get "tied up" in procedural matters concerned with their
legal liabilities as committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> stressed that having the "right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> was just as important if not more so than having the right
rules. In that respect, it was noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> should
possess an "independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>" to ask the tough and probing
questions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> stated that the existing
system for identifying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> might not always be attracting
the "right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." For example, it was stated that some board
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are serving on too many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> to be effective, and that
some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are serving for personal incentives that could
adversely affect their independence. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> believed
that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s environment, potential legal liabilities were
adversely affecting finding qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> believed that there is no shortage of qualified board
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> willing to serve and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> needed to look beyond
the "list of usual suspects."
The traditional financial statements, in terms of form and
content, have not


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Reporting</ENAMEX>
changed much over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. The financial reporting model uses
a mixture of historical costs and fair value to present a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
transactions. This model has value but fails to meet the broader
range of information needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who want more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forward-looking</ENAMEX> information and data that reflect a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
overall performance, risk profile, and expectations for future
performance.
Little progress has been made in moving toward a more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> reporting model that would include both financial
information (financial statements and related disclosures) and
nonfinancial information (such as high-level operating and
performance measures used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and forward-looking
information about opportunities, risks, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s plans).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> stated that the current model is too driven by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accountants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> who have historically focused on the technical aspects of
financial reporting and are more likely to move slowly and
cautiously in making


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting Profession</ENAMEX>
changes. As a result, the current model has failed to get
adequate "traction" to move toward a more comprehensive reporting
model.
Going forward, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> believed that the impetus for change
to the financial reporting model would have to come more from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of financial information who need timely,
accurate, and useful information to make value and risk judgments
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> publicly traded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Also, a safe harbor for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preparers</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> of more forwardlooking information may be necessary to
progress. Other suggestions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> included moving toward
more principle-based accounting rules to provide more substance
versus form in reporting. There was general agreement that (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a
combination of principle-based and rule-based standards would be
needed and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) principle-based accounting rules were not a panacea
to solve financial reporting problems. In that respect, some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> suggested that standard setters <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> needed to get
the basics right with the current financial reporting model, for
example in areas such as accounting for pensions, post-employment
benefits, and pro-forma financial statements, to help restore
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> confidence. It was also suggested that the financial
reporting model have different layers of reporting, while still
having full disclosure, coupled with different levels of assurances
depending on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' needs. Such layering would allow a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to
"drill down" to the level of detail needed.
An expectation gap between what an audit is and is not continues
to exist, especially with regard to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX>'s responsibility
for detecting fraud. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> believed a periodic forensic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">audit</ENAMEX> may be needed to supplement the traditional financial
statement audit to assist in detecting fraud. However, it was
recognized that an audit cannot create precision or certainty where
such factors do not exist, as financial statements are not as
precise as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> may believe. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and audit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX> have important roles and responsibilities for internal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> to prevent and detect fraud. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>
will help to close the expectation gap concerning the effectiveness
management and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> reporting on these controls. Nonetheless, an
expectation gap may still exist as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> may be expecting that an
audit addresses internal control over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s overall
operations and performance. Educating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> on the terminology of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> control reporting, such as reportable conditions, was also
urged so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and capital markets do not over react in
interpreting the internal control reports.


Regulation and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enforcement</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> suggested the need for a new reporting model for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">auditing</ENAMEX>, a renewed focus on the quality of auditing, and building
more effective working relationships with the audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. It
was recognized that the standard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX>'s report could be made
more useful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> who are seeking greater information about what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> did and found, as well as expanded assurances. Tiered
reporting that would provide expanded optional assurances was
suggested. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> stated that the quality of audits can be
adversely affected by "time and fee pressures" that lead to less
substantive auditing. Caution was also urged that rotation of audit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX> does not have
the unintended consequence of adversely affecting the quality of
audits through loss of experience with a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
operations and financial reporting. It was recognized that
confidence in audits needs to be restored not only for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>,
but also to attract and retain the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for the accounting
profession over time.
A strong, viable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>) is
needed to maintain investor confidence in the markets. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX>
recognized that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s resources had not kept up with its
increased workload over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. This situation has adversely
affected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s ability to adequately enforce the securities
laws and also its ability to invest in technology to more
efficiently manage its workload. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> suggested that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> may wish to consider pursuing the status to operate
independently in setting its own funding levels, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve</ENAMEX> does. It was also suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> needed to explore
how it is using its enforcement powers, as civil penalties may
ultimately be hurting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> more than those who have
violated the securities laws. In that respect, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> should
reexamine the amount and targeting of its civil sanctions, its use
of criminal statutes, and working effectively with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> to put violators behind bars when appropriate.
to officially get up and running. Suggested priorities for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> included establishing policies and procedures for
disciplinary actions and conducting inspections of registered
public accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. Also, decisions need to be made on the
setting of standards for auditing, quality control, ethics, and
independence. It was also suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> should evaluate
the recent events that have affected the public's confidence in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> to consider what further actions may be needed beyond
those mandated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX> and recent
regulatory changes and proposals. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> needs to
work cooperatively with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of accountancy.
The fragmentation of the regulatory system for the public
accounting profession was not completely dealt with by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX>. At a minimum, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> will need to
effectively work with the other public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> on
enforcement/disciplinary matters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> generally believed
that the provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX> should be
implemented and assessed before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should consider adding
any new legislative requirements; however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> agreed that
much can and should be done by other responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, such as
by regulatory and self-regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, within their existing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>.
Restoring public trust and confidence in a manner that can be
sustained


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Observations</ENAMEX>
over the long-term will require concerted actions by a variety
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, including accounting and auditing standard setters,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX> provides a strong framework for more
effective corporate governance and regulation of the accounting
profession. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and the stock exchanges, along with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Accounting Standards Board</ENAMEX>, have also been actively
making progress to address a range of issues raised by the
accountability breakdowns. However, the fundamental principles of
providing the right incentives, providing adequate transparency,
and ensuring appropriate accountability are even more important and
relevant as the new structure and reforms are being
established.
It is important to recognize that rules alone will not
effectively resolve the problems that resulted in massive
restatements of financial statements and ultimately bankruptcy of
certain public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> cannot legislate nor can
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> establish by rule human behavior or integrity to always
do the right thing in protecting the public's interest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> needs to set the appropriate "tone at the top"
and that culture needs to be carried throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and
exhibited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> in its oversight of management
and in its protection of shareholder interests.
The accounting profession needs to vigorously work to rebuild
its greatest asset-public trust-in order to restore faith in the
integrity and objectivity of the profession. Accounting and
auditing standards need to be reexamined to provide enhanced value
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of financial statements, related disclosures, and more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> business reporting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> of these products will need
to step forward to help ensure the value of an enhanced financial
reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> assurances for the effective
functioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> capital markets. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Accountants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> who
have historically driven changes to the financial reporting model
do not have the same set of needs as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of financial statements.
In that respect, a broader performance and accountability reporting
model is needed and should include not just financial statements
but also performance and other information necessary to better
assess institutional value and risk.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will continue to play a professional, objective, nonpartisan
and constructive role in assisting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, and
the accounting profession as initiatives are proposed, agreed upon,
and become operational. In that respect, the views of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> represent considerable experience in the
matters discussed and represent one way in which an independent
party, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, can assist those who define and/or implement
policy.
The results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> are organized by the major areas of
discussion and reflect subsequent comments we received from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> on a draft of this report. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Appendix I</ENAMEX> provides a list
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>.
For additional information on our work concerning corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">governance</ENAMEX>, the accounting profession, financial reporting, and
related regulatory matters, please contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey C. Steinhoff</ENAMEX>,
Managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Management and Assurance</ENAMEX>, on (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2600</ENAMEX> or at 
SteinhoffJ@<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gao</TIMEX>.gov.
I wish to thank each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> for taking the time to
share their knowledge and to provide their insights and
perspectives on the important matters discussed during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>. I
look forward to working with them on these important issues of
mutual interest and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> in the future.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David M. Walker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>



Corporate Governance

Defining the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roles and Responsibilities of the Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Directors</ENAMEX>
Recent legislative and regulatory initiatives, such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>) proposals and rules, and proposed revised stock exchange
listing requirements, have addressed weaknesses in corporate
governance exposed by the major financial reporting issues raised
by restatements and corporate failures, placing greater emphasis on
the roles and responsibilities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of directors. Although
these reforms are not yet fully in place and not all issues have
been addressed, many corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> are reassessing their roles.
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> agreed that there is no "silver bullet" and
that it is difficult at this time to say what is working and what
is not working.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> believed that it is important to continue working
toward more effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and discussed the
importance of clearly defining and, in some cases, redefining, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> as a significant measure to help restore investor
confidence in the market. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> has a responsibility to enhance
shareholder value, assess and monitor risk, and ensure management
accountability. In that respect, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of the boards
should reflect a culture that embraces these responsibilities. In
addition to focusing on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, and corporate
management and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> (the "supply side") should do,
boards need to focus more on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of
financial information (the "demand side") want from corporate
governance.
In order to fulfill its responsibility of effectively overseeing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> must have a thorough understanding of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, its business model and related risks, corporate culture,
and the various interests the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> represents. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX>
believed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> has a responsibility to educate itself
through the use of external <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> or other means and not rely
solely on information provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. This will better
allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to raise difficult questions and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> issues to
provide input on strategy, assess and manage risk, and hold
management accountable for its actions. The time frame needs to be
very clear, as creating value is a long-term, not a short-term,
process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> are not looking for quick schemes that endanger
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
In addition to its responsibility to oversee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> also has a responsibility to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX>, and the
public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> need to do a better job
of identifying their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> and understanding and
addressing their concerns. For example, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>'
point of view, many believe that board <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> have not been
working properly to both protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>' interests and grow
share value. We have become a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> need
to focus attention on the fact that there has been a shift from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> not only being individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> but also
institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, such as pension plans and mutual funds,
which are acting as fiduciaries for others. Institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
regarding expectations for corporate governance and the role of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of directors.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> needed to reexamine how they
are structured and how they operate. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> were not perceived
to function properly for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> protection, which is a negative
reflection on the entire corporate governance process. To some
extent, deficiencies in the functioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> may have been
masked by the effect of a flourishing market and may not have been
readily apparent until market downturns began to occur. It is
incumbent upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> to establish processes that are appropriate
and effective to restore investor confidence rather than relying on
a checklist approach to corporate governance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> believed
that information on best practices of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> would be useful to
help to improve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board operations</ENAMEX>. Some best practices include
focusing on improving communications with management and using
external <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>. It was also suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> should
effectively use the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gatekeepers</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> and audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>)
for help in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s oversight of financial management and
reporting activities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">auditing</ENAMEX>, compensation, and nominating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, play an
important role in effective corporate governance. Audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>
should not only oversee both internal and external <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>, but
also be proactively involved in understanding issues related to the
complexity of the business, and, when appropriate, challenge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> through discussion of choices regarding complex
accounting, financial reporting, and auditing issues. In that
respect, the role of the audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, which in some cases has
not been very active or effective in its oversight of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> as related to financial reporting, is evolving into not
just financial management oversight, but the overall aspects of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s financial reporting, such as releases on earnings
expectations and quarterly financial reports. In addition, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX> defines a number of audit committee
responsibilities for the hiring, compensation, and oversight of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>. However, a serious concern exists over whether audit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are focusing more on procedural matters to
protect


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Identifying the Right People to Serve on Boards</ENAMEX>
themselves from liability than on improving their competence and
effectiveness as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. Also, compensation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> need to
understand the implications of compensation to provide incentives
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to do the right thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> versus themselves. Compensation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> need to
focus on executive performance more related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
long-term objectives rather than just short-term business results.
In addition, nominating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> need to ensure that they
identify the right mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> to do the job and make it clear to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> what is expected of them as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> rather than
merely approving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. In that
respect, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> are often made up of
consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> and, in that case, a dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> could effectively control the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s agenda.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also discussed the importance of providing
reasonable transparency of key information, with regard to both
financial information of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and board <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. Boards
need to focus on enhancing the quality and reliability of financial
reporting, identifying key elements of disclosure, and ensuring
that such information is appropriately disclosed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also believed that there is a need for
better transparency of board activities to help restore investor
confidence, such as reporting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s progress against best
practices of leading companies2 noted for the effectiveness of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> is not following best practices, it
should report why it is not following these practices. The point
was also made that successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have reinvented themselves
through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fundamental focuses-ethics/integrity and respect for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. These behaviors have been demonstrated by longterm
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> stressed the importance of independence, both in
fact and appearance, as essential for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to be able to
fulfill its responsibilities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> expressed the belief
that having the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> is just as important if
not more so as having the right rules under which the board
operates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nominating</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> need to identify competent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who possess an "independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>" which allows board
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to raise difficult questions and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> issues related
2One <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> of information on best practices of leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1999 Report and Recommendations of the Blue</ENAMEX> Ribbon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> on Improving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Effectiveness of Corporate Audit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committees</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Page 10 GAO-03-419SP Governance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accountability Forum</ENAMEX>
to management's decisions to ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> operates
honestly and effectively in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>' interest. Even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are independent, they can be ineffective as directors
if they lack expertise or knowledge relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and its
business. Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> must also be willing to educate
themselves about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and the risks it faces rather than
relying on a checklist mentality of corporate governance
requirements issued by the stock exchanges.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also noted that unfortunately, as a result of the
recent major financial reporting issues leading to restatements
and, in some cases, bankruptcy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have focused on the
rules and may be concerned more about their personal reputation and
financial liability rather than focusing on protecting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>' interests and adding shareholder value. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX>
expressed concern that disincentives such as legal liabilities,
including financial and reputation risks, may limit a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s
ability to attract the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to serve over time.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> raised the question whether the current system of
selecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> needs to be reexamined because the existing
system from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>' point of view has not been working to
get the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>. For example, it was viewed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who serve on numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> at the same time and/or
who serve for personal incentives, over time lose the "independent
spirit" needed to be an effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also
stated there is some evidence that the recruiting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> is
being adversely affected by the current environment that is placing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ever-increasing</ENAMEX> demands on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Examples were cited of
increased premiums for finding qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and such
searches needing to identify <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> position
just to get one who is willing to serve. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
commented that there is no shortage of qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to serve on
boards of directors. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are willing to serve higher goals
and the selection process needs to go beyond "its usual pool of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>." Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> suggested that perhaps serving as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> should be a salaried position if shareholders
were willing to bear the cost. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> noted, however,
that having salaried <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> could be problematic because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> would have to be able to hire and fire the directors
that would cause great instability and salaried <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> may
also lack an "independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also discussed the appropriateness of the chief
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>) serving as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX>, which could present potential conflicts resulting from a
single individual functioning in these dual roles. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> believed that separation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> recognizes the differences in their roles and
eliminates conflicts in functions. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> is
responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> in their oversight function should have the ability to
challenge the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> in managing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Although the corporate
governance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> may not currently be
receptive to requiring the separation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, such a practice does exist in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>,
where apparently there is more receptivity. Therefore, regulators
may need to look beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to consider the merit of
whether these positions should be held by different
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> pointed out that not allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> to also
serve as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> does not guarantee
that problems will be avoided if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> lacks an independent
spirit to question <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, citing such examples as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX>,
Global <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossing</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WorldCom</ENAMEX>, all of which had a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separations</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> functions are
successful and others are not. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> may lose authority when the
position is too diluted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have been successful
because they have had strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> running them, and an effective
and strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> can counterbalance a strong
executive.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Reporting</ENAMEX>

Little Has Changed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Reporting Model</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> commented that traditional financial statements, in
terms of their form and content, have not really changed over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The model we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> can be traced all the way back to
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1970s</TIMEX> (back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trueblood Committee</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Participants</ENAMEX>
attributed this lack of change to the financial reporting model
being largely driven by the supply side, that is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, and corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of directors.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> referred to a landmark study on financial reporting by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jenkins Committee4</ENAMEX> as evidence that little has changed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> acknowledged that accounting standards have changed to
capture fair value in addition to historical value, resulting in a
model that is now a mixture of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, whereas the original
financial statement model was based solely on historical costs.
However, the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenkins Committee</ENAMEX>'s recommendations
never got any "traction" to move them forward. The Financial
Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards Board</ENAMEX> (FASB) has many of these items on its
agenda. At the same time, there are many other items on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASB</ENAMEX>'s
agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> felt that if stakeholders were serious about
improving the financial reporting model, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> would be
established and funded specifically for this purpose. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX>
stated that such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenkins Committee</ENAMEX>, but
it was never established. There needs to be a sense of urgency in
order to make the investment, commitment, and ultimately change the
model. However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> questioned that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 10</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> have gone by since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenkins Committee</ENAMEX> made its
recommendations, is there really a demand for change?
3The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trueblood Committee</ENAMEX> (named after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>), a group
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>) to study the objectives of financial reporting, recommended
financial statements that set forth the objectives of financial
accounting and reporting and provided a conceptual framework for
deliberations about accounting matters. (See the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>'s Objectives
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Statements, Report of the Study Group</ENAMEX> on the
Objectives of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Statements</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1973</TIMEX>.)
4The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenkins Committee</ENAMEX> (named after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>), a group
formed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> to address concerns over the relevance
and usefulness of financial reporting, recommended in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
report that standard setters develop a comprehensive reporting
model that includes both financial information (financial
statements and related disclosures) and nonfinancial information
(such as high-level operating data and performance measures used by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s analysis of changes in financial and
nonfinancial data, and forward-looking information about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opportunities</ENAMEX>, risks, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s plans). (See the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Improving Business Reporting-A Customer Focus: Meeting the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Needs of Investors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creditors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive Report</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Committee on Financial Reporting</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>.)


Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Reporting Model Has Limited Value</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Business Environment
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> agreed that financial statements are an
important aspect of overall business reporting, but were concerned
that the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> focuses too much on financial statements
rather than on the broad range of information that is needed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to make good financial decisions. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
commented that financial statements that exist <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, while they
may be useful to some, are not used very much by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>.
Financial statement disclosures are difficult to understand, as
though written in a "foreign language." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> stated that
the disclosures must be made more understandable.
However, there is a lot of dialogue taking place today
concerning business reporting. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> are asking
what should be disclosed, what is the purpose of financial
statements, and how useful are they? What are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> doing with
financial statements? What do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> use to value stock? Are they
using financial statements? If so, what information in the
financial statements are they using to value stock? What additional
information would assist them in more accurately valuing stock?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> noted the need to report information about the
business model, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of financial reports <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> must better
understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>'s business model in order to comprehend
financial and nonfinancial information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>.
Financial statements today focus on reliability much more than
on relevance. Historical information is reliable, but not
necessarily relevant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> value information is evolving but
improvements in reliability are needed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> agreed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reliability</ENAMEX> is fundamental to useful business reporting; however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> felt that financial reporting would be much more
useful if it were expanded to include key performance indicators
and measures (including disclosures on how the key measures were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chosen</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> raised questions about the gaps in reporting
of intangibles. For example, in a knowledge-based economy, one
could argue that the most important assets are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (human
capital); however, current financial reporting records investments
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as an expense and liability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> agreed that it
would be useful if financial reporting recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as assets,
but raised the difficulty in valuing human capital. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX>
generally agreed that there is a demand for both historical and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> value reporting. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASB</ENAMEX> needed
to better differentiate between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. In that respect, some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASB</ENAMEX> is marching toward a "fair value" path
and cautioned that the fair value reporting model is not always
good and needs to be used only where it really makes sense.


Considerations for Moving toward a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive Financial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Reporting Model</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> acknowledged that financial reporting, in addition
to being largely driven by the accounting profession, also has been
driven by the legal system, resulting in an overload of information
that is too complex and not easily understood. Disclosures that run
on for pages are not understandable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> are needed to
interpret the disclosures and sometimes even they cannot decipher
what is being reported. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> understand that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> are taking a risk when they issue an opinion on the
financial statements. The litigious environment has also led to a
"check box" mentality where it is more important to follow the
accounting rules when preparing financial statements than actually
reporting the economic substance of the transaction.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> generally agreed that financial statements are not
designed to serve all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> needs and that other types of
business reporting are needed to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and other users
in making decisions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also generally agreed that the
demand side (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of financial information),
has not been as involved as it needs to be to make financial
reporting more meaningful and understandable. More needs to be done
to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to demand different
reporting. Voluntary disclosures are rare and only in industries
that demand this type of information. The voluntary process has
resulted in some movement toward better reporting, but it is very
slow moving. Change is going to have to come from the demand side
and is going to require a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> from very influential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Input from advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">councils</ENAMEX> may also be beneficial for
developing a broader business reporting model. While it is
essential that a new model not be driven totally by the supply side
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX>), there cannot be a disconnect between the supply and
demand sides.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also cautioned that we need to move forward
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">patiently</ENAMEX> toward a new comprehensive reporting model. It was viewed
that forward, realtime, qualitative information, all of which would
be helpful in predicting future cash flows, may require a safe
harbor from liability. It is also important to keep in mind the
role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> in this process since the public needs to
have confidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> to enforce rules. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Regulators</ENAMEX> may
not be totally supportive of a more comprehensive business model
because they are concerned that the information would be based on a
lot of judgment and, therefore, lack of precision, which could make
enforcement of reporting standards difficult.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> discussed the lack of investor confidence in the
current financial reporting model and the need to first improve the
reliability of financial reporting before adding any new reporting.
First, get the basics right, that is, the "blocking and tackling"
of financial reporting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> cited accounting for pensions,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postemployment</ENAMEX> benefits, and pro-forma financial statements as
examples of accounting treatments that need attention before
building on any new reporting requirements. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Issuers</ENAMEX> of financial
statements who are inappropriately bending the current accounting
rules need to know they cannot get away with this anymore.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> discussed the merits of replacing accounting rules
with principle-based standards to promote more substance versus
form in reporting. However, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> cautioned that
principle-based standards should not be viewed as a panacea to
solve the problems with financial reporting and could lead to an
undesirable situation where you would not have comparability or
agreement as to the treatment of similar transactions. Also,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX> may not interpret principles consistently, and it is
important for stakeholders to have the same conceptual framework as
preparers when interpreting a principle. In addition, you would
need the right kind of implementation guidance to carry out a
principle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> agreed that while accounting rules are also
needed, there should not be such blind adherence to accounting
rules to result in reporting form over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX>
offered that an "artful" blend of both principles and rules would
be useful. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Employee Retirement Income Security Act</ENAMEX> (ERISA) was
cited as an example of an approach that blended both a
principles-based (general fiduciary standards) and rulesbased
(prohibited transactions) approach to an important issue
(retirement security).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also discussed the idea of exploring different
levels or layers of reporting while still having full disclosure.
Such layering will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to get only the information they
need. For example, the basic level of reporting would include
performance and risk data, an industry layer could include
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">benchmarking</ENAMEX> information, and a company specific layer could
include information management feels it is appropriate to disclose
that is not contained in other layers of reporting. Along with this
idea is the need to explore different levels of verification or
assurances by independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' need for such
verification or assurances. For example, what type of assurances
are needed for nonfinanical information and can <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> provide
such assurances? Overall, it is critical to get the demand side
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of financial information) to weigh in on
what information they need and want. It is not realistic to only
expect the supply side (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, and corporate
management and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>) to come up with the best
solutions for improving the financial reporting model.
Although time did not permit its discussion, financial literacy
was raised as an important issue that needs addressing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> agreed that there clearly is a need for more education
and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> assistance in this area.



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting Profession</ENAMEX>

An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Expectation Gap Exists Concerning the Role of Auditing</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> discussed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX>'s responsibility for
detecting fraud and the meaning of the assurances provided by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">auditor</ENAMEX>'s report on the financial statements. These issues have
continued to plague the accounting profession since the 1970s
despite actions taken by the profession to narrow the so-called
"expectation gap" between what the public expects or needs and what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> can and should reasonably be expected to accomplish<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> often equate a clean audit opinion with a seal of approval
that fraud does not exist and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> reports are both complete and
accurate. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> do not provide absolute assurance and
the scope of the opinion is limited to certain financial-related
information. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> explained that there are a lot of
things an audit cannot do. For example, an audit cannot create
certainty in an environment where there is no certainty. An audit
cannot guarantee precision in an environment where estimates are
made. An audit cannot ensure that stock prices will be achieved. We
cannot lose sight of the fact that in a risk-taking environment
businesses do fail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auditing</ENAMEX> is not the "be all" and "end all" to
solve the problems in the business place. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
generally agreed that while the accounting profession needs to take
additional steps to address any misunderstanding as to the limits
of an audit, there is room to improve the audit process and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX>
reporting.
5We reported on this issue in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Accounting Profession</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major</ENAMEX>
Issues: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX> and Concerns 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/AIMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-98</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Page 18 GAO-03-419SP Governance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accountability Forum</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> recognized that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> has the responsibility
for preventing and detecting fraud. At the same time, they agreed
that it is fair to expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> to provide "reasonable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurance</ENAMEX>" of detecting any material fraud. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> discussed
the need to mitigate the opportunity and risk for fraud by
educating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and ultimately changing the tone at
the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> liked the idea of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> periodically performing more of a "forensic-type" audit6
in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> would be more skeptical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, but
cautioned that this approach could have a negative effect on audit
quality because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> might not work as
actively together on an ongoing basis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> agreed that an
adversarial relationship between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> would
not be constructive in that the cooperation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> is
critical to both an effective and efficient audit. However,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> should be more skeptical and
should say no and walk away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> more often than they
currently do. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> applauded the deterrent put in place
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX>, which sends a signal that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who prepare or attest to fraudulent financial statements
can go to jail. This deterrent has raised awareness and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conscientiousness</ENAMEX> within all levels of the financial reporting and
auditing process as to the significance of their job in preparing
financial statements.
6The concept of forensic auditing was recently suggested by the
Panel on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audit Effectiveness</ENAMEX> to improve the likelihood that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> will detect fraudulent financial reporting (see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Panel</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audit Effectiveness Report</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recommendations</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31, 2000</TIMEX>).
Forensic auditing, as explained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Panel</ENAMEX>, would require that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> undertake an attitudinal shift in their degree of
skepticism and presume the possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dishonesty</ENAMEX> at various
levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, including collusion, overriding of controls,
and falsification of documents.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> generally viewed the new internal control reporting
requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX> as a good
requirement. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> added that earlier mandatory internal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> reporting probably would have surfaced problems with
ineffective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>.7 However,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> cautioned that reporting only on internal controls
over financial reporting could lead to more of a gap in what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> perceive as the scope of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX>'s work. For example,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of financial reports are interested in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s overall
performance and outlook and, accordingly, would be interested in
the effectiveness of internal control over the process that
produces that data. In that respect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> also discussed
the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> to expand their focus on internal control to
include controls over performance data in order to better meet the
needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> for assurances on financial statements and for
understanding all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> risks. Also, new information not only
needs to be useful, but also needs to be understood by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>.
For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> do not understand terminology such as
"reportable conditions,"8 which could result in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> over- or
under-reacting to problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also suggested that the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-page audit opinion should be replaced with "tiered" reporting
of audit results, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> can obtain the level of assurance
they desired. For example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s environment, audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>
would most likely ask for the deepest "tier" of audit reporting to
better carry out their responsibilities.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> generally agreed that the profession needs a new
reporting model for audits to eliminate the misunderstanding as to
what an audit of financial statements is and what its limits are.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> acknowledged that the financial audit process is
largely driven by the accounting profession and suggested that the
profession needs to spend more time understanding what the demand
side (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of financial information) needs and
wants from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> recognized that one
of the big obstacles for innovation in
7This comment was based on the standards and guidance contained
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Control-Integrated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Framework</ENAMEX>, published by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee of Sponsoring Organizations</ENAMEX> (COSO) of the Treadway
Commission, for reporting on the effectiveness of internal control,
which addresses a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s control environment including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>.
8The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>'s Generally Accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auditing Standards</ENAMEX> defines a
reportable condition as a significant deficiency in the design or
operation of internal control that could adversely affect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entity</ENAMEX>'s ability to record, process, summarize, and report
financial data consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s assertions in the
financial statements.


More Attention <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Needed on the Quality of Audits</ENAMEX>
reforming the audit process and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> reporting is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">auditor</ENAMEX>'s fear of legal liability. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> added that the
current regulatory structure has dampened the profession's spirit
for innovation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> commented that there are good solid audits being
performed; however, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> expressed concern that
overall, time and fee pressures both from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and
from within the auditing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have resulted in less and less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">auditing</ENAMEX>, particularly less substantive testing of transactions. In
that respect, the financial audit is considered the "loss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>"
in many audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> with a focus on cutting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and costs
and as a means to obtain consulting engagements. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
also pointed out that most of the auditing is currently being
performed by inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>. Further, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
cautioned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> rotation rules currently being developed
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> could further reduce audit quality by resulting
in a loss of continuity, experience, and technical knowledge on an
audit.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> felt that the profession needs to elevate and
restore the importance and the quality of the financial statement
audit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> stated that the accounting profession needs to
candidly discuss what it is doing to improve the audit process to
restore public trust. Further, a growing concern for the profession
is its ability to attract and retain the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over time. It
was stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> frequently leave the profession early in
their careers to join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> are not
practicing public accounting. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> added that the
interest in the profession over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 10 years</TIMEX> has dropped by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, although the recent publicity stemming from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX> and
WorldCom, albeit negative, has actually sparked increased interest
in the profession. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> generally agreed that the
profession needs to aggressively address the issue of attracting
the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the profession.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Auditors</ENAMEX> Need to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strengthen Their Relationship with Others in</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corporate Governance Process</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> generally agreed that improvements in corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">governance</ENAMEX> will bring about improvements in auditing. It was viewed
that one of the more positive outcomes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> is the relationship the act establishes between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX>
and audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> by making the audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> in essence the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, versus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. Historically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> felt
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> communication with audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> has been variable.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> generally agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> should be able to speak
more freely, openly, and honestly with audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> on risks
facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and on the appropriateness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
accounting policies. Audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> should be demanding more
information from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> and asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> if they have
sufficient resources, both in number and expertise, to adequately
perform the audit. Audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> together can
become good safeguards for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. A point was also made that
the role of the internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>, specifically their cooperation
and coordination with the external <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX>, should be improved, which ultimately could improve the
quality of financial reporting and the external audit. In addition,
disclosures, such as those required to be reported to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> on
Form <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-K<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,9</NUMEX> should be improved to be more transparent and helpful to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> in determining the reasons and circumstances surrounding
auditor changes.
9An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">registrant</ENAMEX> must file a Form <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8-K</NUMEX> when its external
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor resigns</ENAMEX>, declines to stand for reelection, or is
dismissed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Page 22 GAO-03-419SP Governance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accountability Forum</ENAMEX>



Regulation and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enforcement</ENAMEX>

Providing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sufficient Resources</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restore Investor</ENAMEX>
Confidence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants uniformly</ENAMEX> agreed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> needs a strong,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">viable SEC</ENAMEX> to instill investor confidence in our markets. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>
plays an important role through its responsibilities to regulate
activities of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> and to conduct
related enforcement actions, as well as to establish and sustain
established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX> until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> is
certified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> as ready to operate. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
noted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> may not have been provided with sufficient resources
to achieve such results. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> stated that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> has recently been operating on a budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $450</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million.10</NUMEX> It was noted that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> authorized about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750 million</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2003</TIMEX>, an amount that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> believed would be sufficient to implement provisions of the
Sarbanes-Oxley legislation to restore investor confidence, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> only proposed a funding level of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $500 million</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> believed that a lack of sufficient funding provides
constraints in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas that are vital to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>-staffing and
technology. To carry out its important function of restoring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> confidence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> may not always be able to attract the
right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and retain them under the existing structure. In
addition, to effectively conduct its reviews of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> will require a large technology investment and related
training of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> questioned whether, given the
current funding restraints, existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> for generating revenues
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> were workable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> believe that models that
provide temporary resources to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>, such as through fellowships
from the accounting profession, are not the answer to its funding
and staffing problems and can raise conflict of interest issues.
Accordingly, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> believed that it is time to think
about having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> operate independently in setting its own
funding levels, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>, and to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>
determine and set its own fees, with industry participation, for
the activities it conducts. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> were able to establish its
own <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget and collect fees, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> would be better able to
conduct its
10Prior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reports and testimonies discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> resource issues
and the need for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> to improve its strategic planning to more
effectively manage its operations and limited resources. See <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC Operations</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Increased Workload</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creates Challenges</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-302</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 2002</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, Protecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>'s Interests:
Considerations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Addressing Selected Regulatory Oversight</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auditing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corporate Governance</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Reporting Issues</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">601T</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 2002</TIMEX>).


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reconsidering the Existing Approach to Enforcement Actions to</ENAMEX>
Restore Public Confidence
activities, attract the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and enhance its technology
to more efficiently and effectively operate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> noted
that even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> were independent regarding its funding, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could still oversee the SEC.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> discussed the importance of effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>
enforcement actions as a means of restoring investor confidence in
the markets. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> tries to create deterrence and be measured in
imposing sanctions. If there are no clear negative consequences to
securities violations or wrongdoing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> may perceive that
the system is not working properly. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> has an array
of sanctions available, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> enforcement actions are civil
based, which ultimately results in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> bearing the burden
of the costs of legal proceedings and sanctions. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> were benefiting from litigation and
questioned the appropriateness of civil-based enforcement actions,
citing the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> have already been financially
hurt by the actions that lead to the sanctions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also
discussed whether the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were being held accountable and
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s civil-based enforcement actions were sufficient
to discourage the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> raised questions about whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> should
reconsider the amount and targeting of its civil sanctions and more
frequently use other types of remedies, such as criminal sanctions,
to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> accountable for wrongdoing. In that respect,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> should be effectively using the
option of referring cases when appropriate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> for investigation for possible violation of criminal
statues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> questioned how well that process was
working.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002</ENAMEX> provides for additional
enforcement authority for both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and the newly created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX>.
In response to the question of whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> should be revisited, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> believed that although
ultimately some technical changes to the act may be necessary, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> needed to move forward to implement the act.
Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> should explore integrating their
activities to get the new enforcement mechanisms in place to
determine how well they may address some of the issues
discussed.


Establishing Priorities for the PCAOB
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> believed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> needs to be quickly set up
and establish its priorities so it can begin the difficult task of
restoring public confidence. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> believed that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX>'s most immediate priority should be implementing a
disciplinary process to let the public know that failed auditing
will be dealt with and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> can be restored. The disciplinary
process needs to have the necessary incentive measures to serve as
preventative measures before problems can become more serious.
Other immediate priorities should be setting up an inspection
function of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> that audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">registrants</ENAMEX> and determining how
standards that govern the work of the accounting profession, such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> independence rules and standards for conducting audits,
should be set. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> believed that the existing
inspection process could be improved by looking less at the
accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>' internal systems for quality control and more at
the quality of the judgments that were made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> in
conducting the audit.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also believed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> also needs to evaluate
the events that have lead to the lack of public confidence in the
markets and take a fresh look going forward. For example, the PCAOB
should consider the reasons the accounting profession is organized
the way it is, including federal/state regulation such as the
licensing structure, reasons accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms practice</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">partnerships</ENAMEX>, the effects of private litigation, and the structure
and role of the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of accountancy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also
noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> should take advantage of the fact that under
the current environment no one has more motivation for getting "bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> off the street" than the accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> themselves. The
accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> do remove "bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>," but this is accomplished
without publicity so that their efforts are not well known.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> also believed that a challenge facing the new PCAOB
will be dealing with the complex relationship between federal and
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> involved in regulating the accounting
profession<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> identified the need for better
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> and sharing of information between federal entities
such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> and the state licensing and
regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are often hampered in
their ability to take appropriate regulatory actions because
11Our report, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Accounting Profession: Status of Panel on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Audit Effectiveness Recommendations to Enhance the Self-Regulatory</ENAMEX>
System 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">411,Washington</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15, 2002</TIMEX>) discusses
the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> that regulate the accounting profession.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Page 25 GAO-03-419SP Governance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accountability Forum</ENAMEX>
they do not get referrals from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>, or because
those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have made the information confidential. Also,
ongoing litigation impedes information flow. In addition,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> stated that some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have been independently trying
to address accountancy reform and, in some cases, have proposed
reforms that have gone further than the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>
because they feared that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would not act. This
has led to additional inconsistency in requirements between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> to work closely
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in taking actions to restore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> confidence and
ensure an appropriate degree of consistency needed for viable
interstate commerce. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> suggested that the PCAOB
consider the banking industry to provide examples of the
integration of federal and state regulation and lessons learned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> and banking crises.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> noted that with increased globalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>'
operations and the need for harmonization of accounting and
auditing standards, as well as the need for preemptive measures,
there may be more federal involvement such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarbanes</ENAMEX>-Oxley
Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>.
Appendix I



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governance and Accountability Forum</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom L. Allen</ENAMEX>
