



Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Frequent Traveler Policy</ENAMEX>
Under current federal laws and regulations, the frequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traveler benefits1</ENAMEX> received by a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> in conjunction
with official travel are generally considered government property,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> may not retain the benefits for personal use. As a
result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> should accept the benefits on behalf of the
government and turn them over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. The agency
should then integrate the benefits into its travel plans to
maximize their value to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
Initially, this policy was enunciated and followed in a number
of prior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> decisions. These decisions were based
on the fundamental rule of law that a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> is obligated
to account for any gift, gratuity, or benefit received from private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> incident to the performance of official duty. Any such
gifts, gratuities, or benefits tendered to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> are viewed
as having been received on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacted a statute designed to help realize to
the maximum extent practicable cost savings for official travel
from frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> benefits. The statute directed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Administrator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> to issue guidelines to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
promote, encourage, and facilitate the use of frequent traveler
programs offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and car rental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> by
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who engage in official travel<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> This act
specifically provides that any awards granted under such a frequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traveler</ENAMEX> program accrued through official travel shall be used only
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> travel<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> has incorporated these policies into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Property</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Regulations5</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Travel Regulation</ENAMEX>,6
applicable to most federal civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Travel Regulations</ENAMEX>,7 applicable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
These include the benefits offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and car
rental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">79</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>) (quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-199656</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 1981</TIMEX>);
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">229</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>). See also, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">233</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>);
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">215826</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 23, 1986</TIMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-257525</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 30, 1994</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Acquisition Streamlining Act of 1994</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.L. 103-355, ยง</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6008</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">102 Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3367</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5702</TIMEX>, note.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.L. 103-355, ยง 6008</ENAMEX>(b). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> issued Bulletin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTR</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, Oct. 24</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, advising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> of the provisions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.L.</ENAMEX> No. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">103-355, ยง</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6008</TIMEX> and reminding them of the existing provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Travel Regulation concerning cost-saving opportunities provided by
the use of frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> benefits. In Bulletin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTR</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> also
encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to establish programs under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> Incentive <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Awards Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4501-4507</TIMEX>, to reward
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who take the initiative to accrue travel savings, and GSA
offered its program as a guide in establishing such reward
programs.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">541</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R. ยง</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25.103</NUMEX>-2.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">41 C.F.R. part</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">301-53</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Paragraph U2010B.</ENAMEX>
the uniformed services, recognize that promotional material
received by a uniformed service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> traveling on official
business at government expense belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and must
be relinquished in accordance with service regulations<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>
Legislation would be required to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s general
policy to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian employees</ENAMEX> and uniformed service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to
retain for personal use frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> benefits accrued on
official travel. Such legislation would be necessary to repeal the
current requirement that such benefits be used only for official
travel9 and to affirmatively authorize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to
retain for personal use these benefits that are now considered the
property of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.


Use of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frequent Flyer Miles for Official Travel Is Difficult</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appears Limited</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive</ENAMEX> governmentwide data are not readily available on
the extent to which federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> capture and use frequent flyer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX> for official travel. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> told us that they do not
collect such data. However, our task <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> did obtain information on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s practices, as well as those of several other federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>. This information follows.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Experience
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has never had a centralized, formal program to reduce its
travel costs by capturing and using its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' official travel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several years ago</TIMEX>, we pilottested a program in one of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters units</ENAMEX> but soon discontinued it for a variety of
reasons. These reasons, which have also discouraged other
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters units</ENAMEX>, include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>' refusal to establish
separate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> and personal travel accounts for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' reluctance to participate, administrative burdens and
costs, and limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, few frequent flyer seats
were available at desired travel times, transfers of free tickets
to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> took time and effort, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who flew on
different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> often took a long time to accumulate enough
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX> for free trips.
Although we never set up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-wide program to capture and use
frequent flyer miles, several of our field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> tried to
establish such programs. Of these, the majority discontinued their
efforts for the same reasons that discouraged our headquarters
units. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> did, however, establish programs and
continue to operate them, yet their dollar savings have been very
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> saved <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,600</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 33 months</TIMEX>. This office
has many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> with enough miles on single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> for free
trips, but these <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> have been difficult to use because few seats
have been available when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> have needed to travel.
Furthermore, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>'s savings were reduced by the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> fee that the contract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> charged for reservations made
less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 weeks</TIMEX> in advance. Accumulating sufficient
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
There are some federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that are not covered by ยง
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6008</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.L. 103-355</ENAMEX> and also have their own property disposal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>. One such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> we are aware of that does not
prohibit its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> from retaining frequent flyer benefits for
their personal use is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
ยง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6008</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.L. 103-355</ENAMEX>.
frequent flyer miles for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> has become more
problematic since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> contracted with a different
carrier for one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>'s most heavily traveled routes. The
other field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, which reported saving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $32,000</NUMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, also noted that multiple changes in contract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> have
made it more difficult to accumulate and effectively use frequent
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">flyer miles</NUMEX>.
Experiences of Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Organizations</ENAMEX>
The other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> we contacted had varied
approaches to capturing and using frequent flyer benefits for
official travel. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> from one--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service, which is not subject to the travel rules that apply to
most federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>--said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> does not prohibit its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> from making personal use of the frequent flyer miles
received on official travel.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of the Interior</ENAMEX> considered establishing
a frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> program that would have been managed by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> rejected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>'s
proposal as too expensive and difficult to implement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>
believed that the fees the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> would have charged were
excessive and the savings were uncertain. In addition, under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contractor</ENAMEX>'s proposal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> would have had to provide the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> with data on the frequent flyer miles received by its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. It would have had to obtain the data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> would not provide the information to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> told us that some of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bureaus</ENAMEX> use frequent flyer benefits to enable their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to
take training and attend conferences because their budgets do not
cover non-program-related travel. Therefore, if frequent flyer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX> received on program-related travel were not captured and used
for this type of travel, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaus</ENAMEX> might not be able to send
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to these types of events. At the same time, if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were allowed to retain the frequent flyer benefits, they
might be willing to use some of their <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> for such travel on a
voluntary basis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> have established
gain-sharing programs that enable frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> to share in
the savings they achieve in airfares, lodging costs, or both. Under
these programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> can obtain cash awards based on savings
they can document by using free tickets from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> frequent flyer
programs or by securing lodging rates below the maximum amounts
allowed.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> considered establishing a
frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX> but abandoned the idea
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> would neither pool the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> received by GSA
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s use nor provide data to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> on the miles
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> received. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> established a
voluntary gainsharing program under which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who use free
tickets awarded for official travel <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> or secure lodging at less
than the established lodging rates can receive cash awards of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to</NUMEX>
half the amount saved for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> reported that from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1995 through September 2000</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $823,000</NUMEX> was saved
under the program, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> that amount in
cash awards. These savings do not take into account the costs of
administering the gain-sharing program, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> believe
were minimal. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> view the program as a limited
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> because the savings are low relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s overall
travel costs, which totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $190 million</NUMEX> for the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> believe that most of the savings
are from the lodging portion of the program rather than from the
use of frequent flyer miles.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> established a program similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> at the
request of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Treasury Employees Union</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> can
accrue savings by such means as using frequent flyer miles to
obtain free airline tickets, sharing hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> with coworkers, or
staying with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> did not
have data on the savings achieved through their program because the
program is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a year old</TIMEX>. However, they view the program as
a success. They said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> like the program and most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> are in lodging costs.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> established its gain-sharing program at
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of fiscal year 1996</TIMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> shares
savings its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> achieve by using frequent flyer miles and
obtaining lodging at reduced costs. The program is discretionary,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> components can choose whether they want to include
frequent flyer savings, lodging savings, or both. Administrative
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> who assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> who achieve savings can also
share in the savings awards. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, it saved about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1996</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$202,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1997</TIMEX> and
paid cash awards equaling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of the savings. Again, these
financial benefits do not factor in the gain-sharing program's
administrative costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> did not provide savings data beyond
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1997</TIMEX>.
According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> does not
have a departmentwide frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> program and has no data on
the extent to which its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> have such programs. He said that
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990s</TIMEX>, his command attempted to, but could not, find an
effective program for capturing and using <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' official
frequent flyer miles anywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>. He believes the use of free
tickets awarded for frequent flyer miles in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> is spotty at best.
He cited many of the same practical difficulties with implementing
the current federal policy that we and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> identified,
including the reluctance of both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to
provide frequent flyer data to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the problems with
tracking and using miles for official travel. He also identified
another difficulty--the time and expense associated with taking
disciplinary action against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who violate the current
policy by making personal use of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> received on official travel.
He said his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> completed a demotion action against an employee
for personal use of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX>, but assistance from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> was
difficult to obtain. Such action, he maintained, was not
cost-effective. These difficulties, combined with a departmental
emphasis on adopting private-sector practices, have led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> to
prepare draft legislation that would abolish the current
restriction and allow military and civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governmentwide</ENAMEX> to retain for personal use frequent flyer benefits
received on official travel. He said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> has discussed its
proposal with other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, which have been supportive.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> is currently considering submitting its proposal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX>.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> informed us that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> began using a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contractor</ENAMEX>'s software <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 to 3 years ago</TIMEX> to facilitate the use of
frequent flyer mileage. She said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' participation in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s frequent flyer program is voluntary and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s savings
have been minimal, in part because frequent flyer tickets do not
give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> flexibility in arranging their travel. Specifically,
she said that it is difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to obtain seating
using frequent flyer tickets because many trips are scheduled,
canceled, or changed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>. Finally, she said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>
is likely to discontinue its contract because the savings, minus
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-percent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>, are not sufficient to
offset <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s "hidden" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and oversight costs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
have not been enthusiastic about participating in the program.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Sector's Practices</ENAMEX>
According to the results of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> recent surveys, the private
sector commonly allows its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to retain for personal use
frequent flyer miles received on business travel. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> may
give the private sector, including government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>, an
advantage over the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in recruiting and retaining
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. While small compared with the higher salaries companies
often pay, this advantage may nonetheless influence the job choices
of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, especially if they are frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Business Travel Association</ENAMEX> surveyed
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> via the Internet on frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> programs.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> responded. Of these, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>
percent said they do not recover frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> benefits
received by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on business travel for their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> said they have no plans to do so. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do not want to become involved in
capturing these benefits because it is too difficult to track miles
or points received.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of National Affairs</ENAMEX> reported the results
of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> on their business travel
policies. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 450</NUMEX> of which responded to the
survey, represented a cross section of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX>
were manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36 percent</NUMEX> were nonmanufacturing
(e.g., service) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 30 percent</NUMEX> were other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">establishments</ENAMEX>, such as health care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, educational
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, and government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seventy</TIMEX> percent of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, and the remainder had
more. According to the survey, most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> with business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> allowed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to keep frequent flyer miles
received on business travel for their own use. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About two-thirds</NUMEX> of
the responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> reported specifically allowing their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to retain the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> for their personal use, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX>
percent reported having no policy at all, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">under 10 percent</NUMEX>
reported requiring their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to relinquish mileage received
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> reported having gain-sharing
programs similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>', and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>'s.
The findings from these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> surveys appear consistent with the
results of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> survey of business travel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, reported in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Travel News</ENAMEX>, a
business travel industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. According to the article
discussing this survey, the trend in the private sector was away
from collecting frequent flyer awards, and the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> doing so was declining. Specifically, the survey
showed that the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> managing and using frequent
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">flyer miles</NUMEX> received by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> fell from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. According to the article, "most companies
neither want the headache of tracking miles nor the disincentive
that taking them away might present to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>." In addition, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> discussed the views of the travel services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that was using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> to aggressively track and use
frequent flyer miles for company business. Although this approach
was saving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of its overall air travel costs,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> said he would rather receive discounts from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> than deal with frequent flyer miles.
These survey results are also consistent with the experience of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that we contacted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> after learning that
it had established a program to capture and use for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> travel
frequent flyer miles received by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on company business. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> later told us that it had discontinued the program because
of its adverse effect on employee morale. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2001</TIMEX>, we
contacted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> again, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> told us that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> continues to allow its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to make personal use of
frequent flyer miles received on company travel.


Views on Frequent Flyer Issue
You asked for our views on this issue as well as those of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Service Officers Association</ENAMEX>. I will discuss the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>'s views <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Affairs</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Service Officers Association</ENAMEX> told us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>
would support legislation that would allow federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to
keep for personal use frequent flyer miles earned on official
travel. He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> recognizes that many foreign
service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> frequently travel long distances and would
therefore receive considerable benefits from such legislation.
However, he noted that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> are often assigned to
hardship locations that require difficult travel. He also said that
if this type of legislation is not feasible, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> would like to be able to use their frequent flyer miles to
upgrade to business class on long flights.
In our view, the current federal policy on frequent flyer miles
was well intentioned as a potential means for reducing federal
travel costs and promoting economy in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. We recognize that
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, might be able to achieve some
additional savings by taking more advantage of frequent flyer miles
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> travel. However, the practical obstacles to
achieving significantly greater savings are such that few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
have overcome them without creating incentives, such as
gain-sharing plans, that have generally reduced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. Additionally, more aggressive efforts to use
frequent flyer miles to reduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s travel costs could,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>, jeopardize its ability to negotiate significant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> under its contract air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> program. This negotiated
travel program saves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. GSA
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> responsible for the program told us they believe the
savings achieved through this program far outweigh the benefits the
government would gain through more aggressive efforts to capture
and use frequent flyer miles for official travel. We do not know
how a change in the current federal policy to permit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> use
would affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s ability to negotiate savings in contract
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airfares</ENAMEX>. However, a change would not seem likely to have a
negative impact, since, in contrast to the current policy, it would
be consistent with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>' position that frequent flyer miles
belong to the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>.
Changing the federal policy on frequent flyer miles would have
some disadvantages for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. First, it would eliminate
any savings that certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> currently achieve by implementing
the policy. In addition, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who now travel on free
tickets obtained with frequent flyer miles might no longer be able
to travel when funds for air travel were not available or were in
short supply. However, these disadvantages would, we believe, be
far outweighed by the advantages of a change, both to federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. A change would eliminate the
current disparity in practice between the private sector and the
government and would put federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on a par with their
private-sector <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>, including federal contractor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, in this area. Like private-sector <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who put up with flight delays and cancellations and
travel on their own time to meet work schedules would then feel
that they were being compensated, in part, for these frustrations
and sacrifices. Establishing parity between the federal government
and the private sector in this area would also aid the government
in recruiting and retaining top-quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.
If the current policy is changed to allow federal civilian and
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to retain their official travel miles for
personal use, controls over the need for travel and the selection
of routes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> would have to be effectively implemented.
These controls are designed to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> from selecting
certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> to earn <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> or otherwise undercutting the
government's negotiated fare agreements with major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>.
Today, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of frequent flyer miles earned on official
travel are going unused, benefiting neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> nor its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. Changing the federal frequent flyer policy-and changing
it retroactively so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> can take advantage of these
unused <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX>--would boost federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' morale and strengthen
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s ability to compete with the private
sector. We therefore believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should consider allowing
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to keep and make personal use of the frequent
flyer miles they have already received and will receive for
official travel. In order to assist the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, we have enclosed
draft legislation that would accomplish this objective (see enc.
I).
If you have any questions on the information we are providing or
if we can be of further assistance, please call me on (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-5500</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John H. Anderson, Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX>, Physical
Infrastructure Issues, on (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2834</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David M. Walker</ENAMEX> Comptroller <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">General Of the United States</ENAMEX>
Enclosure I


-


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>);
and


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
by inserting after subsection (b) the following new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subsection</ENAMEX> (c): "(c) Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>), promotional items an employee (including a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>)
receives as a consequence of using travel or transportation
services procured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or accepted pursuant to
31


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1353</TIMEX> may be retained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> for personal use.
Promotional items include only those obtained under the same terms
as those offered to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and at no additional cost to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Promotional items include but are not limited to
frequent flyer miles, upgrades, and access to carrier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>."
-


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
by redesignating subsection (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">j</ENAMEX>) as subsection (k);
and


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
by inserting after subsection (i) the following new
subsection:


"(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">j</ENAMEX>) Promotional items a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> receives as a consequence of
using travel or transportation services procured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> or accepted pursuant to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1353</TIMEX> may be retained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> for personal use.
Promotional items include only those obtained under the same terms
as those offered to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and at no additional cost to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Promotional items include but are not limited to
frequent flyer miles, upgrades, and access to carrier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 6008 of the Federal Acquisition Streamlining Act</ENAMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">103-355</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5702</TIMEX>, note), is
repealed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4</ENAMEX>. Sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">act</ENAMEX> shall apply to promotional
items received prior to the effective date of this act.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sectional Analysis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 1</ENAMEX> of this legislation would amend section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5702</NUMEX> of title
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5, United States Code</ENAMEX> (Per diem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> traveling on official
business). This amendment would authorize federal civilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, who receive promotional
items incident to using government procured travel or
transportation services, or such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> accepted from non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
sources pursuant to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1353</TIMEX>, to retain such promotional
items for personal use. The travel or transportation services from
which the promotional benefits accrue are intended to include
services provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and rental car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>. The
expected to prescribe regulations under existing authority in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5707</TIMEX> to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> from incurring excess costs
or
improper selection of travel or transportation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> for the
benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>. Enclosure I
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 2</ENAMEX> of this legislation would amend <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 404</ENAMEX> of title
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United States Code</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travel and Transportation Allowances</ENAMEX>). This
amendment would provide the same treatment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
uniformed services. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretaries</ENAMEX> of the services concerned under
existing authority in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง 404</ENAMEX> would be expected to
prescribe regulations similar to those prescribed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Administrator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Services</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 3</ENAMEX> of the legislation would repeal section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6008</NUMEX> of the
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Acquisition Streamlining Act of 1994, Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 103-355, 108</ENAMEX>.
Stat. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3367</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5702</TIMEX> note). <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 6008</ENAMEX> requires the
guidelines to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> promote, encourage, and
facilitate the use of frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> programs offered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and car rental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who
engage in official travel, for the purpose of realizing cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> for official travel. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 6008</ENAMEX> also provides that any
awards granted under such a frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> program accrued
through official travel shall be used only for official travel. It
would be necessary to repeal section <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6008</TIMEX> since its provisions
conflict with the purposes of sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX> of the proposed
legislation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 4</ENAMEX> would make it clear that the legislation is applicable
to any unused promotional benefits received by an employee or
service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> prior to the effective date of the legislation as
well as to such benefits received on and after the effective date
of the legislation.



