



B285663
facility design review area discussed in the study, as well as
the efforts that have been made by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to address the
conditions covered in the study.


Results in Brief
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> study, opportunities exist to significantly
reduce total project cost (TPC) by conducting an effective design
review process. The study found that effective design review
practices result in less rework on the part of the construction
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contractor</ENAMEX>, fewer change orders to correct design errors and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">omissions</ENAMEX>, and lowering the cost of belatedly adding project
upgrade features that should have been addressed in the original
design. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> reported that, historically, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 to 50 percent</NUMEX> of all
construction change orders result from errors in the design
documents directly related to improper interfaces between design
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disciplines</ENAMEX> (civil, structural, architectural, electrical, and
mechanical).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> study notes that attention should be focused on review
of designs during the conceptual planning and design phases, where
the ability to influence ultimate functionality and cost of the
project is the greatest. The study states that the potential
savings resulting from conducting effective design reviews range
from a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX>, and
even higher when indirect savings are taken into account. The FFC
study concludes that, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, effective review of designs
maximizes the probability that a mission or operational requirement
will be successfully supported by a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> that was conceived,
designed, constructed, and placed into operation efficiently and
effectively.
The study identifies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> best practices that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> can use to manage and/or oversee design
reviews throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition process. It organized
the best practices into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> categories related to (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the role of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) teamwork and collaboration, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) advance planning,
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) process, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) benchmarking.


Background
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FFC (</ENAMEX>formerly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Construction Council</ENAMEX>) is a continuing
activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Infrastructure and the Constructed</ENAMEX>
Environment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Research Council</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRC</ENAMEX>). It is a
cooperative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with interests and
responsibilities related to all aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> design,
acquisition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, maintenance, and evaluation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> is
convened under the aegis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRC</ENAMEX>, the operating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> of the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academies</ENAMEX>. Its mission is to identify and advance technologies,
processes, and management practices that improve the performance of
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> over their entire life cycle, from planning to
disposal. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that sponsored the facility design
review study, which was produced as an element of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
Technical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Activities Program</ENAMEX>, included the


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the Civil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Engineer</ENAMEX>;


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air National Guard</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANG</ENAMEX>);


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> for
Installation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX>;


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>);


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Facilities Engineering</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Command</ENAMEX> (NAVFAC);


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> (DOS), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Foreign Buildings</ENAMEX>
Operations;



B285663


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Facilities</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX>;


•


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Services Administration</ENAMEX> (GSA), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Buildings</ENAMEX>
Service;


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Health Service</ENAMEX> (IHS);


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Broadcasting Bureau</ENAMEX>;


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Facilities Engineering Division</ENAMEX>;


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>);


•
Building and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Research Laboratory</ENAMEX>;


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Foundation</ENAMEX>;


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian Institution</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Facilities Services</ENAMEX>;
and


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> (USPS).


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX>'s study discusses the results of a questionnaire survey of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that acquire, maintain, and operate a
significant inventory of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and other constructed facilities
in supporting their mission<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Questionnaires</ENAMEX> were answered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency headquarters</ENAMEX> senior facilities engineering program directors
and fieldactivitylevel project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> used the
results from research done by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Business Roundtable</ENAMEX> (TBR),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRC</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Corps of Engineers</ENAMEX> (USACE), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Construction Industry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> (CII)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> efforts, as well as others, to
augment the study. A literature search was used to identify
facility acquisition practices and industry trends, as well as best
practices and technologies being used to provide adequate
management and oversight of design reviews. Supplemental
information was obtained through interviews with various public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, private sector facility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, trade and professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX>/E <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in order to characterize the current
state of the art from a broader perspective.
The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest building <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>,
acquires <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> to support specific
functions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> and the general conduct of its business. It
spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $20 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> design,
construction, and related services. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Owners</ENAMEX>, the government
included, traditionally have maintained some level of internal
facility planning and design oversight capability to ensure that
new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> acceptably balance the factors of cost, schedule,
quality, and performance.
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>, as a result of efforts to reduce the size
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have downsized their design and engineering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> and relied more on outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> for technical
expertise. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have generally retained their design
oversight responsibilities, fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> resources are now devoted
to reviewing facility designs. The changes in the facilities
acquisition environment led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> to conclude that a review of
issues, practices, and methods related to the design phase of the
acquisition process would be beneficial.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
The report was authored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph S. Spillinger</ENAMEX> in conjunction
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC Standing Committee on Organizational Performance</ENAMEX> and
Metrics. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spillinger</ENAMEX> is a retired federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> with 30 years
experience in planning, design, and construction of federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CII</ENAMEX>'s membership includes several federal agenciesGSA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USACE</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAVFAC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIST</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Valley Authority</ENAMEX>.


B285663



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC Findings</ENAMEX>
The core issues of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> study concern the value added by
design review processes and the appropriate role of facilities
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, particularly federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, in such processes. In
developing a detailed scope of work for its study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> found that
no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the sponsoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> defined the design review process
and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> in exactly the same way. Nor was a common start or
end point identified for design review. In view of the lack of
commonly accepted definitions of the elements, duration, and
substance of the design review process, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> decided to focus on
practices for reviewing facility design over the entire facility
acquisition process. The study viewed design review as a
multiphased process not limited to the reviewing of designs during
the design phase of the acquisition. The objective of the study was
to identify a range of best practices and technologies that could
be used by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to provide adequate
management and oversight of design reviews throughout the facility
acquisition process.
Briefly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> study presents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> key findings on design
review processes.



•
Effective design review processes add value by saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> and money over the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> acquisition
process.

Effective design review processes result in the preparation of
more comprehensive and accurate design and construction documents
that, in turn, result in lower project construction costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Areas</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> include less rework on the part of the construction
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contractor</ENAMEX>, fewer change orders to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> for correction of
design errors or omissions, and a lowering of the cost of belatedly
adding project upgrade features that should have been addressed in
the original design. Indirect cost savings can be realized by
avoiding costs associated with loss of productivity during
constructiondelayed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> startup, and with litigation. In
short, effective review of designs maximizes the probability that a
business requirement will be successfully supported by a facility
that was conceived, designed, constructed, and placed into
operation efficiently and effectively.



•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> responsible for design oversight should include
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of all project stakeholders: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX>/E,
construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> and maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and major
equipment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>.

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> should participate in and contribute to designrelated
activities associated with each phase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition
process, from conceptual planning through startup.


•
The use of metrics by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to measure the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">value</ENAMEX> added by design review processes is not well
established.


Although research has been done by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Construction Industry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to identify metrics that may be
used to measure both the efficiency and the effectiveness of each
phase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition process, the extent to which
individual federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> measure design review processes and
analyze results is highly variable.

B285663



•
To provide effective oversight of design review
processes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s interests are best served when the inhouse
staff can fulfill the functions of a "smart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>.

A smart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> is one who retains an inhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> who
understands the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s mission, its requirements, and its
customer needs, and who can translate those needs and requirements
into corporate direction. A smart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> also retains the requisite
capabilities and technical knowledge to lead and conduct teaming
activities, accurately define the technical services needed,
recognize value during the acquisition of such technical services,
and evaluate the quality of services ultimately provided. As long
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> retains the inhouse capabilities to operate as a smart
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, there does not appear to be any greater risk
from contracting out a broad range of design reviewrelated
functions, so long as such functions are widely available from a
competitive commercial marketplace. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> does not have the
capacity to operate as a smart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> risks project
schedule and cost overruns and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> that do not meet
performance objectives.


•
The ongoing revolution in information technology and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> offers opportunities to improve design review
processes.


Examples include audio and video teleconferencing, immediate and
widespread data distribution via the Internet, computeraided design
and drafting, and a wide range of project management software.
Emerging technologies, such as the use of holographic projection
techniques to create threeand fourdimensional models of project
designs, guarantee a continuing stream of future enhancements.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> study identifies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> best practices for the review of
designs, which it summarized as follows:


Role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Owner</ENAMEX>


•
Be a smart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>.


•
Develop a scope of work that clearly and accurately
defines the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s expectations regarding cost, schedule,
performance, and quality.


•
Avoid the temptation to micromanage the design review
process.




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamwork</ENAMEX> and Collaboration


•
Use teambuilding and partnering techniques.


•
Ensure that all interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> participate in design
review processes.


•
Use the same A/E throughout the process.


•
Use senior, experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to evaluate the evolving
design and guide the review process.


•
Commit for the duration of the activity.


•
Participate in a design awards program.




B285663
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advance Planning</ENAMEX>


•
Focus attention at the front end during the conceptual
planning and design phases, where the ability to influence the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX> cost of the project is the greatest.


•
Do not start the final stage of design until the
preliminary engineering is complete.




Process


•
Tailor the review approach to project
specifics.


•
Keep up the pace of the process to maintain
momentum.


•
Pay special attention to civil, structural,
architectural, electrical, and mechanical interfaces.


•
Exploit technology.


•
Conduct a postoccupancy evaluation to develop a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lessonslearned</ENAMEX> document.




Benchmarking


•
Measure results achieved by the design
process.



•
Document both unusually good and bad
performance.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX>'s study identifies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> areas where it was felt that
additional cooperation, research, and discussion could lead to
either fundamentally new approaches or significant improvements to
current practices. These areas are


•
establishment of a seniorlevel advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> on federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> issues;


•
identification of a set of metrics that could be used to
measure performance across all phases of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition
process;


•
evaluation of current practices of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with
regard to the standards, guidelines, and policies supplied to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Es</ENAMEX>
in support of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition activities; and


•
study of the potential benefits of establishing a peer
review process for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> design review practices.


The study also identifies a number of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> initiatives
related to the design review process. These initiatives are
included in the enclosure to this letter, which provides a more
detailed presentation of pertinent information extracted from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> study relating to the changing facilities acquisition
environment confronting federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> today, facility
acquisition practices and trends, and best practices.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government/Industry Forum</ENAMEX>
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 24, 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> sponsored a government/industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> on
best practices for reviewing facility designs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> registered to attend the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX>. The major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institution</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> highlighted identified best practices and tools that
can be used by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to manage
and/or oversee design reviews throughout the facility

B285663
acquisition process. The findings and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> best practices
highlighted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFCsponsored</ENAMEX> study were presented to the forum
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX>. Government and industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>
discussed best practices, tools, and processes they have used or
seen used to review facility designs, and suggested how federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> could use such tools and processes to foster quality
design.
In addition, presentations were made on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> systems that have
been developed to support different aspects of the design review
process. These design review tools were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s DrChecks
software program for documenting, collecting, distributing, and
archiving design review comments; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Construction Industry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute's</ENAMEX> (CII) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Definition Rating</ENAMEX> Index for preproject
planning; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REDICHECK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Interdisciplinary Coordination</ENAMEX> system
for design reviews-the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> system designed specifically to
correct the interdisciplinary coordination discrepancies that
account for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of the construction change orders involving
errors and omissions.



FFC Comments
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 24, 2000</TIMEX>, we asked both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> and the
primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> study to review and comment on a draft of
this letter and enclosure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX> Both concurred with our presentation
of the information. In her letter dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7, 2000</TIMEX>, the FFC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> said that the letter fairly and objectively presented the
findings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> study, and the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> in his letter
dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 5, 2000</TIMEX>, said that the abridgement of the study both
accurately reflected the report and maintained its spirit and
intent. Both provided minor technical changes and updated
information, which we incorporated into the letter and enclosure I
where appropriate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>'s letter is reproduced in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">enclosure II</ENAMEX>, and the letter of the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> study
is reproduced in enclosure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>.
We are sending copies of this letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George V.</ENAMEX>
Voinovich, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max S. Baucus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Environment and Public Works</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
Franks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wise, Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranking</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on Economic Development</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Buildings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hazardous Materials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pipeline Transportation</ENAMEX>,
request.
If you have any questions about this letter, please call me or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron King</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) 5128387.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard L. Ungar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Business Operations</ENAMEX> Issues
Enclosure I


Abridgment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Facilities Council Study on Facility</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design Reviews</ENAMEX>
WecondensedtheFFCstudyAddingValuetotheFacilityAcquisition
Process: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BestPracticesforReviewingFacilityDesigns</ENAMEX>,FederalFacilities
CouncilTechnicalReport<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#139</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>:NationalAcademy
Press,n.d.),authoredbyRalphS.SpillingerinconjunctionwiththeFFC
StandingCommitteeonOrganizationalPerformanceandMetrics,tofocus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">onissuesthataddresstheconcernsoftherequesters</ENAMEX>.Wemademinor
revisionstothewordinginsomeinstancesforclarityandcontextual
purposes.Wealsoomittedpartsofthestudy,includingsomefootnotes
andbibliographicreferences,toshortenthepresentation.Wehave
neverthelessretainedtheessentialelementsandrelativecompletenessof
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theoriginalFFCstudy</ENAMEX>.

Background
The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, like private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, acquires <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> to support specific functions
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> and the general conduct of its business. Confronted
with a requirement to acquire a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> or other constructed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facility</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner organizations</ENAMEX>, both public and private,
traditionally participate in a multiphased process involving
conceptual planning, design, procurement, construction, and
startup. Throughout this process, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> usually maintain some
level of design oversight to ensure that the acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> is
an acceptable balance of cost, schedule, quality, and
performance.
Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> often maintained an inhouse
facilities engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, comprised in part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, responsible for both the technical
aspects and the oversight of the planning and design phases of the
acquisition process. As a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and legislative
initiatives to reduce the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
have downsized their design and engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> are
increasingly using outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> to provide technical
expertise for the planning and design phases of both new projects
and major renovations of existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Although oversight
responsibility for the facility planning and design phases
generally remains within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> resources are
being devoted to the effort than in the past.
Concurrent with downsizing, procurement regulations have been
modified to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> greater flexibility and choice in
selecting contracting methods for acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. As recently
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as 5 years ago</TIMEX>, the designbidbuild method of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition
was used almost exclusively. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> increasingly rely on
designbuild, construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and program management
contracting methods. Further, advances in computeraided design and
other technologies are occurring

Defining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design Review</ENAMEX>
simultaneously with process changes in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>,
increasing the importance of technology support in the design
process.
Prior to developing a detailed scope of work for the study, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor agencies</ENAMEX> shared information on their own design review
processes and the design review processes of some private sector
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> with which they were familiar. Analysis of this
information revealed that no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> defined the
design review process and its various elements in exactly the same
manner. Nor was a common start or end point identified for design
review as an element of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition process.
For some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, design review was limited to reviewing a
consultantprepared schematic design to ensure that it met the owner
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>'s functional requirements for floor area, functional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjacencies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX>, and budget. For other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>,
design review primarily involved reviewing a more detailed facility
design prepared by an inhouse design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> or a private A/E firm
under contract.
The level of the review and the elements reviewed-for example,
architectural reviews, mechanical and electrical interface reviews,
or constructability1 reviews-also varied. Some processes were
formal, incorporating design reviews at specific design milestones
(such as at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 30</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of design completion). Others
were less formal, relying on periodic meetings between the owner
and the design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to review the progress being made toward
preparation of final construction contract plans and
specifications.
The core issues of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> study concerned the valueadded of
design


Study Purpose and
review processes and the appropriate level of oversight for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of
Objective <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, particularly federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, in such
processes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX>'s objective was to identify a range of best
practices and technologies that can be used by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to provide adequate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and oversight of design
reviews throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition process. Specifically,
it sought to provide answers to the following questions:


•
What is the valueadded of design review
processes?


•
How do (and how can) federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> measure the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valueadded</ENAMEX>?


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">constructability</TIMEX> reviews, experienced construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>
look for such items as inappropriate materials, physical barriers,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> interfaces that will unnecessarily complicate the
construction phase.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD00172R Study on Facility Design Reviews</ENAMEX>


•
What is the role of inhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and what value do they
add to design review processes?


•
What functions are being (and should be) contracted to
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>?


•
What skills and resources do federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> need to
provide effective oversight of design review processes?


•
What risks and liabilities do federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> face in
outsourcing most or all of their design review
functions?


•
How can new and emerging technologies be integrated into
design review processes?




The process of acquiring a
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> usually includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> phases that can be generalized as
conceptual planning, design, procurement, construction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Practices</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry</ENAMEX> and startup. The contracting method used will
determine whether the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> phases occur in sequence or if some
phases occur concurrently. The
contracting method can also affect who is involved at each phase
(A/E,
construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>, etc.). For example, using the
designbidbuild
contract method, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> phases generally occur in sequence
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX>/E
involved in the design phase and a construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> in
the
construction phase. A designbuild acquisition, in contrast, will
use the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> for the design and construction phases, thus
allowing
some phases and activities to occur concurrently. Regardless of
the
contracting method used, the acquisition of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> will
necessarily
involve activities and decisions related to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> phases.
During the conceptual planning phase various feasibility studies
are done to define the scope or statement of work based on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s expectations for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> performance, quality, cost, and
schedule. Several alternative design solutions can be considered
during this phase, leading up to the selection of a single
preferred approach. The preferred approach may be a schematic that
includes functional requirements, such as square footage estimates
for various functions and adjacencies or connections to functions
that are desirable or required.
The design phase usually starts once the statement of work and
preferred design approach have been developed. From the schematic,
the design matures into final construction documents comprising the
plans and specifications from which equipment procurement and
construction bids can be solicited. Estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> cost and
schedule issues receive increasingly intense review during the
design phase so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> has a high level of confidence prior
to bid that the performance, quality, cost, and schedule objectives
defined during the conceptual planning phase can be met.
Complex <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility projects</ENAMEX> usually include a procurement phase in
order to expedite the purchase, manufacture, and delivery of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">longleadtime</ENAMEX> equipment, such as unique process machinery, large
electrical and mechanical equipment, and sophisticated
architectural components. Such equipment procurement may proceed in
parallel with construction phase activities, so that the owner
ultimately is able to furnish longleadtime equipment to the
construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> in a timely manner, thus avoiding
construction delays attributable to late equipment delivery.
Early in the construction phase a formal construction management
plan is developed describing the intended sequence and method of
construction activity as well as the relationships,
responsibilities, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> of all involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX>/E, construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>, specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>, and
relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>). The biggest challenge during the
construction phase is managing changes resulting from such sources
as scope of work changes by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, errors and omissions in the
construction documents, and unknown or changed site conditions. The
construction phase is considered complete when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> accepts
occupancy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>, although final completion of
construction may continue for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> (or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>) until all
discrepancies have been identified, resolved, and mutually agreed
upon.
The startup phase, sometimes called commissioning, begins with
occupancy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>. Building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> are
tested individually and then together with other components in
order to measure and compare their performance against the original
design criteria. Facility operation and maintenance plans are
implemented, tested, and refined as appropriate.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 20 years</TIMEX>, change has been particularly
pronounced with


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downsizing of Facility</ENAMEX>
regard to how corporate and government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> manage the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acquisition Engineering Organizations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>. As noted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBR</ENAMEX> in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> white paper,
"Virtually all major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have reduced the size and scope of
work performed by engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are
drifting because they are uncertain about the appropriate size and
role of their inhouse capital <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">projects organization</ENAMEX>. Nearly every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s engineering and project management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
has been reorganized, sometimes repeatedly, without achieving a
satisfactory result in many cases."<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> engineering downsizing has resulted in
increased use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> to perform design and construction
functions. Graphs published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBR</ENAMEX>, based on data compiled by
Independent Project
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Stake</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Effective Project Systems</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBR</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>).
Analysis (IPA) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,000</NUMEX> projects from
a variety of industries, show a decline in the percentage of major
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>' inhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 30 percent</NUMEX>
during <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19701975</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 25 percent</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19811985</TIMEX>, to less than
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> originally identified the project definition
activity as a core competency<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPA</ENAMEX>'s data indicate that
project definition, too, is increasingly being outsourced. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>
compiled through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CII</ENAMEX>, closely correlates with TBR
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>.4
Fortunately, an increasingly competitive, productive,
sophisticated, and capable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> design and construction
industry is capable and willing to take on this increased workload.
Unfortunately, this trend has not reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>' overall
engineering costs as a percentage of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">TPC.5</NUMEX> The engineering share of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX> has increased over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20 years</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 to 20 percent</NUMEX>. The
interpretation of this increase is controversial: It is not clear
if the increase reflects an increased cost of outsourced
engineering or simply the cost of increased intensity of
engineering required by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s technologydriven projects and more
sophisticated design and construction practices.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, federal regulations have been modified to allow
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">agencies</ENAMEX>


Contracting Methods
greater flexibility and choice in the contract methods used for
acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Downsizing and the increased outsourcing of
design and construction services have provided the impetus for
selecting methods other than the traditional designbidbuild
contract method.
Although there are many variations, current practice recognizes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> basic categories of contract types that apply to several
facility acquisition systems:


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> contract,


•
construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,


•
designbuild, and


•
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
Core competency is defined as an essential skill that should be
retained within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in order to perform
effectively.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benchmarking</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Metrics Summary</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benchmarking</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metrics Committee</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX> is defined as the sum total of all costs associated with a
project's planning, development, design, construction, outfitting,
and startup, not including land costs.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD00172R Study on Facility Design Reviews</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Contract Approach</ENAMEX>
Construction Management Approach
•
•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DesignBuild Contract Approach</ENAMEX>
The general contract approach assumes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> contracts
individually for all engineering and construction services required
to acquire a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. This is the traditional approach that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">largescale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> (both public and private) used to design and
construct their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> until the relatively recent growth of
interest in outsourcing of design and construction services. It is
illustrative of the designbidbuild contract method used by federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
Under this approach, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> manages individual contracts with
all design, engineering, and construction service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>,
implying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> must also manage all interfaces between
service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interface</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> becomes critical because
assessment of accountability for problems incurred during the
project's evolution is difficult due to the variety and separation
of individual contracts. To succeed, such a process requires a
relatively large and experienced facility design, engineering, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management staff</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in order to
protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s interests.
Under the construction management approach, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> contracts
with an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to manage the construction of a project. The
construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> (CM) may function either as an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>, or
as an "atrisk" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency CM</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> holds all individual construction
contracts, and the CM functions as the construction contract
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>, acting on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> and rendering an
account of activities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> is typically not responsible for
construction means and methods, nor does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> guarantee
construction cost, time, or quality. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atrisk</ENAMEX> CM: The actual
construction work is performed by trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> under contract
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>, who then becomes responsible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> for
construction means and methods and delivery of the completed
facility within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s scope of work for cost, time, and
quality.
Under this approach, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> typically retains responsibility
for managing all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">preconstruction A</ENAMEX>/E services, and therefore must
address all interface issues between service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>.
The designbuild contract approach represents a much larger step
toward outsourcing of traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> functions than occurs with
the abovedescribed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> contract. Under this approach, an owner
prepares a project scope definition and then engages a single
entity that will provide all services necessary to complete the
design and construct the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>.
Generally, the scope definition package represents a design that
is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 15 and 35 percent</NUMEX> complete, although variations may
begin much earlier, often with a performance specification, or much
later with perhaps a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX> design package.
Project success under this approach is primarily dependent on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s ability to produce a comprehensive, welldefined, and
unambiguous scope of work upon which all subsequent designbuild
activity will be based. Once the designbuild contract has been
awarded, changes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> requirements will generally incur heavy
penalties to the project cost and schedule. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> is therefore
well advised to ensure that preparation of the project scope
definition package accurately and clearly expresses expectations
for project performance, quality, cost, and schedule.
Use of the designbuild approach for project delivery is growing
dramatically in both public and private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAVFAC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> have become particularly strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of this
approach, but not without controversy.
The program management contract method represents the ultimate
step in outsourcing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s project management functions.
The program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> (PM) is engaged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> to exercise
oversight of the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> delivery process for a multitude
of projects. Similar to the construction management approach, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX> can serve in either an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>" or "atrisk" capacity.
Program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Contract Approach</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Owner</ENAMEX> as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smart Buyer</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business has regained its competitive edge by
reengineering its business practices to improve their effectiveness
and, in the process, downsize their inhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. However,
competitive pressures caused many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to approach staff
downsizing without adequate planning. Mistakes were made:
reductions were insufficient, or too extensive, or made in the
wrong area.
The loss of technical competence through downsizing was
sufficiently pervasive that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX>, in conjunction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBR</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAVFAC</ENAMEX>, conducted the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government/Industry Forum on Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Facilities and Core Competencies</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1998</TIMEX>. A fundamental
finding of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> facilities engineering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> need to identify and retain core competencies-the
essential technical and managerial skills that cannot be outsourced
without serious risk to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s ability to conceive and
acquire necessary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum participants</ENAMEX> recognized the
advisability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> performing as a "smart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outsourced</ENAMEX> services. A smart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> is one who retains an inhouse
staff capable of


•
understanding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s business or mission, its
requirements, its customer needs, and who can translate those needs
and requirements into corporate direction or mission;


•
accurately defining the technical services to be
contracted;


•
evaluating the quality, performance effectiveness, and
value of technical work performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>; and


•
managing the interface between technical service
contractors and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s lineofbusiness <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> who will
ultimately benefit from services provided.


These functions are intrinsic to the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition
process and underscore the need for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s inhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to be
intimately involved in these aspects of the process, particularly
the leadership role.
It should be intuitive that poor planning and design practices
result in


Cost Implications of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Facility</ENAMEX>
Acquisition Practices increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX>. These cost growth drivers
include



•
construction change orders required to correct errors and
omissions in the design documents;

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">•</ENAMEX> ownerdriven construction change orders required to
incorporate desirable features overlooked during design;


•
inefficient construction resulting from a failure to
incorporate constructionenhancing features during
design;


•
rework resulting from unclear construction
documents;


•
standby costs incurred while construction is either
stopped or slowed to incorporate changes;


•
litigation;


•
delayed completion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> (i.e., lost business
revenue, staff standby, nonproductive capital investment costs);
and


•
a poorly performing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>.


Numerous research reports have been published characterizing
cost growth resulting from poor planning and design practices. The
following are a few of the key statistics contained in documents
abstracted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7, 8, 9, 10</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benchmarking</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Metrics Summary</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CII</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benchmarking</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metrics Committee</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Stake</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Effective Project Systems</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBR</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD00172R Study on Facility Design Reviews</ENAMEX>


•
Project design costs average <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX>.


•
Total project engineering costs average <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of TPC
(in addition to design costs discussed above, includes planning,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, and project management costs).


•
Project rework costs average <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.4 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX>
percent of this rework results from errors and omissions in the
design documents. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">The remaining 20 percent</NUMEX> results from poor
construction practices.


•
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Fifty percent</NUMEX> of construction change orders result from
errors in the design documents directly related to improper
interfaces between design disciplines (civil, structural,
architectural, electrical, and mechanical). These change order
costs contribute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from 0.8</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.4 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive</ENAMEX> review of project document development
during the design phase of acquisition should cost from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX>. Properly done (i.e., using best practices discussed
later in this study), such activity should drive down the cost of
construction change orders by an average of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX>.


•
To evaluate the value of thorough concept definition a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIIled</ENAMEX> review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> projects compared final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX> against the
estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time</TIMEX> of project approval for construction. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> with the highest degree of definition averaged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX>
cost underrun. The middle <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> projects averaged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underrun</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> projects with the lowest definition averaged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
percent cost overrun.


•
Indirect costs, the business impact costs discussed
above, are highly variable and very difficult to estimate, but are
potentially huge. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orderofmagnitude</ENAMEX> estimate would be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">815 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX>.


•
Research conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redichek Associates</ENAMEX>, an A/E firm
specializing in outsourced design review, indicates that the single
biggest source of construction change orders (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 50</NUMEX>
percent) is errors in the design documents directly related to
improper interfaces between design disciplines (civil, structural,
architectural, electrical, and mechanical). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redichek</ENAMEX>'s cost for
conducting the discipline interface design review is approximately
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX>, with a resultant reduction of rework cost
ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.8</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.4 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX>. The estimated payback ratio
here ranges from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 to $34</NUMEX> saved for every dollar invested in a
discipline


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
Costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Deviations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design & Construction</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CII</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Publication 101</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William T. Nigro</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha W. Nigro</ENAMEX>, Redicheck
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Interdisciplinary Coordination</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3rd</TIMEX> edition (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peachtree City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REDICHECK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>).
10
Measuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cost of Quality</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design & Construction</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CII</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Publication 102</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD00172R Study on Facility Design Reviews</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Effective Design Review Processes</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC Conclusions</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interface</ENAMEX> design review activity.
The implication of these statistics is that opportunity exists
to significantly reduce TPC by conducting an effective design
review process. The potential savings range from a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 20 percent</NUMEX>, and even higher when indirect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> are taken into account.
Intuitively, good design review practices result in the
preparation of more comprehensive and accurate construction
documents, which in turn result in lower project construction
costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Areas</ENAMEX> of savings include less rework on the part of the
construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>, fewer change orders for correction of
design errors or omissions, and the cost of belatedly adding
project upgrade features that should have been addressed in the
original design. By reducing changes that are required during the
construction phase, good design review practices also generate
significant indirect cost savings by avoiding costs associated with
loss of productivity during constructiondelayed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> startup,
and litigation.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s and 1990s</TIMEX>, a number of business practice
studies were conducted by construction trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>,
professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>, and academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to better understand
which practices produced better results in terms of facility
performance, quality, cost, and schedule. These studies concluded
that quality design yields <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that perform well throughout
their service lives<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX> Quality design resulted when all interested
parties (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX>/E, construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>, and specialty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition process worked together in
an intense, collaborative, complex, and multiphased process
beginning with conceptual planning and concluding after the startup
phase.
These business practice studies also found that decisions made
during the conceptual planning phase will establish initial
constraints limiting future design flexibility. These early
decisions thus have a disproportionately greater influence on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facility</ENAMEX>'s ultimate performance, quality, cost, and schedule than
decisions made later in the process. The conceptual planning phase
should therefore be the phase when the review of designs is most
intense, with the primary focus upon ensuring the appropriateness,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuracy</ENAMEX>, and thoroughness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s expectations regarding
facility performance, quality, cost, and schedule. This will be
especially true when using the designbuild and program management
contract methods when
11
Improving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design Quality of Federal Buildings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRC</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> on Improving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design Quality of Federal Buildings</ENAMEX>,
Building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Board</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Academy Press</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD00172R Study on Facility Design Reviews</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s involvement in design reviews declines after the
conceptual planning phase.
If design review activity during the conceptual planning phase
has resulted in a clear scope of work regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s
expectations, design reviews during the design phase are greatly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simplified</ENAMEX>. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> involved should focus upon ensuring that
the evolving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> design incorporates high standards of
professional engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>, with regard to architectural,
civil, structural, electrical, and mechanical systems and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interfaces</ENAMEX>. Formal reviews may be scheduled periodically during the
design phase, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately the 35</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60, 90</TIMEX>, and/or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>
design completion milestones (although these milestones may vary
significantly depending on the individual project's size and
complexity). Such structured formality helps ensure the widest
possible participation of interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> during the review,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> who bring expertise in such
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> as value engineering, constructability, biddability,12
operability, maintainability, and environmental compliance.
During the procurement phase, the review of designs can continue
to contribute to overall project success by monitoring progress
made in ordering the various items of longleadtime equipment. It is
not unusual for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> to detect errors in the ordering
specifications, or to make substitution recommendations for either
greater economy or performance enhancement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review team</ENAMEX> should
evaluate the impact of these changes on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> performance,
quality, cost, and schedule.
It is almost inevitable during the construction phase that scope
of work changes by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, errors and omissions in the plans,
unknown or changed site conditions, and creative initiatives on the
part of construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> will result in recommended changes to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> design. Design reviews in this phase should focus on
assessing the impact and advisability of changes on facility
performance, quality, cost, and schedule.
Design reviews should continue into the startup phase. At this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juncture</ENAMEX>, it is important to document the results achieved by
conducting what is commonly referred to as a postoccupancy
evaluation, whose purpose is to record lessons learned for future
reference. Facility performance, quality, cost, and schedule
actually achieved should be objectively measured and compared with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s original expectations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lessons</ENAMEX> learned during
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">biddability</TIMEX> reviews, procurement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> look for
conflicts, errors, omissions, and lack of clarity in the
construction documents that could create confusion on the part of
prospective equipment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> or construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD00172R Study on Facility Design Reviews</ENAMEX>
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> acquisition phases concerning design strengths
and weaknesses should be recorded for use in improving future
similar project activities. And perhaps most important, the
facility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' subjective satisfaction with both the acquisition
process as well as the completed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> should be noted.
Based on industry research by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CII</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX>, and similar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, interviews conducted for this study, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s experience, it can be concluded that an effective design
review process will be structured to address all of the topics
included in table <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Topic Key</ENAMEX> question to be addressed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Owner</ENAMEX> satisfaction Does the constructed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> meet the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s expectations as originally defined by the project scope
definition or statement of work (i.e., performance characteristics,
architectural statement, level of quality, cost, schedule, and any
relevant ownerpublished standards and/or policies)?
Sound professional practice Is the approach taken in each of the
specialty areas (architectural, civil, mechanical, and electrical)
commensurate with professional standards?
Code compliance Does the design comply with all applicable
codes, such as fire protection, life safety, and access?
Architectural statement Is the overall presentation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of established architectural standards?
Value engineering Are there any less expensive methods or
materials that could be used in the design without impacting
project quality or performance (or lifecycle costs)?
Biddability Are the construction documents sufficiently clear
and comprehensive so construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> will have no
difficulty developing an accurate bid with minimal allowance for
contingency?
Constructability Does the design impose any unnecessarily
difficult or impossible demands on the construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>?
Operability Does design of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> operating systems ensure
ease and efficiency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>'s useful
lifetime?
Maintainability Does the facility design allow for easy and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">costeffective</ENAMEX> maintenance and repair over the useful life of the
facility?
Lifecycle engineering Does the design represent the most
effective balance of cost to construct, cost to start up, cost to
operate and maintain, and (perhaps most important) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>'s cost
to perform the intended function for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> is being
acquired over the useful life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>?
Postoccupancy evaluation Based on a review of the construction,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">startup</ENAMEX>, and ongoing functioning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>, could any
unexpected difficulty have been avoided by a different design
approach?
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Facilities Council Technical</ENAMEX> Report <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#139</NUMEX>.

Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> comprise a
portfolio of significant, durable assets that have been acquired to
support specific functions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Practices</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> general conduct of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s business. It is
estimated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies government</ENAMEX> spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $20 billion</NUMEX> per
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> for new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and major
renovations of existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Even a relatively small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IHS</ENAMEX> is a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $265 million</NUMEX> of construction
activity in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning</ENAMEX>, design, or construction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as of 1999</TIMEX>. At the other end
of the spectrum are the truly capitalintensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, such as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of the Navy</ENAMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> construction
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>.
As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX>, priorities, and situations change, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> may
experience wide fluctuations in the scope and budget for their
facility acquisition programs. For example, a recent program to
upgrade federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouses</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX>
of dollars to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s construction activity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> is facing a similar
situation. Following the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> bombings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>,
legislation requiring rapid and extensive upgrade of embassy
security features worldwide was enacted which could require several
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion dollars</NUMEX> to execute. Given the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
expenditures on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, it is important that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
have effective design review processes that result in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
that perform well throughout their service lives.
Like private sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' facilities
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineering</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> have been considerably downsized in the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1015 years</TIMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> report of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> noted that "due to budget cuts,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have had to reduce the number of project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, design
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reviewers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>, and field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> they employ."
Procurement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> trained primarily in contract negotiation
and review rather than design and construction have been playing
increasingly greater roles in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">facilities</ENAMEX> development<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX>
The federal downsizing trend accelerated after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> as a result
of a changed global environment, a shift in focus toward smaller
and more costeffective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and a number of legislative
initiatives. In the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that responded to the
questionnaire associated with this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> report, facilities
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineering</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> have been reduced on the order of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 to 65</NUMEX>
percent, with the average at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50 percent</NUMEX>. As a consequence of
the loss of technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>,
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are increasingly outsourcing design and
constructionrelated functions.



Downsizing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Facilities Engineering Organizations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DesignReviewRelated Trends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine Federal Agencies</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing Committee on Organizational Performance</ENAMEX> and
Metrics developed a twopart questionnaire focused on design review
processes and distributed it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor agencies</ENAMEX>. Part one was
sent to senior facilities engineering program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> level and focused on agencywide policy issues. Part
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> was sent to randomly selected project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> at the field
activity level and focused on
13
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Responsibilities of Architects</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineers</ENAMEX> and Their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Clients</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Facilities Development</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ArchitectEngineer Responsibilities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building Research Board</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Academy Press</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD00172R Study on Facility Design Reviews</ENAMEX>
How <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Are Agency Facility Engineering Functions Organized</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Carry</ENAMEX>
Out Their Missions?
What Has Been the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extent of Downsizing on Agency Facility</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineering Organizations</ENAMEX>?
How <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Are Agency Facilities Engineering Organizations Responding</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mitigate the Impacts of Downsizing</ENAMEX>?
individual project review issues. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that
answered the questionnaires were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANG</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IHS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAVFAC</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VA.</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> report included a summary and analysis of questionnaires
returned by each of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that described the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
design review practices at the time of the study. The following
discussion compares and contrasts the responses contained in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>
questionnaires that were returned by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> listed
above.
There is no single organizational model for federal agency
facilities engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are
governmentowned but contractoroperated. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>,
have moved to fieldbased design review and a mix of fieldbased and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headquartersbased</ENAMEX> project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. Others, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>, have a
centralized program policy and oversight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, with all program
and project management functions conducted at the field activity
level. The majority of the responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> maintain multiple
regional project execution <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> engineering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> experienced significant downsizing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1994</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, on the order of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 to 50 percent</NUMEX> reduction of inhouse staff
positions (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>'s reduction has been estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX>). As
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1999</TIMEX>, only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANG</ENAMEX> have been able to maintain a
relatively stable situation with regard to staff size.
During the early stages of downsizing, the responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
simply tried to do more with less. However, this adaptation became
untenable at a certain point. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> then began to reengineer
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> engineering processes and practices. Intensity of
this reengineering varies among the responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, reflecting
the fact that the speed and extent of downsizing has varied greatly
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to another. Impactreducing strategies reported by
various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> include the following:


•
Augmenting inhouse staffing voids through personal
service contracts. Personal service contracts allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to add
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor staff</ENAMEX> to inhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> on a temporary basis to fill
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voids</ENAMEX> in specific disciplines, or to address unusual peaks in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workload</ENAMEX>. Procurement policies vary among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with regard to
allowing use of personal services contracts.


•
Outsourcing functions previously accomplished inhouse.
Nearly all facility acquisition functions except <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> and oversight have been considered for outsourcing by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or another.


•
Reducing the intensity of oversight activities such as
design review and construction inspection by either contracting
such functions to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, or by including the functions
within the scope of the design and/or construction primary
contracts.


•
Eliminating some activities entirely. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NAVFAC</ENAMEX> field
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> reported that it has eliminated formal design reviews on
many smaller projects, holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A/Es</ENAMEX> responsible for instituting a
selfreview process. Similarly, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> region reported that it
generally only requires a single formal progress review during
design.


•
Using project delivery contracting schemes that shift
more responsibility for design and construction oversight to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contractor</ENAMEX>, such as designbuild, construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAVFAC</ENAMEX> reports that designbuild is now
the favored contracting strategy and the traditional designbidbuild
strategy has become the least favored.


Why and How Do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Risk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, compliance with user
expectations, and reductions of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Agencies Approach the Practice</ENAMEX>
change orders were cited as the primary reasons for conducting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">design of Design Review</ENAMEX>? reviews. The least cited reason was to
maintain inhouse core
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">competencies</ENAMEX>. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> report participation
in a
design review process. Significant differences were noted,
however, as
follows:


•
All responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> reported that they participated
in design reviews, although not at every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field office</ENAMEX> (a few field
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of decentralized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> reported
no or minimal design reviews- they rely on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Es</ENAMEX> to selfreview their
work). Also, the degree to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and their field
activities varied the intensity of the design review process
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX> simple and complex projects varied greatly from one agency
to another.


•
Design review functions identified as having the greatest
valueadded were scope and budget compliance, constructability, and
compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> design guides. Functions identified as
adding the least value were the discipline reviews-architectural,
electrical, mechanical, and structural (although the responses did
not support the idea that these functions could be dropped from the
review process without risk.)


•
Nearly all responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> reported conducting formal
design reviews at the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 and 90 percent</NUMEX> project design milestones.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only two</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>) reported conducting formal reviews
routinely earlier than the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> milestone.



•
The primary criteria used to determine the intensity of
design review are project value, complexity, and the project
delivery method. Conversely, these criteria had little impact on
the decision to review with inhouse or

outsourced resources. That decision rested primarily on inhouse
staff availability.


•
When elements of design review are outsourced, all
responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> still use inhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to review project scope
and budget compliance. The most consistently outsourced elements
included constructability, value engineering, and compliance with
building codes.


•
Nearly all responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> exploit technology tools
to support their design review activities, including computeraided
or assisted design software, Internet and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intranet</ENAMEX> communication
links, and computer software word processing and project management
programs.


•
Fewer than half of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> measure performance of
their design review processes.


How Have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Agencies Eight</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
reported that they have changed Changed Their Approach to their
approach to design reviews since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The primary reasons cited
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design Review</ENAMEX>? change are staff downsizing, changes in contract
methods, and business
process reengineering. The most frequently reported changes
included


•
consolidation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> design guides and standards for
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">simplification,</ENAMEX>


•
increased outsourcing of either parts or all of the
design review activity,


•
exploitation of technology to assist the process,
and



•
reduced frequency of formal design reviews.

Several questions related to outsourcing of design review
functions. Opinions and experience on this issue were varied, and
no conclusions could be reached from the data provided. The
following were typical comments:


•
"Outsourcing results in a loss of core design capability.
This in turn results in a lack of ability to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smart Buyer</ENAMEX>. At
some point, we wouldn't even have enough expertise to hire a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> to conduct design reviews."


•
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outsourcing</ENAMEX> poses no risk, as long as the contractors
are liable for performance."


•
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outsourcing</ENAMEX> poses a very significant risk, particularly
on renovation type work. And it is very difficult to have
technically competent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> in specialty areas."


•
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outsourcing</ENAMEX> is our present way of doing business, and we
have experienced little risk."


Looking to the future, about onethird of the responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
reported that they are considering further outsourcing of design
review functions.
During the course of interviews and an extensive literature
search, a


Interesting Initiatives
number of innovative practices were noted that may have broader
implications. These practices are discussed below.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnering</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teambuilding</ENAMEX> Although this practice is achieving
widespread recognition, some
Training programs have proven more effective than others. USACE
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CII</ENAMEX> have both been recognized for their particular programs,
and both offer formal training.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inhouse Training Programs Agencies</ENAMEX> have developed inhouse
training programs specializing in program and project management
practices for federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Among the oldest are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> run by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USACE</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAVFAC</ENAMEX>. More recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> has developed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> 1week short
courses of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> engineering management practices.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Comment USACE</ENAMEX>'s latest software program used for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">documenting</ENAMEX>, collecting,
Documentation distributing, and achieving design review comments
is called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DR CHEKS</ENAMEX>. It runs on a desktop computer and uses the
Internet for communication among design review <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>.
Perhaps most important, it has features to aid followup of actions
taken in response to review comments, which is a particularly
troublesome area.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Management Center of GSA</ENAMEX> recently established the GSA
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Management Center of Expertise Expertise</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> has
been staffed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s most senior and competent project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to
serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> functions:


•
Actively manage all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s uniquely large, complex, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">highvisibility</ENAMEX> projects, regardless of location.


•
Provide mentoring, counseling, and training services in
the area of project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in support of all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s regional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Standards</ENAMEX> Some large A/E <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have secured ISO
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9000</TIMEX> certification as a quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> (ISO) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9000</TIMEX> control
activity. Among federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USACE</ENAMEX>'s district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
Certification have received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9000</TIMEX> certification for their design
and construction
programs. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> are working
toward ISO <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9000</TIMEX> certification for their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> engineering
activities<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX> It should be noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9000</ENAMEX> does not guarantee a
quality product. Rather, it guarantees that the process that
produces the product (good or bad) has been carefully structured,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">documented</ENAMEX>, and measured. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizations</ENAMEX> have
14
Subsequent to the issuance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFC</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> received ISO
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9000</TIMEX> certification for its headquarters <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and each of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> received certification for the design and
construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division of Engineering Services</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD00172R Study on Facility Design Reviews</ENAMEX>
Conceptual or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advance Planning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design Review Lessons Learned</ENAMEX>
A/E <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Historical Performance Database</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Contractor Performance System</ENAMEX>
found that the process of securing ISO <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9000</TIMEX> registration has
been a valuable experience in understanding just what they do and
how they go about it.
Most projects that fail to meet their planned objectives do so
because of faulty or inadequate predesign development. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CII</ENAMEX> has
recently developed a comprehensive preproject planning approach
that allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to measure whether they have adequately
addressed all predesign requirements. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CII</ENAMEX> also has developed a
training module intended to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in adopting this
recommended approach to preproject planning.
Problems identified in the design review process can become a
powerful tool to improve performance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> uses a method of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">documenting</ENAMEX> and publicizing such lessons learned in an innovative
program called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ProCATS</ENAMEX>. Its purpose is to identify recurring
problems that result in change orders, claims, and delays and then
to take positive steps to avoid such problems in the future. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of its kind in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1996</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hammer Award</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USACE has</ENAMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, maintained a database containing
historical evaluations of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX>/E performance on past projects. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">database</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACASS</ENAMEX>, can be queried by any federal agency
interested in a particular A/E's past performance.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> has developed a multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, shared file system that
allows all authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to have access to the completed
contractor performance evaluations of all subscribing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> via
the Internet. A separate module for each subscribing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is
developed with a unique <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX>, allowing each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> control of agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> and access authority. Planned future enhancements include
automated construction and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX>/E forms, electronic storage of
contractors' rebuttal and comments, electronic and encrypted
transmittal of evaluations to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>, and ad hoc reporting.

