



Results in Brief
All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we examined were using
some form of IT to notify the public about opportunities to
participate in rulemaking and to facilitate the receipt of public
comments. All of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> had web sites that conveyed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> information to the public and/or maintained some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> records in electronic form, and all of them accepted
electronic comments for at least some of their proposed rules.
However, the specific features and uses of IT differed
significantly between and sometimes within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> had established an Internet web site that housed
regulatory information for every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and
was searchable in a variety of ways. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> either had no
such information electronically available or the nature of the
information available varied from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to
another. Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were beginning to use targeted,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proactive</ENAMEX> notifications of forthcoming rules, and some were
experimenting with interactive comment processes.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> with whom we spoke did not
identify any potentially beneficial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITbased</ENAMEX> public participation
applications that had not been adopted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of the
regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we examined. However, some of them
indicated that certain IT practices (e.g., proactive notification
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>, portals and gateways to information for particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>,
and interactive participation mechanisms) should be more widely
used. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
move to a more consistent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, content, and presentation
of information to allow for a more common "look and feel" to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies' ITbased</ENAMEX> public participation mechanisms in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contacted</ENAMEX> said that standardization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITbased</ENAMEX> public participation
innovations across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> could lead to more participation in the
rulemaking process, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> that we contacted
generally did not believe that crossagency standardization was
either necessary or appropriate. They said that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> needed
to develop systems appropriate for their particular circumstances
and that there were no data indicating that the current lack of
standardization was a problem, or that standardization would
improve either the quantity or the quality of the participation
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> receive during the rulemaking process. They also said
that standardization would require substantial resources and that
those resources might be better used in other endeavors.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies Differed</ENAMEX> in Their Use of IT to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Facilitate Public</ENAMEX>
Participation in Rulemaking
In order to participate in the rulemaking process, the public
must first be aware that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are considering rules that could
affect their interests. Therefore, we examined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' use of
IT both to inform the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> of opportunities to participate in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> and to facilitate the receipt of public comments. All of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we examined had IT initiatives in both of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, but the size, scope, and specific elements of those
initiatives differed both between and within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Governmentwide IT Applications to Inform the Public of</ENAMEX>
Opportunities to Participate
Federal regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have used both governmentwide and
agencyspecific <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> to notify the public about opportunities
for public comment on upcoming rules. Some of the traditional
governmentwide notification <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> are now being offered to the
public in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and electronic forms. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unified</ENAMEX>
Agenda of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Regulatory</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deregulatory Actions</ENAMEX> is published
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twice each year</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Service Center</ENAMEX> (RISC), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and provides uniform reporting
of data on regulatory activities under development throughout the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The activities included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Unified Agenda</ENAMEX>
are, in general, those expected to have a regulatory action within
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 12 months</TIMEX>, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> may include activities with
an even longer time frame. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Unified Agenda</ENAMEX> contains a wealth of
information-so much, in fact, that locating information about
specific rulemaking actions can prove daunting. For example, the
most recent edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Unified Agenda</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2000</TIMEX>) describes
4,441 rulemaking actions under development or recently completed by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. However, IT has demonstrably
improved access to this information. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1995</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Unified Agenda</ENAMEX> has been published electronically and is searchable
either through RISC's web site (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://reginfo.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>) or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Printing Office</ENAMEX>'s GPO Access web site (which can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accessed</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX>access.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gpo</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shorterterm</ENAMEX> notice of upcoming rules is provided by the NPRMs
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> publish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Agencies</ENAMEX>
also publish information on scheduled hearings and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
RISC is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Services Administration</ENAMEX>, and works
closely with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> to provide information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
and the public about federal regulations.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPO Access</ENAMEX> is funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Depository Library Program</ENAMEX>,
and has grown out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Printing Office Electronic</ENAMEX>
Information <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Access Enhancement Act of 1993</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. L. 10340</ENAMEX>). It
provides free online access to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1,000</NUMEX> databases, including the
Code of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Regulations</ENAMEX>, the Congressional Record, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Business Daily</ENAMEX>.
other opportunities for public participation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX>. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Unified Agenda</ENAMEX>, the printed version of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> is so voluminous as to be daunting. Federal
agencies publish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of proposed rules <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, and finding
a particular rule on which comments are being solicited can be
difficult. This task has been greatly facilitated by making the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> available electronically and searchable through
the GPO Access web site. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPO Access</ENAMEX> can be used to search the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> with particular search parameters
(e.g., proposed rules issued during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX> containing the
phrase "air quality standards")<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>
Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> Web <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sites to Identify Proposed Rules</ENAMEX>
All of the federal regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we examined also
used their own web sites to disseminate information about their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> plans and activities. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' web sites
differed widely in the content and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of rulemaking
information, the array of tools they offer to facilitate use, and
the extent to which they support customized dissemination of
information to the public. These differences are apparent from the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> page in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' web sites-referred to as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>'
home pages. Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' home pages feature direct links
to their rules and regulations. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s home page
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">epa.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>) has a link called "Legislation &
Regulations," which leads to another link entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulations</ENAMEX> and
Proposed Rules." Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>'s home page (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dot</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>)
includes a link to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dockets, Rules & References</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOL</ENAMEX>'s
home page (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dol</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>) contains a link entitled "Laws &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regs</ENAMEX>." In contrast, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">usda.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>) nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>'
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hhs</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>) home pages had visible information about
general rulemaking activities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>.
The regulatory links on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' home pages did not always
directly identify rules available for comment.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Regulations and Proposed Rules</ENAMEX>" link on its home
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX> allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to transfer to the electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> on the GPO Access web site. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> was then required to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exit EPA</ENAMEX>'s site and use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPO</ENAMEX> site's search tools to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
proposed rules among those of every other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. Although
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Regulations and Proposed Rules</ENAMEX>" link also permitted the user
to identify "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Environmental Documents</ENAMEX>" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>, the
search tools identified any document related to a date or keyword,
not just proposed rules.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dockets, Rules & References</ENAMEX>" link on its home
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX> takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to a second page with other links, including
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation Legislation and Regulation</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT Legislative</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rulemaking Documents</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT Regulations</ENAMEX>, Orders, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Policies</ENAMEX>, and
Regulation." However, none of these links provided a listing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>
proposed rules available for comment. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> site, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>
Regulations, Orders, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policies, and Regulations</ENAMEX>" link directs the
viewer to the GPO Access web site.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOL</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Laws and Regs</ENAMEX>" link on its home page ultimately
allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to identify proposed rules within each of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, and provides a hypertext
link that allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to view a copy of the proposed rules.
However, some of the rules


The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> database is also available through GPO
Access. Although it can be searched by keyword, it contains no
fields or section identifiers to facilitate searches.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Page 4 GAO/</ENAMEX>GGD00135R <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> Rulemaking
that were listed had been published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX> previously,
and were no longer available for comment.
Some of the smaller organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> within these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> provided a listing of proposed rules
available for comment. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Animal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plant Health</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inspection Service</ENAMEX>'s (APHIS) web page contained a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Regulations</ENAMEX>"
link that provides a listing of recently published rules, along
with text or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe Portable Document Format</ENAMEX> (PDF) files allowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to read the rules on line. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS's Administration</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> (ACF) had a web page on "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACF Regulations</ENAMEX>
Currently Open for Comment." However, it was not immediately
apparent how to locate that page from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> home page; the user
had to click on "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS Agencies</ENAMEX>" and, at the ACF web page, use a
"dropdown menu" entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Select a Topic</ENAMEX>" within which the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Regulations Currently Open for Comment</ENAMEX>" page is located. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> (e.g., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Aging</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> for
Toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Substances</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disease Registry</ENAMEX>) did not list rules that were
available for comment. Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Air</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Radiation</ENAMEX>
provided a listing of proposed rules available for public comment.
Again, however, locating that information from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s home page was
not easy or immediately apparent. One route required the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to
access the "Information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Dockets</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Radiation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Docket and Information Center</ENAMEX>" web pages before arriving at a link
to proposed rules available for comment. Similar listings of
recently proposed rules available for comment were not available
using this procedure for other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water</ENAMEX> and Solid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste and Emergency Response</ENAMEX>) and programs (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underground</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Storage Tanks</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Featuring Rules of Interest</ENAMEX>
Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> featured links on their home pages
notifying the public about particular regulatory issues of
widespread public interest. For example, the home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of both DOL
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOL</ENAMEX> pointed to a separate web site for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>
proposed rule on ergonomics, which pulled together in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place all
of the electronic information related to this rulemaking (e.g., the
rule, its economic analysis, and hearings transcripts). As will be
discussed in more detail later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> home page identified a
separate web site for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agricultural and Marketing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service's</ENAMEX> (AMS) proposed rule establishing standards for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organically</ENAMEX> produced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. That site provided a wealth of
information about the proposed rule, including the text of the
rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s regulatory impact assessment, and how to submit
comments and search the comments that have already been
submitted.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portals</ENAMEX> and Gateways
Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> had also developed portals or gateways
providing customized information for particular target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> supports a number of these gateways and has a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gateways</ENAMEX>" button
on its home page identifying them, which includes both HHSsponsored
sites (e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Organ Donation" and "YouthInfo</ENAMEX>") and other sites
(e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. State</ENAMEX> &
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Prevention</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Pesticides</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toxic</ENAMEX>
Substances home page did have a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Laws & Regulations</ENAMEX>" link that
contains a link to a list of proposed rules available for
comment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Page 5 GAO/</ENAMEX>GGD00135R <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> Rulemaking
Local <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gateway"</ENAMEX>). The state and local gateway was designed to
give state and local government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> easy access
to federal information, and includes a link to a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laws/Regulations</ENAMEX>"
page that organizes the information by topic (e.g.,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Families/Children</ENAMEX>") or by related links (e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Laws/Regs/<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presidential Documents</ENAMEX>," where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> can link to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPO Access</ENAMEX> site). One such related link, entitled "Electronic
Rulemaking," identified several electronic rulemaking initiatives
across the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> (e.g., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> docket management
system discussed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>), and provided links to these initiatives.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> had a link on its home page for particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience groups</ENAMEX>. One
such link was a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Gateway</ENAMEX>," which organizes
regulatory information of special interest to small businesses.
This gateway guides small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to a variety of environmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">information</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, and provides links to related resources
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA Small Business Gateway</ENAMEX> also provides a link to
environmental regulations and laws, including "new regulations,
proposed rules, important notices, and the regulatory agenda of
future regulations." However, this is a link to electronic
documents available in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPO Access</ENAMEX>
web site, not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>- specific proposed rules, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> is then
required to use that site's search tools to identify particular
proposed rules.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proactive Notification Systems</ENAMEX>
All of the governmentwide and agencyspecific resources discussed
thus far are passive information systems, requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to take
the initiative and find out about upcoming and recently proposed
rules. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are beginning to use more proactive mechanisms
for alerting the interested public about impending regulatory
actions and opportunities for participation. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>
created a web site for the administrative simplification provisions
that provided information on several related proposed rules. The
site permitted the interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to subscribe to a list server
that would notify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> by email when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPRMs</ENAMEX> and final rules
are published or posted. Similarly, the APHIS web page on recently
published rules and regulations allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to enter keywords and
receive email when certain key words appear on the pages.


Using IT to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Facilitate the Receipt of Public Comments</ENAMEX>
All of the regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we examined explicitly
permitted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to submit electronic comments on some, but not
all, of their recent proposed rules. By creating electronic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dockets</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were expanding the options for public review
and comment not only on proposed rules, but also on regulatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">analyses</ENAMEX> and the variety of other materials that make up the public
record for the rulemaking. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> were also beginning to offer
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> more interactive options for participating in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX>. However, there were significant differences in how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> had implemented these capabilities.
Filing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comments Electronically</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPRMs</ENAMEX> that are published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> have
traditionally instructed interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to submit written
comments on a proposed rule to the appropriate rulemaking docket,
and have provided a mailing address where such comments can be
filed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislative</ENAMEX> and administrative initiatives have encouraged,
and in some cases required, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to provide
information to them electronically. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Elimination Act</ENAMEX> requires OMB to ensure that federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, "when practicable," allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and other entities
the option to submit information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> electronically and
maintain records electronically by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 21, 2003</TIMEX>.
For the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> on which we focused in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX>, we examined the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">576</NUMEX> proposed rules that they published in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">calendar year 1999</TIMEX> to determine the
extent to which they explicitly noted that public comments could be
submitted electronically or by facsimile<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> The results, presented
in figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, indicate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> varied substantially in
those dimensions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOL</ENAMEX> explicitly permitted electronic
comments in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of the rules they proposed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> allowed electronic comments in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 10 percent</NUMEX> of
its proposed rules. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> also varied in the extent to which
they explicitly permitted comments via facsimile, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> not
calling for facsimile comments in any of its proposed rules during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
We excluded from this review proposed rules that were routine or
administrative in nature (e.g., within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Coast Guard</ENAMEX> rules
establishing bridgeopening schedules). A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said that the
Department permits the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to submit comments electronically on
all of its proposed rules.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Page 7 GAO/</ENAMEX>GGD00135R <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> Rulemaking
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies Varied</ENAMEX> in Percentage of Proprosed Rules
Published During <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Calendar Year 1999 Explicitly Permitting</ENAMEX>
Electronic or Facsimile Comments

Note: Comments were considered "electronic" when the rule
explicitly provided for comments to be submitted through the
Internet, by email, or on a computer disk. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX> DOT
rules that did not explicitly provide for electronic comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>
referred the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to its docket management system for more
information about the rule. In that system, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> could file
electronic comments.
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPO Access</ENAMEX>.
In some cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> did not allow "standalone"
electronic or facsimile comments. For example, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> rule and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOL</ENAMEX> rules, any electronic comments that were submitted had to
be accompanied by paper comments as well.6 In other cases,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attachments</ENAMEX> or additional materials, such as studies or journal
articles, could not be submitted electronically; commenters had to
submit those materials separately (in duplicate) to the appropriate
docket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOL</ENAMEX> rules allowing participation by
facsimile, commenters had to submit original written comments as
well.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> said that any public comments submitted electronically for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Superfund Docket</ENAMEX> must also be submitted as a paper
copy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Page 8 GAO/</ENAMEX>GGD00135R <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> Rulemaking
We accessed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> notices for each of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">576</NUMEX>
proposed rules electronically through the GPO Access web site.
Although many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPRMs</ENAMEX> provided an email address to which
comments could be filed, the current system for electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Register notices does not permit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to provide a "hypertext"
link to a site where comments could be immediately filed. An
official at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the Federal Register</ENAMEX> told us that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Printing Office</ENAMEX> was experimenting with upgrading its
publishing system to permit the use of hypertext links in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electronic</ENAMEX> rules. He also noted that any such upgrade would be a
large and expensive effort, and that it was unclear when, if ever,
hypertext links could be added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>. Some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' web sites currently provide for such hypertext links, but
not for comments on rules.7 For example, a button is provided at
the end of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> press release that immediately permits the
interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to file a comment on the announcement. However,
none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> rules that we could access through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s web
site had this feature. Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> rules with their own
dedicated web sites provided separate links to both the rules and
electronic comment procedures (e.g., the AMS organic standards rule
site within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>'s site).
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Providing Access to Regulatory Supporting Materials</ENAMEX>
Regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are required to prepare supporting materials
for many of their proposed and final rules, including economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">analyses</ENAMEX> (i.e., the alternatives considered, and the costs and
benefits of the alternative selected); and descriptions of how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have complied with various rulemaking requirements (e.g.,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, and
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order 12866</ENAMEX>). These materials, as well as the comments
filed by the public in response to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPRM</ENAMEX>, have traditionally been
housed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' rulemaking dockets. Access to these materials
can permit public comments filed on rules to be more informed and
targeted to particular issues.
Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we reviewed had begun to make
supporting materials and public comments electronically available
to the public. DOT had the most extensive docket system-an
electronic, imagebased database covering every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> action within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. The database contained
over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800,000</NUMEX> pages of regulatory and adjudicatory information
stored online for research and retrieval via the Internet. The
information in the docket was searchable by keyword, docket
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">identification</ENAMEX> number, or in other ways. For example, entering the
word "airbag" in the keyword search box yielded a listing of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> documents, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> reports, hearing summaries,
and comments filed by other interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Each of these
documents could then be obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> docket management
system. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> told us that the electronic docket has become
the official rulemaking record for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, enabling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> to
save over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> each year in administrative costs and
facilitating the rulemaking process in other ways (e.g., permitting
agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> to review comments at their desks or at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">home</ENAMEX>).
The closest to this type of electronic commenting system that we
found was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>. There, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> could read a copy of a proposed rule in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX>, click
on a link for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>'s docket management system, and then access that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>'s electronic commenting process. However, the link did not
transfer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to a comment box particular to the rule at
issue.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> either had no such electronic dockets or their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> were not as comprehensive or sophisticated as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>'s system.
Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOL</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> systematically provided regulatory background
information to the public through their web sites. To view most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> rulemaking materials in the official record, even if they were
submitted electronically, interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> must go to the
docket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> and examine the paper files. The
information electronically available in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' rulemaking
dockets sometimes varied within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. For example, the web
site for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> docket contained risk assessments for
many of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> organophosphate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> for just one of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> pages of information about
the rule (e.g., health effects assessment, environmental fate and
effects assessment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> correspondence, and registrant comments).
On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Water</ENAMEX> docket site contained a
narrative description of the docket, an email address, and other
written descriptions; no electronic rulemaking materials were
available. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> recognized that this
varying level of service was being provided to many of the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, and therefore was in the process of improving the
quality and consistency of their electronic dockets.
As previously noted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> sometimes provided electronic
access to docket information for particular rules. For example, the
web page for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX>'s proposed ergonomics rule provides full
transcripts of its public hearings and copies of both its health
effects and economic analyses for the rule, including the expected
effects on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and other small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. In some
cases, though, this information can be difficult to locate. For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s web site provided detailed information on its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
proposed rules on lead and lead compounds and other persistent
bioaccumulative toxins. However, to obtain this information from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s home page a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> must maneuver through a series of pages
(e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX>," a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toxics & Chemicals</ENAMEX>" sublink, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toxic</ENAMEX>
Release Inventory") before arriving at a page featuring links to
the rules and related documents.
Viewing/<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Responding to Comments of Others</ENAMEX>
Several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we examined were using IT to permit
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to view the comments the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> had received on
proposed and final rules. However, the extent to which these
comments were electronically available and the role that this
access played in the rulemaking process varied substantially. In
each of these dimensions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>'s docket management system appeared
to allow substantial public access and utility.


•
In some cases, comments were available to the public only
if those comments had been filed electronically. However, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>'s
document management system, comments received on paper are scanned
into the system, thereby permitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to view all of the
comments submitted by others, regardless of the medium that was
used.


•
In some cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> could view comments only for
rules issued by certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, or for certain rules
within certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. However, public comments were
accessible through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>'s document management system for
virtually all rules issued in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>.


•
In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> could access the
comments filed only after the comment period had closed. However,
in other cases the comments were available while the comment period
was open, thereby allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to respond to the comments
filed by others. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>'s docket management system
maintained all materials submitted during the


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> in the official electronic record. As a result, the
online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> could review all comments on a rulemaking and file a
responding comment while the comment period was still open.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> made comments available electronically for
certain rules or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of rules. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> made an index of
public comments and the text of the comments electronically
available for selected regulatory documents as part of a pilot
program. Comments filed electronically in relation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>
administrative simplification initiative were stored automatically
in a database, and the comments were then publicly available via
the initiative's web site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> could search for comments either
overall, for particular rules, or within particular sections of the
rules. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX> had experimented with several approaches to
accepting and posting electronic comments on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX> different
proposed rules in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. In one of these approaches, users
were asked to answer specific questions identified as areas where
APHIS most needed comments, the answers to the questions were
entered into a database with a web interface, and commenters were
allowed to review all the electronic comments posted and to post
other comments to the site. At the time of our review, APHIS
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were attempting to identify the circumstances in which
electronic comment approaches work best. For example, they said
that electronic comment processes for controversial rules on which
a large number of comments are filed may ultimately yield little
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a</NUMEX> count of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. However, they also
said that electronic comments appeared particularly helpful on less
controversial rules with technical elements and on which commenter
interaction was possible-in essence, a realtime, informal "peer
review."
Use of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">IT in Other Forms of Interactive Participation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> have also used IT to facilitate other forms of public
participation in the rulemaking process. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small</ENAMEX>
Business <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Enforcement Fairness Act</ENAMEX> (SBREFA) requires that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> convene a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review panel</ENAMEX> before issuing a
proposed rule that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> believes will have a significant
economic impact on a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. The
panels are to collect advice and recommendations from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of affected small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> as part of their
deliberative process. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> told us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is
using email as a way to facilitate the delivery of documents to the
small entity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> and to receive their comments. He also
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> had created web sites for several rules that were
used in conjunction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBREFA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> to pull together information
that commenters needed.
The related literature indicates that some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have
begun to experiment with online dialogs or interactions among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> during the rulemaking process. For example, as a part
of its rulemaking to develop rates that would finance Internet
connections in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications</ENAMEX>
Commission sponsored "moderated, online policy dialogues" for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">educators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarians</ENAMEX> that, according to an unpublished report,
enabled over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> from across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to learn about
the proposed rule, share their views with each other, and offer
also indicated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department's Research and Special Programs</ENAMEX>
Administration had used a "chat room" arrangement during some of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s rulemaking comment periods.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Multidimensional Electronic</ENAMEX> Rulemaking
Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' electronic rulemaking systems contained
several of the innovative dimensions previously discussed. As noted
previously, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>'s docket management system permits comments to be
submitted electronically or on paper, allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to comment
on other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' comments, and permits access to a wide range of
regulatory supporting materials. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' had these and, in
some cases, other innovative features. However, unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>
system that is applicable to all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>'s rules, the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' multidimensional systems focused on just a few
rules, or even a single rule.
For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> has been conducting an electronic
rulemaking for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 3 years</TIMEX> that encompasses a number of
innovative design elements. The proposed rule was published in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1997</TIMEX>, and is intended to establish standards for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organically</ENAMEX> produced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. The program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> for the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organic Program</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> knew that the rule would be
controversial, so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> decided to take advantage of IT's potential
to facilitate the comment process, allowing comments to be provided
via mail, fax, and email. Comments were posted for public view and
response in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s web site, along with transcripts of
national public meetings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 275,000</NUMEX> comments
on the rule, which were assigned key words to facilitate subsequent
analysis. As a result of the comments received, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> changed the
proposed rule and it was republished for comment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX>. AMS
said in the proposal that it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s intention to have all
comments, regardless of media, available for viewing on the
program's home page or at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s docket <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. As previously
noted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> maintains a link to this rule on its home page, and the
organic standards site contains the text of the proposed rule, its
regulatory impact statement, and instructions on how to submit
comments and search the comments that had already been submitted.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> system also allows users to search the full text of the
public comments, identifies form letter comments and ex parte
communications<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,8</NUMEX> and provides a list of related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> web
sites-features that are currently not available in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> docket
management system. Although currently limited to this one rule, the
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> plans to use these electronic
rulemaking features in other potentially controversial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemakings</ENAMEX>.
According to the AMS program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, the interactive comment
process changed the dynamic of rulemaking participation.
Previously, he said, commenters typically waited until the last
minute to file comments so that no one could see their views until
after the comment period was over. In the organic standards rule,
however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> submitted comments early in the process to have the
greatest influence on the evolving discussion. The Under Secretary
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture for Marketing and Regulatory Programs</ENAMEX> said that
fullscale Internet access had dramatically increased public
awareness and participation, and had saved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> in administrative costs associated with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX>.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX>, form letter comments are separately identified
because they share the same themes and are received by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> in large volumes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> said an ex parte communication is
an oral or written private communication from someone outside of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>
official who is involved in decisionmaking on a pending rulemaking
proceeding. The ex parte communication is received through channels
not prescribed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, and it concerns the merits of
that proceeding.



Several <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Observers Suggested Greater Diffusion of IT Innovations</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consistency</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that we contacted for this
portion of the review included academicians, interest group
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> who were
knowledgeable about electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and rulemaking issues.
Although not inclusive of all such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>,
those we contacted did not identify any entirely new categories of
potentially beneficial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITbased</ENAMEX> public participation applications
that had not been adopted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of the regulatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we examined. However, they noted that the current
uses of IT in rulemaking are often pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> of limited scope,
and suggested more widespread adoption of some of those innovations
by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, or by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as a whole. The
examples that they cited included the following.


•
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> representing small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> indicated
that it would be helpful if there was a single portal or
"electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clearinghouse</ENAMEX>" to which small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> could turn to
obtain information about rulemaking activities throughout the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> (i.e., similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s small business portal).
More generally, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commenter</ENAMEX> said there should be a single
regulatory portal for all federal rulemaking activity.


•
Other commenters suggested greater use of proactive and
customized regulatory notification systems. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has established a list server, centrally managed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division of Information Services</ENAMEX>, which can be used by
all state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to selectively notify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of opportunities
to participate in government decisionmaking, including rulemaking.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizens</ENAMEX> are able to register to be placed on the listserver for
particular topics.


•
Other commenters suggested greater use of interactive
participation mechanisms, including online dialogs and meetings,
and the use of video. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State of Washington</ENAMEX>
currently uses a statewide video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> for meetings and
collaboration, with videos available over the Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> is also using networked cameras to conduct legislative
hearings, through which geographically dispersed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> can
participate. Although it was not clear whether these video networks
had been used in a regulatory context in these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, the
commenters suggested that they could be used to facilitate
participation in rulemaking.


•
Some of the commenters also said that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
should more commonly provide access to the economic analyses and
other underlying rulemaking information that frequently resides in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' dockets. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> commenter suggested that a central,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governmentwide</ENAMEX> site be established linking together the information
available in individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, thereby enabling the
public to "drill down" into individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> as well as obtain
similar information across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.


•
This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> also said that the fully electronic
rulemaking at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> on organic standards should be replicated in
other parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>. However, he also noted that parts of the
electronic system for the organic standards rule were developed by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> using proprietary software, and because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> does not
own the application, even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> cannot use it for other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemakings</ENAMEX>.


Several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that we contacted
also suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> move to a more consistent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, content, and presentation of information to allow for
a more common "look and feel" to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITbased</ENAMEX> public
participation mechanisms in rulemaking.


•
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> representative of state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> said that
coordination or standardization across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is
"almost mandatory." He said that many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are establishing state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief information officers</ENAMEX> who are generally responsible for
creating an interoperable infrastructure and common data standards
for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.


•
Several of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> also
indicated that a common <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> or approach for public
participation in rulemaking made sense. For example, one agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> said that the use of commonly accepted models for
such administrative tasks as receiving and logging correspondence
and storing documents could save money and facilitate access. He
specifically cited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> docket management system as the type of
model that could have broader applicability.


•
Similarly, a public interest group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> said
that it would be very helpful to have a regulatory taxonomy or
thesaurus relating similar terms, which could be used to improve
the quality of searches in different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' search engines. More
generally, another public interest group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> said that a
"common look and feel" for regulatory information within federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> could make it much easier for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to locate, read,
and digest relevant information. However, he cautioned that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have important differences, which may suggest that a
"onesizefitsall" approach would not be desirable.




<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Agencies Generally Questioned Need for Standardized Uses of IT</ENAMEX>
to Facilitate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking Participation</ENAMEX>
Several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that we contacted
during this review indicated that standardizing innovative uses of
IT to facilitate public participation in rulemaking could have
advantages when compared with the current fragmented system. For
example, some of them generally indicated that standardization
could make the current system more accessible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>,
thereby leading to more participation in the rulemaking process.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> simply indicated that greater standardization made
sense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> included in our review
also indicated a few areas in which standardization, or at least
more coordination, among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in this area could be helpful.
First, they said that standardization is probably a good approach
for resolving legal issues that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> will have ultimately to
face, such as the use of copyrighted material and censorship of
comments received by the public that might be accessible to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>.
They also said that coordination could facilitate information
sharing among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, thereby speeding the diffusion of
innovations that are appropriate and useful within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>'
particular context, keeping each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> from having to "reinvent
the wheel." Currently, they said, there is no structured way for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to learn about best practices in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. For
example, one agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> told us that she was unaware
until recently of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> docket management system.
Overall, though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> questioned the need
for a standardized approach to using IT to facilitate public
participation in rulemaking. They said that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> is somewhat different. Therefore, they said, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> need to be able to design their public participation
procedures to fit the particular circumstances appropriate for each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> (within the parameters of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> and other applicable
statutes). They said that the current system reflects that
diversity, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> developing new participation processes and
information management systems as needed for their individual
programs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. For example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> representative
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>'s docket management system could not simply be
replicated at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> because of differences in the degree of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management centralization</ENAMEX> and independence afforded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituent agencies</ENAMEX>. Standardization, they said,
could decrease the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' ability to tailor regulatory
approaches and inhibit further agency innovation by "freezing into
place" the particular practices that have been developed so far.
They also said that the current flexible arrangement permits agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to ensure that the use of IT in rulemaking is carried out
within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s overall IT strategic planning efforts.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> also said that they were not aware of
any data suggesting that the lack of a standardized approach to
regulatory participation was a problem to either the public in
general or to the regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that are most likely to
participate in rulemaking. Therefore, they said, determining
whether there is a problem by gathering information from the public
through surveys or other means might be a good <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step before
proceeding to a standardization "solution." Several of the agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> also questioned whether moving toward a standard,
electronic system would enhance public participation, either in
terms of the number of comments submitted or the quality of those
comments, or would improve the quality of the rule under
consideration.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> said that standardization of ITbased
public participation <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> would require scarce agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>, and that any resources provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to
improve their IT <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> might be better spent in areas other than
public participation in rulemaking (e.g., using IT to facilitate
regulatory compliance or some nonregulatory area). They did not
believe that every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> should be required to have a
"regulations" link on its home page, noting that many different
organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and interests are vying for space on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>'
home pages. They also saw no need for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to always provide an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">email</ENAMEX> address or web site to which electronic comments on proposed
rules could be addressed. Doing so for all rules, they said, could
overwhelm the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' systems; may be unnecessary for some
relatively uncontroversial rules; and may be a less effective use
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s resources than more traditional methods (e.g.,
placing notices in trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> or setting up a call
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX> They also said that, once established, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> would
have to be concerned about ongoing maintenance of some of these
standardized systems to make sure that the information therein is
timely, accurate, and complete.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> also made a number of other points
that suggested that standardization of participation processes was
not needed or could be undesirable.
• Several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> indicated that standard
electronic approaches to learning about participation opportunities
already exists-the electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Unified Agenda</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> indicated that the system
overload problem could be solved by developing information
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retrieval</ENAMEX> systems ahead of time that would accommodate large
traffic volumes. For example, he said his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> had developed a
format into which electronic comments could be filed, which greatly
facilitated the subsequent analysis of the comments.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD00135R Federal</ENAMEX> Rulemaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on the GPO Access web site. They said that
anyone could use that site to find out about any upcoming and
recently proposed rules.


•
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> indicated that an ITbased
"solution" to improving public participation in rulemaking could
underscore the "digital divide" that currently exists in the
country between those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the public that currently have
regular access to a computer and those that do not.


•
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> said that differences in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' current hardware and software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> could make it
difficult to adopt standards, and that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> may not allow them to receive and archive nontextual
materials such as graphs, compact discs, or physical items that are
part of many rulemaking records. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> said that
IT is changing so rapidly that establishing a standardized
electronic approach to public participation may have some real
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disadvantages</ENAMEX> later on, locking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> into outmoded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>.


Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that we contacted, including
a public interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, a business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, and an academician, also
cited concerns about a "onesizefitsall" approach being applied to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with vastly different missions. Also, a small business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> told us that, although she believed that there is a
need for more coordination and cooperation across federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>,
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are generally skeptical about the benefits of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standardization</ENAMEX> because their interests may be neglected.


Conclusions
Participation in the rulemaking process requires (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the public
to be aware of opportunities to participate and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) systems that
will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to receive comments in an efficient and
effective manner. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> can use IT to inform the public about
participation opportunities either through passive systems that
require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to take the initiative to discover rules available
for comment or proactive systems that alert interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> about impending regulatory actions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passive</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> include both governmentwide web sites that allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to
find out about proposed rules in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPO Access</ENAMEX>) and
web sites for particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> that have identified
rules available for comment (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA/APHIS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS/ACF</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Radiation</ENAMEX>). However, none of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> departments
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we contacted had links on their home pages that
identified all rules available for comment within their entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proactive</ENAMEX> systems permit the interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to be
notified by email when proposed rules are published (e.g., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>
web site for its administrative simplification initiative), but
were much less common than passive systems.
One relatively simple way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to facilitate the receipt
of public comments is to provide an email address at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
proposed rules to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> could respond electronically.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies</ENAMEX> could also state that comments could be provided by
facsimile. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we contacted differed
substantially in the extent to which they explicitly provided for
these modes of comment during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">calendar year 1999</TIMEX>, and none of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> permitted either mode of communication for all of their
proposed rules. Some of the rules with their own dedicated web
sites (e.g., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOL/OSHA</ENAMEX> ergonomics rule and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA/AMS</ENAMEX> organic
standards rule) provided links to both the rules and electronic
comment procedures.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to facilitate the receipt of informed public comments is
to permit electronic access to regulatory supporting materials,
such as economic analyses and the comments of others. DOT had the
most developed electronic docket system of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we
contacted, covering every rulemaking action in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and
including all public comments received regardless of medium. DOT
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> had saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> more than a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> each year in administrative costs and facilitated
the rulemaking process in other ways. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have begun to
use IT to facilitate interactive public comments, permitting users
to comment on the comments filed by others (e.g., at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> and in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA/AMS</ENAMEX> organic standards site) or to participate in online
dialogs with rule <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT's Research and Special Programs</ENAMEX>
Administration).
All of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that we contacted during
this review were developing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITbased</ENAMEX> public participation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> that they believed were best suited to their particular
needs. As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' participation vehicles varied
substantially. Several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contacted</ENAMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> should move to a more standardized
approach, and said that standardization could make the current
system of participation more accessible to the public. However,
many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> questioned the need for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standardization</ENAMEX>. They said that (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> need to be able to
design their procedures to fit their particular circumstances
(e.g., the degree of management centralization in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>);
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) standardization would require scarce agency resources that
might be better spent elsewhere; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) a good <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step might be
to determine whether lack of standardization is really a problem.
On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> were supportive of
efforts to better coordinate the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITbased</ENAMEX> participation
mechanisms in order to avoid each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> "reinventing the wheel."
Such coordination will require better communication within and
among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The ultimate adoption of particular approaches
within those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> will require sufficient resources and an
understanding of how the approaches will fit into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>'
overall IT strategic plans.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> Comments
We provided a draft of this letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> and comment on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17, 2000</TIMEX>, but we did not receive any
official OMB comments on the report within the time allowed.
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> provided information during and at the
conclusion of the review that was incorporated where
appropriate.
As we arranged with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, unless you publicly announce
this letter's contents <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, we plan no further distribution of
it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> after the date of this letter. We will then send
copies to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Government Reform</ENAMEX>; and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Committee on Governmental Affairs</ENAMEX>. We will
also provide copies to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Jacob J. Lew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Dan Glickman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honorable</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna E. Shalala</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Alexis M. Herman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honorable</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney E. Slater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honorable</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol M. Browner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>. We will also make copies
available to others on request.
Please contact me or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curtis Copeland</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5128676</TIMEX> if you or
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> have any questions.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Brostek</ENAMEX>
Associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Management and Workforce</ENAMEX> Issues

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ordering Copies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Reports</ENAMEX>
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> copy of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report and testimony is free.
Additional copies are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> each. Orders should be sent to the
following address, accompanied by a check or money order made out
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Superintendent of Documents</ENAMEX>, when necessary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VISA</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> credit cards are accepted, also. Orders for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> or more
copies to be mailed to asingleaddress arediscounted <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX>.
Order by mail:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.O. Box 37050</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC 20013</ENAMEX>
or visit:


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Room 1100 700 4th St.</ENAMEX> NW (corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">4th</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G Sts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NW</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC Orders</ENAMEX> may also be placed by calling (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5126000</NUMEX> or by using fax number (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5126061</NUMEX>, or TDD (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5122537</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> issues a list of newly available reports and
testimony. To receive facsimile copies of the daily list or any
list from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 days</TIMEX>, please call (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5126000</TIMEX> using a touch
tone phone. A recorded menu will provide information on how to
obtain these lists.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viewing GAO Reports</ENAMEX> on the Internet
For information on how to access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reports on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNET</ENAMEX>,
send email message with "info" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">info@www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX> or
visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldWide Web Home Page</ENAMEX> at: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>
ReportingFraud,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste</ENAMEX>,and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AbuseinFederal Programs</ENAMEX> To contact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FraudNET</ENAMEX> use: Web site:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/fraudnet/fraudnet.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm</ENAMEX>


EMail: fraudnet@<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gao</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov Telephone: 18004245454</ENAMEX> (automated
answering system)


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bulk Rate Postage & Fees Paid GAO Permit No.</ENAMEX> G100
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205480001</NUMEX>


Official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Penalty</ENAMEX> for Private Use <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Address Correction Requested</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">410365</ENAMEX>)




