



Testimony
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>

Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management</ENAMEX>,
Restructuring, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmental Affairs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>

Statement



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Reform</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elements of Successful Improvement</ENAMEX>
Initiatives
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX>:
We are pleased to be here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to contribute to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX>'s ongoing efforts to identify ways to improve the
management and performance of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. As you know,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX> we issued a new volume of reports, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Performance</ENAMEX> and
Accountability <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX>, outlining the major management challenges
confronting our largest federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and the substantial
opportunities for improving their performance<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> Many of the
challenges discussed in that series represent long-standing,
difficult, and complex problems that our work has shown will not be
easily or quickly resolved. In fact, implementing and sustaining
major change initiatives requires a cultural transformation for
many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Therefore, given the magnitude of the problems an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> may face, and the extensive effort and long period of time
it can take before problems are fully resolved, progress must often
be measured initially in terms of whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has a well
thought out management improvement initiative in place to guide its
reform efforts.
As agreed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> we will discuss
the elements that our wide-ranging work on federal management
issues suggests are particularly important in implementing and
sustaining management improvement initiatives that genuinely take
root and eventually resolve the problems they are intended to fix.
These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> are (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a demonstrated leadership commitment and
accountability for change; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the integration of management
improvement initiatives into programmatic decisionmaking; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
thoughtful and rigorous planning to guide decisions, particularly
to address human capital and information technology issues; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> involvement to elicit ideas and build commitment and
accountability; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) organizational alignment to streamline
operations and clarify accountability; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) strong and
continuing congressional involvement. Not surprisingly, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> of successful management improvement initiatives that we
will discuss <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are consistent with the approaches shared by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">performance-based</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> efforts under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
Performance and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Results Act</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Results Act</ENAMEX>) and quality management
that we discussed in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29, 1999</TIMEX>, statement for this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX>.2 Our statement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is based on our broad body of
work and resulting knowledge of management issues, including our
examination of the implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Results Act</ENAMEX> and related
initiatives, our reviews of selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Partnership</ENAMEX> for
Reinventing
1Maj 
or Management Challenges and Program Risks
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/OCG-99-SET</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1999</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Reform</ENAMEX>: Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Results Act</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Management</ENAMEX>
to Improve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Performance</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-GGD-99-151</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29, 1999</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>

Demonstrated <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leadership Commitment and Accountability for</ENAMEX>
Change
Government (NPR) recommendations, and our ongoing analyses of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>-specific improvement efforts, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>) modernization.
Perhaps the single most important element of successful
management improvement initiatives is the demonstrated commitment
of top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to change. This commitment is most prominently shown
through the personal involvement of top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in developing and
directing reform efforts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizations</ENAMEX> that successfully address
their long-standing management weaknesses do not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> out"
responsibility for leading change. Top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> involvement and
clear lines of accountability for making management improvements
are critical to overcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>' natural resistance to
change, marshalling the resources needed in many cases to improve
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and building and maintaining the organizationwide
commitment to new ways to doing business.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossotti</ENAMEX>'s efforts at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> provide a clear example
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>'s commitment to change. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> has
articulated a new mission for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, together with support for
strategic goals that balance customer service and compliance with
tax laws<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moreover</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> has initiated a modernization
effort that touches virtually every aspect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, including
business practices, organizational structure, management roles and
responsibilities, performance measures, and technology.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossotti</ENAMEX> has assigned clear executive ownership of
each of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' major initiatives and is using executive steering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX> to provide oversight and accountability for driving the
change efforts.
Sustaining top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> commitment to improvement is
particularly challenging in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> because of the
frequent turnover of senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. As a
result, sustaining improvement initiatives requires commitment and
leadership by senior career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, as well as political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can help provide the long-term focus
needed to institutionalize reforms that political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>' often
more limited tenure does not permit. In addition, the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> of successful management improvement initiatives that we
shall turn to shortly are important for institutionalizing reform
initiatives.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' new mission statement reads, "Provide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>
top quality service by helping them understand and meet their tax
responsibilities and by applying the tax law with integrity and
fairness to all." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' supporting strategic goals are to (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
provide top quality service to each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) provide service
to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> by applying the law with integrity and fairness,
and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) increase productivity by providing a quality work
environment for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integration of Management Improvement Initiatives</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Programmatic Decisionmaking</ENAMEX>
Traditionally, the danger to any management reform is that it
can become a hollow, paper-driven exercise where management
improvement initiatives are not integrated into the day-to-day
activities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. Thus, successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
recognize-and implement reform efforts on the basis of-the
essential connection between sound management and the programmatic
results those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> hope to achieve.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Results Act</ENAMEX> provides a ready-made statutory mechanism for
making this essential connection, engaging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in a discussion
of how and when management problems will be addressed, and helping
to pinpoint additional efforts that may be needed. We have found
that annual performance plans that include precise and measurable
goals for resolving mission-critical management problems are
important to ensuring that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have the institutional capacity
to achieve their more resultsoriented programmatic goals. Moreover,
by using annual performance plans to set goals to address
management weaknesses, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> provide themselves and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
with a vehicle-the subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> performance reports-for
tracking progress in addressing management problems and considering
what, if any, additional efforts are needed.
Unfortunately, we found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> do not consistently
address major management challenges and program risks in their
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX> performance plans<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX> In those cases where
challenges and risks are addressed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> use a variety of
approaches, including setting goals and measures directly linked to
the management challenges and program risks, establishing goals and
measures that are indirectly related to the challenges and risks,
or laying out strategies to address them. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> shows the
distribution of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Financial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX> Act and their different approaches to addressing
management challenges and program risks in their annual performance
plans.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
Managing for Results: Opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Continued Improvements</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies' Performance Plans</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/AIMD-99-215</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20, 1999</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Approaches Used to Address Management Challenges and</ENAMEX>
Program Risks


































Note: Numbers do not add <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 100 percent</NUMEX> due to rounding.
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> analysis based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>
performance plans.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has important management reform initiatives underway to
address long-standing management weaknesses, but it missed the
opportunity to demonstrate these actions in its portion of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX> performance plan. For
example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of the Treasury</ENAMEX>'s plan has no goals,
measures, or strategies to address several of the high-risk areas5
we have identified at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, including


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> control weaknesses over unpaid tax assessments
(We found that the lack of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> ledger impairs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' ability
to effectively manage its unpaid assessments. This weakness has
resulted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> inappropriately directing collection efforts
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> after amounts owed have been paid.);


•
the need to assess the impact of various efforts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has
under way to reduce filing fraud;


•
the need to improve security controls over information
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> and address weaknesses that place sensitive taxpayer data
at risk to both internal and external threats (Our high-risk update
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
These areas are characterized as "high-risk" because of their
greater vulnerability to waste, fraud, abuse, and
mismanagement.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>
controls do not adequately reduce vulnerability to inappropriate
disclosure.); and
• weaknesses in internal controls over taxpayer receipts.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2000</TIMEX> annual performance plan does not address several
long-standing problems identified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX>.
These problems include top management's lack of emphasis on
ensuring that the internal controls are in place to deter fraud,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waste</ENAMEX>, and abuse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s plan also does not fully address issues
raised by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> related to developing new
management information systems and ensuring that automated
information systems have the proper controls and safeguards. These
omissions are significant because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s governmentwide oversight
and service-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> role, its extensive interaction with the
private sector, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> dollars involved in
carrying out its activities, make it especially important that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s operations be adequately protected.


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thoughtful and Rigorous Planning to Guide Decisions</ENAMEX>
The magnitude of the challenges that many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> face in
addressing their management weaknesses necessitates substantive
planning be done to establish (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) clear goals and objectives for
the improvement initiative,


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
the concrete management improvement steps that will be
taken, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) key milestones that will be used to track the
implementation status, and


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
the cost and performance data that will be used to gauge
overall progress in addressing identified weaknesses. Our work
across the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has found the effective use of human
capital and information technology-both separately and,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">importantly</ENAMEX>, as they relate to one another-are areas where
thoughtful and rigorous planning is needed if fundamental
management improvements are to be made.


For example, we looked at the efforts of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX>) to both improve services and reduce staffing
levels in their personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> through the better application of
information technology.6 The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> planned to increase operating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">efficiencies</ENAMEX> and improve services by automating paper-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> processes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> expected that new hardware and/or
software technology would reduce paperwork and workload, thereby
permitting sizable staff reductions. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> made the
staffing reductions before much of the new automation was in place,
and automation efforts had not been fully implemented as of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Reform</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies</ENAMEX>' Initial Efforts to Restructure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personnel Operations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/GGD-98-93,July</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 1998</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>
late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were struggling to achieve
their efficiency and service improvement objectives.
On a more positive note, we recently reviewed the efforts of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Veterans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Service</ENAMEX>) to more strategically manage
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and assets by forming business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> with
the private sector.7 In each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> that we
reviewed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> built the expertise to engage in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnership</ENAMEX> and make it successful. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX> established a separate organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> staffed
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> experienced in management, architecture, civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineering</ENAMEX>, and contracting to manage its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX>.
With regard to planning for major technology projects, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has
historically lacked disciplined and structured processes for
developing and managing information technology. We reported in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1998</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> had not clearly defined system modernization
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phases</ENAMEX>, nor had it adequately specified organizational roles,
making it unclear who was to do what<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' systems modernization
challenges include completing a modernization blueprint to define,
direct, and control future modernization efforts and establishing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and engineering capability to build and acquire
modernized systems. The key to effectively addressing these
challenges is to ensure that long-standing modernization management
and technical weaknesses are corrected before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> invests large
sums of modernization funds. As we have reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> recently
initiated appropriate <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> steps to address these weaknesses via
its initial modernization expenditure plan that represents the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in a longterm, incremental modernization program.9
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX>, through its effective use of technology in
expanding the electronic availability of census data, demonstrates
how federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> can leverage performance and customer
satisfaction through the better use of technology. Before applying
technology to its data dissemination efforts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> released
massive amounts of data in printed reports. Now, by using the
Internet as its principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> for disseminating data, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>
is able to reduce its reliance on printed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Public-Private Partnerships: Key Elements</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Buildings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Facility Partnerships</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-23</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax Systems Modernization: Blueprint Is a Good Start But Not Yet</ENAMEX>
Sufficiently Complete to Build or 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acquire Systems</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/AIMD</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/GGD-98-54</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Systems Modernization</ENAMEX>: Results of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' Initial
Expenditure Plan (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/AIMD</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/GGD-99-206</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15,1999</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employee Involvement</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elicit Ideas and Build Commitment and</ENAMEX>
Accountability
materials, reach a wider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, and provide its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> with
information in a format that better meets their needs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>
reports that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are responding positively to the shift,
with significant growth in the number of customer hits on the
Census Internet site, from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10,000</NUMEX> per day in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> to more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">850,000</NUMEX> per day in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> plans to use the Internet
as its principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> for releasing data from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>.
Successful management improvement efforts require the active
involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to
provide ideas for improvements and supply the energy and expertise
needed to implement changes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> at all levels of
high-performing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> participate in--and have a stake
in--improving operational and program performance to achieve
results. Our work has shown that high-performing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> use
a number of strategies and techniques to effectively involve
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, including (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) fostering a performanceoriented culture,
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) working to develop a consensus with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> on goals and
strategies, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) providing the training that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> need to work
effectively, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) devolving authority while focusing
accountability on results.
Fostering a performance-oriented culture requires agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to communicate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to
involve them in the process of designing and implementing change.
Setting improvement goals is an important step in getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to engage seriously in the
difficult task of change. The central features of the Results
Act-strategic planning, performance measurement, and public
reporting and accountability-can serve as powerful tools to help
change the basic culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in
developing and implementing these goals and measures can help
direct a diverse array of actions to improve performance and
achieve results. However, our survey of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, conducted
in late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996 and 1997</TIMEX>, indicates there is substantial room for
improvement in this area. This survey found that only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">non-SES</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> (as opposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly three-fourths</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>) reported they had been involved in establishing long-term
strategic goals for their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.10
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> in high-performing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> understand the
importance of and the connection between their performance and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>'s
10
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Government Performance and Results Act</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> Governmentwide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Implementation Will Be</ENAMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uneven</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/GGD-97-109</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2, 1997</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>
11
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>. The failure to constructively involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>'s improvement efforts means running the risk that the
changes will be more difficult and protracted than necessary. For
example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1997</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuclear Regulatory Commission</ENAMEX>'s
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRC</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> surveyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRC</ENAMEX> staff to obtain
their views on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s safety culture. In its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> had a strong
commitment to protecting public health and safety but expressed
high levels of uncertainty and confusion about the new directions
in regulatory practices and challenges facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX>
who are confused about the direction their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is taking will
not be able to effectively focus on results or make as full a
contribution as they might otherwise.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way high-performing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> can enhance employee
involvement and gain agreement on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s goals and
strategies is by developing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> with employee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s long-standing challenges in labor-management
relations illustrate the importance of having a shared set of
long-term goals and strategies agreed upon by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. As we have reported, labor-management relations at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> have been characterized by disagreements that have,
among other things, hampered efforts to automate some postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> that could have resulted in savings and helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>
reach its performance goals<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> Although there has been some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progress</ENAMEX>, problems persist and continue to contribute to higher
mail processing and delivery costs. To help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
resolve its problems, we have long recommended that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> and
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> establish a framework
agreement to outline common goals. We have also noted that the
Results <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> can provide an effective framework for union and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management representatives</ENAMEX> to discuss and agree upon goals and
strategies.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX>' capabilities also play an important role in achieving
performance improvements, and training is a key factor enabling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> involvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> that expect their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to take
greater responsibility and be held accountable for results must
ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> have the training and tools they need to
fulfill these expectations. In that regard, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> is beginning to
implement significant changes that will require training for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frontline</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX>. For example, in lieu of
hiring a large number of seasonal
11
Major <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Management Challenges and Program Risks: A</ENAMEX> Governmentwide
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perspective</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/OCG-99-1,January</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
12
Major <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Management Challenges and Program Risks:</ENAMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OCG</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-21</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January1999</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to handle return processing workload during the annual
filing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> plans to increase the number of permanent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and expand their job responsibilities to include
compliance work that they can do after the filing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>. Those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> will have to be cross-trained so that they can handle
both their return processing and compliance responsibilities.
Training is expected to be a key factor in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' efforts to provide
top-quality customer service. Further, given the dynamic
environment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> face, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> need incentives, training, and
support to help them continually learn and adapt. Our 1996/97
survey found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 60 percent</NUMEX> or more of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> reported that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> had not provided them with
the training necessary to accomplish critical, results-oriented
management tasks.
High-performing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> also seek to involve and engage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> by devolving authority to lower levels of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> are more likely to support changes when
they have the necessary amount of authority and flexibility--along
with commensurate accountability and incentives--to advance the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s goals and improve performance. Allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to bring
their expertise and judgement to bear in meeting their
responsibilities can help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> capitalize on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">talents</ENAMEX>, leading to more effective and efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and
improved customer service<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.13 Some</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Administration</ENAMEX> (SSA), are exploring new ways to
involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> by devolving decisionmaking authority. Although
the efficacy of this initiative has not been fully assessed, SSA
has been implementing a pilot program to establish a "single
decision <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>" position. This program expands the authority of
disability <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiners</ENAMEX>, who currently make initial disability
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">determinations</ENAMEX> jointly with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, and allows the single
decision <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> to make the initial disability determination and
consult with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> only as needed<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX>
Our work has shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> can improve the extent to which
they devolve authority for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to make decisions and the
extent to which they hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> accountable for results. Our
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1996/97</NUMEX> survey of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than one-third</NUMEX>
of non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> felt that to a great or very great extent they
had the decisionmaking authority needed to accomplish strategic
goals. Likewise, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> we
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">13 Executive Guide: Effectively Implementing the Government</ENAMEX>
Performance and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Results Act</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/GGD-96-118</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1996</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SSA Disability Redesign: Actions Needed To Enhance Future</ENAMEX>
Progress 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/HEHS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-25</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12,1999</NUMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>
surveyed reported that they were being held accountable for
program results.
Our work has also shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> can do a better job of
providing incentives to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to improve performance
and achieve results. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one-fourth</NUMEX> of non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> reported
that to a great or very great extent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> received positive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> for efforts to help accomplish
strategic goals. At the request of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX>, we are
surveying federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> again to follow up on whether there have
been improvements in these critical areas.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have explored new ways of devolving decisionmaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> in exchange for operational flexibility and
accountability for results. For example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1996</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Health Administration</ENAMEX> (VHA) management structure was
decentralized to form <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Integrated Service Networks.15 VA</ENAMEX>
gave these networks substantial operational autonomy and the
ability to perform basic decisionmaking and budgetary duties. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>
made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> accountable for results such as improving patient
access, efficiency, and reducing costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> also established
performance measures, such as increasing the number of outpatient
surgeries, reducing the use of inpatient care, and increasing the
number of high-priority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> served to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> accountable for results.


Organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alignment to Streamline Operations and Clarify</ENAMEX>
Accountability
Successful management improvement efforts often entail
organizational realignment to better achieve results and clarify
accountability. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> has sought to improve its
efficiency and effectiveness by changing its organizational
structure to separate its policymaking functions from its
operations that provide services. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> recognized that it suffered
from conflicting policymaking and service-providing roles and
needed to replace its outmoded methods of delivering service. To
address this issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> established the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Policy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning</ENAMEX>,
and Evaluation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, which it later renamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmentwide Policy</ENAMEX>, to handle policy decisions separately from
functions that deliver supplies or services. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> believes that this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">realignment</ENAMEX> has improved efficiency and reduced the perception of
conflict of interest that existed prior to the separation of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">policymaking</ENAMEX> and service-delivery roles.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s efforts thus far are an important reform, additional
opportunities for organizational realignment appear to exist. For
example,
15
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA Health Care</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More Veterans Are Being Served</ENAMEX>, But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX>
Oversight Is Needed 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/HEHS-98-226</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 28, 1998</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> has expressed concerns that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> and management structure has not kept pace with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downsizing</ENAMEX>, streamlining, and reform efforts. In addition, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> has said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>'s organizational structure does
not seem to match the responsibility for managing programs with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> to do so. As a result, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> has faced
situations where regions (which operate independently) have taken
divergent positions on similar issues, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector</ENAMEX>
General.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' ongoing efforts provide another example of the importance
of aligning organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossotti</ENAMEX> has
stated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' current cumbersome organizational structure and
inadequate technology are the principal obstacles to delivering
dramatic improvements in customer service and productivity. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> is reorganizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> with the aim of building an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> designed around taxpayer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and creating
management roles with clear responsibilities. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the first
organizational realignments taking place is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Taxpayer Advocate</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is intended to, among other things,
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> who cannot get their problems resolved through
normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> channels. Formerly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocate's Office</ENAMEX> had to rely on
functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, like examination and collection, to
provide most of its program resources-including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, space, and
equipment.16 When functional needs conflicted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocate Office</ENAMEX>
needs, there was no assurance that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> needs would be met. In
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> program resources will be
controlled and managed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Taxpayer Advocate</ENAMEX>. By organizing this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> hopes to improve both program efficiency and service to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>.
The organizational realignments at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> are consistent
with a more general exploration under way to use streamlined and
clarified organizational arrangements to help enhance
accountability and improve performance. For example, building on
reform efforts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, the
Administration has proposed creating Performance-Based
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizations</ENAMEX> (PBOs) in which selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that deliver
measurable services receive greater organizational autonomy in
exchange for heightened accountability for results on the part of
top and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, in an attempt to address
significant management and accountability problems with federal
student financial aid programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacted the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> PBO, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Financial Assistance</ENAMEX>, within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>. We have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS Management</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS Faces Challenges</ENAMEX> as it Restructures the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taxpayer Advocate</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/GGD-99-124</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 1999</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>
identified the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of student financial aid programs,
with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $150 billion</NUMEX> in outstanding student loans, as being
at high-risk to waste, fraud, abuse, and mismanagement.
The PBO structure exemplifies new directions in accountability
for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Operating</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX>, who reports to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>, is held
directly and personally accountable, through an employment
contract, for achieving measurable organizational and individual
goals. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Operating Officer</ENAMEX> is appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
Education to a minimum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year</TIMEX> and a maximum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year term</TIMEX>, and may
receive a bonus for meeting the performance goals or be removed for
failing to meet them.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Student Financial Assistance</ENAMEX> was provided with
increased flexibility for procurement and personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and
key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are to be held directly accountable for performance
objectives that include
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) improving customer satisfaction; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) providing high quality
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">costeffective</ENAMEX> services; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) providing complete, accurate, and
timely data to ensure program integrity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Operating</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> is to enter into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> performance agreements containing
measurable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and individual goals with key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, who
can receive a bonus or can also be removed.
An additional accountability mechanism is that the Chief
Operating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> are required to
agree on, and make public, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 5-year</TIMEX> performance plan that
establishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>'s goals and objectives. To further
underscore accountability issues, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Operating</ENAMEX> Officer
is to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> prepare and submit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>, a report on the performance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBO</ENAMEX>. The report is to
include an evaluation of the extent to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> met the
goals and objectives contained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 5-year</TIMEX> performance plan. In
addition, the annual report is to include (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) an independent
financial audit, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) applicable financial and performance
requirements under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Financial Officers</ENAMEX> Act and the Results
Act, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the results achieved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> relative to its goals,
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) an evaluation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Operating Officer</ENAMEX>'s performance, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)
recommendations for legislative and regulatory changes to improve
service and program integrity, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) other information as
detailed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>


Strong and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continuing Congressional Involvement</ENAMEX>
Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> plays a crucial role in management improvement
efforts throughout the executive branch through its legislative and
oversight capacities. On a governmentwide basis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, under
the bi-partisan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Reform Committee</ENAMEX>, has established a statutory framework
consisting of requirements for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goal-</ENAMEX>setting and performance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, all aimed at improving the performance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and
accountability of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Through the enactment of
the framework and its efforts to foster the framework's
implementation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has, in effect, served as an institutional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champion</ENAMEX> for improving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
providing a consistent focus for oversight and reinforcement of
important policies. On an agency-specific basis as well, support
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has proven to be critical in instituting and
sustaining management reforms, such as those taking place at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>, and elsewhere across the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, in its oversight role, can monitor management
improvement initiatives and provide the continuing attention
necessary for reform initiatives to be carried through to their
successful completion. Information in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' plans and reports
produced under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Results Act</ENAMEX>, high quality financial and program
cost data, and other related information, can help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in
targeting its oversight efforts and identifying opportunities for
additional improvements in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' management. In this regard, we
have long advocated that congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> of jurisdiction
hold augmented oversight hearings on each of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> at
least once each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could examine, for example, the
degree to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are building the elements of successful
management improvement initiatives that we have discussed today
into their respective management reform efforts. Such hearings will
further underscore for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> the importance that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> places
on creating high-performing government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. Also, through
the appointment and confirmation process, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has an added
opportunity to make clear its commitment to sound federal
management and explore what prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> plan to do to
ensure that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are well-managed and striving to be
high-performing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
In summary Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, serious and disciplined efforts are
needed to attack the management problems confronting some of our
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Successful management improvement efforts often
contain a number of common critical elements, including top
leadership commitment and accountability, the integration of
management
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/T-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-26</NUMEX>
improvement initiatives into programmatic decisions, planning to
chart the direction the improvements will take, employee
involvement in the change efforts, organizational realignment to
streamline <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and clarify accountability, and congressional
involvement and oversight. Experience has shown that when these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> are in place, lasting management reforms are more likely
to be implemented that ultimately lead to improvements in the
performance and cost-efficiency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, this concludes our prepared statement. We would be
pleased to respond to any questions that you or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> may have.

Contacts and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acknowledgement</ENAMEX>
For further contacts regarding this testimony, please contact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Mihm</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8676</TIMEX>. For information regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
work on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> modernization, please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James R. White</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-9110</ENAMEX>, and for information regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSA</ENAMEX>, please
contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard L. Ungar</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-4232</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> making key
contributions to this testimony included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsey Bright</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah</ENAMEX>
Junod, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Ragland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Reinsberg</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-GGD-00-26 Page 15 GAO/T-GGD-00</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ordering Information</ENAMEX>
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> copy of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report and testimony is free.
Additional copies are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> each. Orders should be sent to the
following address, accompanied by a check or money order made out
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Superintendent of Documents</ENAMEX>, when necessary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VISA</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> credit cards are accepted, also. Orders for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> or more
copies to be mailed to a single address are discounted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
percent.
Order by mail:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.O. Box 37050</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC 20013</ENAMEX>
or visit:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Room 1100 700 4th St.</ENAMEX> NW (corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">4th</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G Sts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NW</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>


Orders may also be placed by calling (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6000</ENAMEX> or by using
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">fax</ENAMEX> number (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-6061</TIMEX>, or TDD (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2537</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> issues a list of newly available reports and
testimony. To receive facsimile copies of the daily list or any
list from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 days</TIMEX>, please call (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-6000</TIMEX> using a
touchtone phone. A recorded menu will provide information on how to
obtain these lists.
For information on how to access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reports on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNET</ENAMEX>,
send e-mail message with "info" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to:
info@<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>
or visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web Home Page</ENAMEX> at:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bulk Rate Postage & Fees Paid GAO Permit No.</ENAMEX> G100
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">20548-0001</ENAMEX>


Official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Penalty</ENAMEX> for Private Use <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Address Correction Requested</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">410502</ENAMEX>)





