



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">272364.1</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John McCain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Daniel K.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inouye</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Indian Affairs United States</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Don Young</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable George Miller</ENAMEX>
Ranking Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Resources House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: Contracts Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Self-Determination</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Education Assistance Act</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Indian Affairs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Health Services</ENAMEX>, entitled "Contracts
Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Self-Determination</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Education Assistance Act</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RINs</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1076-AD21 and 0905-AC98</TIMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32481</NUMEX>.
The joint rule is issued to permit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX> to award
contracts and grants to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> without the confusion
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sets of rules for a single program.
This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> attempt by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX> to issue such a
rule. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> directed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX> to develop
regulations to implement amendments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Self-Determination Act</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93-638</NUMEX>) contained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Determination</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Education Assistance Act Amendments</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-23</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 100-472</ENAMEX>). Those amendments were intended to increase
tribal participation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Indian Programs</ENAMEX>
and to help ensure long-term financial stability for tribal-run
programs. When the proposed regulation was published for public
comment (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3166</TIMEX>), reaction was critical over the lack of
tribal participation in the latter stages of the drafting process
and the overall length of the proposed regulation.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reexamination</ENAMEX> of the regulation drafting process
led to the passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> Self-Determination Act Amendments
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 103-413</ENAMEX>). This Act removed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' prior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX>' general legislative rulemaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Act</ENAMEX> and limited it to certain subject matter
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas enumerated</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. Moreover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> required the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments</ENAMEX>, in issuing any new rules in those areas, to utilize
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Negotiated Rulemaking Act of 1990</ENAMEX> as a guide with the direct
participation of tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> in the rulemaking.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX> chartered a negotiated rulemaking committee
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Advisory Committee</ENAMEX> Act to develop this rule. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> representing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tribes</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between April 1995 and May 1996</TIMEX>.
The rule is the result of consensus by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> except in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> areas: internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> procedures, contract renewal
procedures, conflicts of interest and construction management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> of tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> met with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX> to present the tribal views
of the unresolved areas and the rule incorporates the decisions
made based on that meeting.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of the Interior</ENAMEX> and
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
Departments complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James W. Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Indian Affairs</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor S. Rezendes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy, Resources</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rezendes</ENAMEX>
can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-3841</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health and Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Health Services</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David P. Baine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Delivery and Quality Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baine</ENAMEX> can be reached
at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7101</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc: Ada E. Deer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Secretary</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Affairs Department of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael H. Trujillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.Ph.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Health Service</ENAMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ISSUED BY THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEPARTMENT</ENAMEX> OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERIOR, BUREAU OF INDIAN AFFAIRS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERVICE ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "CONTRACTS UNDER THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INDIAN</ENAMEX> SELF-DETERMINATION AND
EDUCATION ASSISTANCE ACT" (RINs: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1076-AD21 and 0905-AC98</TIMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX> have advised our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> that they were not
required to prepare and did not prepare a cost-benefit analysis of
the rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX> certified
in the preambles to both the proposed rulemaking (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2038, 2044</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 24, 1996</TIMEX>)) and the final rulemaking (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32481, 32500</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24, 1996</TIMEX>)) that the rule would not have a
substantial effect on a significant number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
Therefore, they were not required to prepare an initial or final
regulatory flexibility analysis under sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">604</NUMEX> of the
Act. For the same reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 607</ENAMEX> is inapplicable. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section 609</ENAMEX> likewise is inapplicable, the preamble in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX> wanted to afford public
participation to the maximum extent and, therefore, the negotiated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> meetings were open to the public and all
sessions were announced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>.
According to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of the Interior</ENAMEX>,
publication of the certifications in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> was
treated as providing notice under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Administration</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocacy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>
has confirmed that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> follow this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> without
objection from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX>, this rulemaking action does not
impose unfunded mandates under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32500</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-23</NUMEX>
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was promulgated through the notice and comment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> procedures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments</ENAMEX>
afforded interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> the opportunity to comment on the
proposed rule, and evaluated and responded to the comments in
connection with publication of the final rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule contains information collection requirements regarding
contract proposal contents, programmatic reports and data
requirements, property donation procedures and construction
contracts. The requirements were negotiated and agreed upon by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments</ENAMEX> and the tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> during the negotiated
rulemaking process.
The preamble to the proposed rulemaking set forth the reasons
for collecting the information and the burden estimates and
solicited comments regarding the collection to be submitted to both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Departments</ENAMEX> submitted the proposed collection requirements to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>
as required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> has approved the
information collection requirements and assigned control number
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1076-0136</TIMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 107</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> Self-Determination Act, as
amended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Self-Determination Contract Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 103-413</ENAMEX>) authorized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX> to jointly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promulgate</ENAMEX> regulations limited solely to self-determination
contracts or the approval, award or declination of such contract
regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Federal Tort Claims Act</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Contract Disputes Act</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">declination</ENAMEX> and waiver procedures, appeal procedures, reassumption
procedures, discretionary grant procedures, property donation
procedures, internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> procedures relating to implementation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, retrocession and tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> relinquishment
procedures, contract proposal contents, conflicts of interest,
construction, programmatic reports and data requirements,
procurement standards, property management standards and financial
management standards. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 107</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) required that the
Departments use the negotiated rulemaking procedures contained in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Negotiated Rule Making Act of 1990</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">561-570</ENAMEX>).
Executive Order No. 12866
The rule was determined to be a "significant regulatory action"
under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12866</ENAMEX> requiring review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX> approved the final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 19, 1996</TIMEX> as complying
with the requirements of the Order based on the information
supplied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX>, including a planned regulatory action
document describing the reason for the rule and an assessment of
the costs and budgetary impact of the rule.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive</ENAMEX> Orders and Statutes
The preamble to the final rule states that the rule is not
subject to review under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Orders 12630</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property</ENAMEX> rights)
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12612</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism</ENAMEX>). Also, the rule does not significantly
affect the quality of the human environment and no detailed
statement is required under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Environmental Policy</ENAMEX> Act
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32500</NUMEX>. Further, the rule is not subject to
the requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Orders 12606</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> issues), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12875</NUMEX>
(intergovernmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12988</NUMEX> (civil justice reform) and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12948</NUMEX> (environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Departments</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statute or executive
order imposing procedural requirements relevant to the rule.



