



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-274403
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 26, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Alfonse D'Amato Chairman The Honorable Paul S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarbanes Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking, Housing</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Affairs United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rule 11AC1-4</ENAMEX> (Limit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Order Display Rule) and Amendments to Rule</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AC1-1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quote</ENAMEX>
Rule)
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rule 11AC1-4</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Limit Order Display Rule</ENAMEX>) and
Amendments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AC1-1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rule</ENAMEX>) (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-AG66</TIMEX>)
the rule and amendments on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 9, 1996</TIMEX>. They were published
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 12, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48290</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> adopted the Limit Order <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Display Rule</ENAMEX> and amended
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rule</ENAMEX> pursuant to its authority under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities</ENAMEX>
Exchange <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1934</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">78a-78ll</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Limit Order Display Rule</ENAMEX> requires the public display of
customer limit orders priced better than an exchange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX>'s
or market <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>'s quote. The rule also requires that specialists
and market makers add limit orders priced at their quote to the
size associated with their quote when that quote represents the
best marketwide price. The rule will set standard display
requirements for limit orders in all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-43</NUMEX>
markets. The rule represents a major change for the handling of
limit orders in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> market where such orders have never been
displayed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> believes that the new rule will benefit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> because the publication of trading interest at prices
that improve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>' and market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>' quotes presents
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> with improved execution opportunities and improved access
to best prices when they buy or sell securities.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> also adopted amendments to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rule</ENAMEX> to
ensure that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are fully informed of the best price at
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> or market <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> are willing to trade a security.
Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> and market makers may privately display a
better price than their public quotations through certain private
trading systems in which priced orders are invisible and
inaccessible to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> at large. The amendment to the rule
benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> by bringing into public view the better prices
in these systems and by allowing all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to trade at these
prices. In addition, the rule was amended to require that
substantial market makers for any security listed on an exchange
publish their quotations for that security. According to the
Commission, this benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> by enhancing the public
availability of prices for all listed securities, some of which
were not published before.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s compliance with
the procedural steps required by sections 801(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule and amendments. Our review
indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable
requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen E. Wannisky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8326</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
Bothwell, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Financial Institutions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Markets</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bothwell</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8678</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan G. Katz</ENAMEX> Secretary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange</ENAMEX>
Commission
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-43</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>งย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF RULE 11AC1-4
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIMIT ORDER DISPLAY RULE</ENAMEX>) AND <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMENDMENTS TO RULE 11 AC1-1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QUOTE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMMISSION</ENAMEX>



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

us that it was not required to prepare, and did not prepare, a
cost-benefit analysis of the rule and rule amendments. Instead,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">78w</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is directed to consider
the impact that the rule may have on competition. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
stated that the competition analysis which it prepared provides
information very similar to that provided by a cost-benefit
analysis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> concluded that the rule and rule
amendments will not impose any unnecessary or inappropriate burdens
on competition.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
In its <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">52792,</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 10, 1995</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> included a summary of its Initial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis.</ENAMEX> In accordance with sections
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603</NUMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> describes the reasons for the
proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> actions and its objectives and legal basis. With
regard to sections 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">iii) and</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> states that
it uses certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commissionadopted</ENAMEX> definitions of "small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>"
for purposes of its analysis and concludes that it is unable to
quantify reasonably the impact that the proposed rule and
amendments would have on small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX>.
The summary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> does
not address any other relevant federal rules that duplicate,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overlap</ENAMEX>, or conflict with this rule and amendments as provided for
by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>).
Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> rejected the alternative of exempting
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> from the proposed rules and amendments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-43</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> published a summary of its Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 12, 1996</TIMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48325</NUMEX>) and provided us with a copy of the full text
of the analysis.
Pursuant to section 604a(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> provides a statement
of the need for, and objectives of, the rule and the rule
amendments. In accordance with section 604a(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), it provides a
summary of the significant issues raised in the comments submitted
in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> and its
reaction to those comments. It specifically addresses concerns
raised suggesting (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> should better quantify
the effects of the proposals on the market (especially the
anti-competitive effects) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s estimates
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>) were too
low. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> discusses how it amended the proposals in
response to these comments.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> discusses the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of small
entities that would be subject to this rulemaking and concludes
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker-dealers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 960</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> Small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cap</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">issuers</ENAMEX> could be affected by this rulemaking.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> describes the projected compliance requirements
of the rules and describes the steps taken to minimize the economic
impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, including consideration of several
significant alternatives to both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rule</ENAMEX> and the Display
Rule. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> states that it believes that the rule and
amendments as adopted impose a smaller burden upon small brokers
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> than any of the alternatives.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> provides generally descriptive statements of the
effects of the rules as suggested in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 607 of the Act</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> that to encourage small
entities to participate in the rulemaking process as called for by
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 609</ENAMEX>, it distributed a "plain <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>" version of the
proposing release, it posted the proposals under the "Items of
Interest to Small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Businesses</ENAMEX>" section of its Internet Web-site, it
met with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that represent small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security Traders Association</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Specialists</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, and its senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> gave speeches describing the
proposals and encouraging comments.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> states in its report to us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unfunded</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX> does not apply to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange Commission</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-43</NUMEX>
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> promulgated this rulemaking under the notice and
comment procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. An initial <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of Proposed
Rulemaking was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 10</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52792</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> received comments on the
proposals from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX> individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> discusses these comments and any actions
taken in reaction to them in the supplementary information provided
when the Final Rules were published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 12, 1996</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">48290-48332</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Display Rule</ENAMEX> and the
proposed amendments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rule</ENAMEX> contain collections of
information within the meaning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>. They
were both submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>)
for review under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 3507 of the Act</ENAMEX>. They were both approved
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> and assigned control numbers: control number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32350461</NUMEX> for
the amendments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rule</ENAMEX> and control number <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-0462</TIMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Display Rule</ENAMEX>. An additional notice of information collection
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rule</ENAMEX> was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 12, 1996</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48333</NUMEX>) proposing an additional
amendment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rule</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> will make a decision regarding
approval of this information collection between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 and 60 days</TIMEX>
Statutory authorization for the rules
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> adopted the Limit Order <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Display Rule</ENAMEX> and amended
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rule</ENAMEX> pursuant to its authority under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities</ENAMEX>
Exchange <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1934</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">78a-78ll</ENAMEX>), in particular pursuant
to the mandate to develop a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Market System</ENAMEX> contained in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 11A of the Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">78k</ENAMEX>-l.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive</ENAMEX> Orders and Statutes
As discussed above, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities</ENAMEX>
Exchange <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1934</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยง</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)) requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
to prepare an analysis of the effect of these rules on competition.
Such an analysis was prepared. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not identify any
other statutes or executive orders imposing requirements relevant
to these rules.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-43</NUMEX>



