



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">272531.1</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Richard G. Lugar Chairman The Honorable Patrick J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leahy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nutrition</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forestry United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Pat Roberts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable E</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kika</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Agriculture House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Pathogen Reduction</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazard Analysis and Critical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Point</ENAMEX> (HACCP) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Safety and Inspection Service</ENAMEX>, entitled "Pathogen
Reduction: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Point</ENAMEX> (HACCP)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0583-AB69</ENAMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10, 1996</TIMEX>.
It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38805</NUMEX>.
The rule establishes requirements applicable to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and poultry
establishments designed to reduce the occurrence and numbers of
pathogenic microorganisms on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry products</ENAMEX>, reduce the
incidence of foodborne illness associated with the consumption of
those products and provide a new framework for modernization of the
current system of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX> inspection.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Safety and Inspection</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the procedural steps required by sections
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule.
Our review indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Safety and Inspection Service</ENAMEX>
complied with the applicable requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-31</NUMEX>
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James W. Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Safety and Inspection Service</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Agriculture Issues</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> has
issued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Safety and Quality-Uniform</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Risk</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inspection</ENAMEX>
System Needed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ensure Safe Food Supply</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/RCED-92-152</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>
Safety-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Risk</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inspections</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microbial Monitoring Needed</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Meat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poultry</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/RCED-94-110</ENAMEX>) concerning the subject of this
rule. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-5138</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael R. Taylor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator Food Safety and Inspection</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-31</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ISSUED BY THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE, FOOD SAFETY AND INSPECTION</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERVICE ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">PATHOGEN REDUCTION</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAZARD ANALYSIS AND CRITICAL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONTROL POINT</ENAMEX> (HACCP) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SYSTEMS</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0583-AB69</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Safety and Inspection Service</ENAMEX> (FSIS) prepared a
cost-benefit analysis which concludes that the costs associated
with the rule are far outweighed by the public health benefits to
be derived.
The analysis concludes that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> industry costs are
estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$969 to $1,156 million</NUMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> cost to the
government to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$56.5 million</NUMEX>. The analysis considers data for
average wages, the cost of specific processing equipment and the
cost of conducting specific laboratory analyses.
The potential health benefits resulting from the elimination of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pathogens is estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.13 to $26.59 billion</NUMEX> over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>. The range of benefits occurs because of the current
uncertainty in the estimates of the number of cases of foodborne
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> and death attributable to the pathogens that enter the meat
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX> supply at the manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX> has concluded that the rule will have
a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX> and an initial regulatory flexibility analysis and final
regulatory flexibility analysis has been prepared and included in
the notice of proposed rulemaking and the final rule notice,
respectively, as required by sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603 and 604</NUMEX>. The analyses
comply with the informational requirements of the sections
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> subject to the requirement
and alternatives considered to reduce to the burden on the small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>.
The final regulatory flexibility analysis discusses the comments
received from both the industry and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Advocacy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Administration</ENAMEX> and the changes made to the proposed rule
to grant regulatory relief to the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> including the
sequencing of implementation by establishment size.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-31</NUMEX>
The analyses use both quantifiable and general descriptions of
the effects of the rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> as required by section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607</NUMEX> and small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, in addition to the actions required by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>, participated in the numerous meetings, forums and
conferences held in connection with the preparation of the final
rule as required by section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
Based on the cost-benefit analysis performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX>, the rule
will impose an unfunded mandate on the private sector of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$99.6</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$119.8 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> and therefore the rule is subject to the
requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
As required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 205, FSIS</ENAMEX> considered several regulatory
alternatives to the imposition of the mandatory HACCP but
determined that the requirements expressed in the final rule
constituted the most cost-effective and least burdensome
alternative that would meet the objective of the rule.
To fulfill the requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 204</ENAMEX> regarding providing
an opportunity for input from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, local and tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>,
a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>-State-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relations Conference</ENAMEX>" was held and the numerous
comments received from these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> were considered and are
discussed in the preamble and the final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact</ENAMEX>
Analysis.
Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX> considered the comments of several state
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that the rule imposed an unfunded mandate on
State inspection programs because of the need for these programs to
remain "at least equal to" the Federal inspection program. FSIS
concluded that because of the necessary restructuring and
reprogramming of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> inspection programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX> assistance and
the flexibility provided under the "equal to" provisions, most
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> should be able to complete the modifications to their
programs with minimal additional cost. Moreover, any additional
costs would be eligible to receive <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 50 percent</NUMEX> Federal
matching funds.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was promulgated using the notice and comment procedures
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. A notice of proposed rulemaking was published on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 3, 1995</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6774</TIMEX>. The initial comment period of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120 days</TIMEX> was extended for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an additional 30 days</TIMEX> and later reopened
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an additional 95 days</TIMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX> held <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> informational
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">briefings</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> scientific and technical conferences, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 2-day</TIMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-31</NUMEX>
public hearing, a scoping session, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> issue-focused public
meetings, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>-State conference, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Safety Forum</ENAMEX>. In
addition to the information gained through these meetings and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conferences</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,800</NUMEX> comments were received in response to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> notice.
The preamble to the final rule contains an extensive discussion
of the comments received and the changes to the proposed rule which
were made was a result.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> to document their compliance
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Points</ENAMEX> (HACCP)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the development of a plan and thereafter in a
continuous record of process performance. The information
collection requirements were discussed in the preamble to the
proposed rule making published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 3, 1995</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6832</TIMEX>). At the same time, public comments to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> were requested.
In the preamble to the final rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX> has approved its information collection
requirements system under OMB No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0583-0103</TIMEX> with an annual burden
of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14,371,901 hours</TIMEX>. However, in view of comments received and a
reevaluation of the requirements by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> subject matter experts
and private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX> has reduced the annual burden to
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8,053,319 hours</TIMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6,318,582-hour</TIMEX> reduction. This reduction was
obtained through more accurate burden estimates and the elimination
of certain requirements including time and temperature reports and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> resumes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment employees</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX> has submitted these changes in the information collection
requirements to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for its approval and certified to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> that the
information collection complied with each of the objectives
identified in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3506</TIMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>).
Statutory authorization for the rule
This rule is promulgated under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">451-470</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poultry Products Inspection Act</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">601-695</ENAMEX>
(Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Meat Inspection Act</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901-1906</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Humane Methods of Slaughter Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>).
Executive Order No. 12866
The rule has been determined to be economically significant
under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX> requiring review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information and Regulatory Affairs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>. Both the proposed rule and
the final rule were reviewed and approved as complying with the
requirements of the Order based on the information supplied by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX>, including the initial and final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact</ENAMEX>
Analyses.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-31</NUMEX>
Executive Order No. 12988
According to the preamble, the final rule was reviewed pursuant
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12778</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Justice Reform</ENAMEX>. However, that
Executive Order has been replaced by Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order 12988</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Reform</ENAMEX>, effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5, 1996</TIMEX>. The prior Executive Order
contained a similar requirement now found at Section 3(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of
the newly effective Order requiring that the preemptive effect of
the rule be specified. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">FSIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poultry Products</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Inspection Act</ENAMEX> (PPIA) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Meat Inspection Act</ENAMEX> (FMIA),
cited above, state and local jurisdictions are preempted from
imposing any requirements with respect to federally inspected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premises</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> that are in addition to, or different from,
those imposed under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">PPIA</ENAMEX> or FMIA.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSIS</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statute or executive order
imposing procedural requirements relevant to the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-31</NUMEX>



