



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-272939
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 8, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Larry Pressler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Ernest F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interconnection</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resale Obligations Pertaining</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial Mobile Radio</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Report</ENAMEX> and Order:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interconnection</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resale Obligations Pertaining</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobile Radio Services</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-263</NUMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38399</NUMEX>.
In this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Report</ENAMEX> and Order, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> adopts a
transitional rule requiring all cellular and broadband personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> services and certain specialized mobile radio
providers to permit unlimited resale of their services. The First
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order also eliminates an exception to an existing rule
which permitted cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">licensees</ENAMEX> under some circumstances to
restrict resale by their licensed cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. It also
provides that the resale rule will sunset <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 years</TIMEX> after the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of licenses for currently allotted personal communications
services spectrum is awarded (expected to occur <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a year</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-32</NUMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, the purpose of the above actions is
to make the mass market for two-way switched voice mobile services
more competitive while that market is in a transitional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> as
well as to encourage new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrants</ENAMEX> into the market by allowing them
to resell their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>' services while they build out their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications</ENAMEX>
Commission's compliance with the procedural steps required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sections 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Report</ENAMEX> and Order. Our
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen E. Wannisky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-5207</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2834</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew S. Fishel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-32</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REPORT AND ORDER</ENAMEX>: INTERCONNECTION AND <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RESALE OBLIGATIONS</ENAMEX> PERTAINING
TO <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMMERCIAL MOBILE RADIO SERVICES</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-263</NUMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> stated in its submission to us that it was not
required to prepare and did not prepare a cost-benefit analysis of
the rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking and Notice</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inquiry</ENAMEX> that
addressed a number of commercial mobile radio services regulatory
issues. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Access</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Interconnection Obligations Pertaining</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial Mobile Radio Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC Docket</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94-54</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> Rcd
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5408</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>)). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> subsequently modified its proposal
regarding resale in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Second Notice of Proposed</ENAMEX> Rulemaking
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interconnection</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resale Obligations Pertaining</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobile Radio Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC Docket</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94-54</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> Rcd 10666
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>)).
In both notices, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> prepared and published an
Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> and invited written public
comments on the proposed rulemaking, including comments on the
initial regulatory flexibility analysis.
The analysis included in the proposed rulemaking provides the
information required by sections 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>). It describes
the reasons for the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> action and its objectives and
legal basis. The information required by sections 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
concerning the estimate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> subject to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order and the projected reporting, recordkeeping and
other compliance requirements of the proposed rule is also
included. In accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
notes that the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX> and Order does not duplicate, overlap
or conflict with any other relevant federal rule.
Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> solicited comments on a variety of
alternatives regarding interconnection, roaming and resale
obligations for commercial mobile radio service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> in
compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603</ENAMEX>(c).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-32</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
includes the full text of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38399</NUMEX>. This analysis includes
information required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 604</ENAMEX> including a description of the
need for and purpose of this Report and Order and a discussion of
comments received in regard to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Analysis.
Although no comments were filed in direct response to the
initial analysis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> stated that some general comments
related to issues that could affect small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
discussed these comments in its final analysis and concluded that
the comments were not well-founded.
The analysis further describes the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> affected by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order; summarizes the projected reporting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recordkeeping</ENAMEX> and other compliance requirements; and describes the
steps taken to minimize the economic impact on small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.
Finally, the analysis discusses several significant alternatives
that were considered and rejected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, including
expanding the universe of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> covered by the rule, more
narrowly defining the universe of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, and continuing the
resale rule indefinitely.
We have confirmed that copies of both the Initial and the Final
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analyses</ENAMEX> were provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocacy</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX> as required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section 605</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 607</ENAMEX>: Preparation of analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s analysis addressed the effects of the rule on
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in a general manner, consistent with the
requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 607</ENAMEX>. It also points out that the rule
imposes no affirmative compliance actions by any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> to which
it applies. Rather, the rule operates in a manner that prohibits
restrictions on the resale of service.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 609</ENAMEX>: Participation by small entities
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> offered the opportunity to comment on both the
initial and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> proposed rule and order to any interested
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, including small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s submission to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> did not highlight any other actions taken to encourage small
entity participation in the rulemaking process.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-32</NUMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is not
subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> promulgated this rule under the notice and
comment procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. An initial notice of proposed
rulemaking was released on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 1994</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> Rcd <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5408</TIMEX>) and a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> notice of proposed rulemaking was released on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 20, 1995</TIMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC Rcd</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10666</NUMEX>). Summaries of the notices of these proposed
rulemakings were published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>. (See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35664 and 60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20949</NUMEX>). Fifty-one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> filed
comments and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> filed replies in response to comments. The
Commission indicates that it gave full consideration to the
comments filed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. A detailed discussion of the
Commission's consideration of these comments is considered in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> text of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule does not impose information collection requirements
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
Authorization for this rulemaking is contained in sections <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1,</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>(i), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">j</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">201, 202, 303</ENAMEX>(r), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">309, 332</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">403</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Act of 1934</ENAMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">151, 154</TIMEX>(i),
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">154</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">j</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">201, 202, 303</ENAMEX>(r), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">309, 332</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">403</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statutes or executive
orders imposing requirements relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-32</NUMEX>



