



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-274798
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 17, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John H. Chafee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Max Baucus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control of Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pollution: Final Rule for New Gasoline Spark-Ignition Marine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engines; Exemptions</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Nonroad Compression-Ignition Engines</ENAMEX> at
or above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kilowatts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Nonroad Spark-Ignition Engines</ENAMEX> at or
Below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> Kilowatts
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Control of Air Pollution: Final Rule</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Gasoline Spark-Ignition Marine Engines; Exemptions for New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonroad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Compression-Ignition Engines</ENAMEX> at or above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kilowatts</ENAMEX> and
New <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nonroad Spark-Ignition Engines at or Below 19 Kilowatts</ENAMEX>" (RIN:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2060-AE54</ENAMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 10, 1996</TIMEX>. It was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 4</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52087</NUMEX>.
The rule regulates exhaust <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from new spark-ignition
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SI</ENAMEX>) gasoline marine engines including outboard engines, personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">watercraft</ENAMEX> engines and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet boat</ENAMEX> engines beginning with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year</TIMEX> and the rule is fully phased-in by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006 model year</TIMEX>.
The regulation of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> became necessary under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">213</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>, as amended, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> found that
these nonroad engines were significant contributors to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon monoxide</ENAMEX> concentrations in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> nonattainment area.
A nonattainment area is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-45</NUMEX>
specified area that has failed to attain the applicable National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambient Air Quality Standard</ENAMEX> for a given pollutant. In addition,
the rule exempts new nonroad compression-ignition engines at or
above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> kilowatts and new nonroad sparkignition engines at or
below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> kilowatts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the procedural steps required by sections
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule.
Our review indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guerrero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerrero</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6111</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas E. Kelly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">AIR POLLUTION</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FINAL RULE FOR NEW GASOLINE SPARK-IGNITION MARINE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ENGINES; EXEMPTIONS FOR NEW NONROAD COMPRESSION-IGNITION ENGINES AT</ENAMEX>
OR ABOVE <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> KILOWATTS AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEW NONROAD SPARK-IGNITION ENGINES</ENAMEX> AT OR
BELOW <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KILOWATTS</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2060-AE54</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has prepared an analysis of the costs and benefits of the
rule which is contained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact Analysis.</ENAMEX> The
analysis explains the methodologies and the reasons behind their
use in arriving at the cost and benefits of the rule.
In achieving the rule's goal of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> reduction in
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydrocarbon</ENAMEX> emissions by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2025</TIMEX>, such a reduction will also
contribute to the reduction of volatile organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compounds</ENAMEX> and ozone
in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> attainment areas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> finds that the benefits of a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">590,254 tons</NUMEX> of hydrocarbons reduced per year by the rule more than
offsets the increase in oxides of nitrogen of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25,440 tons</NUMEX> per year
which will result.
The annualized costs associated with the rule in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX> will
exceed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$370 million</NUMEX>, which is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> of the projected
expenditure on these engines in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>. The average increase in
cost for the engines would be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10-15 percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700</NUMEX> per engine. The
analysis contains tables which show the annual cost from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the
effective date of the rule, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2051</TIMEX>, by which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
expects the entire existing fleet of these engines to have been
replaced, to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15.5 million to $336.2 million</NUMEX>, respectively.
The cost-effectiveness of the rule has been calculated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to
be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $1,000</NUMEX> per ton of hydrocarbons reduced.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
In the preamble to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55966</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> concluded that the rule would have a significant
impact on a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, especially in
view of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, which considers any impact
a significant impact.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-45</NUMEX>
However, in the preamble to the final rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has now
determined that the rule will not have a significant impact on a
substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. This change is due to the
deletion from the rule of the regulation of stern drive and inboard
engines, which are mainly manufactured by small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
believes that, at most, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> which manufacture
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outboard</ENAMEX> or personal watercraft and jetboat engines that qualify as
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> notes in the preamble to the final rule that it has reduced
the burdens where possible on these small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> following
consideration of the comments received. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> states that it has
taken into consideration the potential competitive impact on these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and has eased the burden by permitting averaging emissions
across product lines, reduced production line testing, reduced
in-use testing, simplified certification procedures and allowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to purchase emission credits from the market place as
an alternative to employing control technologies to meet the
standard.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
Based on the cost benefit analysis performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, the rule
will not impose an intergovernmental mandate because there are no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enforceable</ENAMEX> duties on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, local or tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. However,
the rule will impose a mandate on the private sector in excess of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any one year</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has prepared both a qualitative and quantitative assessment
of the benefits and costs of the rule in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact</ENAMEX>
Analysis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has considered numerous regulatory alternatives to the final
provisions of the rule, which are discussed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summary</ENAMEX> and
Analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comments</ENAMEX>, but has determined that the requirements
expressed in the final rule constitute the most cost-effective and
least burdensome alternative that would meet the mandate of section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">213</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
Instead of the notice and comment procedures in the
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> promulgated this rule using
the procedures, which have similar notice and comment requirements,
contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 307</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>, as amended. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7607</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)). The use of these procedures regarding rules
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pertaining</ENAMEX> to nonroad engines or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> is mandated by section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">307</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-45</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> published a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 9</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55930</NUMEX>) requesting comments on the proposed rule.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 7, 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> published a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental Notice</ENAMEX> of
Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4600</TIMEX>) to refine some of the
proposals made in the prior notice and to respond to comments which
had been received. In the preamble to the final rule (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52090</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> discusses the changes made in the proposed rule in
finalizing the rule and advises that the significant comments
received and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s responses thereto are available to the public in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary and Analysis of Comments document</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule contains information collection requirements which are
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> originally submitted
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> information collection requests (ICRs) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) for approval under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Act</ENAMEX> in
connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> originally
denied all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> requests but subsequently approved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the
requests. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has resubmitted all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> requests based on reduced
reporting and recordkeeping requirements resulting from changed
requirements in the final rule. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> notes that it has taken steps
to reduce the administrative burden as much as possible and in the
final rule estimates that the burden for the collection of
information under all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICRs</ENAMEX> would average <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6,900 hours</TIMEX> annually
for a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>.
The ICRs contain the information required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> including
the reasons for the collection of the information, the type of
information and an estimate of the burden imposed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has solicited comments on the proposed information collection
requirements to be sent to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for consideration
during the approval process.
The information collection requirements of the rule will not be
effective until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approval is obtained.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has cited sections <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202, 203, 204, 205, 206, 207, 208,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">209, 213, 215, 216, and 301</ENAMEX>(a) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>, as amended,
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7521, 7522, 7523, 7524, 7525, 7541, 7542, 7543, 7547</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7549, 7550 and 7601</TIMEX>(a)). In particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 213 of the Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7547</TIMEX>) requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator of EPA</ENAMEX> to regulate
emissions from nonroad engines and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and to issue
regulations containing standards applicable to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from these
categories of new nonroad engines and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> reviewed the rule under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX> as a
"significant regulatory action." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Information</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Affairs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approved the
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-45</NUMEX>
final rule as complying with the requirements of the Order based
on the information supplied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, including a planned regulatory
action document describing the reason for the rule and an
assessment of the costs and budgetary impact of the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-45</NUMEX>



