



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271810.5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Larry Pressler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Ernest F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s Rules Regarding a Plan
for Sharing the Cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microwave Relocation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Report</ENAMEX> and
Order and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Further Notice of Proposed Rule Making</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s
Rules Regarding a Plan for Sharing the Cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microwave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relocation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Report</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order and Further Notice</ENAMEX> of Proposed
Rule <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making"</ENAMEX> (WT Docket No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95-157</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-196</NUMEX>). We received the
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a
final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29679</NUMEX>.
This rule changes and clarifies certain aspects of the
Commission's microwave relocation rules and adopts a plan for
sharing the costs of relocating microwave <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> currently
operating in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1850 to 1990</TIMEX> MHz (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2GHz</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> has been
allocated for use by broadband <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Communications Services</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCS</ENAMEX>) licensees.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications</ENAMEX>
Commission's compliance with the procedural steps required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sections 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-14</NUMEX>
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates
applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James W. Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John H. Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of
reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2834</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew S. Fishel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-14</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A MAJOR</ENAMEX>
RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">AMENDMENT</ENAMEX> TO THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMMISSION</ENAMEX>'S RULES REGARDING A PLAN FOR SHARING
THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COST OF MICROWAVE RELOCATION</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIRST REPORT AND ORDER AND</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">FURTHER NOTICE OF PROPOSED RULE MAKING</ENAMEX> (WT Docket No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95-157</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-196</NUMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> stated in its submission to us that it was not
required to prepare and did not prepare a cost-benefit analysis of
the rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The proposed rulemaking, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55529</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1, 1995</TIMEX>),
incorporated an initial regulatory flexibility analysis of the
expected impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
The analysis included in the proposed rulemaking provides the
information required by paragraphs 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>). It
describes the reasons for the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> action, and its
objectives and legal basis. It also describes the small entities
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCS</ENAMEX> licensees) to which the proposed rule will apply. The
information required by paragraph 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) concerning an estimate
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> subject to the requirement and the
type of professional skills necessary for preparation of the
required report is contained in the preamble under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork</ENAMEX>
Reduction Act section as permitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(a). In accordance
with paragraph 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> notes that the proposed
rule does not duplicate, overlap, or conflict with any relevant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> rule. Finally, the analysis reports, as required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">paragraph 603</ENAMEX>(c), that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has reduced burdens where
possible and that the regulatory burdens retained are necessary to
ensure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> receives the benefits of the new services in a
prompt and efficient manner.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
with the final rule includes the full text of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s
final regulatory flexibility analysis. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29688</NUMEX>. This
analysis includes the information required by paragraph 604(a) by
summarizing and evaluating comments received.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-14</NUMEX>
Numerous comments were received regarding the proposed plan to
convert microwave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> to secondary status when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relocation</ENAMEX> rules sunset in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> and thereafter, licensees would not
be required to pay relocation costs after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that date</TIMEX> to such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incumbents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Public Power Association</ENAMEX> commented that
conversion to secondary status would have a severe impact on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX> budgets of small, non-profit public utility systems.
Incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> noted that this will encourage licensees to
"wait out" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> and increase the likelihood that incumbents
would have to assume the costs of their own relocation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">licensees</ENAMEX> argued that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX>'s equipment would be
fully amortized or in need of replacement.
In an attempt to balance the interests, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has
decided to retain the sunset date of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the date</TIMEX> after which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">licensees</ENAMEX> would not have to pay relocation costs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> but
decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> would not convert to secondary status until
and unless an emerging technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">licensee</ENAMEX> required use of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectrum</ENAMEX>, regardless of the sunset date.
The final analysis was forwarded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for
Advocacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 605</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Avoidance</ENAMEX> of duplicative or unnecessary
analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not invoke any of the exemptions or special
procedures authorized by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX> in preparing its regulatory
flexibility analysis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 607</ENAMEX>: Preparation of analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s analysis uses both quantifiable and general
descriptions of the effects of the rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 609</ENAMEX>: Participation by small entities
In addition to the actions required by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>, the
Commission also made available a complete copy of the proposed and
final rulemaking materials via the Internet.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is not
subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-14</NUMEX>
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> promulgated the rule under the notice and comment
procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. A notice of proposed rulemaking was
published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1, 1995</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55529</NUMEX>. The
Commission received comments on the proposed rule from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commenters</ENAMEX>. In the preamble to the final rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
responded to issues raised during the comment period.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> portions of the rule contain information collection
requirements covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. The rule requires that once a PCS
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">licensee</ENAMEX> and a microwave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> have signed an agreement with
respect to relocation of the microwave license, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> would
submit the relocation agreement to an industry-supported
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clearinghouse</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55536</NUMEX>. The rule further requires
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microwave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">licensees</ENAMEX> who seek special status as public safety
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">licensees</ENAMEX> in order to obtain special consideration (ie. an extended
voluntary negotiation period) obtain a certification confirming
their public safety status from the department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> responsible for
system oversight.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has published in both the proposed and final
rulemaking notices the information required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. These
requirements include the reasons for the collection of the
information, the type of information and an estimate of the burden
imposed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>. Comments were solicited from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>,
other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has advised our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> portions of
the rule requiring approval by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Act</ENAMEX> will not become
effective until such approval is received. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> estimates
these dates will be later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
publication.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has cited as authority Sections 4(i), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 303</TIMEX>(c),
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(f), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(r) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">332</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX>
Â§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 154</NUMEX>(i), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">157, 303</TIMEX>(c), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(f), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(r) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">332</NUMEX>, as amended.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sections 303</ENAMEX>(f) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>) empower the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to make such
regulations as necessary to prevent interference between stations
and encourage the larger and more effective use of radio in the
public interest, respectively. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 332</ENAMEX> requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>,
in managing the spectrum used by private land mobile services, to
encourage competition and provide services to the largest feasible
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-14</NUMEX>
Executive Order No. 12866
The rule, promulgated by an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, is
not subject to the review requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX> Order No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statutes or Executive
Orders imposing requirements relevant to the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-14</NUMEX>



