



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-271810
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John H. Chafee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Max Baucus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revision of Fee Schedules</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> Fee <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Recovery,</ENAMEX> FY
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuclear</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Commission</ENAMEX> entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revision of Fee Schedules</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> Fee
Recovery, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>" (RIN <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3150-AF39</TIMEX>). The rule implements for fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 1966</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 6101 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2214</TIMEX>, which requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
to recover from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> and licensees <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 100</NUMEX>
percent of its budget authority less amounts appropriated from the
Nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste Fund</ENAMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a
final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16203</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s compliance with
the procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-9
If you have questions concerning the substance of the rule,
please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor S. Rezendes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy, Resources</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Issues</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-3841</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John C. Hoyle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission Nuclear</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Commission</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-9
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS OF NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION 1996 FEE SCHEDULE RULE</ENAMEX>
UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

A cost-benefit analysis was not required or prepared for the
rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> determined that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the fee
schedule--specifically, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fee for materials
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">licensees</ENAMEX>--will have a significant impact on a substantial number
of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. Therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> prepared an initial
and final regulatory flexibility analysis under sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">604</NUMEX> of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, respectively.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial regulatory flexibility analysis
The proposed rulemaking, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2948</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 30, 1996</TIMEX>),
incorporates in its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> the full text of an
initial regulatory flexibility analysis that describes the impact
of the proposed rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. This analysis was
transmitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocacy</ENAMEX>, as required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subsection</ENAMEX> 603(a).
The analysis included in the proposed rulemaking provides the
information required by paragraphs 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>). It
describes the reasons for the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> action, and its
objectives and legal basis--i.e., to comply with the costrecovery
requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 6101 of the Omnibus Budget</ENAMEX> Reconciliation
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1990</ENAMEX>. It also describes the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> to which the
proposed rule will apply and estimates their number. With respect
to paragraph 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> states that
the proposed rule does not impose reporting or other
information-collection requirements. With respect to paragraph
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603</NUMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>), the analysis does not identify any relevant federal
rules that may duplicate, overlap, or conflict with the proposed
rule. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> advised us that there are no such rules.
With respect to subsection <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603</NUMEX>(c), the analysis describes several
alternative means of assessing fees for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that might
lessen the economic impact of the rule on them.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final regulatory flexibility analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
with the final rule includes the full text of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s
final regulatory flexibility analysis. See Appendix A to the Final
Rule, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">16224-16226</ENAMEX>. This analysis includes the
information required by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">subsection 604</TIMEX>(a). In particular, it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">summarizes</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/OGC-96-9</ENAMEX> evaluates comments concerning alternative means of
establishing fees for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> and evaluates these
alternatives. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> determined to retain its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior year</TIMEX>
practice of mitigating the impact of the fees by establishing
maximum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fees for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 605</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Avoidance</ENAMEX> of duplicative or unnecessary
analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not invoke any of the exemptions or special
procedures authorized by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX> in preparing its regulatory
flexibility analyses. Its impact analyses do consider information
and comments developed in connection with its fee schedule rules
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 607</ENAMEX>: Preparation of analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s analyses use both quantifiable and general
descriptions of the effects of the rule and alternatives on small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 609</ENAMEX>: Participation by small entities
In addition to the actions required by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>, the
Commission transmitted a complete copy of the proposed and final
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> materials to each of its licensees, including small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The rule, promulgated by an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, is
not subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was promulgated through the general notice of proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> procedures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
afforded interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> the opportunity to comment on the
proposed rule, and evaluated and responded to the comments in
connection with publication of the final rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3512</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> determined that the rule contains no information
collection requirements subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/OGC-96-9 Statutory</ENAMEX> authorization for the rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 6101 of the Omnibus Budget and Reconciliation Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2214</TIMEX>, requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to
recover from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> and licensees, for each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, an amount that approximates <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the
Commission's budget authority less any amount appropriated to the
Commission from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuclear Waste Fund</ENAMEX>. Such fees include amounts
collected from specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 9701 of title 31</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Code</ENAMEX>, for individually identifiable services provided
to them.
Executive Order No. 12866
The rule, promulgated by an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, is
not subject to the review requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX> Order No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statutes or Executive
orders imposing requirements relevant to the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-9



