



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-274091
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 19, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Larry Pressler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Ernest F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revision</ENAMEX> of the
Commission's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rules To Ensure Compatibility with Enhanced 911</ENAMEX>
Emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calling Systems</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wireless E911 Rules</ENAMEX>)
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revision of the Commission</ENAMEX>'s
Rules <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Ensure Compatibility with Enhanced 911 Emergency Calling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wireless E911 Rules</ENAMEX>)" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-264</NUMEX>). We received the rule
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a
final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40348</NUMEX>.
In adopting this Report and Order, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> promulgates
requirements for basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wireless 911</ENAMEX> services and establishes a
framework for improving wireless 911 services. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
adopts these rules pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">301 and 303</TIMEX>(r) of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Act of 1934</ENAMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">301</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(r).
For basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wireless 911</ENAMEX> services, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order</ENAMEX> requires covered
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> to transmit to public safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> calls
originating from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile handsets</ENAMEX> that transmit a code
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">identification</ENAMEX> number without any form of validation. If the public
safety <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> decides to receive all calls from these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order</ENAMEX> requires
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-34</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> to route all such calls even if they do not come from
units that generate any code identification. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order</ENAMEX> also
requires that, within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 year</TIMEX>, covered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> must be capable of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transmitting wireless 911</ENAMEX> calls made by hearing-or speech-impaired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> through the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTY</ENAMEX> or similar devices.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order</ENAMEX> also requires covered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> to offer certain 911
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enhancements</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 18 months</TIMEX>, including the ability to relay
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX>'s phone number and the location of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base station</ENAMEX> or
cell site receiving a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">911</ENAMEX> call. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 5 years</TIMEX>, the Order
requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> to provide a very specific geographical location
under some circumstances.
At the same time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is issuing this Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and
Order, it is also issuing a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Further Notice of Proposed</ENAMEX> Rulemaking
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40374</NUMEX>) to develop additional means of ensuring that
improvements made possible by technological advances are
incorporated into enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">911</ENAMEX> systems in the future.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications</ENAMEX>
Commission's compliance with the procedural steps required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sections 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to this Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order. Our
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen E. Wannisky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-5207</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2834</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew S. Fishel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-34</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMMISSION</ENAMEX>'S RULES TO <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ENSURE COMPATIBILITY WITH ENHANCED 911</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMERGENCY CALLING SYSTEMS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIRELESS E911 RULES</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-264</NUMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> stated in its submission to us that it was not
required to prepare and did not prepare a cost-benefit analysis of
this Report and Order.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> initiated this proceeding with a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of
Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking</ENAMEX> that addressed issues raised by the provision
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> and enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">911</ENAMEX> services through certain technologies.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revision of the Commission</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rules to Ensure Compatibility with</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enhanced 911 Emergency Calling Systems</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC Docket</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94102</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>
Rcd <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6170</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>)). In that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> prepared and
published an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> and invited
written public comments on the proposed rulemaking, including
comments on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis.</ENAMEX>
The analysis included in the proposed rulemaking provides the
information required by sections 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>). It describes
the reasons for the proposed action and its objectives and legal
basis. The information required by sections 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) concerning the estimate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of small entities
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order and the projected reporting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recordkeeping</ENAMEX> and other compliance requirements of the proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> is also included.
In accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> stated its
belief that the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order does not duplicate,
overlap or conflict with any other relevant federal rules. Finally,
in considering any significant alternatives minimizing the impact
on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> asks for comments on whether the
rule should be applied in situations with very limited PBX
configurations in compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603</ENAMEX>(c).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-34</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
includes the full text of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40348</NUMEX>. The analysis includes
information required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 604</ENAMEX>, including a description of the
need for and purpose of this Report and Order. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s
analysis describes how this Report and Order will make <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">911</ENAMEX> and
enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">911</ENAMEX> services for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of wireless telephones more widely
available and much more effective.
Although no comments were submitted in direct response to the
Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> noted that
a number of the general comments on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> might have an effect
on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, particularly on site-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Specialized Mobile</ENAMEX>
Radio (SMR) licensees and on rural cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. The
Commission describes how, in response to these comments, it
attempted to minimize the burdens on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> by:
--limiting the regulations to mass market two-way voice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>,
--providing for waivers for small rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>,
--accepting the recommendation of trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and public
safety <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to extend the implementation period for some
provisions over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 5-year</TIMEX> period, and
--offsetting the burden on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> by requiring that a
cost recovery mechanism will be in place before requiring
implementation of the requirements.
The analysis further describes the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> covered by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order, addressing separately cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">licensees</ENAMEX>,
broadband personal communication service licensees, and specialized
mobile radio licensees. The analysis also discusses the projected
reporting, recordkeeping and other compliance requirements of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order.
Finally, in compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 604</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>), the analysis
describes the significant alternatives considered and rejected,
including universal applicability to commercial mobile voice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, automatic exclusion of all rural cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>, and a
Commission-developed set of standards for implementation. The
analysis discusses why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> rejected these alternatives
and instead selected those adopted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Report</ENAMEX> and
Order.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-34</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 609</ENAMEX>: Participation by small entities
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> offered the opportunity to comment on the
proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order to any interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, including
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. In its <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX>, the
Commission specifically stated that the proposed regulation would
affect a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> both large and small. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
published the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC Record</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> that should be easily
obtained by small as well as large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in the
telecommunications industry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s submission to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> did
not highlight any other actions taken to encourage small entity
participation in the rulemaking process.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is not
subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> promulgated this rule under the notice and
comment procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of Proposed
Rulemaking was released on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 19, 1994</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> Rcd <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6170</TIMEX>). A
summary of the notice was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54878</NUMEX>). In response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 110</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> filed
comments and reply comments regarding the wireless <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> issues. The
commenters included wireless service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, public safety
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, equipment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and others. Appendix A to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order lists the commenters. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Report</ENAMEX> and
Order provides a detailed discussion of comments and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
reactions to them.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order does not impose an information collection,
although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> expects that future rulemaking in this area
will impose such a requirement. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> released this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26, 1996</TIMEX>, it included a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Further Notice</ENAMEX> of
Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Further Notice</ENAMEX> does anticipate an
information collection and invites comments from the general public
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX>. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40374</NUMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-34</NUMEX>
Statutory authorization for the rule
Authorization for this rule is contained in sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">301</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(r) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Act of 1934</ENAMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">301 and 303</TIMEX>(r).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statutes or executive
orders imposing requirements relevant to this Report and Order.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-34</NUMEX>



