



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">272303.1</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Alfonse M. D'Amato Chairman The Honorable Paul S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarbanes Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking, Housing</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Affairs United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable James A. Leach Chairman The Honorable Henry B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking and Financial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendments to Regulation X</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Estate Settlement</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Procedures Act</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Withdrawal of Employer/Employee and Computer Loan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Origination Systems Exemptions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">FR-3638</ENAMEX>); and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Statements</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-1</TIMEX> (regarding computer loan origination systems); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-2</TIMEX>
(regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sham</ENAMEX> controlled business arrangements); and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-3</TIMEX>
(rental of office space, lock-outs, and retaliation)
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>) entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amendments to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulation X</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act</ENAMEX>: Withdrawal
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employer/Employee and Computer Loan Origination Systems</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exemptions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">FR-3638</ENAMEX>); and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Statements</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-1</TIMEX> (regarding
computer loan origination systems); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-2</TIMEX> (regarding sham
controlled business arrangements); and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-3</TIMEX> (rental of office
space, lock-outs, and retaliation)" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2502-AG26</TIMEX>). We received
the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29238</NUMEX>.
The final rule revises <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulation X</ENAMEX>, which implements the Real
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974</ENAMEX> (RESPA). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESPA</ENAMEX> generally
prohibits compensated referrals in connection with real estate
settlements involving federally related mortgage loans. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2607</TIMEX>(a). However, it also authorizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> to exempt payments
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-22</NUMEX>
or classes of payments from this prohibition. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2607</TIMEX>(c), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2617</TIMEX>(a). A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> rule created exemptions for payments by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and for payments by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> to computer
loan origination systems. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49600</NUMEX>. The final rule
withdraws both exemptions and introduces <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> limited exemptions
for permissible payments by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to bona fide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. In
addition, the rule revises certain controlled business disclosure
requirements. Further, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> statements of policy accompany the
final rule, one analyzing payments for computer loan origination
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESPA</ENAMEX> regulations and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> others on issues raised
by comments on the proposed rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by sections 801(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>
either has complied with or is in the process of complying with
applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen T. Desaulniers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-4740</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy England-Joseph</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Community Development</ENAMEX>
Issues. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7631</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson A. Diaz</ENAMEX>, Esq. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel Department of Housing</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Development</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-22</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ENTITLED <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"AMENDMENTS TO REGULATION X</ENAMEX>, THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REAL ESTATE SETTLEMENT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">PROCEDURES ACT</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WITHDRAWAL OF EMPLOYER/EMPLOYEE AND COMPUTER LOAN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORIGINATION SYSTEMS EXEMPTIONS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">FR-3638</ENAMEX>); AND POLICY STATEMENTS
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-1</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REGARDING COMPUTER LOAN ORIGINATION SYSTEMS</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-2</TIMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REGARDING SHAM CONTROLLED BUSINESS ARRANGEMENTS</ENAMEX>); AND <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-3</TIMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RENTAL OF OFFICE SPACE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LOCK-OUTS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AND RETALIATION</ENAMEX>)" (RIN:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2502-AG26</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
As discussed below, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Housing and Urban</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>) submitted the proposed Amendments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation X</ENAMEX>
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) for review as a
"significant regulatory action" under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12866</ENAMEX>. Since
the rule was determined to be potentially "economically
significant,"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> prepared an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Analysis</ENAMEX>, which was also
reviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic</ENAMEX>
Analysis was submitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> made changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> to
maintain its consistency with the rule, to which minor changes had
been made as described below. These changes were also submitted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for approval.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Analysis</ENAMEX> indicates that it is difficult to quantify
the costs and benefits of the exemptions for certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer/employee</ENAMEX> payments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> also states that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> lacks
"essential information" to estimate the economic consequences of
its action with respect to computer loan origination systems
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLOs</ENAMEX>). However, in both areas, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> includes a discussion
of cost- and benefit-related issues and the possible effects of the
changes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regulation X.</ENAMEX>
With respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s Statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLOs</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that the guidance provided should enable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLOs</ENAMEX> to develop
with much greater certainty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about RESPA</NUMEX> consequences and with few
restrictions on reasonable pricing and compensation. It also states
that these actions should lead to faster development of
1In response to our inquiry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> advised that the rule
could be "economically significant," and "major," because it could
adversely affect competition. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> also informed us that generally
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulation X</ENAMEX> matters had been designated "major rules" under
Executive Order 12291.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-22</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLOs</ENAMEX>, which should ultimately lead to greater consumer and
producer surplus. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> summarizes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other Statements
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy</ENAMEX> issued with the final rule.
In its submission, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> states that its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> "reflects [its]
assessment that


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
changes in the rule's treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>/employee
payments are desirable to prevent any abuse of the relationship of
trust between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of settlement services; and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the elimination of the exemption for payments by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> to
CLOs enhance[s] the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLOs</ENAMEX>."


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


In the preambles to the proposed and final rules, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> states
without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">elaboration2</ENAMEX> that "by approving [the rule the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>]
certifies that [it] does not have a significant economic impact on
a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, other than those impacts
specifically required to be applied universally by the RESPA
statute."<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37373</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29251</NUMEX>. Accordingly,
under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 605</NUMEX>(b), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> did not prepare initial or final
regulatory flexibility analyses. Sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX> of title 5
were also inapplicable.
In the discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>, the
preamble to the final rule states that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Analysis</ENAMEX>
considers the impact of the rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>. In
connection with the employer/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> payments exemption, the
Analysis indicates only that large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are likely to find the
practice of dedicating an individual to marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX>'
products more attractive than small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. In connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLOs</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> identifies potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of small real estate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX>, but also sets forth potential advantages of CLOs
to those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 605</ENAMEX>(b) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that the certification and explanatory
statement shall be provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocacy of</ENAMEX>
inquiry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> explained that its procedures do not include
providing a separate copy of the certification to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> and that it
did not do so in this instance. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> has confirmed that
some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> follow this practice, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> has not objected
to it.
2Section 605(b) provides that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> makes a
certification under that section, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> shall publish such
certification in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> along with a succinct
statement explaining the reasons for such certification.
3HUD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> explained that the exemptions at issue here would not
have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>, to the extent that such an impact could be
determined.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-22</NUMEX>
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
In its submission, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> explains that the final rule is not
likely to result in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> expenditures of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more by
State, local, or tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> in the aggregate, or by the
private sector. Therefore, sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202 and 205</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unfunded</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Mandates Reform Act of 1994</ENAMEX> are inapplicable.
In addition, the final rule does not affect small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> or
contain a significant intergovernmental mandate. Accordingly,
sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">203 and 204</NUMEX> of the act, which require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to consult
with small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and solicit input from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, local, and
tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, are also inapplicable.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> promulgated the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendments to Regulation X</ENAMEX> under the notice
and comment procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> 553.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> determined that a review of certain policies
embodied in the controversial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> rule would be useful prior to
promulgation of a proposed rule. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29239</NUMEX>. Therefore,
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6, 1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> published a "notice of written comment period
and informal public hearing." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36176</NUMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 6</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> conducted a public hearing, which produced testimony and
documents from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>; in addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> received
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,526</NUMEX> comments on the matters at issue. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29240</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> published a proposed rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 21, 1994</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37360</NUMEX>. In the preamble to the proposed rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> discussed the
comments received in response to its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6, 1993</TIMEX> solicitation and
invited further comments. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37360</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">37362-73</ENAMEX>. In
addition, following promulgation of the proposed rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>
conducted an open house for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLOs</ENAMEX>. The open house was
designed to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> to demonstrate their systems to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> and
to the public. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29240</NUMEX>. Further, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> convened <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> working <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> meetings of
interested industry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to obtain
their input and to further explore the status of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLOs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>.
According to the preamble to the final rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">354</NUMEX>
comments on the proposed rule. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29241</NUMEX>. Throughout the
preamble to the final rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">discusses</ENAMEX> and responds to issues
raised during the comment period, as well as the information
gathered during the open house and subsequent working group
sessions. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29241-51</NUMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-22</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule continues a requirement that, in controlled
business situations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> making referrals of settlement services
make certain disclosures to those being referred. Under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, these disclosure requirements are to be
submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for approval. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> had believed that the
controlled business disclosure requirements were included in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESPA</ENAMEX> information collection submission last approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6, 1994</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2502-0265</TIMEX>). The final rule did not substantially modify
the requirements for the controlled business disclosure and,
therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> did not submit the disclosure requirements to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> in
connection with this rulemaking.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> has discovered that the controlled business disclosures,
which are mandated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 8</ENAMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESPA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2607</TIMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)(A), were omitted from the RESPA submission approved by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> has begun to take the steps necessary to rectify
this problem, including preparation and publication of a correction
to the final rule and proper submission of the controlled business
disclosure requirements for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> review and public comment.
Statutory authorization for the rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> promulgated these amendments to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulation X</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accompanying Statements</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy</ENAMEX> under the authority in section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESPA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2617</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 8</ENAMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESPA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2607</TIMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>), permits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> to exempt "other payments or classes of
payments" from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESPA</ENAMEX>'s prohibition on compensated referrals, after
consulting with specified Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 19</ENAMEX>(a), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2617</TIMEX>(a), authorizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> to grant "reasonable exemptions
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of transactions, as may be necessary to achieve the
purposes of [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESPA</ENAMEX>]." The preamble to the final rule states that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> consulted with other Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, as required by section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29245</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Environmental Policy</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>
The preambles to both the proposed and final rules reflect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s
finding that the rule will not have a significant impact on the
environment. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37373</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29251</NUMEX>.
Accordingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> did not prepare an environmental impact statement
in connection with this rule.
Executive Order 12866
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> reviewed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendments to Regulation X</ENAMEX> and accompanying
Statements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12866</ENAMEX> as a "significant
regulatory action." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> advised that, after submission to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> made technical, editorial, and clarifying changes to the
rule, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> also approved.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-22</NUMEX>
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive</ENAMEX> Orders
In response to our inquiry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> advised that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> reviewed
the rule under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12988</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Justice Reform</ENAMEX>). We
note that the final rule does clearly specify its affects on
existing regulations. In addition, the preambles to the proposed
and final rules address Executive Orders <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12612</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism</ENAMEX>) and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12606</NUMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Family</ENAMEX>). With respect to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federalism Order</ENAMEX>, they
state that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> has determined that the policies contained in the
rule will not have substantial direct effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX> or their
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subdivisions</ENAMEX>, or the relationship between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
government and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX>, or on the distribution of power and
responsibilities among the various levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. As a
result, the rule is not subject to review under that Order. With
respect to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Order</ENAMEX>, the preambles similarly state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s
determination that the rule does not have the potential for a
significant impact on family formation, maintenance, and general
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">well-being</ENAMEX>, and, thus, is not subject to review under the Order. 59
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37373</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29251</NUMEX>. Further, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
Orders on property rights (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">12630</ENAMEX>), intergovernmental partnership
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">12875</ENAMEX>), and environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">12948</ENAMEX>) are similarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inapplicable</ENAMEX>.
In its submission, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statute or
executive order imposing procedural requirements relevant to the
rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-22</NUMEX>



