



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-274142
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 29, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Larry Pressler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Ernest F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX>: Access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecommunications Equipment</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Services by Persons With</ENAMEX>
Disabilities
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>, entitled "Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecommunications</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equipment and Services</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Persons With Disabilities</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-285</NUMEX>).
We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 14, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42181</NUMEX>.
In adopting this Report and Order, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> amends its
rules to require that, either at specific dates in the future or on
a phased-in basis, all telephones in workplaces, confined settings
(such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> be
hearing aid compatible; have volume control; and have the letters
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">HAC</ENAMEX>" affixed to them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order also requires that, as
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">importers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> include volume
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> in all new phones for use in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The
Commission believed these actions were needed to provide greater
access to telephones by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> with hearing disabilities, as
required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hearing Aid Compatibility Act of 1988</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">610</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-36</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications</ENAMEX>
Commission's compliance with the procedural steps required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sections 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to this Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order. Our
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen E. Wannisky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-5207</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2834</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew S. Fishel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-36</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TELECOMMUNICATIONS EQUIPMENT AND SERVICES</ENAMEX> BY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PERSONS WITH</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DISABILITIES</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-285</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BACKGROUND OF REPORT AND ORDER</ENAMEX>
rules to implement the requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearing Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Compatibility Act of 1988</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">610</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, reacting to
petitions filed by establishments affected by the rules, the
Commission suspended portions of the rules stating that these
establishments were experiencing serious difficulties in their
attempts to comply with the rules. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> Rcd <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4958</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26692</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> announced the formation of the
Hearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Compatibility Negotiated Rulemaking Committee</ENAMEX>, an
advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that would consider whether the rule suspension
should be lifted and whether new rules should be proposed. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60343</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1539</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27945</NUMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> included telephone equipment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>
with disabilities, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>'s Final
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>, adopted by unanimous consent, was filed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1995</TIMEX>.
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 610</ENAMEX>(e) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hearing Aid Compatibility Act of 1988</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">610</ENAMEX>, requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to consider the costs and
benefits of proposed rules to all telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> with and without hearing disabilities. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of
Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking the Commission</ENAMEX> solicited comments on the costs
to establishments of providing volume control and hearing aid
compatibility. After reviewing the comments, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
concluded that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$.50 to $1.00</NUMEX> per unit increase in manufacturing
costs does not impose a significant additional cost to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>,
especially considering the lengthy phase-in period for the
requirements. It also concluded that any costs are significantly
outweighed by the benefits to be achieved.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-36</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> initiated this proceeding with a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of
Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> Rcd <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4338</TIMEX>) that reflected the
recommendations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hearing Aid Compatibility Negotiated</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking Committee</ENAMEX>. That notice was summarized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63667</NUMEX>). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
published an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> and invited
written public comments on the proposed rulemaking, including
comments on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis.</ENAMEX>
The analysis included in the proposed rulemaking provides the
information required by sections 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), describing the
reasons for the proposed action and its objectives and legal basis.
The information required by sections 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) concerning
the estimate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> subject to the Report
and Order and the projected reporting, recordkeeping and other
compliance requirements of the proposed rulemaking is also
included.
In the analysis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> stated its belief that the
proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order does not duplicate, overlap, or conflict
with any other relevant federal rules in accordance with the
provisions of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> did not discuss any
significant alternatives minimizing the impact on small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
includes the full text of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42181</NUMEX>. That analysis includes
information required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 604</ENAMEX>, including a description of the
need for and purpose of this Report and Order.
Although no comments were submitted in direct response to the
Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> noted that
a number of the general comments on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of Proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking</ENAMEX> raised issues that could affect small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. In
response to comments, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> extended the compliance
deadline for volume control from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 year to 2 years</TIMEX> and for HAC
labelling of telephones by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 months</TIMEX>.
The analysis describes and estimates the number of small
entities affected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order, addressing separately
workplaces, confined settings such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">importers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-36</NUMEX>
of telephones for use in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The analysis also
discusses the projected reporting, recordkeeping and other
compliance requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order.
Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> considered two significant alternatives
that could minimize the impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) not
including within the purview of "telephones provided for emergency
use" those telephones in workplace noncommon areas, in confined
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">settings</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) not requiring volume
controls on the covered telephones. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> stated that it
rejected both alternatives because both seriously decreased the
ability of hearing- impaired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to gain access to phones
in emergency situations.
Commission <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> confirmed that copies of both the Initial
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Regulatory Flexibility Analyses</ENAMEX> were submitted to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 609</ENAMEX>: Participation by small entities
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order, in large part, adopts the unanimous
recommendations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hearing Aid Compatibility Negotiated</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking Committee</ENAMEX>, an advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> established by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. According to the
Commission, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>'s membership included small businesses
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> representing both large and small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> as
well as a telecommunication <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> representing end-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>,
some of whom are small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is not
subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> promulgated this rule under the notice and
comment procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of Proposed
Rulemaking was released on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 28, 1995</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> Rcd <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4338</TIMEX>). A
summary of the notice was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63667</NUMEX>). In response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> filed
comments, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> filed informal comment letters, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> parties
filed reply comments. Appendix A to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order lists the
parties filing comments and reply comments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order
provides a discussion of these comments and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> reaction to
them.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-36</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> solicited public comment on
specific aspects of the collections and was submitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for
review pursuant to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3507</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> assigned control
number <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3060-0687</TIMEX> to the collection and approved several of the
proposals while filing comment on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the proposed
requirements.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> discussed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> requirements
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995</ENAMEX>. First, the item
proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">importers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> of new telephones for use
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> be required to stamp the date of manufacture
on new telephones. Under current rules, the date of manufacture is
optional. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> stated that a date stamp on a telephone
would indicate to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> that a telephone is hearing aid compatible
if it were imported or manufactured after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 16, 1989</TIMEX>, when all
new telephones were required to be hearing aid compatible. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
until the rules for all workplace telephones go into effect, the
Commission proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> designate certain hearing aid
compatible telephones for emergency use. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
proposed to amend a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> rule regarding packaging to clarify
that the type of hearing aid compatibility referred to is
electro-magnetic coil compatibility.
As a result of comments from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> representing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> with
hearing disabilities and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX>, the
Commission modified its date stamp proposal in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and
Order. Instead of requiring a date stamp, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order
required that new telephones be stamped with the letters "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAC</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commenters</ENAMEX> stated that a date stamp would be meaningless to many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">installers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, but that a letter stamp would be much more
informative. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> also changed the effective date of the
letter stamping requirement from the effective date of the Report
and Order to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1, 1997</TIMEX>, to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">importers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>
time to make equipment changes.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> also confirmed, in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order, its
proposal to require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to designate emergency use telephones
until the new hearing aid compatibility rules are implemented. The
Commission rejected suggestions to issue specific signage
requirements, saying that the requirement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> designate
the telephones was sufficient. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> also amended its rule
regarding packaging to clarify the type of hearing aid
compatibility to which the rule refers.
The final requirements were submitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23, 1996</TIMEX>,
pursuant to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3507</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) for approval. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order is
effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 23, 1996</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 days</TIMEX> after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 14, 1996</TIMEX>,
publication of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-36</NUMEX>
Statutory authorization for the rule
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has promulgated this rule pursuant to provisions
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hearing Aid Compatibility Act of 1988</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 610</NUMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statutes or executive
orders imposing requirements relevant to this Report and Order.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-36</NUMEX>



