



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">274636</NUMEX>; B-274637
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 23, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Richard G. Lugar Chairman The Honorable Patrick J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leahy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nutrition</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forestry United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Pat Roberts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable E</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kika</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Agriculture House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Crop Insurance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catastrophic Risk Protection Endorsement</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrative Regulations</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Crop Insurance Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulations for Implementation</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major rules promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Crop Insurance Corporation</ENAMEX>, entitled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Catastrophic Risk Protection Endorsement</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrative Regulations</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Crop Insurance Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Regulations for Implementation"</ENAMEX> (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0563-AB11</ENAMEX>). We received
the rules on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 12, 1996</TIMEX>. They were published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> as final rules on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 20, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42979</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42970</NUMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> listed rule provides for a catastrophic risk
protection plan of crop insurance and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> rule provides
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">noninsured</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policyholders</ENAMEX>, and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> the
regulations applicable to the catastrophic risk protection program.
This new catastrophic risk protection level of insurance was
mandated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Crop Insurance Reform Act of 1994</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">103-354</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-47</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Crop Insurance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the procedural steps required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sections 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to
the rules. Our review indicates that the Corporation complied with
the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James W. Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Crop Insurance Corporation</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Agriculture Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>
can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-5138</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Ackerman</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Crop Insurance</ENAMEX>
Corporation
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-47</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TWO</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAJOR</ENAMEX>
RULES ISSUED BY THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE, FEDERAL CROP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INSURANCE CORPORATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CATASTROPHIC RISK PROTECTION</ENAMEX>
ENDORSEMENT" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0563-AB09</ENAMEX>) AND "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GENERAL ADMINISTRATIVE</ENAMEX>
REGULATIONS; FEDERAL <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CROP INSURANCE REFORM ACT OF 1994</ENAMEX>, REGULATIONS
FOR IMPLEMENTATION" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0563-AB11</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Crop Insurance Corporation</ENAMEX> (FCIC) prepared a
cost-benefit analysis in connection with the final rules. The costs
and benefits discussed in the analysis consider both rules.
The analysis estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX> in savings associated with
requiring a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> to obtain at least catastrophic coverage for
any crop of economic significance as a condition of receiving
benefits for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> under certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>
programs (linkage requirement) or signing a waiver for eligibility
for emergency crop loss assistance. A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> cost resulting
from the loss of revenue is estimated from the tobacco marketing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> and the undivided interest language which allows a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX>
to obtain catastrophic coverage to satisfy the linkage requirement
for all other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landowners</ENAMEX> who hold an undivided interest in given
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insurable</ENAMEX> acreage. Therefore, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> savings is
estimated to result from the rules.
In addition, the rule is expected to result in less volatility
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>' incomes and less risk of no income due to adverse
weather events and rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> will benefit
from the certainty of payments in times of catastrophic yield
losses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> benefits from a single disaster protection
program, as opposed to the previous ad hoc disaster programs, and
reduced Federal outlays.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCIC</ENAMEX> certified in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preambles</ENAMEX> to both the interim rules (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000 and 1996</TIMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 6, 1995</TIMEX>)) and the final rules (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42980</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42970</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 20, 1996</TIMEX>)) that the rules would not have a
significant impact on a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
Therefore, there was no requirement to prepare an initial or final
regulatory flexibility analysis under sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">604</NUMEX> of the
Act. For the same reason, sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inapplicable</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-47</NUMEX>
However, the preambles to the final rules do discuss additional
flexibility and cost savings for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in several areas.
First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> are no longer required to obtain at least
catastrophic coverage for economically significant crops but may
sign a waiver foregoing emergency crop loss assistance. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> with a share in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> are allowed to be under
one marketing card to insure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> under one insurance policy.
Finally, with certain restrictions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who hold an undivided
interest in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> may be eligible to purchase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> insurance policy
covering all shares to satisfy linkage requirements, thereby not
having to pay the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> processing fee in these situations.
According to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCIC</ENAMEX>, publication of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">certifications</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> was treated as providing
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>'s
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocacy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> has confirmed that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> follow this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> without objection from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
In the preambles to the final rules, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCIC</ENAMEX> explains that the
rules do not contain a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> mandate under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title 2 of the Act</ENAMEX> for
State, local or tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> or the private sector and
therefore, sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202 and 205</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> are inapplicable.
In addition, the final rules do not affect small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> or
contain a significant intergovernmental mandate. Accordingly,
sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">203 and 204</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, which require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to consult
with small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and solicit input from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, local, and
tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, are also inapplicable.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rules were promulgated through the notice and comment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> procedures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. Because the
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Crop Insurance Reform Act of 1994</ENAMEX> required that the
statutory changes be implemented by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 crop year</TIMEX> and many of
the changes were mandated by the statute, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCIC</ENAMEX> invoked the
exception to the notice and comment requirements contained in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 553</NUMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>) that it would be impractical and contrary to the
public interest to publish the rules prior to making the rules
effective. Therefore, the rules were published as interim rules
rather than as proposed rules.
However, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 day</TIMEX> period was afforded for comments to be
submitted on the interim rules, which period was reopened on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 1995</TIMEX> and extended to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 18, 1995</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> comments were
received and considered prior to the issuance of the final rules.
Each of the comments and the response and changes
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-47</NUMEX>
made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCIC</ENAMEX> based on such comments are discussed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preambles</ENAMEX> to the final rules.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The information collections contained in the rules, which
include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crop Insurance Application and Crop Insurance Acreage</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>, were submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>)
for approval as required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. The submittal, which was made
available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, contained the reasons for collecting the
information and the burden estimates, as required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22, 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approved the information collection and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assigned OMB Control</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0563</NUMEX>-003.
Statutory authorization for the rules
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> is authorized under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1506</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">l</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX>)
to issue regulations to carry out the function of providing crop
insurance. These rules implement <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 106 of the Federal Crop</ENAMEX>
Insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reform Act of 1994</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 103-354</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 193</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 104-127</ENAMEX>) requiring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCIC</ENAMEX> to offer catastrophic risk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
The rules were determined to be "economically significant" under
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order 12866</ENAMEX> requiring review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Regulatory Affairs</ENAMEX> (OIRA). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX> approved the
final rules as complying with the requirements of the Order based
on the information supplied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCIC</ENAMEX>, including a planned regulatory
action document describing the reasons for the rules and an
assessment of the costs and budgetary impact of the rules.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive</ENAMEX> Orders and Statutes
The preambles to the final rules state that the rules have been
reviewed under Executive Orders Nos. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12372</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intergovernmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cooperation</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12612</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism</ENAMEX>) and found not subject to those
Orders.
Also, according to the preambles, the final rules were reviewed
pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12778</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Justice Reform</ENAMEX>).
However, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order</ENAMEX> has been replaced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order</ENAMEX>
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12988</NUMEX>, effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5, 1996</TIMEX>. The prior Executive Order
contained a similar requirement now found at <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 3</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of
the newly effective Order requiring that the preemptive effects of
the rule be specified. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCIC</ENAMEX> has been determined that the provisions
of the rules that preempt
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-47</NUMEX>
State and local laws to the extent such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and local laws are
inconsistent with the rules meet those standards.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-47</NUMEX>



