



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271810.8</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 6, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Alan K. Simpson Chairman The Honorable John D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Veterans</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Bob Stump Chairman The Honorable G.V. Montgomery</ENAMEX>
Ranking Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Veterans' Affairs House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Compensation for Disability Resulting</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hospitalization</ENAMEX>, Treatment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examination</ENAMEX>, or Vocational
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rehabilitation</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Compensation for Disability</ENAMEX>
Resulting from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hospitalization</ENAMEX>, Treatment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examination</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vocational Rehabilitation</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2900-AH44</TIMEX>). We received the rule
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a
final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25787</NUMEX>.
This rule adopts, with minor, nonsubstantive changes, an interim
rule amending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> adjudication regulations concerning compensation
for disability or death resulting from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> hospitalization, medical
or surgical treatment, or examination. Before the interim rule,
establishing entitlement to compensation for adverse results of
medical or surgical treatment required that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> be at fault or that
an accident occur. The interim rule, to conform the regulations to
a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.Ct</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">552</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>)), deleted the fault-or-accident requirement
and instead provided that compensation is payable for all but those
injuries that are the certain, or very nearly certain, result of
properly administered medical treatment to which a veteran
consented. (For example, if a veteran had
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1024627</NUMEX>
consented to the amputation of a gangrenous leg, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> would not
compensate him for the loss of a limb.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen E. Wannisky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8326</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David P. Baine</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Delivery and Quality Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baine</ENAMEX> can be
reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7101</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas O. Gessel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Regulations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Department of Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1024627</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ISSUED BY THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "COMPENSATION
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FOR DISABILITY RESULTING FROM HOSPITALIZATION</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TREATMENT</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EXAMINATION, OR VOCATIONAL REHABILITATION</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2900-AH44</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
As part of its implementation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12866</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>) prepared a cost and budgetary
analysis. The estimated cost to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> (and benefit to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans disabled</ENAMEX> as a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> hospitalization, medical or
surgical treatment) is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$166.5 million</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1996</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$244.7 million</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1997</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$327 million</NUMEX> during fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 1998</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$413.6 million</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$504.3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>. The estimated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year</TIMEX> benefit cost
is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,656,100,000</NUMEX>. A copy of that analysis was provided to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> when the final rule was submitted
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 1996</TIMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> certified in the
preamble to the interim rule (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14222, 14223</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 16</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>)) that the rule would not have a significant economic impact
on a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> as they are defined in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>. Therefore, it was not required to
prepare an initial or final regulatory flexibility analysis under
sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603 and 604</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. For the same reason, sections 607
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX> are inapplicable.
According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) certification
was not provided separately to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocacy</ENAMEX>. Rather, in accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>'s
practice, publication of the certification in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
was treated as providing notice to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> has
confirmed that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> follow this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> without objection
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, this rulemaking action does not impose unfunded
mandates under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1024627</NUMEX>
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 553</NUMEX>(b)(A), does not require
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to give general notice of a proposed rulemaking when
issuing an interpretive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rule1</ENAMEX> such as this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> promulgated this
rule through the general notice of proposed rulemaking procedures
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> afforded interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> the
opportunity to comment on the interim rule. The preamble to the
final rule evaluated and responded to the comments received.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
This rule contains no information collection requirements
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1151</TIMEX> provides for the payment of disability or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dependency</ENAMEX> and indemnity compensation for additional disability or
death resulting from an injury or aggravation of an injury suffered
as the result of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> hospitalization, medical or surgical treatment,
examination, or pursuit of a course of vocational rehabilitation
under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ch. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
Based on its economic impact, the rule was determined by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> to be a "significant regulatory
action" within the meaning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>
planned regulatory action document that described the reason for
the amendment to existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> regulations and also assessed the
costs and budgetary impact of the rule. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information and Regulatory Affairs</ENAMEX> reviewed the rule at the
final stage and suggested no changes.
Executive Order No. 12899
According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, relevant portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order</ENAMEX>
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12899</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Justice Reform</ENAMEX>, were considered in issuing this
final rule. Our review of both the interim and final rules and
accompanying documentation suggests that appropriate consideration
was given to this Executive Order.
1This rule amends <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>'s regulations regarding the award of
compensation for disability resulting from hospitalization,
treatment, examination, or vocational rehabilitation to reflect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1151</TIMEX> as stated in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.Ct</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">552</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 1024627</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 3</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>) requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to make every reasonable
effort to ensure that the regulation specifies in clear language
the effect on existing <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal</ENAMEX> law or regulation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> clearly
indicated in both the interim rule and the final rule the
amendments to the previous adjudication regulations necessitated by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.Ct</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">552</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 3</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(C) requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to provide a clear legal
standard rather than a general standard. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> adopted the standard
for determining a veteran's right to compensation contained in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.Ct</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">555</NUMEX>, and incorporated it into the final rule in
what appears to be a clear and unambiguous manner.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 3</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>) requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to specify in clear
language the retroactive effect, if any, given to the regulation.
In the preamble to the interim rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> clearly states that the
effective date of the rule is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 25, 1991</TIMEX>, the date of the
Court of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Appeals</ENAMEX> decision that invalidated the former
regulations. In the preamble to the final rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> responded to
comments submitted on the interim rule, including comments
concerning the effective date. After discussing the comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>
again stated that the effective date of the rule would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 1991</TIMEX>.
Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 3</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>) requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to define key
terms in their regulations. The regulation includes a definition of
the term "necessary consequences," a key element to be considered
in determining a veteran's eligibility for compensation under this
rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statute or executive order
imposing procedural requirements relevant to the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1024627</NUMEX>



