



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">272425.1</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John H. Chafee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Max Baucus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation of Fuels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fuel Additives</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Certification</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards for Deposit Control Gasoline Additives</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation of Fuels</ENAMEX> and Fuel
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Additives</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Certification Standards for Deposit Control Gasoline</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Additives"</ENAMEX> (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2060-AG06</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">FRL# 5528-5</ENAMEX>). We received the rule on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35309</NUMEX>.
This rule establishes a certification program for detergent
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additives</ENAMEX> used to control the formation of deposits in gasoline
engines. This certification program requires the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergents</ENAMEX>
in most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasolines</ENAMEX> used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as mandated by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990</ENAMEX> and replaces an interim program
which began on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 1995</TIMEX>. The final rule contains
standardized test procedures and performance standards to ensure
that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent gasolines</ENAMEX> provide an effective level of protection
against certain engine deposits.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the procedural steps required by sections
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) of title 5
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-27</NUMEX>
with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable
requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guerrero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerrero</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6111</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas E. Kelly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Regulatory Management</ENAMEX>
OF <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FUELS</ENAMEX> AND <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FUEL ADDITIVES</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CERTIFICATION STANDARDS FOR DEPOSIT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONTROL GASOLINE ADDITIVES</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2060-AG06</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">FRL# 5528-5</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
determined that this final rule was a "significant regulatory
action" based on an annual economic impact of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more
under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12866</ENAMEX> and submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
Management and Budget the required regulatory impact analysis which
contains an analysis of the costs and benefits of the rule.
The total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> costs estimated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> including the costs of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">certification</ENAMEX>, addization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergents</ENAMEX>, recordkeeping and
enforcement through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $704 million</NUMEX>. The cost
to the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>, if all the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX> is passed
along to the consumer anew, even by those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> who already
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> fully additized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>, would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.00</NUMEX> per year.
The benefits to be gained in air quality were calculated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first six years</TIMEX> (including the interim program) to be
reductions of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">125,000 tons</NUMEX> of hydrocarbons, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,388,000 tons</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon monoxide</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">450,000 tons</NUMEX> of nitrogen oxide. Increased fuel
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> achieved by a reduction of engine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">deposits</ENAMEX> is estimated to
be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $295 million</NUMEX> for the same time period. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
anticipates there will also be vehicle maintenance benefits,
sufficient data was not available to quantify the benefits.
This analysis was revised when it was determined that the
interim program, which began on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 1995</TIMEX>, would last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> rather than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX> and there were changes in the
estimated cost of deposit control testing and the addition, in the
final rule, of a required deposit demonstration test to qualify
test <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> for certification testing purposes.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
The impact of this rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> was considered in a
regulatory flexibility analysis under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603</ENAMEX> that was
summarized in the preamble of the interim program (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54705</NUMEX>) and the entire analysis, which was included in the
regulatory impact analysis, was available for review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s
public docket. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-27</NUMEX>
preamble to the final rule addresses changes made to the
regulatory impact analysis, as discussed under the cost-benefit
analysis section above, and the impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
Following this analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has concluded and certified that
the rule will not have a significant economic impact on a
substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. The analysis states that the
industry affected by the rule includes numerous business entities
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> production and the business size
considered to be a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> varies from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIC Codes</ENAMEX> and size standards of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business</ENAMEX>
Administration. Therefore, the impact of the rule varies based on
the type of business and its place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of production and
distribution. However, the overall impact is expected to be modest,
even for those industries most heavily impacted, and for small
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additive</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additive</ENAMEX> injection equipment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, the rule
could result in additional economic opportunities through increased
sales. The analysis also discusses alternative approaches which
were considered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> but were found lacking because they did not
either significantly reduce the burden on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> or would
have jeopardized the program's projected air quality benefits.
According to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, publication of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">certifications</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> in connection with the
interim program and the final rule was treated as providing notice
under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocacy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> has confirmed that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> follow this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> without objection from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, the final rule will not impose any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mandates</ENAMEX>, as defined in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title II of the Act</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, local or
tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> nor any enforceable duties on those governmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>. Therefore, sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">203 and 204</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> are not
applicable.
However, the rule does contain Federal mandates that will result
in the expenditure of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any one year</TIMEX> for the
private sector. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, in the preamble to the final rule, states
that the certification program represents the least costly, most
cost-effective approach to achieving the air quality goals by
relying on the cost-benefit analysis performed in connection with
Executive Order No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>, as permitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 202</ENAMEX> (b) and (c)
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35355</NUMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-27</NUMEX>
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule complied with the notice and comment rulemaking
procedures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> action which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has undertaken to implement the
requirement contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 211</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">l</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>
Amendments of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6, 1993</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> was
published. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64213</NUMEX>. Subsequently, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 14, 1994</TIMEX>,
the rule for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interim Detergent Program</ENAMEX> was published. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54678</NUMEX>. In order to obtain more comments regarding the possible
requirement for control of combustion chamber deposits in the final
rule and to seek more public input in other areas involving the
certification testing and various implementation and enforcement
provisions, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Reopening of the Comment Period</ENAMEX> was
published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 28, 1994</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> written comments and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> oral presentations
were made at a public hearing held by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s response to
the comments received are summarized in the preamble to the final
rule and a detailed presentation and evaluation of the comments
received are contained in a separate "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis of</ENAMEX>
Comments." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Docket Item V-B-02</ENAMEX>. Comments regarding enforcement
issues and questions raised by the regulated industry were
addressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detergent Rule Question</ENAMEX> and Answer
Documents." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Docket Nos. IV-C-08</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV-C-09</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV-C-10</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV-C-11</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule contains information collection requirements which will
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to determine that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent additives</ENAMEX> which are effective
in controlling deposits are used and that emission control goals
are realized. The information to be submitted is of various types
and complexities depending upon the role of the submitter (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additive</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, refiners, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">truckers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>) in the
manufacturing and distribution process. The preamble to the final
rule sets forth the reasons for collecting the information and the
burden estimates for the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has certified under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 3506</ENAMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> and
submitted the information collection requirement to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) for approval as required by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX> and has solicited comments regarding the
proposed collection requirements to be submitted to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>. The collection requirement will not be effective until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>
approval is obtained. Therefore, the information collection
requirements contained in the
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-27</NUMEX>
interim program (already approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) will continue to be
effective until replaced by the requirements contained in the final
rule.
Statutory authorization for the rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 211</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">l</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">101-549</ENAMEX>) provided that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator of EPA</ENAMEX> shall promulgate a
rule establishing specifications for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent additives</ENAMEX> to
implement the requirement, also contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 211</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">l</ENAMEX>), that,
effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 1995</TIMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> may be sold or dispensed
which does not contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additives</ENAMEX> to prevent the accumulation of
deposits in engines or fuel systems.
Executive Order No. 12866
Based on its economic impact, the rule was determined to be a
"significant regulatory action" within the meaning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
Order No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>. Consistent with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX> order, the rule was
initiated through an advance notice of proposed rulemaking and a
regulatory impact analysis was included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interim Program</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>. The analysis was forwarded to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Affairs</ENAMEX> (OIRA) for its consideration and comments as
contemplated by the Order. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX> suggested no changes in the rule
but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> supply more elaboration in the preamble to the
final rule concerning the deposit control test standards and the
retention of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> flow loss performance standard rather than
the industry supported <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> flow loss.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statutes or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive</ENAMEX> orders
imposing requirements relevant to the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-27</NUMEX>



