



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-274402
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 4, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John H. Chafee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Max Baucus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Regulations for</ENAMEX>
Revisions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Test Procedure</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Emissions</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Motor</ENAMEX>
Vehicles
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Regulations for Revisions to the</ENAMEX>
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Test Procedure</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Emissions</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motor Vehicles</ENAMEX>" (RIN:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2060-AE27</ENAMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 29, 1996</TIMEX>. It was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 22</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54851</NUMEX>.
The final rule revises the tailpipe emission portions of the
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Test Procedure</ENAMEX> for light-duty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and light-duty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>. A new <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental Federal Test Procedure</ENAMEX> has been added to
address areas not represented in the current procedures including
aggressive (high-speed and/or high acceleration) driving behavior,
rapid speed fluctuations, driving behavior following startup and
use of air conditioning. Also included is a new set of requirements
to more accurately reflect real road <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> on the test
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynamometer</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the procedural steps required by sections
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) of title 5
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-42</NUMEX>
with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable
requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guerrero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerrero</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6111</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas E. Kelly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Regulatory Management</ENAMEX>
REGULATIONS FOR REVISIONS TO THE FEDERAL <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TEST PROCEDURE</ENAMEX> FOR
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMISSIONS FROM MOTOR VEHICLES</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2060-AE27</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
and benefit analysis regarding the final rule which is contained in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact Analysis.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> scenarios in arriving at the estimated cost of test
facilities implementing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental Federal Test Procedure</ENAMEX>.
One is the use of air conditioning simulation and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is for
the use of full environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> for air conditioning testing.
The analysis found an annual cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$198.9 million</NUMEX> associated with
the simulation scenario or a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13.26</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. Under the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> environmental cell scenario, the estimated annual cost would
be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$244.5 million</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.30</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. These amounts include the
cost of recalibration, redesign, mechanical integrity testing,
certification durability demonstration, annual certification, test
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> hardware.
The environmental benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> estimates will be a per vehicle
lifetime emission reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4.4 pounds</NUMEX> of nonmethane
hydrocarbons, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">277 pounds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon monoxide</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23.5 pounds</NUMEX> of
oxides of nitrogen.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has determined that the final rule will not have a
significant economic impact on a substantial number of small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobile</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> regulated by the rule do not
qualify as small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> within the meaning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
Flexibility Act. Therefore, neither an initial nor final regulatory
flexibility analysis was performed.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
Based on the cost benefit analysis performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, the rule
will not impose an intergovernmental mandate because there are no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enforceable</ENAMEX> duties on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-42</NUMEX>
or tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. However, the rule will impose a mandate
on the private sector in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> in any one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has prepared both a qualitative and quantitative assessment
of the benefits and costs of the rule in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact</ENAMEX>
Analysis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has considered numerous regulatory alternatives to the final
provisions of the rule, which are discussed in both the preamble to
the final rule and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact Analysis</ENAMEX>, but has
determined that the requirements expressed in the final rule
constitute the most cost-effective and least burdensome alternative
that would meet the mandate of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 206</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air</ENAMEX>
Act.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
Instead of the notice and comment procedures in the
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> promulgated this rule using
the procedures, which have similar notice and comment requirements,
contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 307</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>, as amended. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7607</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)). The use of these procedures regarding rules
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pertaining</ENAMEX> to the promulgation or revision of regulations and test
procedures for new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motor vehicles</ENAMEX> or engines is mandated by section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">307</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> published a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 7</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7404</TIMEX>), and conducted a public hearing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 and 20, 1995</TIMEX> on the proposed rule. The comment period was to
close on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22, 1995</TIMEX>, but was extended until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19, 1995</TIMEX>,
because additional time was necessary to gather and analyze data
relating to the rule.
The preamble also notes (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54853</NUMEX>) that additional
comments, data and analyses were received after the close of the
comment period and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> considered such information in
developing test procedures, cost estimates and lead time. <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">307</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) permits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to put documents in the rulemaking
docket after the comment period is over. This type of addition to
the record after the close of the comment period and the need to
reopen the comment period are discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Costle</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">657 F. 2d 298</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">392</NUMEX>-400 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>)), where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> held such action
was not required because there was adequate time for response. We
have been advised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> that the additional comments and data were
added to the public docket between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1995</TIMEX> and
therefore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 6 months</TIMEX> was available for responses or
objections to be filed.
The preamble to the final rule discusses the comments received
and any action taken as a result of the comments.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule contains information collection requirements which are
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has submitted an
Information <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collection Request</ENAMEX> (ICR) document to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX> for approval.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ICR</ENAMEX> contains the information required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> including
the reasons for the collection of the information, the type of
information and an estimate of the burden imposed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>.
The burden of the requirement (testing, recordkeeping and reporting
requirements) is estimated to average <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">566 hours</TIMEX> annually for a
typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has solicited comments on the proposed information
collection requirements to be sent to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for
consideration during the approval process. The information
collection requirements will not be effective until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approval is
obtained.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has cited sections <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202, 206, 208</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">301</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean</ENAMEX>
Air Act, as amended. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7521, 7525, 7542 and 7601</TIMEX>). In
particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 206</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7525</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>))
requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to review and revise the
regulations regarding the testing of motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and motor
vehicle engines to insure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> are tested under
circumstances which reflect the actual driving conditions under
which motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> are used, including conditions relating to
fuel, temperature, acceleration and altitude.
Executive Order No. 12866
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> reviewed the rule under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX> as a
"significant regulatory action." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Information</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Affairs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approved the final rule as complying with
the requirements of the Order based on the information supplied by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, including a planned regulatory action document describing the
reason for the rule and an assessment of the costs and budgetary
impact of the rule.
In its submission, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statute or
executive order imposing procedural requirements relevant to the
final rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-42</NUMEX>



