



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271810.6</NUMEX>
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Alfonse M. D'Amato Chairman The Honorable Paul S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarbanes Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking, Housing</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Affairs United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities Credit Transactions; Review of Regulation T</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dealers</ENAMEX>"
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve System</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit Transactions; Review of Regulation T</ENAMEX>, 'Credit by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dealers</ENAMEX>'" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7100-AB28</ENAMEX>). Among other things, the rule amends
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation T</ENAMEX> to (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) eliminate restrictions on the ability of
broker-dealers to arrange for credit; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) increase the type and
number of domestic and foreign securities that may be bought on
margin and increase the loan value of some securities that already
are marginable; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) delete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> rules regarding options
transactions in favor of the rules of the options <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>; and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) reduce restrictions on transactions involving foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>,
securities, and currency. We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 9, 1996</TIMEX>. It
was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20386</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-15</NUMEX> If you have any questions about this report,
please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry R. Wray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8581</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve System</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James L. Bothwell</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Financial Institutions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Markets</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bothwell</ENAMEX>
can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8678</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald J. Winn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board Board of Governors</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve System</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-15</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ENTITLED "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SECURITIES CREDIT TRANSACTIONS; REVIEW OF REGULATION T</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'CREDIT</ENAMEX> BY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BROKERS AND DEALERS</ENAMEX>'" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7100-AB28</ENAMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

A cost-benefit analysis was not required or prepared for the
rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> certified in
the preamble to both the proposed rulemaking (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">33763,</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33771</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29, 1995</TIMEX>)) and the final rulemaking (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20386, 20389</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6, 1996</TIMEX>)) that the rule would not have a
substantial effect on a significant number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.1
Therefore, it was not required to prepare an initial or final
regulatory flexibility analysis under sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">604</NUMEX> of the
Act. For the same reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 607</ENAMEX> is inapplicable. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section 609</ENAMEX> likewise is inapplicable, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s submission to our
Office states that, in addition to publishing the proposed rule in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>, it took several steps to give small entities
the opportunity to participate in the rulemaking. Specifically, the
proposal was distributed to interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> by the twelve
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dealers</ENAMEX>.
According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b)
certifications were not provided separately to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business</ENAMEX>
Administration (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocacy</ENAMEX>. Rather, in
accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s practice, publication of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">certifications</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> was treated as providing
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> has confirmed that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
follow this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> without objection from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>.
1The preamble to the final rule actually states that the rule
will not have a substantial "adverse effect" on a significant
number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker-dealers</ENAMEX>. However, we understand from the
preamble to the proposed rule and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s letter to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> intended this statement to constitute a
certification under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) that the rule would not have any
significant economic impact on a substantial number of small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> confirmed our understanding.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-15</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202-205</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The rule, promulgated by an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, is
not subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the Act</ENAMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was promulgated through the notice and comment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> procedures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. The proposed
rulemaking was published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29, 1995</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33763</NUMEX>, and
afforded interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> the opportunity to comment on the
proposed rule. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 23, 1995</TIMEX>, the comment period was extended
at the request of commenters. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43726</NUMEX>. The preamble to
the final rule evaluated and responded to comments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3512</TIMEX>
The rule does not impose information collection requirements
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The rule was authorized by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 7</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities Exchange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1934</ENAMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">78g</ENAMEX>, which directs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>
to prescribe regulations with respect to the amount of credit that
may be extended by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broker-dealer</ENAMEX> on any non-exempted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>.
The preamble to the final rule notes that the rule is
encompassed within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s regulatory review under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 303</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riegle Community Redevelopment and Regulatory Improvement</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1994</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4803</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> did not identify any other
statutes or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive</ENAMEX> orders imposing requirements relevant to the
rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-15</NUMEX>



