



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-274307
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 12, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Larry Pressler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Ernest F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexible Service</ENAMEX>
Offerings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial Mobile Radio Services</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flexible Service Offerings in</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial Mobile Radio Services</ENAMEX>" (WT Docket No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-6</NUMEX>). We
received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 21, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 29, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45336</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications</ENAMEX>
Commission's (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>) compliance with the procedural steps required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sections 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
In its notice of proposed rulemaking, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6189</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 16, 1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> sought comments on proposals for
expanding permitted offerings of fixed wireless services by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial Mobile Radio Service</ENAMEX> (CMRS) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, as well as
comments in connection with the regulatory treatment for such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Summary</ENAMEX> indicates comments received in
response to the proposed rulemaking provided strong support for
allowing the provision of fixed wireless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-40</NUMEX>
services by the licensees operating on the CMRS bands. The final
rule amends the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> rules to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of narrowband and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">broadband CMRS</ENAMEX> services to offer fixed wireless services (excluding
broadcast) on their assigned spectrum on a coprimary basis with
mobile services.
If you have any questions about this report, please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-4586</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8234</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew S. Fishel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX> ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(A)(i)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERVICE OFFERINGS</ENAMEX> IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMMERCIAL MOBILE RADIO SERVICES</ENAMEX>" (WT
Docket No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-6</NUMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> indicated in its submission that it was not
required to prepare a cost-benefit analysis of the rule


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX> Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603 of the Act</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> incorporated
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> (IRFA) in its <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of
Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking</ENAMEX>, and written comments were requested. The
preamble to the rule states that no comments were received
specifically in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRFA</ENAMEX>, but that issues were raised
that might affect small business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. In particular, a small
business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commenter</ENAMEX> argued that the proposed flexibility in the use
of the CMRS bands not be extended to cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> initially
in order to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Communications Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCS</ENAMEX>) licensees an
opportunity to establish themselves. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> also reports
that it forwarded a copy of its initial regulatory flexibility
analysis to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Advocacy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business</ENAMEX>
Administration (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>) as required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX> Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> prepared a Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 604</ENAMEX>. That analysis notes that the rule will
carry out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' intent to establish a consistent regulatory
framework for all commercial mobile radio services and that the
rule will assist in the development of competition between wireless
and wireline services for the benefit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>.
The analysis notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rulemaking</ENAMEX> applies to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of
cellular, narrowband and broadband PCS, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMRS</ENAMEX>, specialized mobile
radio services, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMRS</ENAMEX> paging commercial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">220</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHz</ENAMEX> services, and
for-profit interconnected business radio services.
Each category of services was analyzed separately.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-40</NUMEX>
Cellular. In absence of its own standards, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
defined small business with respect to cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> by
utilizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> definition for radiotelephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, e.g., an
entity employing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 1,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. Because of the absence of
meaningful data concerning the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> which are small,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> used the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census of Transportation</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications and Utilities</ENAMEX> conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of the Census</ENAMEX>
as the most recent information available. That census indicated
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 12</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,178</NUMEX> radiotelephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> or more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. That data does not, however, indicate the number of
cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,178</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. Based on the above, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> concluded that for the purpose of the final regulatory
flexibility analysis, all cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">licensees</ENAMEX> are small businesses
as defined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCS</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> (with the approval of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>) has defined small
business in this category to mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> who have gross
revenues not to exceed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> per year for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the prior 3</TIMEX>
calendar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadband PCS</ENAMEX> licenses were auctioned for Blocks
A,B, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. No</ENAMEX> auction has been held for blocks D, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> asserts that it has insufficient information upon which
to determine whether any small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>-approved
definition were successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX> for blocks A and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> For block C,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> nondefaulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX> are small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.
For blocks D, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> has switched from the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX>
million criteria to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">under 1,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> category. Given that
nearly all radiotelephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 1,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> concludes that all of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,479</NUMEX> licenses for these blocks
will be awarded to small businesses. Because of a similar lack of
meaningful data, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has concluded that all of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
regional licenses for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">narrowband</TIMEX> PCS and all of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> licenses for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">narrowband</ENAMEX> nationwide PCS licenses have been awarded to small
business.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> has created <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tiers of small business for this
service with the approval of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Firms</ENAMEX> with not more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>
million gross revenue for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> preceding calendar
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> are categorized as very small; with not more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX>
for the same period are small. According to the analysis, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHz</ENAMEX> licenses qualify as small entities
(no breakdown of small vs. very small). There has been no auction
for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHz</ENAMEX> licenses.
Interconnected business services. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>, there is
no meaningful data as to the number of for-profit interconnected
business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> (IBS) licensees that are small business, although
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> concludes that all of the current license holders
are small based on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> employee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> criteria. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> notes
that while there are in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,000</NUMEX> for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBS</ENAMEX> licenses, a
single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">licensee</ENAMEX> may hold multiple licenses so that it is not
possible to determine the actual number of individual licensees for
the service.
The analysis concludes that the rules do not impose additional
reporting, record keeping, or other compliance requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 605</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Avoidance</ENAMEX> of duplicative or unnecessary
analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not invoke any of the exemptions or special
procedures authorized by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX> in preparing its regulatory
flexibility analysis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 607</ENAMEX>: Preparation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX>
Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 607</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s submission does not
specifically indicate the potential economic impact on the small
entities affected. However, the regulatory flexibility analysis
indicates that the rule will benefit all CMRS small business
licensees by providing them greater flexibility to determine which
service they will provide to the public.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 609</ENAMEX>: Participation by small entities
Based on the information before us, it appears that there were
no special efforts made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to involve small entities
in the rulemaking process, other than the actions required by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> 553.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is not
subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§ 551 et</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seq</ENAMEX>. The rule was promulgated through the general notice of
proposed rulemaking
procedures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> afforded
interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> the opportunity to comment on the proposed rule,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order addresses these comments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX> The rule does
not contain either a proposed or modified information collection.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The rules are promulgated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> provided in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Act of 1934</ENAMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 154</NUMEX>(i),
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">154</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">j</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">157</NUMEX>(a), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(b), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(f), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(r), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">332</NUMEX>(a), and
(c).
Executive Order No. 12866
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> as defined in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3502</TIMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> is not subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statutes or Executive
Orders imposing requirements relevant to the rule.



