



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-272940
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 8, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Alfonse D'Amato Chairman The Honorable Paul S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarbanes Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking, Housing</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Affairs United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable James A. Leach Chairman The Honorable Henry B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking and Financial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX>: Single
Family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mortgage Insurance; Loss Mitigation Procedures</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Single Family</ENAMEX>
Mortgage Insurance; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loss Mitigation Procedures"</ENAMEX> (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2502-AG72</TIMEX>).
We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 25, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as an interim rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
35,014.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by sections 801(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>
complied with the applicable requirements.
The interim rule eliminates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mortgage Assignment Program</ENAMEX> and
provides alternative procedures to foreclosure for mortgagors in
default such as special forbearance, loan modifications, and deeds
in lieu of foreclosure. The rule provides for recompense to the
mortgagees for using these alternative procedures and provides for
payment to the mortgagee of a partial claim which would be applied
to the arrearage. As a result of these procedures, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>
estimates an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> net savings of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$545 million</NUMEX>. Under the rule,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> may also accept an assignment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-33</NUMEX>
a mortgage which has been recast or modified to cure the
default, but where repooling of the loan is not possible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>
reports that such circumstances should be rare.
If you have any questions about this report, please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-4586</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy England-Joseph</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Community Development</ENAMEX>
Issues. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) 5125167.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson A. Diaz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Housing and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Development</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-33</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A MAJOR</ENAMEX>
RULE
ENTITLED "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SINGLE FAMILY MORTGAGE INSURANCE; LOSS MITIGATION</ENAMEX>
PROCEDURES" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2502-AG72</TIMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agency</ENAMEX> performed an economic analysis dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31, 1996</TIMEX>.
That document analyzes the various loss mitigation procedures
promulgated in the interim rule and concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> will realize
an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> net saving of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$545 million</NUMEX> from implementation of the
interim rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>.


Pursuant to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 605</NUMEX>(b), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> has certified that
the interim rule will not have a significant economic impact on a
substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. Such certification was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35017</NUMEX>. As a
consequence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> was not required to prepare either an initial or a
final regulatory flexibility analysis under sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603 and 604</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, and sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX> are not applicable.
According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b)
statement and certification were not separately provided to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Advocacy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>.
Rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> was treated as
providing notice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> has not objected to this
procedure.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> the rule will not result in expenditures
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any year</TIMEX> by either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Local</ENAMEX> or Tribal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> in the aggregate or by the private sector. In addition,
the rule neither affects small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> nor contains a
significant intergovernmental mandate. Consequently the rule does
not impose unfunded mandates under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-33</NUMEX>
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Omnibus Consolidated Rescissions and Appropriations Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104134</NUMEX> directed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> to issue interim
regulations within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> of the date of enactment. As a
consequence, the notice and comments procedures in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> 553
were impracticable. Nonetheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> specifically
requested comments from interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, which are due by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 3, 1996</TIMEX>. An agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> has advised that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> will
subsequently issue final regulations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> has requested, but has not yet received an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>
approval of the information collection requirements of the rule. In
the preamble to the rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> states that it may not conduct or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is not required to respond to a collection of
information until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> has issued the control number.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The statutory requirement to issue these interim regulations is
contained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Balanced Budget Downpayment Act</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104-99</NUMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 26, 1996</TIMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> reports that the interim rule and the accompanying economic
analysis were reviewed and approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> as required by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.O.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> received the approval from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10, 1996</TIMEX> and no
changes were made.
Executive Order No. 12612
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> states that the interim rule will not have a substantial,
direct effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX> or on the relationship between the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX> or on the distribution of power
or responsibilities among various levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> because the
interim rule primarily involves relationships between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> and
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12606
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> reports that the interim rule will have only an indirect
impact on family formation, maintenance, and general well-being and
that such impact will be beneficial because it will assist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mortgagors</ENAMEX> in maintaining ownership of their properties. In the
preamble, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> states that no further review is necessary.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-33</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Environmental Policy</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>.
A finding of no significant impact on the environment has been
made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> in accordance with its regulations implementing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Environmental Policy</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-33</NUMEX>



