



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-274333
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 12, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Nancy Landon Kassebaum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward M. Kennedy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Labor</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Resources United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cigarettes and Smokeless Tobacco to Protect Children</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Adolescents</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>, entitled
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smokeless Tobacco</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Protect Children and Adolescents"</ENAMEX> (RIN:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0910-AA48</ENAMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 26, 1996</TIMEX>. It was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 28</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44395</NUMEX>.
The rule prohibits the sale of nicotine-containing cigarettes
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smokeless tobacco</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> under the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>; requires
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> to comply with various
conditions regarding the sale and distribution of these products;
requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> to verify a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchaser</ENAMEX>'s age by photographic
identification; prohibits all free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX>; limits the distribution
of these products through vending machines and self-service
displays by permitting such methods of sale only in facilities
where access by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 18</TIMEX> is prohibited; limits the
advertising and labeling to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> are
exposed; prohibits promotional, non-tobacco items such as hats and
tee shirts; prohibits sponsorship of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-38</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sporting</ENAMEX> and other events, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and entries in the brand name
of tobacco products; and requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to provide intended
use information on all cigarette and smokeless tobacco product
labels and in cigarette advertising.
The rule is predicated on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>'s
assertion of jurisdiction under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic</ENAMEX>
Act over cigarettes and smokeless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> as delivery devices for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nicotine</ENAMEX>. The lengthy jurisdictional determination was published in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 28, 1996</TIMEX>, as an annex to the final
rule.
The rule will become effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 year</TIMEX> from the date of
publication in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> except that the prohibition
regarding sale to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> younger than 18 years of age and the
requirement for photographic identification to verify the age of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchasers</ENAMEX> will become effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 months</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. The
restriction on event sponsorship and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>' compliance with
existing device registration and listing requirements and good
manufacturing practice requirements will become effective 2 years
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>'s
compliance with the procedural steps required by sections
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule.
Our review indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> complied with the
applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James W. Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah F.</ENAMEX>
Jaggar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality and Public Health</ENAMEX>
Issues. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaggar</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7119</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Services</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-38</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRUG ADMINISTRATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "REGULATIONS RESTRICTING THE SALE AND
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CHILDREN</ENAMEX> AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADOLESCENTS</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0910-AA48</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
An analysis of the costs and benefits of the rule was conducted
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>) and published in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> of proposed rulemaking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 11, 1995</TIMEX>, and is contained
in the preamble to the final rule. The analysis in the final rule
has been revised based on comments the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> received and now also
considers the costs and benefits associated with a rule issued by
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAMHSA</ENAMEX>) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 19, 1996</TIMEX>, governing a program of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>-operated
enforcement activities to restrict the sale or distribution of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco products</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 18</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> considers
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> rules complementary and cannot separately quantify the
benefits of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs and since both rules work collectively
to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> access to tobacco products, the costs attributable
to the SAMHSA program are included in the analysis.
The analysis based its benefits on achieving the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Healthy People</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> program, goal of reducing underage <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> use
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-half</NUMEX> in order to prevent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 60,000</NUMEX> early deaths. The
analysis places a monetary value of these health benefits (at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
percent discount rate) at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated $28 to $43 billion</NUMEX> per year,
including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.6 billion</NUMEX> in medical cost savings, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900 million</NUMEX> in
productivity gains from reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24.6 to $39.7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">billion</NUMEX> per year in willingness-to-pay values for averting
premature fatalities. The analysis states that if the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>
reduction in underage <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> use is not reached and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5 percent</NUMEX>
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> who become new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> are deterred,
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> benefits would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.8 to $4.3 billion</NUMEX> per year.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> estimates the overall compliance costs of the rule to be
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$174 million to $187 million</NUMEX> in one-time costs and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$149</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$185 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> operating costs. These costs will
be borne by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$78 to $91 million</NUMEX> in one-time costs and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> costs), retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$96 million</NUMEX> in
one-time costs and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$78 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> costs), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 to $5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in enforcement costs per year) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> per year in administering various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAMHSA</ENAMEX> enforcement
programs).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-38</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> recognizes that it could not quantify every regulatory cost
because of significant distributional and transitional effects of
the rule. For example, lost sales experienced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> of
advertising were considered distributional impacts because the
dollars not spent on advertising are not lost to the economy but
will be spent on other goods and services. Also, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and
Federal excise taxes remain at the current levels, tax revenues
will decrease over time because of decreased sales.
In conclusion, the analysis finds that while compliance with the
rule will bring significant health benefits to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and
also exact long-term revenue losses on the tobacco industry and
short-term costs on various affiliated industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX>, the
benefits of the rule will greatly exceed the compliance costs on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> economy.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has concluded that the rule will have a significant
economic impact on a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> and an
initial regulatory flexibility analysis and final regulatory
flexibility analysis have been prepared and included in the notice
of proposed rulemaking and the final rule notice, respectively, as
required by sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603 and 604</NUMEX>. The analyses comply with the
informational requirements of the sections including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> subject to the rule and alternatives considered to
reduce the burden on the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
The final analysis discusses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s decision not to exempt
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> from the rule because an exemption for small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> would shift underage sales to those locations, lessening
or eliminating the effectiveness and benefits of the access
restrictions. However, a total ban on vending machines and direct
mail order sales have been deleted from the final rule because of
their impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
The analyses use both quantifiable and general descriptions of
the effects of the rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> as required by section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607</NUMEX> and numerous small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> participated in the rulemaking as
required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 609</ENAMEX> by submitting comments on the proposed
regulation following the inclusion in the notice of proposed
rulemaking of the initial regulatory flexibility analysis which
discussed the economic impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-38</NUMEX>
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
Based on the cost-benefit analysis performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, the rule
will impose an unfunded mandate on the private sector of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $100</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> and therefore the rule is subject to the
requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
As required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 205</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> considered regulatory
alternatives to the requirements of the rule but determined that
the provisions of the final rule constituted the most
cost-effective and least burdensome alternative that would meet the
objective of the rule.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> rejected the regulatory alternative of a total ban on
all tobacco advertising. Also, a more prescriptive requirement for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to monitor the sales and distribution of retail
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">establishments</ENAMEX> was not imposed because it would have imposed an
additional cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85 million</NUMEX> per year. Finally, a requirement to
include package inserts containing educational information in
cigarette and smokeless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> was not chosen because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> was
not certain the benefits would justify the compliance costs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 204</ENAMEX> requires that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, local and tribal governments
have an opportunity for input and numerous comments were received
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, substance
abuse programs and law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. These comments were
reviewed and considered as discussed in the preamble to the final
rule.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> promulgated the rule under the notice and comment
procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX> and its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> regulation
regarding the promulgation of regulations found at section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.40</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title 21 of the Code</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Regulations</ENAMEX>.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 11, 1995</TIMEX>, the proposed rule was published in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41314</NUMEX>) and in the same issue, a
document entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Analysis Regarding The Food And Drug</ENAMEX>
Administration's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jurisdiction Over Nicotine-Containing Cigarettes</ENAMEX>
And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smokeless Tobacco Products</ENAMEX>" was published and comments were
requested. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41453</NUMEX>. The comment period, following an
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">extension</ENAMEX>, remained open for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">144 days</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months</TIMEX> that followed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of the proposed rule and during the comment period,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> made available to the public over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> pages of
documents which were cited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or considered in the
promulgation of the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-38</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 700,000</NUMEX> comments in response to the
proposed rule. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> reports many of the comments were form
letters, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 95,000</NUMEX> distinct or unique comments filed
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>.
The preamble to the final rule discusses many of the comments
received and the action taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in response or why the
comments did not change the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s position.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The proposed rule contained information collections which would
have required the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> of cigarettes and
smokeless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> to use established names for cigarettes and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">smokeless</ENAMEX> tobacco products, establish and maintain educational
programs, observe certain formats and content requirements for
labeling and advertising and the submission of labels, labeling and
advertising to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> solicited comments on the above
information collections including among other information, the
necessity of the collection, the accuracy of the estimated burden
and ways to enhance the information collection.
Following the receipt and evaluation of the comments, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
has revised certain burden estimates and has deleted the
requirement for the submission of labeling to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> and the
establishment of educational programs.
The information collections in the proposed rule were approved
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> under OMB No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0910-0312</TIMEX>.
Because of the above noted changes to the collections, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has
resubmitted the matter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for review and approval and prior to
the effective date of the rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> will publish a notice in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>'s action on the provisions.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has cited sections <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">502, 510, 518, 519</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">520,701</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">704</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">903</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">352,</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">360, 360h</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">360i</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">360j</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">371</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">374 and 393</NUMEX>) as authority for the rule
and in particular, the device provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, including the
restricted device <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 520</ENAMEX>(e) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX>
Â§ 360j(e).
Executive Order No. 12866
The rule was determined to be a "significant regulatory action"
under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX> requiring review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX> approved the final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 22, 1996</TIMEX>, as
complying with the requirements of the Order based on the
information supplied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, including a planned regulatory action
document
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-38</NUMEX>
describing the reason for the rule and an assessment of the
costs and budgetary impact of the rule.
Executive Order No. 12606 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> considered whether the rule would have a significant impact
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> formation, maintenance and general well-being as required
by the Order and found that the rule would not have a negative
impact in these areas. In the preamble to the proposed rule, it was
noted that the rule would help the significant majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
that seek to discourage their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from using cigarettes and
smokeless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41356</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> responds in the preamble
to the final rule to several comments it received and maintains its
conclusion that the rule does not have a negative impact.
Executive Order No. 12612 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism</ENAMEX>)
The rule was reviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> under the Order which requires
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to examine regulatory actions to determine if they
have a significant impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX>, on the relationship
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX> and the Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and on the
distribution of power and responsibilities among the various levels
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In the preamble to the final rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> addresses
the various issues raised by commenters in this area, including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preemption of State</ENAMEX> and local laws which are different from or in
addition to the requirements under the final rule; whether there is
an infringement on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' right to regulate tobacco and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and protect the health of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>;
the allocation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>'s resources and the rule's possible
impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' economies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> concludes that the
preemptive effects of the final rule are consistent with the
Order.
Executive Order No. 12630 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property Rights</ENAMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> reviewed the rule under the Order and concluded that the
affect of the final rule would not constitute a "taking" of private
property. The preamble to the final rule discusses issues raised by
various commenters in the areas of the use of self-service
displays, vending machines, restrictions on sponsorship of events
except in the corporate name and loss of employment and maintains
its conclusion that there would be no "taking" under the Order. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s position is that reductions in personal property's value,
even prohibitions on all economically viable uses, and financial
expenditures to comply with a regulatory requirement do not
necessarily establish a taking, citing various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> decisions for
support.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statute or executive order
imposing procedural requirements relevant to the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-38</NUMEX>



