



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271810.7</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Larry Pressler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Ernest F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment of Parts 2 and 15 of the Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communication Commission</ENAMEX> Rules to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deregulate the Equipment</ENAMEX>
Authorization Requirements for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Devices</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amendment of Parts 2 and</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s Rules to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deregulate the Equipment</ENAMEX>
Authorization Requirements for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Devices</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ET Docket No.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95-19</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-208</NUMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 30, 1996</TIMEX>. It was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 19</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order amending Parts 2 and 15 of Title 47</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Regulations</ENAMEX>, deregulates the equipment
authorization requirements for personal computers and peripherals.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order</ENAMEX> provides for a new selfauthorization process based on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX>'s declaration of compliance with all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>
requirements. The original certification procedure required
submission of a written application, test report and fee (and a
device for testing in some cases) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>
estimates that the new procedure will save industry approximately
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> in administrative expenses.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-21</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-4586</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>,
reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8234</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew S. Fishel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications</ENAMEX>
Commission
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-21</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ANALYSIS OF AMENDMENT OF PARTS 2 AND 15</ENAMEX> OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMMISSION</ENAMEX>'S
RULES TO <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEREGULATE THE EQUIPMENT AUTHORIZATION REQUIREMENTS FOR</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIGITAL DEVICES RULE</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(A)(i)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(I)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> indicated in its submission that it was not
required to prepare a cost-benefit analysis of the rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial regulatory flexibility analysis
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603 of the Act</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> incorporated
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> in it Notice of Proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule Making</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proposed Rule Making</ENAMEX> was published in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15116</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22, 1995</TIMEX>. Our
review of the initial analysis indicates that the requirements of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603</ENAMEX> have been met. At that time, written comments on the
proposal were requested. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> also reports that it
forwarded a copy of its initial regulatory flexibility analysis to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Advocacy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>) as required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> did not file
comments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final regulatory flexibility analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> prepared a Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 604</ENAMEX>. That analysis notes that the rule was
needed in order to reduce regulatory burdens on computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, to remove impediments to flexible systems design and
construction techniques, and to reduce the potential for
interference to radio services by improving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s
ability to ensure that personal computers comply with the
Commission's standards and testing procedures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
further notes that no commenting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> raised issues specifically
in response to the initial regulatory flexibility analysis, and
that no significant alternatives were considered.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 605</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Avoidance</ENAMEX> of duplicative or unnecessary
analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not invoke any of the exemptions or special
procedures authorized by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX> in preparing its regulatory
flexibility analysis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-21</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 607</ENAMEX>: Preparation of analyses
Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 607</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s submission does not
specifically indicate the potential economic impact or the number
of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> affected. However, the initial regulatory
flexibility analysis indicates that the rule will result in a
significant decrease in the amount of testing and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
authorization of computer systems with a resultant reduction in
economic burden. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> notes that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-150
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> of various component devices but does not indicate
what the ratio of large to small business might be in this mix.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 609</ENAMEX>: Participation by small entities
In addition to the actions required by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>, the
Commission also made available a complete copy of the proposed and
final rulemaking materials via the Internet. There were no special
efforts made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to involve small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in the
rulemaking process.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is not
subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was promulgated through the general notice of proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> procedures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
afforded interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> the opportunity to comment on the
proposed rule, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and Order adopted on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1996</TIMEX>, and released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14, 1996</TIMEX>, addresses these comments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Report</ENAMEX> and Order is subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, and has received OMB clearance (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB #</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3060-0636</TIMEX>).
Statutory authorization for the rule
The new rules are promulgated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> provided in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Act of 1934</ENAMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Sections 154</ENAMEX>(i),
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">301, 302, 303</TIMEX>(e), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(f), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(r), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">304 and 307</NUMEX>. In addition, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Telecommunications Act of 1996, Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX>,
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-21</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">110 Stat.56</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), provides specific new authority to the
Commission to eliminate unnecessary regulations and functions, and
among other things, authorizes the use of private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> for
testing and certifying the compliance of devices with regulations
promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statutes or Executive
Orders imposing requirements relevant to the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-21</NUMEX>



