



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271810.2</NUMEX>
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Larry Pressler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Ernest F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Light Truck</ENAMEX> Average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fuel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economy Standard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Model Year</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Light Truck</ENAMEX> Average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fuel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Model Year 1998</ENAMEX>" (RIN <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2127-AF16</TIMEX>). We received the rule on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 22, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 3, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14680</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 32902</ENAMEX>(a) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 49, United States Code</ENAMEX>, requires the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> to prescribe by regulation, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 18</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> in advance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each model year</TIMEX>, average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">fuel</ENAMEX> economy
standards (known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corporate Average Fuel Economy" or "CAFE</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standards</ENAMEX>) for non<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-passenger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> manufactured in that model
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. Under subsections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32902</NUMEX>(a) and (f), the standard is to be the
maximum feasible average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">fuel</ENAMEX> economy level that the Secretary
decides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> can achieve in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that model year</TIMEX> taking into
consideration technological feasibility, economic practicability,
the effect of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-11</NUMEX> motor vehicle standards on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">fuel</ENAMEX> economy, and the
need of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
conserve energy.
The light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> CAFE standard for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 1997</TIMEX> was
established at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20.7 miles per gallon</NUMEX> (mpg). During the development
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAFE</ENAMEX> standard for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Related Agencies Appropriations</ENAMEX> Act, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104-50</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15, 1995</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">109 Stat</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">436</NUMEX>, was enacted. <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">330</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Appropriations Act</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">109 Stat</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">457</NUMEX>, provides:
"None of the funds in this Act shall be available to prepare,
propose, or promulgate any regulations pursuant to title V of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motor Vehicle Information</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Cost Savings Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. 32901</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seq</ENAMEX>.) prescribing corporate average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">fuel</ENAMEX> economy standards for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">automobiles</ENAMEX>, as defined in such title, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any model year</TIMEX> that
differs from standards promulgated for such <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> prior to
the enactment of this section."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> interprets <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330 of the Appropriations Act</ENAMEX> as
requiring it to prescribe the same light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> CAFE standard for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 1998</TIMEX> that applies to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 1997</TIMEX>. Accordingly, the
rule continues the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20.7</NUMEX> mpg standard for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. As discussed in the enclosure,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> did not follow many of the steps that ordinarily would apply
to the rule, based in part on its interpretation that section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">330</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Appropriations Act</ENAMEX> required it to fix the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> standard at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20.7</NUMEX> mpg and thereby deprived the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> of any discretion over the
standard. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330</ENAMEX>, while not
necessarily the only plausible approach, is supported by the
language and legislative history of this provision. Nevertheless,
we do not view <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330</ENAMEX> as exempting the rulemaking from the
requirements referred to in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
(iv), particularly the analysis called for by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32902</NUMEX>.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry R. Wray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8581</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
1Authority to prescribe fuel economy standards under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">32902</ENAMEX> has been delegated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-11</NUMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John H. Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecommunications</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2834</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy E. McFadden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-11</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIGHT TRUCK CAFE STANDARD RULE</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3, 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> published a notice of proposed
rulemaking which proposed a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> standard of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20.7</NUMEX> mpg. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">145</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> accompanying the proposed
rule contains a discussion and assessment of the economic impacts
of the proposed standard, including its potential costs, benefits,
and alternatives. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> prepared a Preliminary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Evaluation</ENAMEX> of the proposed standard, which was included
in the docket for the rulemaking and contained more detailed
analyses of these and other affects of the proposed standard. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> did not prepare a Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact Analysis</ENAMEX> in
connection with the final rule "because of the restrictions imposed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 330 of the FY 1996 DOT Appropriations Act</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14682</NUMEX>.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial regulatory flexibility analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> accompanying the proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> includes a certification, pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5</ENAMEX>, that the proposal would not have a significant impact on a
substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, thereby exempting the
proposed rule from the requirement for an initial regulatory
flexibility analysis. The certification was accompanied by a
statement that few, if any, light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> subject to
the proposed rule would be classified as small businesses. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">155</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 605</ENAMEX>(b) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that the certification and statement shall
be provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Advocacy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business</ENAMEX>
Administration (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>). According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Transportation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, the certification and statement were not separately
provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocacy</ENAMEX>. They stated that,
in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>'s practice, publication of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) certifications in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> is treated as
providing notice to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> confirmed that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> follow this practice, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> has not objected to it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> indicated, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>'s policy may change since
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">certifications</ENAMEX> will need to be justified more specifically
and will be subject to judicial review.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-11</NUMEX> Section 604: Final regulatory flexibility
analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> did not conduct a final regulatory flexibility analysis
under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 604</ENAMEX>, nor did it make a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX>(b) certification,
in connection with the final rule. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> viewed such an
analysis as "unnecessary" in light of its lack of discretion with
respect to the rule, but stated that past evaluations indicated few
if any small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> would be affected. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14682</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 605</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Avoidance</ENAMEX> of duplicative or unnecessary
analysis
As noted above, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> invoked the exemption from the initial
regulatory flexibility analysis requirement with respect to the
proposed rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 607</ENAMEX>: Preparation of analysis
As noted above, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> did not prepare an initial or final
regulatory flexibility analysis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 609</ENAMEX>: Participation by small entities
The requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 609</ENAMEX> are inapplicable to this rule
since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> did not determine that it would have a significant
impact on a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
Since the standard appears to constitute a federal mandate
resulting in aggregate annual private sector expenditures of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> or more, it would be subject to the requirements of section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Statements to Accompany Significant Regulatory</ENAMEX>
Actions). Neither the proposed nor the final rulemaking expressly
refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> or includes the
statements required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 202</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX>
accompanying the proposed rule does include some of the information
covered by section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>.
The rule also appears subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 205 of the Act</ENAMEX>,
relating to consideration of regulatory alternatives. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>
did not explicitly address <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 205</ENAMEX>, it complied in substance
with the requirements of this section. Potential alternatives were
considered and discussed at the proposed rulemaking stage, and the
final rulemaking describes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>'s determination that there was no
alternative to the standard adopted.
The requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 203</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Government Agency</ENAMEX> Plan)
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 204</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Local</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribal Government Input</ENAMEX>) appear
to be inapplicable to the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-11</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) Other relevant information or
requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive</ENAMEX> orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was promulgated through the general notice of proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> procedures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> afforded
interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> the opportunity to comment on the proposed rule.
The final rulemaking, however, does not address comments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule does not refer to information collection requirements
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, and, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>, the rule imposes no
such requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Environmental Policy</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยงยง 4321 et</ENAMEX> seq.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> did not conduct an evaluation of the impacts of the rule
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Environmental Policy</ENAMEX> Act. The Supplementary
Information accompanying the final rule <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in this regard:
"There is no requirement for such an evaluation where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
has eliminated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s discretion by precluding any action
other than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> announced in this notice." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14682</NUMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> accompanying the final rule
discusses at length its legal basis. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 32902</ENAMEX>(a) of title <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Code</ENAMEX>, requires that light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> CAFE standards be
prescribed for each model year in accordance with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maximum</ENAMEX>
feasible" criteria specified in that subsection and subsection
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32902</NUMEX>(f). However, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330 of the Appropriations Act</ENAMEX>
effectively prohibited issuance of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAFE</ENAMEX> standard "that differs
from standards promulgated . . . prior to the enactment of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>." According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>'s legal analysis detailed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplementary Information, section 330 of the Appropriations Act</ENAMEX>
precluded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> from prescribing any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAFE</ENAMEX> standard different
from the most recent standards prescribed at the time of its
enactment--those applicable to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 1997</TIMEX>. Thus, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330</ENAMEX> deprived the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> of the discretion it
otherwise would have under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 32902</ENAMEX> to determine the
applicable standard under the criteria set forth therein. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>
concluded that while <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330 superseded the section 32902</ENAMEX>
criteria, it did not supersede the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 32902</ENAMEX> mandate that there
be CAFE standards for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 1998</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> noted that the only other possible interpretation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330</ENAMEX> was to treat the phrase "standards promulgated . . .
prior to the enactment of this section" as
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-11</NUMEX> encompassing any standard prescribed for
any prior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year</TIMEX>. In addition to the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20.7</NUMEX> mpg standard, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> other light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> standards--ranging
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17.5</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21.0</NUMEX> mpg--were promulgated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior model years</TIMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> rejected this interpretation on the basis that it
could also conflict with the "maximum feasible" criteria under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">32902</ENAMEX>, and that it would be illogical to assume that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> intended to arbitrarily limit the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> standard to one of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these prior year</TIMEX> levels even if some other level was determined to
be the "maximum feasible" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 1998</TIMEX>.
Accordingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> concluded that the only legally permissible
alternative was to establish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the model year 1998</TIMEX> standard at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20.7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mpg</ENAMEX>. As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> did not complete its analysis to
determine what the "maximum feasible" level actually would be for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 1998</TIMEX> under the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">32902</ENAMEX> criteria.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>'s legal interpretation is supported by the language and
legislative history of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330</ENAMEX>. As the analysis points out, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Appropriations Committee</ENAMEX> report and a floor statement by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal sponsor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>--describe
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section 330</ENAMEX> as permitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> to establish a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> standard
"identical to" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the model year 1997</TIMEX> standard. The conference report
describes <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330</ENAMEX> as prohibiting the use of funds for
"regulations that prescribe changes in" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAFE</ENAMEX> standards.
On the other hand, we question whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> was compelled by
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section 330</ENAMEX> to forego completion of the analysis otherwise mandated
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยง</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32902</NUMEX> to determine the "maximum feasible" level for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 1998</TIMEX>. The legislative history of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330</ENAMEX>, taken as a
whole, suggests that the fundamental purpose of this provision was
to prevent an anticipated increase in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAFE</ENAMEX> standards.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Representative DeLay</ENAMEX> observed in his floor statement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> was
engaged in a rulemaking "which could result in a sharp increase in
the standards for light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and vans" and that "this action
would be devastating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>'s economy." <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">141 Cong</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rec</ENAMEX>. H7605
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ed.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 25, 1995</TIMEX>). He also stated that section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">330</NUMEX>
"imposes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 1-year</TIMEX> freeze on the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> to increase the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAFE</ENAMEX> standards" and that "it was my intent that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> would
withhold any further action directed toward increasing CAFE
standards . . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">..</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>. In this context, the references in the
history to requiring an identical standard or precluding any
changes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> may have been based on the assumption that the
outcome of any change would be an increase in the standard.
Completing the analysis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 49</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง 32902</ENAMEX> would have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">provided NHTSA</ENAMEX> more information on which to assess the relationship
between that section and section
1These standards are listed in a table included in the final
rule. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> mpg standard was initially prescribed for model year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, but was amended to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19.5</NUMEX> mpg before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the start of that</TIMEX> model
year
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-11 330</NUMEX>. For example, if the analysis indicated
that the "maximum feasible" level for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> was at or closer to one
of the lower <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior year</TIMEX> standards than it was to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> standard,
prescribing that lower standard would not necessarily be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impermissible</ENAMEX>. Such an action would give greater effect to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">32902</ENAMEX> than using the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20.7</NUMEX> mpg standard and would satisfy
the plain terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330</ENAMEX>. Nor is it clear that such action
would conflict with the purpose underlying <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 330</ENAMEX>. The history
does not explicitly address the possibility that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20.7</NUMEX> mpg
standard might exceed the "maximum feasible" level for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
indicated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">under 49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> 32902.
Executive Order No. 12866
Based on its economic impact, the rule was determined to be a
"significant regulatory action" within the meaning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
Order No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>. Consistent with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX> order, the rule was
initiated through an advance notice of proposed rulemaking
published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6, 1994</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16324</NUMEX>. As noted
previously, the proposed rulemaking published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3, 1996</TIMEX>,
includes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preliminary Regulatory Evaluation</ENAMEX>. The final rule,
however, does not include a Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact Analysis.</ENAMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Information and Regulatory</ENAMEX>
Affairs reviewed the rule at the proposed and final stages and
suggested no changes.
Executive Order 12612
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> accompanying the proposed rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that, based on an analysis of the principles and criteria
contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12612</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> determined that the
proposed rule would not have sufficient federalism implications to
warrant preparation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism Assessment</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">155</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Information</ENAMEX> accompanying the final rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that the final rule was not analyzed under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order</ENAMEX>
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12612</NUMEX> because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX>'s lack of discretion with respect to
the rule. It adds that prior light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> standards have not been
viewed as having federalism implications warranting preparation of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism Analysis.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14682</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statutes or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive</ENAMEX> orders
imposing requirements relevant to the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-11</NUMEX>



