



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-274332
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Larry Pressler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Ernest F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX>: Policies and Rules
Concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Television Programming/Revision of</ENAMEX>
Programming Policies for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television Broadcast Stations</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Policies</ENAMEX> and Rules Concerning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television Programming/Revision of Programming Policies</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television Broadcast Stations</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-335</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MM Docket No.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93-48</NUMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 21, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 27, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43981</NUMEX>.
The rule is designed to strengthen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s enforcement
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Television</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> (CTA). It provides a safe
harbor processing guideline for processing the CTA portion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX>' license renewal applications, adopts a definition of
programming specifically designed to educate and inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Core Programming</ENAMEX>), and requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> to provide better
information to the public about their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Core Programming</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications</ENAMEX>
Commission's compliance with the procedural steps required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sections 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-37</NUMEX>
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James W. Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John H. Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of
reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2834</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew S. Fishel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-37</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RULES CONCERNING CHILDREN'S TELEVISION PROGRAMMING/REVISION OF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PROGRAMMING POLICIES FOR TELEVISION BROADCAST STATIONS</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-335</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MM Docket</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93-48</NUMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has advised our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> that it was not required
to prepare and did not prepare a cost-benefit analysis of the
rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The proposed rulemaking, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20590</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26, 1995</TIMEX>),
incorporated an initial regulatory flexibility analysis of the
expected impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
The analysis included in the proposed rulemaking provides the
information required by paragraphs 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>). It
describes the reasons for the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> action, and its
objectives and legal basis. It also describes the total number of
entities of all sizes that may be affected by the rule. (See
below.) The analysis also requests comments regarding the reporting
and record-keeping requirements of the proposed rule. In accordance
with paragraph 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> notes that the proposed
rule does not duplicate, overlap or conflict with any relevant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> rule. Also, it states that the proposed rule has been
designed to minimize the impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> while retaining
the benefits of encouraging television broadcast programming that
satisfies the requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Television</ENAMEX> Act of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The preamble to the final rule includes the full text of the
final regulatory flexibility analysis. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43992</NUMEX>. The
analysis includes the information required by paragraph 604(a) by
summarizing and evaluating relevant comments received.
A major portion of the analysis describes the steps the
Commission took in attempting to determine the number of small
entities affected by the rule based on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-37</NUMEX>
various criteria, databases and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> information. This
was necessary because of the inadequacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business</ENAMEX>
Administration's definition for television broadcasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>,
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> receipt data collected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, and the
classification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> with network affiliation. Under various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">analyses</ENAMEX>, the worst case scenario would be the application of the
rule to a low of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">771</NUMEX> commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68 percent</NUMEX> of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX>) to a high of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,155</NUMEX> commercial and noncommercial stations
(<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> believes that these
estimates greatly overstate the number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> affected
and reserves the right to adopt a more suitable definition of
"small business" as applied to television broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> at a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later date</TIMEX> following the conclusion of several pending proceedings
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> seeking comment on the definition of and data
relating to small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 601</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>.
The final analysis discusses the comments received and the
alternatives considered and the steps taken to minimize the impact
on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. It appears that many of these changes will also
reduce the burden on non-small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
These steps include the deletion of the requirement in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> that a broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> utilize an
icon for the identification of core programming. The method of
identification is now at the discretion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. The
Commission also rejected a proposal that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> consult with
educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> in order for a program to qualify as core
programming. Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> will issue a standardized
reporting form for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s programming report to
ease the information collection burden on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
The final analysis was forwarded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for
Advocacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 605</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Avoidance</ENAMEX> of duplicative or unnecessary
analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not invoke any of the exemptions or special
procedures authorized by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605</ENAMEX> in preparing its regulatory
flexibility analysis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 607</ENAMEX>: Preparation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s analysis used both quantifiable and general
descriptions of the effects of the rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 609</ENAMEX>: Participation by small entities
In addition to the actions required by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>, the
Commission also made available a complete copy of the proposed and
final rulemaking materials via the Internet.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-37</NUMEX>
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is not
subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> promulgated the rule under the notice and comment
procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. A notice of proposed rulemaking was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26, 1995</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20586</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> received numerous formal and informal
comments on the proposed rule during the comment period which was
extended twice. In the preamble to the final rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
responds to issues raised by the comments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> to maintain a file for public
inspection containing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Television Programming Report</ENAMEX>
and to identify programs specifically designed to educate and
inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at the beginning of those programs and to furnish
such information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> of program guides. These
represent a new and a modified information collection that has been
submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) for its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> and approval. Comments are solicited from the general
public, other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 28, 1996</TIMEX>.
The preamble to the final rule contains significant information
about the proposed collection of information including the reasons
for collecting the information, the type and number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>,
and the estimated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> burden. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43991</NUMEX>.
The portion of the rule containing the above collection
requirements will not become effective until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approval is
obtained.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The rule is issued pursuant to the authority contained in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sections 4</ENAMEX>(i) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">j</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(r), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">308 and 403</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1934</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 154</NUMEX> (i) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">j</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(r), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">308 and 403</NUMEX>, as
amended, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Television</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">303b</ENAMEX>(a), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">303b</TIMEX>(b) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">394</NUMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-37</NUMEX>
The rule promulgated by an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is not
subject to the review requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX> Order No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-37</NUMEX>



