



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-274387
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 13, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable William V. Roth, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Finance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Bill Archer Chairman The Honorable Sam M. Gibbons</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Financing Administration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Program</ENAMEX>; Changes to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital Inpatient Prospective Payment Systems</ENAMEX> and Fiscal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 1997</TIMEX>
Rates
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financing Administration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Program</ENAMEX>; Changes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inpatient Prospective Payment Systems</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fiscal Year 1997 Rates</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIN</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0938-AH34</TIMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 29, 1996</TIMEX>. It was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 30</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46166</NUMEX>.
The final rule revises the prospective payment systems for
operating and capital costs for inpatient services under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
Part A. Among other things, the final rule adjusts the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classifications</ENAMEX> and weighting factors for diagnosis related groups
as required by section <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1886</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)(C) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1395ww</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)(C); updates the wage index associated with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX> operating costs; and makes certain clarifications
concerning the calculation of payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> excluded from
the prospective payment systems.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-41</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by sections 801(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that HCFA
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen T. Desaulniers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-4740</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Scanlon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Systems</ENAMEX>
Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scanlon</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7119</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-41</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>งย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 801</NUMEX>(A)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
HEALTH AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUMAN SERVICES ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDICARE PROGRAM; CHANGES TO</ENAMEX>
THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HOSPITAL INPATIENT PROSPECTIVE PAYMENT SYSTEMS AND FISCAL YEAR</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> RATES" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0938-AH34</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 1102</ENAMEX>(b) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1302</TIMEX>(b),
requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> to prepare regulatory impact analyses for
any rule that may have a significant impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of a
substantial number of small rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. An initial analysis,
to be prepared for a proposed rule, is to describe the impact of
the proposed rule on such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and include the matters
required under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603</ENAMEX>. The final analysis, to be prepared
for a final rule, must include, with respect to small rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, the matters required under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">604</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Financing Administration</ENAMEX> (HCFA) determined that the proposed
rule would affect a substantial number of small rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>,
and that the effects on some could be significant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> also
determined that the rule could have a significant impact on other
classes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> as well<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Therefore</ENAMEX>, as discussed below, HCFA
prepared combined regulatory impact/regulatory flexibility analyses
in connection with the rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> did not prepare an additional analysis under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
Order 12866.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) Actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
Initial analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> included the full text of its combined initial regulatory
impact/regulatory flexibility analysis (analysis) as an appendix to
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31, 1996</TIMEX> proposed rule. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">27566-27584</ENAMEX>. In
response to our inquiry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> explained that it did not
submit a copy of the analysis to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>. However, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>'s view, its
publication of the full text of the analysis with the proposed rule
satisfied the
1HCFA considers all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> to be small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> for purposes
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-41</NUMEX>
submission requirement. We have learned that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
follow this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> without objection from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>.
As required by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>งย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 603</NUMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), the analysis,
coupled with the summary in the preamble, explains the reasons and
objectives, as well as legal bases, for the proposed rule. <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1886</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1395ww</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>),
generally provides for a system of payment for the operating costs
of hospital inpatient services under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> Part A based on
prospectively set rates. In addition, under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 1886</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>) of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1395ww</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>), capital-related costs
for those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> whose operating costs are paid under a
prospective payment system are also to be paid based on
prospectively set rates. In response to directives contained in
these sections and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>'s experience, the rule adjusts various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> costs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">27444-27445</ENAMEX>. According to the analysis, the changes are designed to
further the objectives of the prospective payment system<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,2</NUMEX> while
maintaining the financial viability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> industry and
ensuring access to high quality health care for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27566</NUMEX>.
Consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), the analysis describes, and
estimates the number of, small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> to which the rule will
apply. The rule will apply to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82 percent</NUMEX> of the general,
short-term, acute care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> that participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
program, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,130</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, all of which are considered small
entities by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,130</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,252</NUMEX> are rural. The
analysis describes and illustrates the impact of the rule on
various types of rural and urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>.
As discussed below, the proposed rule would modify an existing
reporting requirement applicable to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> serving Medicare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> did not discuss the proposed change in its
analysis, but in the preamble to the proposed rule<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> Thus, HCFA
also satisfied its responsibility under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 603</NUMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>).
Finally, with respect to sections 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) and (c), the
analysis does not identify any federal rules that duplicate,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overlap</ENAMEX>, or conflict with the proposed rule or any significant
regulatory alternatives. Since, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
subject to the rule are small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, it would be difficult to
minimize the impact of the rule on such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> within the
constraints of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program. As discussed
2The objectives of the prospective payment system are to
encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> to operate efficiently, while ensuring that
they are compensated for legitimate costs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27566</NUMEX>.
3Under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 605</NUMEX>(a), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> may perform the analyses
required by sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603 and 604</NUMEX> in conjunction with or as part of
any other agenda or analysis required by other law if such other
analysis satisfies the provisions of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-41</NUMEX>
below, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> addressed comments on various elements of the
proposed rule throughout the preamble to the final rule.
Final analysis
Consistent with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">604</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> included the full text of
its final analysis as an appendix to the final rule. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">46166, 46303-46320</ENAMEX>. As in the case of the initial analysis, HCFA
summarized the need for the rule in the preamble. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">46166-46167</ENAMEX>. In the final analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> replaced the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Objectives</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> with a discussion of changes to the initial analysis. See
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">46303-46304</ENAMEX>.
With respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 604</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), the analysis issued with the
final rule states that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> received no comments on the methodology
used in its initial analysis. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46304</NUMEX>. It also states
that any differences between the two analyses resulted from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>'s
use of "more recent or more complete hospital data." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46303</NUMEX>.
The analysis describes, and estimates the number of, small
entities to which the rule will apply as required by section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">604</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>). See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46304</NUMEX>. The analysis indicates that
the rule will apply to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,129</NUMEX>, rather than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,130</NUMEX>, general,
short-term, acute care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>. The analysis indicates a
decrease of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and an increase of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, for a net decrease of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46306</NUMEX>. The
final analysis also describes the rule's impact on covered entities
and, like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> analysis, specifically distinguishes between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> and rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> did not discuss its proposed modification of an existing
reporting requirement in the analysis, as described in section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">604</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>), but in the preamble. Also, like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> analysis,
the final analysis does not discuss steps taken to minimize the
economic impact of the rule on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 604</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>).
Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> did not discuss regulatory alternatives in the earlier
analysis, it did not describe the reasons for its approach in the
final analysis.
Sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 607</ENAMEX> permits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, in complying with sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">604</NUMEX>, to provide either a quantifiable or numerical description of
the effects of a rule or more general descriptive statements if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quantification</ENAMEX> is not practicable or reliable. The analyses issued
with the proposed and final rules provide quantifiable descriptions
of the rule's impact on covered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, including rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. See, e.g., <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">46306</NUMEX> (describing percent
changes in payments per case due to changes in the prospective
payment system for operating costs).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-41</NUMEX>
Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 609</ENAMEX>(a) requires that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> ensure that small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> are given an opportunity to participate in a rulemaking
through the reasonable use of techniques such as those enumerated.
As discussed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> published the full text of its initial analysis
as an appendix to the proposed rule and invited comments from small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> has advised that it did not take any other
actions specifically designed to ensure participation by small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>, including rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, in this rulemaking. However,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> also pointed out that, in carrying out its
responsibilities under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> maintains an
appropriate ongoing working relationship with industry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>.
(iii) Actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unfunded</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1995,2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
Since the rule does not impose a federal intergovernmental or
private sector mandate, as defined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unfunded Mandates Reform</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">204 and 205</NUMEX> of the act are inapplicable.
Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 203</ENAMEX> of the act is inapplicable because the rule
will not significantly affect small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive Orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง 551 et</ENAMEX> seq.
With the exception of the matter discussed below, HCFA
promulgated the changes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> prospective payment systems
under the notice and comment procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 1871</ENAMEX>(b) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1395hh</ENAMEX>(b)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>
The proposed rule was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> stated that it would consider comments received by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 1996</TIMEX>. The final rule was published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 30, 1996</TIMEX>. HCFA
received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">511</NUMEX> timely pieces of correspondence containing comments on
the proposed rule. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46167</NUMEX>. Those comments are
discussed throughout the preamble to the final rule.
In the final rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> revised certain regulations pertaining
to the costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> medical education programs to conform to a
recently enacted statute. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> appropriation requires
that, for certain purposes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Government</ENAMEX> "deem accredited
any postgraduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> training program that would be
accredited but for the accrediting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s reliance upon an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accreditation</ENAMEX> standard that requires an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> to perform an
induced abortion or require, provide, or refer for training in the
performance of induced abortions, or make arrangements for such
training . . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">..</ENAMEX>" See Section 101(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">134</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 1996</TIMEX>.
4Section <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX>(b) provides that, with exceptions not pertinent
here, before issuing any final rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> shall provide
for notice of the proposed regulation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> and a
comment period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 60 days</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-41</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> found that notice and comment procedures were unnecessary
with respect to this regulatory change since it did not involve an
exercise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> discretion. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46224</NUMEX>.
Accordingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> did not follow notice and comment procedures with
respect to this provision. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 553</NUMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>); <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง
1395hh(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(C).
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule modifies an existing requirement applicable to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> that provide services to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>. At
present, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> are required to distribute a statement entitled
"An Important Message from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at or about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of admission. Under the modified requirement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> would
be required to distribute the statement "during the course of the
hospital stay" rather than at admission. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">46213-46214</ENAMEX>. The preambles to the proposed and final rules discuss
this modification to the reporting requirement, explaining the
reasons for the change and providing a burden estimate. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27490</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27478</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">46223, 46213-46214</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> solicited and evaluated comments on its modification to the
reporting requirement. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">27489-27490</ENAMEX>. HCFA
declined to accept the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commenter</ENAMEX>'s suggestion that it require
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX> distribution of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Important Message</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>" to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> while they are healthy and do not have plans to be
hospitalized. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46214</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> submitted its proposed modification of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
reporting requirement to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>)
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19, 1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> has not yet approved the modification and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preambles</ENAMEX> to the proposed and final rules state that the
modification will not be effective until it is approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>. 61
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46223</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27490</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Statutory Authorization</ENAMEX> for the rule
Both the proposed and final rule cite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>'s broad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> to promulgate regulations necessary for the efficient
administration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">27492-27493, 46224-46225</ENAMEX> (citing primarily sections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1102 and 1871</TIMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1302 and 1395hh</TIMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX>
5The statement advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> of their rights to be fully
informed about decisions affecting their coverage or payment and
about their appeal rights should they be notified that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
will no longer cover their care. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">46213-46214</ENAMEX>.
6As discussed above, both sections impose specific procedural
requirements applicable to the rulemaking at issue here.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-41</NUMEX>
In addition, the preambles and appendices to the proposed and
final rules cite numerous statutory provisions associated with
particular aspects of the rule. For example, section <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1886</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)(C)
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1395ww</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)(C), requires
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> adjust the weights and classifications
for the diagnosis related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>'
hospital stays may be assigned. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46167</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1886</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง
1395ww(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>), requires that, as part of the methodology for
determining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> payments, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> annually make
adjustments for area differences in hospital wage levels by a
factor reflecting the relative wage level for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> in a
particular geographic area compared to a national average. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46177</NUMEX>. See also section <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1886</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(A) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1395ww</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(A) (providing for the
payment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>' capital costs under a prospective payment
system established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46166</NUMEX>.
Executive Order 12866
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) reviewed the rule as
an economically significant regulatory action under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> advised that after submission of the rule to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> made changes to its discussion of the rule's effective date,
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> also approved.
In its submission, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statute or
executive order imposing procedural requirements relevant to the
rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-41</NUMEX>



