



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-272247
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John H. Chafee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Max Baucus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accidental Release Prevention Requirements</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risk</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Programs</ENAMEX> Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act Section 112</ENAMEX>(r)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accidental Release Prevention</ENAMEX>
Requirements: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risk Management Programs</ENAMEX> Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act Section</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">112</NUMEX>(r)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">#5516-5</ENAMEX>, RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2050-AD26</TIMEX>). We received the rule on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 20, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31668</NUMEX>.
This rule implements <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 112</ENAMEX>(r) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>
Amendments of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, which mandates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> promulgate regulations
and develop guidance to prevent accidental releases to the air from
stationary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> and mitigate the consequences of such releases
by focusing prevention measures on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> that pose the greatest
risk to the public and the environment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by sections 801(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
complied with the applicable requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-26</NUMEX>
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen E. Wannisky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-5207</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter F. Guerrero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerrero</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6111</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Matthiessen</ENAMEX> Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical Engineer Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-26</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACCIDENTAL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RELEASE PREVENTION REQUIREMENTS</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RISK MANAGEMENT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PROGRAMS</ENAMEX> UNDER <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CLEAN AIR ACT SECTION 112</ENAMEX>(r)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)" (RIN:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2050-AD26</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> determined that the rule was an "economically
significant regulatory action" under terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>, it prepared an economic impact analysis in support of the
rule on risk management program regulations. It submitted that
analysis to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7, 1996</TIMEX>, along
with a copy of its final rule. The economic impact analysis
describes the regulatory options <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> considered for revising its
earlier proposed risk management requirements and estimates the
costs and benefits attributable to these options.
The chart below, extracted from the analysis, shows that, with
the exception of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> believes that the cost of the
benefits associated with the implementation of the rule's
requirements greatly exceed the costs of implementation of the
rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ANNUALIZED NET COSTS</ENAMEX> AND BENEFITS OF THE FINAL RULE

In addition to the estimated benefits of reduced damages from
releases of toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s analysis also highlights what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> believes to be additional qualitative benefits including
those resulting from efficiency gains, increased technology
transfer, indirect cost savings, increased goodwill, and increased
public awareness.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-26</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial regulatory flexibility analyses
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX> requires federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to
evaluate the effects of a proposed rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
prepared an initial regulatory flexibility analysis in compliance
with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 603 of the Act</ENAMEX>; it published a summary of that
analysis in the preamble to the proposed rule in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 20, 1993</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54212</NUMEX>. The analysis
concluded that the economic burden for initial compliance would be
minimal for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 90 percent</NUMEX> of the small businesses affected. For
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">the remaining 10 percent</NUMEX>, however, the analysis stated that the
program would impose a significant adverse effect in the first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
Based on the information presented during public hearings and in
comments received on the proposed rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> published a
supplemental notice of proposed rulemaking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 13, 1995</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13526</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> included in the
preamble to the revised proposed rule a summary of its updated
regulatory flexibility analysis. The analysis concluded that the
rule as proposed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> would have had severe adverse effects on
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. The revised analysis evaluates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> alternatives
to the initially proposed rule and assesses the burdens and impacts
of each. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s discussion, the streamlined
requirements of the revised proposed rule drastically reduce the
burden on both small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final regulatory flexibility analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> published a summary of its final regulatory flexibility
analyses as required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 604 of the Act</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 20, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31715</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> estimated that
the total number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> affected by the rule was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,500</NUMEX>
or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX> of the affected universe. No detailed analysis of the
impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> was performed because of the relatively
low cost of implementation estimated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> (for most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>
substantially <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1 percent</NUMEX> of sales <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> and
considerably less in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">subsequent years</TIMEX>; for non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> less
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> for initial compliance).
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s analysis, a number of decisions adopted in
the final rule (specifically, the adoption of tiers ("programs"),
the reduced requirements for the risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> plan and the
development of guidance for offsite consequence analysis) have
significantly reduced the burden on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> considered
comments on both the initial and the proposed rule in making these
decisions.
All analyses prepared in accordance with this <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> were submitted
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-26</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 607</ENAMEX>: Preparation of analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s analyses use both quantifiable and general descriptions of
the effects of the rule and alternatives on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 609</ENAMEX>: Participation by small entities
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> included small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> (from both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and business)
in focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, public hearings, seminars, and meetings to develop
this rule.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has determined that this rule contains a federal mandate
that may result in expenditures of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more for state,
local, and tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, or the private sector in only its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year. In compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 202</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unfunded Mandates</ENAMEX>
Reform Act, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> prepared a written statement, including a cost
benefit analysis, assessing the impact of the rule, which it
published with both the proposed and the final rule. As discussed
previously, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> considered the future compliance costs in assessing
the impact of the rule.
Consistent with the intergovernmental provisions of sections 203
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">204</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act, and Executive Order 12875</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enhancing the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intergovernmental Partnership</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> involved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, local, and
business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> in focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, public hearings,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seminars</ENAMEX>, and meetings to develop the rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 205 of the Act</ENAMEX> requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to identify and
consider a reasonable number of regulatory alternatives and to
adopt the least costly, most cost-effective or least burdensome
alternative that achieves the objectives of the rule. The preamble
to the final rule indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> evaluated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different
methodologies for implementation. It ultimately chose what it
believed to be the least costly and least burdensome
alternative.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
This rule was promulgated through the general notice of proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rulemaking</ENAMEX> procedures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> afforded
interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> several opportunities to comment. Following
publication of the proposed rule (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54190</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> held
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> public hearings and received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 770</NUMEX> written
comments. Because of these comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> issued a supplemental
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> of proposed rulemaking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 13, 1995</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60 FR 13526</NUMEX>) for
comment on:
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-26</NUMEX>
approaches for setting different requirements for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> that
pose different levels of hazard (tiering); worst-case releases and
other hazard assessment issues; accident information reporting;
public participation; inherently safer approaches; and
implementation and integration of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 112</ENAMEX>(r) with state
programs, particularly state air permitting programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> held a
public hearing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31, 1995</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>, and received
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 283</NUMEX> written comments. In total, commenters represented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>
chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX> petroleum
industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">174</NUMEX> industry trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> other trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX> agricultural supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">102</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">propane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">132</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> water treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">utilities</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> other federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. This rule reflects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s
consideration of all comments; major issues raised by commenters
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s response are briefly discussed in the preamble. A summary
of all comments submitted and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s response to them is available
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule imposes information collection requirements in the
registration process, in the preparation and submission of the risk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">management</ENAMEX> plans, and in the maintenance of on-site documentation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> describes in the preamble to the rule the reasons for the
collection of information, the type of information and an estimate
of the burden imposed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. Both initial and supplemental
proposed rule publications invited comments on the information
collection requirements imposed by the rule. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53212</NUMEX>. 60
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13543</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 3506</ENAMEX>(c) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> requires each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to establish an
independent process to review each proposed collection of
information before submitting the proposal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for review. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Planning and Evaluation</ENAMEX> conducted such a review.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> subsequently sent the information collection requirements to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> for approval under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Act</ENAMEX>. 44
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3507</TIMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s discussion of its compliance
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX> was omitted from the final rule,
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s response to comments by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX> required to be
discussed in the final rule by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3507</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>).
Consequently, there is no evidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s filing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX>'s
comments on, approval or disapproval of, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s information
collection requirements. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> did, however, reduce the potential
burden of required information collection in drafting the final
rule. See discussion below.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> appears to meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> requirement (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R. Â</ENAMEX>§
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1320.8</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)) that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> evaluate the use of automated<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
electronic or other technological collection forms by allowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to register and file risk management plans electronically,
thus avoiding what could have been a huge paperwork burden.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-26</NUMEX>
Executive Order No. 12866
Based on its economic impact, the rule was determined to be an
"economically significant regulatory action" within the meaning of
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order 12866</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> submitted both the proposed rule and the
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX>) for review. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX> raised some concerns
about the scope of information collection requirements initially
proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> addressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX>'s concerns by lessening the
information collection requirements for risk management plans in
its final rule. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> notice, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> described
lessening risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> plan information requirements as
follows:
". . . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has limited the requirements for information to that
which can be reported as data elements. In contrast, the rule as
proposed would have required <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to document for each process
all major hazards, the consequences of each of these hazards, the
risk reduction steps taken to address each hazard, and the
consequences of each risk reduction step. The result would have
been, for large, complex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, documents of a l<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,000</NUMEX> pages or
more."
Statutory authorization for the rule
This rule is promulgated under sections 112(a), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">301</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>), title
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> as amended (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§ Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7412</TIMEX>(r),
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7601</TIMEX>(a)(i), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7661-7661f</TIMEX>). The intent of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 112</ENAMEX>(r) is to prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accidental</ENAMEX> releases to the air and mitigate the consequences of
such releases by focusing prevention measures on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> that
pose the greatest risk to the public and the environment. <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">112</NUMEX>(r)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) mandates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> promulgate a list of regulated
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX>, with threshold quantities; this list defines the
stationary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> that will be subject to accident prevention
regulations mandated by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 112</ENAMEX>(r)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> promulgated its list
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 31, 1994</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4478</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statute or executive order
imposing procedural requirements relevant to this rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary</ENAMEX> information
The rule is not covered in the judicial review provisions
recently added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small</ENAMEX>
Business <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Enforcement Act of 1996</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 104-121</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Title</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29, 1996</TIMEX>) because it was published as a final rule before
the effective date of those provisions. It is, however, reviewable
under
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-26</NUMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7607</TIMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>). Under that
provision, judicial review of the requirements contained in this
rule is available only by petition for review in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> District
publication of this final rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-26</NUMEX>



