



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271810.3</NUMEX>
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Frank H. Murkowski</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett Johnston Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Energy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Resources United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open Access Same</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Information System</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conduct</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Regulatory Commission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX>,
entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Open Access Same-Time Information System and Standards of</ENAMEX>
Conduct" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Docket No.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RM95-9-000</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Order No. 889</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
issued the final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24, 1996</TIMEX>, and we received it on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 25, 1996</TIMEX>. The final rule was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21737</NUMEX>.
A companion rule entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Promoting Wholesale Competition</ENAMEX>
Through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Access Non-Discriminatory Transmission Services</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Utilities</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Recovery of Stranded Costs</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Utilities</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transmitting Utilities</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Docket Nos. RM95-8-000</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RM94-7-001</ENAMEX>;
Order No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">888</NUMEX>) was also published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21540</NUMEX>. Today, we are issuing a separate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, captioned B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271810.4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-13</NUMEX> on the companion rule.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1, 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Franks</ENAMEX> introduced a joint
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> to disapprove both final rules pursuant to section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">802</NUMEX>(a) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">142 Cong</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rec</ENAMEX>. H4397.
This rule would require each public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> that owns, controls,
or operates transmission <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> used for transmitting electric
energy in interstate commerce to create or participate in an open
access same-time information system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OASIS</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The OASIS</ENAMEX> would provide potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> with
information needed to obtain the open access non-discriminatory
service required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s companion rule. This rule
would also require public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> to implement standards of
conduct to functionally separate transmission and wholesale power
merchant functions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s compliance with
the procedural requirements referred to in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">801</TIMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)
through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review
indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable
requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen T. Desaulniers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-4740</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor S. Rezendes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy, Resources</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>
Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rezendes</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-3841</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honorable Elizabeth A. Moler Chair Federal Energy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Commission</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-12</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACCESS SAME-TIME INFORMATION SYSTEM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OASIS</ENAMEX>) AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STANDARDS OF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONDUCT</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DOCKET NO. RM95-9-000; ORDER NO. 889</ENAMEX>)



(i)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cost-Benefit Analysis</ENAMEX>

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> indicated in its submission to us that it was
not required to prepare and did not prepare a cost-benefit analysis
of the rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency Actions Relevant</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The preamble to the proposed rule stated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that
would be required to comply with the rule are public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> and
transmitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> that do not fall within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>'s definition of small entity<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1 60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">66197-8</ENAMEX>. Accordingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> certified, pursuant to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 605</NUMEX>(b), that the rule would not have a significant
economic impact on a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> and did
not prepare an initial regulatory flexibility analysis. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66198</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 605</ENAMEX>(b) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that the certification and
explanatory statement shall be provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Counsel</ENAMEX> for
our inquiry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did
not provide a separate certification and statement to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> because
it considers publication of the certification in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> to be notice to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> has confirmed that
some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> follow this practice, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> has not objected to
it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
1Section 601(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>, provides that
the term "small business" generally has "the same meaning as the
term 'small business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>' under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 3</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business</ENAMEX>
Act." <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 3</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Act</ENAMEX> defines a "small business
concern" as a business which is independently owned and operated
and which is not dominant in its field of operation. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">632</NUMEX>(a).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-12</NUMEX> In the preamble to the final rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
reiterated that the rule would only apply to public and
transmitting utilities and again certified that the rule would not
have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small
entities within the meaning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>. See
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21762</NUMEX>. Therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not conduct a
final regulatory flexibility analysis under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 604</NUMEX>(a). One
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commenter</ENAMEX> expressed concern that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> would extend the
requirement for an open access same-time information system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OASIS</ENAMEX>)
to nonpublic, not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cooperative utilities</ENAMEX> and stated that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> would then be required to analyze the requirement's
effect on those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX>. In response, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> emphasized
that the rule would only apply to public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> that own,
operate, or control transmission facilities subject to the
Commission's jurisdiction. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21763</NUMEX>. By letter of
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> informed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> of its certification.
In light of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s determination that the rule would
not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, sections 605(a) and (c), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inapplicable</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">iii) Agency Actions Relevant</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sections 202-205</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is not
subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv) Other Relevant Information Under Acts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
Orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> promulgated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OASIS</ENAMEX> rule under the notice and
comment procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. A notice of proposed
rulemaking was published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 21, 1995</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66182</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> received comments on the proposed rule from
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">104 commenters.</TIMEX> In the preamble to the final rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
responded to issues raised during the comment period.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule requires public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> to create or participate in
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OASIS</ENAMEX> designed to provide potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> with information
by electronic means about available transmission capacity and
prices. According to the preambles to the proposed and final rules,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> reviewed its proposed information collection and,
among other things, assessed the need for the information, how the
information would be used, and the associated burden. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66184</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66198</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">21739, 21763</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-12</NUMEX> In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> solicited and
evaluated comments on the proposed information collection. The
Commission specifically solicited public comments on the need for
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> of the information; the accuracy of the burden estimate
contained in the preamble to the proposed rule; ways to enhance the
quality, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>, and clarity of the information to be collected;
and suggested methods for minimizing the burden. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66184</NUMEX>. In the preamble to the final rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
responded to comments on various aspects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OASIS</ENAMEX> requirement.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> also adjusted its burden estimate in response to
issues raised by commenters. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">21739, 21763</ENAMEX>.
Consistent with the requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>,
the preambles to the proposed and final rules set forth significant
information about the proposed collection of information. Among
other things, the preambles included a title and reasons for the
information collection, the proposed use for the information, a
description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, and the frequency of responses. 60
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66198</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21763</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">preambles</ENAMEX> also cited
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>'s clearance requirements, though not specifically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3507</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66198</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21763</NUMEX>.
At the same time as it requested public comments, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
submitted its proposed collection of information and certification
under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3506</TIMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>). See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66184</NUMEX>. In response to our inquiry,
Commission <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> advised that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approved the information
collection requirement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> also asked that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> examine
the burden associated with "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> reporting" and ensure that
this burden was reflected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s final rule. The
Commission also submitted the final rule to OMB. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21763</NUMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3, 1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> again certified to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>
that the information collection complied with each of the
objectives identified in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3506</TIMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Statutory Authorization</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX>
In the preambles to the proposed and final rules on the open
access nondiscriminatory tariff and "stranded costs," the
Commission explained that sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205 and 206</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Power</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">824d and 824e</TIMEX>, require it to ensure that, with
respect to any transmission in interstate commerce or any sale of
electric energy for resale in interstate commerce by a public
utility, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is subject to any undue prejudice or
disadvantage. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17664</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21541</NUMEX>. In the
preamble to the final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OASIS</ENAMEX> rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> explained that
2Section <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3506</TIMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>) requires each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to establish a
process to ensure that each information collection indicates the
collection is in accordance with the clearance requirements of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3507</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-12</NUMEX>
the information access requirement embodied in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OASIS</ENAMEX> rule is
necessary to meet the requirements of the open access rule. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21739-40</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statute or executive
order imposing procedural requirements relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OASIS</ENAMEX>
rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-12</NUMEX>



