



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-277027
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 20, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John H. Chafee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Max Baucus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Motor Vehicles</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Motor Vehicle Engines Air Pollution Control</ENAMEX>: Voluntary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards for Light-Duty Vehicles</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Final Rule</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Motor Vehicles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Motor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vehicle Engines Air Pollution Control: Voluntary Standards for</ENAMEX>
Light-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Duty Vehicles; Final Rule"</ENAMEX> (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2060-AF75</TIMEX>). We received the
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14, 1997</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a
final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 6, 1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31192</NUMEX>.
The rule provides the main regulatory framework for the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Low Emission Vehicle</ENAMEX> program and creates the means whereby
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">automobile</ENAMEX> and light-duty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> can volunteer to
comply with tailpipe standards that are more strict than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> can
mandate at this time. The rule is the result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ozone Transport</ENAMEX>
Commission (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTC</ENAMEX>) recommendation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> mandate a low emission
vehicle program based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> program. The OTC consists
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> (or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-45</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">designee</ENAMEX>) of each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ozone Transport Region</ENAMEX> (OTR)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,1</NUMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA Administrator</ENAMEX> (or designee), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional EPA Administrator</ENAMEX>
(or designee), and an air pollution control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> representing
each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Without a national program, each of the OTC states
would adopt a state-by-state program, mostly based on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> program, unless a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> could show it could meet the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> requirements by some other means. The remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would be subject to the requirements of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean</ENAMEX>
Air Act standards at least until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 2004</TIMEX>.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, these regulations and other actions taken by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> substantially harmonize federal and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> motor vehicle
standards, and once a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> opts into the program,
enforcement would be the same as any other federal motor vehicle
pollution control program. The quid pro quo for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>
opting into the program and subjecting themselves to the mandates
of the regulation is regulatory stability and the need to meet only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of nationwide standards to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> can be designed,
manufactured, and tested. Although the rule is made effective on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 5, 1997</TIMEX>, because it is voluntary it cannot be implemented
until the OTC and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> reach final agreement on
certain remaining issues.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-4586</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guerrero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>,
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerrero</ENAMEX> can be reached at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6111</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas E. Kelly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Regulatory</ENAMEX>
1The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTR</ENAMEX> is made up of northeastern states: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, the northern portion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-45</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEHICLES AND NEW MOTOR VEHICLE ENGINES AIR POLLUTION CONTROL</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VOLUNTARY STANDARDS FOR LIGHT-DUTY VEHICLES; FINAL RULE</ENAMEX>" (RIN:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2060-AF75</TIMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> included an analysis of the costs and benefits of a
national low emission vehicle program with its submission to this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>. That analysis shows an annual estimated cost (vehicle price
increases) of the national program for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> other than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$950 million</NUMEX>, as opposed to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> cost for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> alone. Although the national program and the OTC
program would appear to achieve the same pollution reduction in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTR</ENAMEX>, it would do so at a lower per vehicle cost (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$76</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>)
based on national sales volumes as opposed to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84</NUMEX> per vehicle
cost for the sales volumes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTR</ENAMEX>. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> to change the current <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> standards before
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 2004</TIMEX>, implementation of the voluntary program will
result in substantially reduced exhaust <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> nationwide
earlier than could otherwise be achieved because of the more
stringent standards of this rule. The benefits of these reductions
do not appear to have been monetized in the analysis.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has concluded that it was not necessary to prepare a
regulatory flexibility analysis because the rule only affects motor
vehicle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that is not comprised of a
substantial number of small businesses.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
Although the rule qualifies as a covered rule within the meaning
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>), it appears not to
qualify as either a federal intergovernmental mandate or a federal
private sector mandate because it results in "a duty arising from
participation in a voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> program" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Section</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">421</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)(a)(i)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">II</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)(A)(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Impoundment Control Act of 1974</ENAMEX> as added by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 104-4 Â§</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>)).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-45</NUMEX>
As a consequence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> did not prepare the statements required by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> did, however, prepare a regulatory impact analysis
which it furnished to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was promulgated using the notice and comment procedures
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. A notice of proposed rulemaking was published on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 10, 1995</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52734</NUMEX>, and comments were requested.
The preamble states that numerous comments were received and a
widely attended public hearing was held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1, 1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
avers that it fully considered all of the timely received public
comments and its responses to significant comments are either
contained in the preamble or included in the public docket.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule contains information collection requirements which are
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> submitted the
information collection request to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>, which has not yet approved
it.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> cites the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7521-7525</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7541, 7542</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7601</TIMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> submitted the rule to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for review under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
Order <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX> as a "significant regulatory action." The agency
reports that any changes made in response to OMB suggestions or
recommendations will be documented in the public record.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-45</NUMEX>



