



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-275821
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 16, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Alfonse M. D'Amato Chairman The Honorable Paul S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarbanes Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking, Housing</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Affairs United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Jim Leach Chairman The Honorable Henry B. Gonzalez</ENAMEX>
Ranking Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking and Financial Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-manipulation
Rules Concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities Offerings</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-manipulation Rules
Concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities Offerings</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-AF54</TIMEX>). We received the
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 23, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3, 1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">519</NUMEX>.
The final rule (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation M</ENAMEX>) governs the activities of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underwriters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">issuers</ENAMEX>, selling securityholders, and others in
connection with offerings of securities. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation M</ENAMEX> is intended
to preclude manipulative conduct by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> with an interest in the
outcome of an offering. It significantly eases the regulatory
burdens on offering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> by eliminating the trading
restrictions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underwriters</ENAMEX> of activelytraded securities of large
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">issuers</ENAMEX>, reducing the restricted periods for other securities,
providing a more flexible framework for stabilizing transactions,
expanding the securities eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> passive market making
during an offering, and deregulating rights offerings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-11</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bothwell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Institutions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Markets</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bothwell</ENAMEX> can be reached at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8678</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan G. Katz</ENAMEX> Secretary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange</ENAMEX>
Commission
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-11</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANTI-MANIPULATION RULES CONCERNING SECURITIES OFFERINGS</ENAMEX>" (RIN:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-AF54</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
report to us that it was not required to prepare, and did not
prepare, a cost-benefit analysis of the rule. Instead, pursuant to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">78w</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> is directed to consider the impact
that the rule may have on competition.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> believes that the benefits of the rule outweigh the
costs attributed to it since it will significantly ease the
regulatory burden by eliminating the trading restrictions for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underwriters</ENAMEX> of actively-traded securities, reducing the restricted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods</TIMEX> for other securities, provide a more flexible framework for
stabilizing transactions, expanding the securities eligible for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> passive market making during an offering and deregulating
rights offerings.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> expects the rule will cause the costs associated with
offerings to decrease significantly and also decrease the costs of
distributions. Recordingkeeping requirements are estimated to cost
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker-dealers</ENAMEX> to comply with the rule.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 603</ENAMEX>: Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
In its <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17107, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 1996</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> included a summary of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis.</ENAMEX> In accordance with sections 603(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> describes the reasons for the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> actions
and its objectives and legal basis. In discussing various
alternatives to the proposed rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> decided that, since
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> will benefit from the less restrictive nature of the
rule, acceptance of any of the alternatives was not preferable to
the rule as proposed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-11</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX>: Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> published a summary of its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Analysis in the preamble to the final rule and provided our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>
with a copy of the full text of the analysis. The analysis provides
a statement of the need for and the objective of the rule and the
fact that there were no comments received with respect to the
Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis.</ENAMEX>
The analysis discusses the definitions of "small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>" for
the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> subject to the rule which definitions were
adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities Exchange Release No. 18452</ENAMEX>, dated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 28, 1982</TIMEX>. While no firm estimate of the number of small
entities subject to various provisions of the rule is given, the
overall effect of the rule for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> will be beneficial
through a shorter cooling-off period and increased eligibility for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passive</ENAMEX> market making.
The analysis also addresses the various alternatives to the
final rule which were considered, including differing compliance or
reporting requirements, use of performance rather than design
standards, and an exemption for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> from coverage of the
rule. These alternatives were rejected because the burden of
compliance was not that great for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> or because of the
need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> protection.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange</ENAMEX>
Commission is not subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the Unfunded Mandates</ENAMEX>
Reform <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was promulgated using the notice and comment procedures
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> was published in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18, 1996</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17107</NUMEX>) and
comments were requested to be submitted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17, 1996</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> comments and in the preamble to the final
rule discusses the comments received and the modifications made to
the proposed rule as a result of the comments.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-11</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule contains information collections which are
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX> and review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX>.
The preamble to the proposed rule contained an explanation of
the need for the information, the burden estimates related to each
portion of the rule, and requested comments be submitted to both
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> regarding the information collections. Following
receipt of comments, some of which challenged the burden estimates
contained in the proposed rule but none of which contained
alternatives to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s estimates, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> reviewed its estimates
and retained the estimates set forth in the proposed rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approved the information collections and issued control
numbers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-0464</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-0465, -0466, -0467, -0201, -0418</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-0071</NUMEX> for
the requirements.
Statutory authorization for the rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation M</ENAMEX> is adopted under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Securities Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง
77a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> seq., particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sections 7, 17</ENAMEX>(a), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>(a), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.ยงย</ENAMEX>ง
77g, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77q</TIMEX>(a), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77s</TIMEX>(a); the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Exchange Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยง</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">78a et seq.</TIMEX>,
particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sections 2, 3, 9</ENAMEX>(a), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 11A</TIMEX>(c), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 13, 14, 15</TIMEX>(c),
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>(a), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>(a), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">78b</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78c</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78i</TIMEX>(a), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">j</ENAMEX>),
78k-1(c), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78l</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78m</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78n</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78o</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78q</TIMEX>(a), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78w</TIMEX>(a) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">78dd-1</ENAMEX>; and the
Investment <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Company Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80a-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">et seq</ENAMEX>., particularly
Sections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 30</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80a-23</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80a-29</ENAMEX>, and
80a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
The rule, promulgated by an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, is
not subject to the review requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX> Order No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> did not identify any other statutes or executive orders
imposing requirements relevant to the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-11</NUMEX>



