



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-275070
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 24, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Nancy Landon Kassebaum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward M. Kennedy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Labor</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Resources United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Administration: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Devices</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Current Good Manufacturing</ENAMEX>
Practice (CGMP) Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rule; Quality System Regulation</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>, entitled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Medical Devices; Current Good Manufacturing Practice</ENAMEX> (CGMP) Final
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rule; Quality System Regulation</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0910-AA09</ENAMEX>). We received the
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 7, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52601</NUMEX>.
The final rule revises existing current good manufacturing
practice requirements for medical devices and incorporates them
into a quality system regulation. The quality system regulation
includes requirements related to the methods used in, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> and controls used for, designing, manufacturing,
packaging, labeling, storing, installing and servicing of medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">devices</ENAMEX> intended for human use. The rule adds preproduction design
controls and is intended to achieve consistency with quality system
requirements worldwide.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>-3
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>'s
compliance with the procedural steps required by sections
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule.
Our review indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> complied
with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The official
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Slomba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Director</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slomba</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-9910</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Services</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>-3
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRUG ADMINISTRATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDICAL DEVICES; CURRENT GOOD</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANUFACTURING PRACTICE</ENAMEX> (CGMP) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FINAL RULE; QUALITY SYSTEM</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REGULATION</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0910-AA09</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>) performed a cost and
benefit analysis evaluating the economic impact of the final
rule.
The estimated total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> incremental cost to the industry is
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$81.9 million</NUMEX>. The majority of the costs (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$57.5 million</NUMEX>) represent
the establishment of design controls for new products. Most of the
remaining costs are attributable to extending the quality system
and requiring appropriate documentation, evaluating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> and
contractors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> review.
The benefits to the public health are estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36 to 44</NUMEX>
fewer deaths per year and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">484 to 677</NUMEX> fewer serious injuries per
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> attributable to design-related device failures. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> assumed an
economic value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> per fatality avoided, so that the
monetary savings per year would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180 to $220 million</NUMEX> per year.
These figures do not include any monetary savings associated with
the reduction in serious injuries. Additionally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> states
that the rule will result in fewer product recalls and better
product quality.
Finally, since the final rule is designed to harmonize with the
international standards, device <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> will not have to
maintain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different quality systems to compete both nationally
and internationally.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has concluded that the rule will have a significant
economic impact on a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> because
almost all medical device <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> are classified as small
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>'s definition of size. An
initial regulatory flexibility analysis and a final regulatory
flexibility analysis have been prepared and included in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preambles</ENAMEX> to the proposed rule and the final rule notice,
respectively, as required by sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603 and 604</NUMEX>. The analyses
comply with the informational requirements of the sections
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>-3
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> subject to the rule and
alternatives considered to reduce the burden on the small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, in drafting the rule to ease the burden on small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>, has not applied the design requirements to all Class I
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">devices</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component suppliers</ENAMEX> have been removed from the rule's
coverage. Also, the requirement for traceability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> has
been limited to where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> believes it is necessary to
protect the public health. In addition, other revisions were made
to make the final rule less prescriptive and to allow
establishments greater flexibility in meeting the requirements.
Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> will conduct workshops, issue guidance manuals and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">videotapes</ENAMEX>, and hold teleconferences to aid small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in
complying with the rule.
The analyses use both quantifiable and general descriptions of
the effects of the rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> as required by section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607</NUMEX> and numerous small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> participated in the rulemaking as
required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 609</ENAMEX> by submitting comments on the proposed rule
and by attending an open public meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1995</TIMEX> and the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1995</TIMEX> meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Good Manufacturing Practice Advisory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> examined the final rule as prescribed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> and
found that no mandate will be imposed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, local or tribal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and it believes that the burden on the private sector
will be below the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> expenditure level to require
compliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. However, while the cost estimated by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> on the private sector is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$81.9 million</NUMEX>, in view of the
uncertainties in the estimates, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has followed the requirements
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
As required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 205</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> considered regulatory
alternatives to the requirements of the rule but determined that
the provisions of the final rule constituted the most
cost-effective and least burdensome alternative that would meet the
objective of the rule.
To ease the regulatory burden, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has extended the
effective date of the rule to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 1997</TIMEX>, and will not take
regulatory action for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an additional year</TIMEX> on the design control
requirement. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> exempted almost all Class I devices.
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> rejected suggestions that low-risk devices be exempted
because the cost of implementation will exceed the public health
benefits gained. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> found that all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Class</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> and III devices, even
those devices from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> with excellent past records, should be
covered because their failure could adversely affect public
health.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>-3
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was promulgated using the notice and comment procedures
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX> and the procedures contained at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§
360j(f)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) concerning the establishment of an advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to
advise and submit recommendations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> regarding
regulations concerning good manufacturing practices.
Meetings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Device Good Manufacturing Practice Advisory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMP Advisory Committee</ENAMEX>) were announced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> publication on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 25, 1990</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17502</NUMEX>) and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17, 1991</TIMEX> ( <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15626</NUMEX>). An advance notice of proposed
rulemaking was published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15, 1990</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24544</NUMEX>), and
the proposed rule was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1993</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61952</NUMEX>), soliciting comments from the public.
In addition, various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and working drafts of the rule were
made available to the public and an open public meeting on the rule
was held.
The preamble to the final rule discusses the comments which were
received and the changes which were made to the rule based on such
comments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule contains information collections that are subject
to review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> and include device
master records, device history records, quality system records and
complaint files. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> solicited comments on these requirements
in the notice of proposed rulemaking and has evaluated and
responded to them in the preamble to the final rule.
The preamble to the final rule contains an explanation of the
need for the information and the burden estimates relating to each
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> of the rule. The information collections associated with
the final rule contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,527,901</NUMEX> burden hours which include
1,433,579 burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time start up expenditure for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,237</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,094,321</NUMEX> burden hours expended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,237</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> solicits comments on the information collections
contained in the final rule until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6, 1996</TIMEX>, regarding the
necessity of the collection, the estimate of the burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to minimize the burden including electronic submission of
responses. After receipt of these comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> will publish a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is submitting the
collections to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for approval and again when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> makes a decision
on approval, modification or disapproval. The information
collections in the rule will not become effective until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>
approval is obtained and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> control number has been issued.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>-3
Statutory authorization for the rule
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe Medical Devices</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">101-629, November</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28, 1990</TIMEX>), amended <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 520</ENAMEX>(f) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Food, Drug and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Cosmetic Act</ENAMEX> providing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> with the authority to add
preproduction design controls to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Current Good Manufacturing</ENAMEX>
Practices regulation. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">360j</ENAMEX>(f)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(A).
Executive Order No. 12866
The rule was determined to be an "economically significant
regulatory action" under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX> requiring review
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Affairs</ENAMEX> (OIRA). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX> approved the final rule as
complying with the requirements of the Order based on information
supplied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, including a planned regulatory action document
describing the reason for the rule and an assessment of the costs
and budgetary impact of the rule.
Executive Order No. 12875 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intergovernmental Partnership</ENAMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has reviewed the rule under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12875</ENAMEX>
and finds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order</ENAMEX> does not apply because the rule is not
applicable to government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> but to finished device
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. However, regarding consultation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, local
and tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> notes that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> state
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> who were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturing Practices Advisory Committee</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> which explored
the need to revise the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Current Good Manufacturing Practices</ENAMEX>
regulation.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>-3



