



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-277047
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Alfonse M. D'Amato Chairman The Honorable Paul S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarbanes Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking, Housing</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Affairs United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rules Implementing</ENAMEX>
Amendments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investment Advisers</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rule 203A-2</ENAMEX>)
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange Commission</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rules Implementing Amendments to</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investment Advisers</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rule 203A-2</ENAMEX>)" (RIN:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-AH07</TIMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 16, 1997</TIMEX>. It was published
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22, 1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28112</NUMEX>.
The final rule, which was issued simultaneously with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> other
rules relating to the amendment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investment Advisers</ENAMEX> Act by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">National Securities Markets Improvement Act of 1996</ENAMEX>,
particularly title III, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investment Adviser Supervision</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Coordination Act</ENAMEX>, exempts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> from the
prohibition on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> registration. These are: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) certain pension
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) nationally recognized statistical rating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> affiliated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>-registered
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) newly formed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> that have a
reasonable expectation of becoming eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> registration
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120 days</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-46</NUMEX>
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Stromberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Institutions and Markets</ENAMEX> Issues. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stromberg</ENAMEX> can be
reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8678</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Jonathan G. Katz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> Securities and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange Commission</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-46</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMPLEMENTING AMENDMENTS</ENAMEX> TO THE <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">INVESTMENT ADVISERS ACT OF</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RULE 203A-2</ENAMEX>)" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-AH07</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> has submitted to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> a cost-benefit analysis of
the final rule. The analysis concludes that the quantifiable costs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the rule are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pension Consultant</ENAMEX>
exemption, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,000</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationally Recognized Statistical Rating</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> exemption, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affiliated Adviser</ENAMEX>
exemption, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,700</NUMEX> for the New <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adviser</ENAMEX> exemption for a total of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$926,700</NUMEX>.
The analysis lists quantifiable benefits of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000,000</NUMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affiliated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adviser</ENAMEX> exemption and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000,000</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Adviser</ENAMEX>
exemption. In addition, another benefit includes permitting real
estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> to pension plans to continue to register with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>, which will allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> to comply with the requirements
Also, new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> would not have to register initially with a
state or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, then deregister and register with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> if they
had the expectation of being eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> registration within
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120 days</TIMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> prepared an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRFA</ENAMEX>) in connection with the proposed rule, which was summarized
in the notice of proposed rulemaking (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68480, 68491-92</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 27, 1996</TIMEX>), and was available to the public in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entirety</ENAMEX>. One comment was received in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRFA</ENAMEX>.
The preamble to the final rule contains a summary of the Final
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>, a complete copy of which was
submitted to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> and was available to the public. The
analysis describes the reason for the final rule and the legal
basis for it; descriptions and estimates of the number of small
entities affected by the rule; a discussion of the recordkeeping,
reporting, and other compliance requirements; and the steps taken
to minimize the burdens on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> estimated that of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23,350</NUMEX> investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>
currently registered with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,650</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> would be
considered small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 8, 1997</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-46</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">850</TIMEX> of those small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> would remain eligible
for registration with the SEC.
The comment received in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRFA</ENAMEX> concerned the
impact of the proposed rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that manage funds
regulated under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ERISA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ERISA</ENAMEX> protects a plan's named fiduciary from
liability for the individual decisions of an "investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>"
appointed by the fiduciary to manage the plan's assets. "Investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>" is defined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERISA</ENAMEX> to include investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>
registered under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Advisers Act</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERISA</ENAMEX> has been amended
to include stateregistered investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> as "investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>," the amendment expires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 years</TIMEX> after enactment. When this
amendment expires, small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> effectively will not be able to
manage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERISA</ENAMEX> funds.
While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> found that it would be inconsistent with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Coordination Act</ENAMEX> to grant an exemption for the above-described
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> has written to the congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">committees</ENAMEX> concerned urging that the sunset provision be eliminated
and the ERISA exemption be made permanent.
Also, in response to concerns expressed, the final rule
increases the threshold for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> registration from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 to $30</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> of assets under management.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> is not subject to
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The final rule was promulgated using the notice and comment
procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. A notice of proposed rulemaking was
published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 27, 1996</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68480</NUMEX>, and requested
the submission of comments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX> comments in
response to the proposed rule. The comments received and actions
taken as a result of the comments are discussed in the preamble to
the final rule, including the redrafting of certain language on the
Form ADV-T for greater clarity.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule requires the collection of information which is
subject to review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>)
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> has approved the information
collection contained on the Form <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADV</ENAMEX> and has
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-46</NUMEX>
issued OMB No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-0049</TIMEX> following the submission of revised
burden hour estimates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> now estimates that the annual burden
estimate for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> to Form <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADV</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18,128 hours</TIMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> cites section 203A(c) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investment Advisers</ENAMEX> Act of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80b-3A</ENAMEX>(c)) as authority for the promulgation of
the final rule.
Executive Order No. 12866
The rule, promulgated by an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, is
not subject to the review requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX> Order No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-46</NUMEX>



