



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-276296
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 12, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Alfonse M. D'Amato Chairman The Honorable Paul S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarbanes Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking, Housing</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Affairs United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Jim Leach Chairman The Honorable Henry B. Gonzalez</ENAMEX>
Ranking Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking and Financial Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
Holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> and Change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank Control</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation Y</ENAMEX>)
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve System</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank Holding</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> and Change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank Control</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation Y</ENAMEX>)" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Docket</ENAMEX> Nos.
R-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0935</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0936</NUMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 24, 1997</TIMEX>. It was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 28</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9290</TIMEX>.
The final rule amends <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation Y</ENAMEX> to improve the
competitiveness of bank holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> by eliminating
unnecessary regulatory burden and operating restrictions and
streamlining the application and notice process.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Governors</ENAMEX>' compliance
with the procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)
through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review
indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Governors</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable
requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-28</NUMEX>
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governors of the Federal Reserve System</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Gleason</ENAMEX>
Stromberg, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Financial Institutions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Markets</ENAMEX> Issues. Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stromberg</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8678</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald J. Winn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board Board of Governors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve System</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-28</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ENTITLED "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BANK HOLDING COMPANIES AND CHANGE IN BANK CONTROL</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REGULATION Y</ENAMEX>)" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOCKET NOS. R</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0935</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0936</NUMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

A cost-benefit analysis was not required or prepared for the
final rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Governors</ENAMEX> has concluded that the final rule will
have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>, and an initial regulatory flexibility analysis and final
regulatory flexibility analysis have been prepared and are included
in the notice of proposed rulemaking and the final rule notice,
respectively, as required by sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603 and 604</NUMEX>. The analyses
comply with the informational requirements of the sections
including the number and sizes of the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> affected and
the alternatives considered to reduce the burden on small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>.
The final analysis points out that the expedited
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">application/</ENAMEX>notice procedures and the removal of unnecessary and
outmoded regulatory restriction will be particularly helpful to
small bank holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The rule, promulgated by an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, is
not subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the act</ENAMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was promulgated through notice and comment rulemaking
procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. The proposed rulemaking was published
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 6, 1996</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">47242,</ENAMEX>
and afforded interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> the opportunity to comment on the
proposed rule. Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> comments were received.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-28</NUMEX>
The final rule discusses and summarizes the comments submitted
and the response to them in promulgating the final rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The preamble to the final rule discusses the information
collection requirements of the final rule, the reason for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">collections</ENAMEX>, and burden estimates.
The various information collections have already been approved
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> under the act and issued OMB
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> numbers which are listed in the preamble.
The preamble points out that the number of responses and burden
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> associated with the collections are greatly reduced because
of the streamlined procedures now available to bank holding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> under the final rule. The total cost of complying with
the information collections prior to the issuance of the final rule
was estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,743,130</NUMEX>. It is estimated that the reduction
in responses and burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> will result in a savings of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,273,975</NUMEX> or a new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> cost of compliance of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,469,155</NUMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The final rule was promulgated under the authority of section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>(b) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bank Holding Company Act of 1956</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1844</TIMEX>(b));
sections <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8 and 13</NUMEX>(a) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">International Banking Act of 1978</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3106 and 3108</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 7</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">j</ENAMEX>)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13</NUMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Deposit</ENAMEX>
Insurance Act, as amended by the Change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank Control</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1817</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">j</ENAMEX>)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13</NUMEX>)); <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 8</ENAMEX>(b) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Deposit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1831i</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 106 of the Bank Holding Company Act</ENAMEX>
Amendments of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§ 1972)</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Lending</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supervision Act of 1983</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Law</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-181</NUMEX>).
Executive Order No. 12866
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, rules promulgated by the
review under the executive order.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-28</NUMEX>



