



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-277228
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable James M. Jeffords Chairman The Honorable Edward M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Labor and Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Administration<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Substances Prohibited From Use in Animal Food or</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feed; Animal Proteins Prohibited in Ruminant Feed</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>),
entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Substances Prohibited From Use in Animal Food or Feed</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Animal Proteins Prohibited in Ruminant Feed"</ENAMEX> (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0910-AA91</ENAMEX>). We
received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10, 1997</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 5, 1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30936</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> is issuing this rule to reduce the risk of an outbreak of
transmissible spongiform encephalopathy (TSE) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX>, bovine spongiform
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">encephalopathy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>), is believed to be linked to cattle feed
containing rendered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein by-products</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> and goats
infected with scrapie, a disease related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> suggests there
may be an association between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> and a form of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TSE</ENAMEX> known as
new variant Creutzfeldt-Jakob <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> has not been diagnosed
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. This rule is intended to prevent the
establishment and amplification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> through
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX> and, thereby, to minimize the risk to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-51</NUMEX>
This rule amends <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> regulations to provide that animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>
derived from mammalian tissues for use in ruminant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX> is a food
additive subject to certain provisions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Food, Drug</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Cosmetic Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§ 301 et</ENAMEX> seq.). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> is taking this
action because ruminants are being fed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> derived from animals
in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX> has been found and such <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> may cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">TSE</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ruminants</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Wannisky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-5207</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Administration</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-5138</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Donna E. Shalala</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-51</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRUG ADMINISTRATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SUBSTANCES PROHIBITED FROM USE IN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ANIMAL FOOD OR FEED; ANIMAL PROTEINS PROHIBITED IN RUMINANT FEED</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIN</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0910-AA91</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
In the preamble to the rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> presents a summary of its
economic analyses, discussing the potential benefits of the
proposed rule and the economic impact that could occur as a result
of its implementation. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> texts of both the cost analysis and an
addendum were provided to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> at the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> filed the rule
with us. In accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12866</ENAMEX>, the analyses
describe the regulatory options available to reduce the risk of an
outbreak of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the costs and benefits
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with each option.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> estimates the direct compliance costs of the rule will be
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $44.3 million</NUMEX> per year and that the initial value of the
affected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone meal</ENAMEX> will be reduced by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$171 million</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. In contrast, nonruminant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> may gain up to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$162 million</NUMEX> in lower <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX> costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> estimates that the aggregated
net annualized costs of the rule, accounting for both losses and
gains, will total <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52.9 million</NUMEX>.
The primary benefit of this rule, as described in the economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">analyses</ENAMEX>, is the costs that would be averted by reducing the risk
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> becoming established and proliferating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
through <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> stated that it could not quantify the costs of
all the benefits associated with this rule, such as the value of
human lives saved or the medical costs that would be avoided by
preventing an outbreak of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>. However, it did provide estimates of
some of the costs that might be incurred if the rule were not
implemented and an outbreak of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> were to occur in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> estimates that costs of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$93 million</NUMEX> would be incurred
in direct livestock losses due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infection, that costs of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> would be incurred slaughtering at-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> culled to
prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> spread, and that costs of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$593 million</NUMEX> would be
incurred imposing feed regulations at the time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> was
detected.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-51</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3, 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> published a summary of its Initial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact Analysis</ENAMEX> in the preamble to the proposed rule (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">552</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">572</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> concluded that the rule will have a
significant impact on a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. The
vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> involved in ruminant production and meat
preparation are considered small businesses according to size
standards set by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>. The analysis
also discusses the regulatory alternatives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> considered in
drafting the proposed rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> published a summary of its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Analysis in the preamble to the final rule published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 5</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30936</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">30966</ENAMEX>). In that analysis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> discusses
the need for the rule, the benefits anticipated from the
implementation of the rule, and a summary of the impacts of the
final rule. The preamble summarizes the issues raised by the public
comments to the proposed rule, describes the numbers of small
entities affected by the rule, and describes the recordkeeping
burden of the rule. The preamble also describes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
alternatives considered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> in promulgating this rule and why it
believes that the alternative selected (the mammalian-to-ruminant
prohibition--with exceptions) is the most cost-effective regulatory
alternative that meets the objective of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> also points
out that it revised the rule in several respects to decrease the
burden on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in response to comments received from
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> determined that, because this rule imposes no mandates on
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> and will result in expenditures of less that
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any one year</TIMEX>, that no further analysis is needed
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
This rule was published as a notice of proposed rulemaking on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3, 1997</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">552</NUMEX>) under the notice and comment
procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. Based on the numerous comments it
received, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> published the codified provisions of the draft final
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17, 1997</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18728</NUMEX>) and provided an
opportunity for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to comment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> made some changes to the
draft language based on those comments and published the final rule
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 5, 1997</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30936</NUMEX>). The preamble to the final
rule discusses the comments received and the actions taken upon
them.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-51</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
This final rule contains information collection requirements
which are subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> submitted the
information collection request to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for approval at the time the
proposed rule was published (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3, 1997</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> did not approve
the information collection as submitted, but required <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> to invite
comments on the information collection when the final rule was
published. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> evaluates the comments received, makes any
revisions, and receives final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approval for the information
collection, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> will announce in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> that approval
and the effective date of the part of the regulations that relate
to the information collection.
Executive Order 12866
This final rule is considered to be an "economically significant
regulatory action" under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12866</ENAMEX>. In accordance with
the provisions of the executive order, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> assessed the costs and
benefits of regulatory alternatives and appears to have selected
the approach that maximizes net benefits while still meeting agency
objectives.
Executive Order 12612
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> states that it has analyzed this rule in accordance with the
principles set forth in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12612, Federalism</ENAMEX>, and has
determined that the rule does not warrant the preparation of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism Assessment</ENAMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
Food<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">321, 342, 343, 348</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">721</NUMEX>) as statutory authority for this rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-51</NUMEX>



