



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-276709
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable James M. Jeffords Chairman The Honorable Edward M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Labor and Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Market Health Insurance Reform</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portability From Group</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individual Coverage; Federal Rules</ENAMEX> for Access in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individual</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Market; State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alternative Mechanisms</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Rules</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individual Market Health</ENAMEX>
Insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reform: Portability From Group to Individual Coverage</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Rules</ENAMEX> for Access in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individual Market; State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alternative Mechanisms</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Rules</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0938-AH75</TIMEX>). We
received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 9, 1997</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 8, 1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16985</NUMEX>.
The rule implements <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 111</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Insurance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Portability and Accountability Act of 1996</ENAMEX> (HIPAA) to improve
access to the individual insurance market. Certain "eligible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>" who lose group health insurance coverage are assured
availability of coverage in the individual market, on a guaranteed
issue basis, without preexisting condition exclusions. Also, all
individual health insurance coverage must be guaranteed renewable.
The rule also sets forth the procedures that apply to states that
choose to implement a mechanism under state law, as an alternative
to the federal requirements with respect to guaranteed availability
for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-38</NUMEX>
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and the rules that apply if a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> does
not substantially enforce the statutory requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>' compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>
complied with the applicable requirements.
Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> has performed work relating to this area recently,
including "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Insurance Portability</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> Could Ensure
Continued Coverage for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 25 Million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HEHS-95-257</ENAMEX>).
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Scanlon</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Financing and Systems</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scanlon</ENAMEX> can be
reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7114</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Donna E. Shalala</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-38</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INDIVIDUAL MARKET HEALTH INSURANCE REFORM</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PORTABILITY FROM GROUP</ENAMEX>
TO <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INDIVIDUAL COVERAGE; FEDERAL RULES FOR ACCESS</ENAMEX> IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INDIVIDUAL</ENAMEX>
MARKET; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STATE ALTERNATIVE MECHANISMS</ENAMEX> TO FEDERAL RULES" (RIN:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0938-AH75</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>, in conjunction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments of Labor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>,
has prepared a combined economic impact analysis for this interim
final rule and the interim final rule issued jointly by the three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments</ENAMEX>, and published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>,
concerning group market provisions because the effects of the
reforms and burdens imposed overlap the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">issuers</ENAMEX>. 62
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">16908-16920</ENAMEX>.
For the portability from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to individual coverage under this
rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> cites estimates formulated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget</ENAMEX>
Office which shows the initial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> cost (direct cost to the
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX>) to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> covered and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth year</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> covered. The
analysis also discusses social welfare effects of the rule such as
freeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from "job lock," the inability to change jobs
because of the possible loss of coverage.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
Since the rule was issued as an interim final rule and not as a
general notice of proposed rulemaking, the rule is not subject to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
Since the rule was issued as an interim final rule and not as a
general notice of proposed rulemaking, the rule is not subject to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-38</NUMEX>
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
300gg-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>) provides that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> may promulgate any
interim final rules determined to be appropriate to carry out the
provisions of Part B of the act. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> has determined that
there is good cause under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 553</ENAMEX>(b) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrative</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Procedure Act</ENAMEX> to not issue a notice of proposed rulemaking because
it would be impracticable, unnecessary, or contrary to the public
interest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> has found that without prompt guidance,
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> would have difficulty
complying with the requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIPAA</ENAMEX> and insured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> will not understand the benefit to them of having a
certificate of prior coverage to present upon entering the
individual health insurance market.
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> is accepting comments on the interim final rule for
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90-day</TIMEX> period for consideration in the development of the final
rules to be issued implementing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIPAA</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The interim final rule contains information collections subject
to review and approval by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> under
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> has requested emergency review of the collections because
the collection of the information is needed before the expiration
of the normal time limits of the act to assure guaranteeing
availability of individual health insurance coverage to certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with prior group coverage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> is requesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>
provide a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30day</TIMEX> comment period with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approval by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 1997</TIMEX>,
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 180-day</TIMEX> period. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 180-day</TIMEX> period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> will publish a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> initiating a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> agency review
and public comment period with submittal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for review and an
extension of the emergency approval to follow.
The notice contained in the preamble to the interim final rule
complies with the requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX> by
explaining the need for the information, the parties affected, and
the burden estimate related to the collection.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> estimates that the total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> responses will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 and 1999</TIMEX> with the total
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> estimated to range from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">335,000 to 586,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">384,000</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">882,000 hours</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">377,000</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">882,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. The total annual cost of complying with the
information collection is estimated to range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.9 million</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.8 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.1 million to $8.7 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>; and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.4 million to $8.7 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-38</NUMEX>
Statutory authorization for the rule
The rule is promulgated under authority of sections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2741</TIMEX> through
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2763, 2791</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2792</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health</ENAMEX> Service Act (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§
300gg-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">300gg-63, 300gg-91</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">300gg-92</ENAMEX>).
Executive Order No. 12866
The interim final rule was found to be an "economically
significant" regulatory action by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> under Executive Order No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX> and as such was reviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> based on the information
supplied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>, including a planned regulatory action document
describing the reason for the rule and an assessment of the costs
and budgetary impact of the rule. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approved the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 1997</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-38</NUMEX>



