



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-276222
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 26, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable William V. Roth, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Finance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Bill Archer Chairman The Honorable Charles B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rangel Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Ways and Means House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Administration</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplemental Security</ENAMEX>
Income<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">; Determining Disability for a Child Under Age 18; Interim</ENAMEX>
Final Rules with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Request for Comments</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Administration</ENAMEX> (SSA), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental Security</ENAMEX>
Income<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">; Determining Disability for a Child Under Age 18; Interim</ENAMEX>
Final Rules with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Request for Comments"</ENAMEX> (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0960-AE57</ENAMEX>). We
received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 12, 1997</TIMEX>. It was published in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as an interim final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 11, 1997</TIMEX>. 62
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6407</TIMEX>.
This interim final rule implements the childhood disability
provisions of sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">211 and 212</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">104-193</ENAMEX>, the
Personal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Those sections provide a new definition of disability for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, mandate changes to the evaluation process for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
disability claims and continuing disability reviews, and require
that disability redeterminations be performed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-olds</TIMEX>
eligible as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> before they attain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 18</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-23</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
SSA complied with the applicable requirements.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1995</TIMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> issued a report on the subject of this
rule entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Functional Assessments for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> Raise <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eligibility Questions"</ENAMEX> (HEHS-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95-66</NUMEX>).
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Administration</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Income Security</ENAMEX>
Issues. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7215</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Coyne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the Commissioner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Administration</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-23</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ISSUED BY THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOCIAL SECURITY ADMINISTRATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "SUPPLEMENTAL
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SECURITY INCOME; DETERMINING DISABILITY FOR A CHILD</ENAMEX> UNDER AGE <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">INTERIM FINAL RULES WITH REQUEST FOR COMMENTS"</ENAMEX> (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0960-AE57</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Administration</ENAMEX> performed a cost-benefit
assessment of the impact of the interim final rule. The assessment,
which is summarized in the preamble to the rule in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX>, was submitted to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> in its entirety.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> estimates that reduced program outlays resulting from the
rule will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.7 billion dollars</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 6 years</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34.7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> spent during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that 6-year</TIMEX> period on childhood disability
benefits. In addition, it is estimated that there will be a
reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> program outlays of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$590 million</NUMEX> during that
period.
The cost of conducting the medical redeterminations is expected
to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$185 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1997</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130 million</NUMEX> in fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 1998</TIMEX>. After that time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> estimates that administrative costs
will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> less each year from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999 through 2002</TIMEX>.
The redeterminations are expected to result in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
having benefits terminated as a result of these changes in the
law.
The assessment also discusses the costs involved in two
alternatives that were considered but were found not to adequately
reflect the intent of the legislation, as reflected by the
legislative history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Law</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX>-193.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> has certified that the interim final rule will
not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> since the rule only affects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-23</NUMEX>
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The interim final rule does not impose any unfunded mandates
upon <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, local or tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> or the private sector under
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> determined under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 553</NUMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>) that good
cause existed for dispensing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed</ENAMEX> Rulemaking
procedures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Administrative Procedure Act</ENAMEX> and has issued the
rule as an interim final rule with a request for comments by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 1997</TIMEX>. Since sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">211 and 212</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">104-193</ENAMEX> were
effective upon enactment and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 215</ENAMEX> required the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commissioner</ENAMEX>
to issue regulations to carry out the amendments within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 months</TIMEX>
after enactment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> found that it would be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impracticable</ENAMEX> and contrary to congressional intent to follow the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPRM</ENAMEX> procedures.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> will consider the comments received by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14, 1997</TIMEX>, and
will issue revised regulations if necessary.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule contains a new information collection requirement which
emergency procedures and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> has approved the collection
requirements and issued OMB No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0960-0568</TIMEX>.
The new collection of information is the completion of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Childhood Disability Evaluation Form</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Disability</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Determination Services</ENAMEX>. The submission to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> lists the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX>
usage rate of the form at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 800,000</NUMEX> and there is a
one-time disability redetermination workload of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">266,000</NUMEX> to be
processed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. The submission estimates the burden per response
to be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> for an annual hour burden of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">355,333</NUMEX>. The cost to
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.7 million</NUMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The interim final rule is issued pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 215</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">104-193</ENAMEX> to implement sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">211 and 212</NUMEX> of the
Personal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">110 Stat.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2105</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-23</NUMEX>
Executive Order No. 12866
The interim final rule was determined to be a "significant
regulatory action" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX> and was
as complying with the requirements of the order based on
information supplied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX>, including a planned regulatory action
document describing the reason for the rule and an assessment of
the costs and budgetary impact of the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-23</NUMEX>



