



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-276901
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John H. Chafee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Max Baucus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Addition of Facilities</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Certain Industry Sectors; Revised Interpretation of Otherwise</ENAMEX>
Use; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Toxic Release Inventory</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX> Right-to-Know
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>), entitled "Addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Facilities</ENAMEX> in
Certain <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Industry Sectors; Revised Interpretation of Otherwise Use</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toxic Release Inventory; Community</ENAMEX> Right-to-Know" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2070-AC71</TIMEX>).
We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 29, 1997</TIMEX>. It was published in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1, 1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23834</NUMEX>.
The final rule adds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> industry groups subject to the
reporting requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 313</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emergency Planning</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Right</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Know Act of 1986</ENAMEX> (EPCRA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ย</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ง11023</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 6607 of the Pollution Prevention Act of 1990</ENAMEX> (PPA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">13106</ENAMEX>, and in addition revises the interpretation of the
phrase "otherwise use" which is undefined in the acts but is one of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> activities
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-41</NUMEX>
requiring reporting.1 The information obtained from these
reports becomes part of the publically available data base known as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Toxic Release Inventory</ENAMEX> or TRI. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRI</ENAMEX>'s basic purpose is to
inform the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> of chemical hazards in their areas which in turn
permits communities to respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> spills and other
emergencies<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
We are also enclosing a copy of materials which were forwarded
to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> from an industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> regarding the rule.
If you have any questions about this report, please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-4586</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guerrero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>,
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerrero</ENAMEX> can be reached at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6111</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosures - 2
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas E. Kelly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">142 U.S.C ยง 11023</ENAMEX>(a) provides that "(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX>)he owner or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> of a
facility subject to the requirements of this section shall complete
a toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> release form . . . for each toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> listed
. . . that was manufactured, processed, or otherwise used in
quantities exceeding the toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> threshold quantity
established . . . ." Likewise, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 11023</NUMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) provides
that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator</ENAMEX> on his own motion or at the request of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> . . . may apply the requirements of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section to</ENAMEX> . . . any particular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> that manufactures,
processes, or otherwise uses" a listed toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> under the
conditions stated in the statute.
2A detailed discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRI</ENAMEX> is available at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s internet
site--<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">epa.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/opptintr/tri/.</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-41</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ENCLOSURE I</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACILITIES IN CERTAIN INDUSTRY SECTORS; REVISED INTERPRETATION OF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OTHERWISE USE; TOXIC RELEASE INVENTORY</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMMUNITY RIGHT</ENAMEX>-TO-KNOW"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIN</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2070-AC71</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has included a detailed economic analysis in its
submission to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, setting forth and assessing the costs, benefits,
and associated impacts of the rule. The preamble to the rule
contains summaries of the aforementioned assessments. Included in
the analysis is what can best be described as the social impact and
costs of toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> releases and other waste management
activities and the value of the information to society that will be
available from the reports from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> added by the
rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> also has concluded that although there is some overlap
between other reporting requirements for environmental releases and
other management activities mandated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPCRA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPA</ENAMEX>, and other
statutes, the reporting requirements of this rule do not conflict
because of the differences in information collected, entities
covered, reporting frequencies, how the data are reported, and so
forth.
The analysis indicates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> submitting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42,500</NUMEX>
reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> will be added by the rule to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">360</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in
the existing manufacturing sector submitting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,600</NUMEX> reports for a
total compliance cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$226 million</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX>, declining
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$143 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">subsequent years</TIMEX>. The difference in cost for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and subsequent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> appears to be based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s estimate
that each task required including compliance determinations for the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> covered, the overall affect of the modified
interpretation of "otherwise use," rule familiarization, and report
preparation will be substantially higher during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX>.
Benefits are not monetarily quantified because of the lack of
any existing methodology to do so. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> notes that the benefits to
be derived are basically those to be achieved directly through the
knowledge about the use and disposition of toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> and the
changes in behavior that may result from the information reported
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRI</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-41</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 603 -</ENAMEX> Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> published the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> (IRFA)
as required by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง 603</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33612, June 27, 1996</TIMEX>. The IRFA
explained that it defined small business as any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-49</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> rather than the under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> criteria used by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX>. Using this criteria the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> estimated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,600</NUMEX> of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> affected by the rule would be small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in the industry groups affected
by the proposed rule would not be affected as they employed less
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRFA</ENAMEX> also considered various alternatives to
the proposed rule, including different reporting requirements and
reporting thresholds.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section 604</ENAMEX> - Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> analyzed the potential impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Industrial Classification</ENAMEX> (SIC) code and concluded that
there would not be a significant economic impact on a substantial
number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> prepared an
extensive analysis of the impact on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. This assessment
is based on an estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that will be affected,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,600</NUMEX> of which can be categorized as small by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA SIC</ENAMEX> code. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s
analysis indicates that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2,895</NUMEX>) of the
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> will expend <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1 percent</NUMEX> of their annual
revenue for the rule's compliance costs, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">569</ENAMEX>) will
expend <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 1 percent and 3 percent</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> will
expend <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> or more of their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> revenues for compliance.
These figures drop significantly during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and ensuing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, e.g., <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3,353</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1 percent</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">171</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 1 percent and 3 percent</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 59</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>
with an economic impact of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> or greater. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> also estimates
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> owned by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">municipalities</ENAMEX> will be
affected by the rule, and of that total, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> small governmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX>) affected will expend less than
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> revenues for compliance.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has included an <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> Statement
with its report to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>. That statement declares that the
rule will not result in expenditure to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, local, or tribal
governments3 in the aggregate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more in
3The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> affected are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> publically owned electric
utilities with combined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> expenditures estimated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to be
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,065,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,342,000</NUMEX> thereafter.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-41</NUMEX>
any year, but that the rule "may" result in private sector
expenditures of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$226 million</NUMEX> the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$143 million</NUMEX> thereafter). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> avers that it has
not identified any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of federal financial assistance to
defray the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, local, or tribal expenditures under the rule or
other federal resources available to carry out the
intergovernmental mandate included in the rule. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> claims that
because the expenditures by publically owned electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> are
so modest the rule does not impose a "significant" federal
intergovernmental mandate. In any event, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> claims to have
"engaged in a number of efforts to consult with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> of
government" as described in the proposed rule, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33587</NUMEX>
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33615</NUMEX>, and that it received and considered comments on the issue
as discussed in the preamble to the final rule, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23834</NUMEX>
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23864</NUMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงยง</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rules were promulgated using the notice and comment
procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. A notice of proposed rulemaking was
published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27, 1996</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33587</NUMEX>, and comments were
requested. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> initially provided for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> comment period but
then granted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an additional 30 days</TIMEX> for comments from interested
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,715</NUMEX> comments4 at the close of the public
comment period on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 25, 1996</TIMEX>. Comments were considered and
discussed in the preamble.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The rule contains information collection requirements which are
subject to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> submitted the
requirements to OMB which approved them as an extension of the
currently approved information requirements. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approved the
requirements as an addendum to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICR</ENAMEX> approved under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB Control</ENAMEX>
No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2070-0093</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> control number for this action is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2070-0157</TIMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> cites sections 313(b) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">328</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emergency Planning</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Community Right-to-Know Act of 1986</ENAMEX> (EPCRA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX>
ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">งยง11023</NUMEX>(b) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11048</NUMEX> as the statutory authority for the issuance of
this rule. .
4Industry provided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">470</NUMEX> comments, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">86</NUMEX> were received from trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> from environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,875</NUMEX> from private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizens</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> from other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> from state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">108</NUMEX> from public interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> from labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-41</NUMEX>
Executive Order No. 12866
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> reviewed the rule under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX> as a
"significant regulatory action." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> reports that any
substantive comments or changes made during the review have been
incorporated into the final rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-41</NUMEX>



