



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-275318
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 31, 1996</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Richard G. Lugar Chairman The Honorable Patrick J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leahy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nutrition</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forestry United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Pat Roberts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable E</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kika</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Agriculture House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Certification Provisions</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Leland Childhood Hunger</ENAMEX> Relief Act
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Certification Provisions of the Mickey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Leland Childhood Hunger Relief Act</ENAMEX>." We received the rule on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 7, 1996</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a
Final Rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 17, 1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">61 Fed Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54270</NUMEX>.
This action is required as a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Leland</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Childhood Hunger Relief Act</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title XIII, Chapter 3, Omnibus Budget</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reconciliation Act of 1993, Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">103-66</NUMEX>), amendments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Stamp Act of 1977</ENAMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2011-2032</TIMEX>. The Leland Act
amendments: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) simplify the household definition; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) establish
eligibility for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who live with their food stamp eligible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> or alcohol rehabilitation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) exclude
from resources the value of vehicles used to transport <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) increase the fair market value exclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> for
determining a household's resource limit; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) exclude certain
General Assistance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> payments; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) exclude the earnings of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) increase the maximum amount of the dependent
care deduction; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>) eliminate the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>-2
federally-imposed limit and require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to establish
a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Statewide</ENAMEX> limit on the dependent care reimbursement paid to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Stamp Employment and Training Program</ENAMEX>; and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>) require proration of benefits only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the initial month</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">certification</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>'s
compliance with the procedural steps required by sections
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the
rule.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen E. Wannisky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8326</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
relating to the rule is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A. Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture Issues, Resources</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community and Economic Development</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-5138</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Haas</ENAMEX> Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Food, Nutrition</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Services Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>-2
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ISSUED BY THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "CERTIFICATION
PROVISIONS OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">MICKEY LELAND CHILDHOOD HUNGER RELIEF ACT</ENAMEX>"



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> did not prepare and submit to us a
separate cost-benefit analysis, it did include a brief discussion
of the benefits and costs associated with this rule in its
regulatory impact analysis. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, this
action increases the number of potentially eligible food stamp
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and increases the benefit level of certain households
that are affected by these provisions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> estimates
that this action will increase the annual cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Stamp</ENAMEX>
Program by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $207 million</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1998</TIMEX>.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> reports that it reviewed this rule in relation to
the requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603-605, 607</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>. The Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Food, Nutrition</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Services</ENAMEX> has certified under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 605 of the Act</ENAMEX> that
this rule does not have a significant economic impact on a
substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, this rule does not impose unfunded
mandates under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acts</ENAMEX> and
Executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> promulgated this rule under the notice and
comment procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. An initial <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of Proposed
Rulemaking was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 30, 1994</TIMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44866</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> received comments from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>
State and local welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and public interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The
Department discusses these comments and any action taken in
reaction to them in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>-2
the supplementary information provided when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Final Rule</ENAMEX> was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 17, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54270</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, this rule affects the determination
of eligibility and benefit levels; it does not affect the current
information collection requirements for making such determinations.
Those information collection requirements were previously approved
under OMB No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0584-0064</TIMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
This rule was determined to be economically significant and is
therefore subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX>. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> has reviewed the
rule.
Executive Order No. 12778
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, this rule was reviewed under
Executive Order No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12778</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Justice Reform</ENAMEX>. We note that the
Executive Order has been replaced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12998</ENAMEX>,
effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5, 1996</TIMEX>. However, the requirements now found at
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 3</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A), (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>), and (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>) were similarly included in the
previous version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order</ENAMEX> and it appears that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> meets those requirements. The supplementary information
published with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Final Rule</ENAMEX> clearly states the preemptive effect
to be given to the rule; what, if any, retroactive effect its
provisions may have; and the administrative procedures to be
followed prior to any judicial challenge to provisions of the
rule.
Executive Order No. 12372
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, this rule was reviewed under
Executive Order No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12372</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intergovernmental Review of Federal</ENAMEX>
Programs, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> determined that it was not covered by
the Order.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Statutory Authorization</ENAMEX> for the rule
This action is required as a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title XIII, Chapter 3</ENAMEX>,
Omnibus <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993, Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">103-66</NUMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Mickey Leland Childhood Hunger Relief Act</ENAMEX>, amendments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Stamp Act of 1977</ENAMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2011-2032</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>-2



