



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-277346
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Richard G. Lugar Chairman The Honorable Tom Harkin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forestry United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honorable Bob Smith</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Charles W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stenholm Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Agriculture House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inspection Service: Importation of Beef</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argentina</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Importation of Beef</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0579-AA71</ENAMEX>). We received
the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24, l997</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 26, 1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34385</NUMEX>.
regulations concerning the importation of animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> to allow,
under certain conditions, the importation of fresh, chilled, or
frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> states that the change is in
keeping with provisions of trade agreements recently entered into
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as it removes unnecessary restrictions on such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">importation</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s decision to consider <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> a region from which
beef could be imported with a negligible risk of introducing or
disseminating foot and mouth disease was based on an analysis of a
number of risk factors detailed in the supplementary information
published with the final rule. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> will require
certification by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that a number of mitigating
measures
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-52</NUMEX>
have been taken before the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> is made available for
importation into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34385</NUMEX> at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34386</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plant Health</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inspection Service</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the procedural steps required
by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen E. Wannisky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-5207</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inspection Service</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-5138</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry L. Medley Administrator Animal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plant Health</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inspection Service Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-52</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INSPECTION SERVICE ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">IMPORTATION OF BEEF FROM ARGENTINA</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIN</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0579-AA71</ENAMEX>)
Background
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18, 1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plant Health Inspection</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> (APHIS), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, published in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1697817105</NUMEX>) a proposed rule that was
intended to revise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title 9 of the Code</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Regulations</ENAMEX>. These revisions established importation
criteria for certain animal and plant products based on the level
of disease risk in specified geographical locations.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> initially solicited comments for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90-day</TIMEX> period
ending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17, 1996</TIMEX>. It later extended the period for an
additional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX>.
Based on its review of the comments received, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX> has decided
that further analysis of most parts of the proposed rule is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warranted</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX> did determine, however, that the amendments to the
regulations allowing, under certain conditions, the importation of
fresh, chilled, or frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> could be issued as a final rule at this time. This report
addresses only that final rule.
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
An economic impact analysis is included with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
Impact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34389</NUMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX>, if
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> was able to fill its <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 thousand metric ton</NUMEX> (KT) quota of
nonfed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> would save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $90 million</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. This would be offset, however, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> losses of more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> sectors because of
lower prices for products. These losses translate into reduced net
farm income of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just over $15</NUMEX> per beef <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$83</NUMEX> per dairy
farm.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-52</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18, 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX> published its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> in the preamble to the proposed rule (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16978</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">17016</ENAMEX>). The analysis concluded that, because the rule
relaxed the foot and mouth disease-related restrictions on the
importation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>, the proposed rule could have a
significant economic impact on a substantial number of small
entities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 95 percent</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> and dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> are composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that can be categorized as small according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Administration</ENAMEX>'s size classification. The analysis
discussed the potential impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> livestock sector,
feedlot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>, live cattle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>/transporters, cattle
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">slaughterers/</ENAMEX>primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processors</ENAMEX>, and the dairy industry. The
analysis invited comments on these potential impacts.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 26, 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX> published its Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34385</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">34389</ENAMEX>). In that
analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX> discusses the reason for the final rule and the
legal basis for it. It also describes and estimates the number of
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> affected by the rule and discusses the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recordkeeping</ENAMEX>, reporting, and other compliance requirements.
Finally, it describes the alternatives considered in the
development of the rule and why it rejected them and adopted the
rule as proposed. The alternatives included
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) not lifting the current importation restrictions for beef
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) allowing importation under either less or
more stringent conditions than those adopted in the rule. APHIS
rejected the first alternative because it believed scientific
evidence permitted importation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> under certain
conditions and not permitting such importation would be contrary to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> agreements entered into by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX> rejected
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> alternative because it believed that less stringent
mitigating measures than the ones proposed would increase the risk
of the introduction of foot and mouth disease into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and that more stringent mitigating conditions would be
unnecessarily restrictive.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX>, this rule contains no federal mandates
(under the regulatory provisions of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title II of the Unfunded</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>) that may result in expenditures by
state, local, and tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, in the aggregate, or to the
private sector, of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any one year</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-52</NUMEX>
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The rule was issued as a notice of proposed rulemaking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 1996</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16978</NUMEX>) under the notice and comment
procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. Initially, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX> allowed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 days</TIMEX> for
comments, but in response to several requests that the comment
period be extended, it allowed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an additional 60-day</TIMEX> comment period.
All comments were due by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 17, 1996</TIMEX>. During the comment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">period APHIS</ENAMEX> also held <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> public hearings at which both oral and
written comments were received. In total, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">113</NUMEX> comments were
received from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of state and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>,
international economic and political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, veterinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>, state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> of agriculture, livestock industry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>, exporting and importing industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, and
other interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Based on the number and complexity of the
comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX> decided to issue only a small portion of the
proposed rule at this time and to review and reanalyze the other
portions of the rule before issuing them as final.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX>, the information collection and recordkeeping
requirements included in this final rule have been approved by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) in accordance with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>. The assigned OMB control number is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0579-0015</TIMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">APHIS</ENAMEX> cites as statutory authorization for this rule <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§
147a, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">150ee</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">161, 162</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1306</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">111,</ENAMEX>
114a, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">134a</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">134b</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">134c</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">134f</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">136a</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9701</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4331 and 4332</TIMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
The final rule is considered to be an "economically significant
regulatory action" under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX> and was reviewed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for compliance with that order.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Environmental Policy</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§ 4321 et</ENAMEX> seq.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">APHIS</ENAMEX> performed an environmental assessment and determined that
the actions required or authorized by this rule will not present a
significant risk of introducing or disseminating foot and mouth
disease into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and will not have a significant
impact on the quality of the human environment. Based on those
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-52</NUMEX>
findings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator</ENAMEX> has determined that an environmental
impact statement need not be prepared.
Executive Order No. 12988
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX>, this rule has been reviewed under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
Order No. 12988 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Justice Reform</ENAMEX>) and has been found to meet
the standards set forth in the order. The final rule preempts all
state and local laws and regulations that are inconsistent with the
final rule, has no retroactive effect, and does not require
administrative proceedings before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> may file suit in court
challenging this rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-52</NUMEX>



