



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-276475
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 28, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Orrin G. Hatch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Patrick J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leahy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on the Judiciary United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Henry J. Hyde Chairman The Honorable John Conyers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr. Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on the Judiciary House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Naturalization</ENAMEX>
Expedited Removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aliens; Detention and Removal of Aliens</ENAMEX>;
Conduct of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Removal Proceedings; Asylum Procedures</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration Review</ENAMEX> (EOIR), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inspection</ENAMEX> and
Expedited Removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aliens; Detention and Removal of Aliens</ENAMEX>;
Conduct of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Removal Proceedings; Asylum Procedures"</ENAMEX> (RIN:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1115-AE47</ENAMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 14, 1997</TIMEX>. It was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a interim rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 6</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10312</NUMEX>.
The interim rule implements the provisions of the Illegal
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIRIRA</ENAMEX>) governing expedited and regular removal proceedings,
handling asylum claims and other activities involving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apprehension</ENAMEX>, detention, hearing of claims and ultimately the
removal of inadmissible and deportable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-32</NUMEX>
The interim rule has an effective date of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1, 1997</TIMEX>, which
is less than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay in a major rule's effective date
required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Regulatory Enforcement</ENAMEX> Fairness Act
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> (SBREFA). In establishing the effective date, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> and EOIR
state in the preamble to the interim rule that they find good cause
to make the rule effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1, 1997</TIMEX>, in order to meet the
statutory deadline imposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIRIRA</ENAMEX>. The preamble states that
the statutory deadline necessitated the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-day</TIMEX> comment period in
the notice of proposed rulemaking because of the time needed to
draft the rule, coordinate with interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, and complete
the required <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> review process.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EOIR</ENAMEX>'s compliance with
the procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EOIR</ENAMEX>, with the exception of the delay in the effective
date, complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Naturalization Service</ENAMEX> and
Administration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabkin</ENAMEX> can be reached at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8777</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">cc: The Honorable Doris Meissner Commissioner Immigration and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naturalization Service</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-32</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ISSUED BY THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE, IMMIGRATION AND NATURALIZATION</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INSPECTION AND EXPEDITED REMOVAL OF ALIENS; DETENTION AND REMOVAL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OF ALIENS; CONDUCT OF REMOVAL PROCEEDINGS; ASYLUM PROCEDURES</ENAMEX>" (RIN:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1115-AE47</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
analysis of the impact on their budgets of the interim rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> estimates that the cost to enforce the requirement to detain
all criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $205 million</NUMEX>, consisting of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,284,000</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and nonpersonnel costs of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$139,732,000</NUMEX>.
The nonpersonnel figure includes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$82,782,000</NUMEX> for bed space and
related alien custody requirements (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,600</NUMEX> beds at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$63.00</NUMEX> per day),
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36,000,000</NUMEX> increase for alien travel expenses (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,600</NUMEX> removals at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> each), and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $20,950,000</NUMEX> for detention vehicle
expenses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> is currently attempting to estimate the increased
budgetary impact of detaining all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> with administratively
final orders of deportation pending their removal.
Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> estimates training <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on the new provisions of
the law will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,977,500 and $2,000,000</NUMEX> for additional forms and
changes needed to current forms.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">EOIR</ENAMEX> states that the provisions of the interim rule will
require additional immigration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration Court</ENAMEX> presence
at existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> detention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, and construction of new
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Immigration Courts</ENAMEX> at new detention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. While there are
several unknown variables which could effect the total cost, EOIR
estimates that the annual cost could be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as high as $25,000,000</NUMEX>
including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21,300,000</NUMEX> for hiring new immigration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and legal
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> has certified that the interim rule will
not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> because it only affects the federal government
operations regarding examination, detention, and removal of aliens
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-32</NUMEX>
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The interim rule does not impose any federal mandates under
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the</ENAMEX> act on state, local or tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> or the
private sector of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any one year</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The interim rule was issued under the notice and comment
procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> published the proposed rule on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3, 1997</TIMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">444</NUMEX>. The
proposed rule only allowed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> for comment in view of the
statutory deadline of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1, 1997</TIMEX>, for implementing the changes
required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Responsibility Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
The proposed rule's request for comments resulted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">124</NUMEX>
comments being received, which the preamble to the interim rule
discusses, along with the actions taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EOIR</ENAMEX> as a
result of the comments. In addition, the interim rule contains a
request for additional comments to be submitted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 120-day</TIMEX>
comment period.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The information collection requirements of the interim rule have
been previously reviewed and approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> control
numbers have been issued.
We have been advised by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> that the Application
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Asylum and Withholding of Removal Form</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> Form <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-589</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control No.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1115-0086</TIMEX>) was resubmitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for approval because
of minor revisions necessary to comply with the provisions of the
interim rule. However, the revisions did not impact the burden
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> previously approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The interim rule is promulgated under the authority of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nationality Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1101 et seq.</TIMEX>, as
amended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Responsibility Act of 1996</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">104-208, Sept. 30, 1996</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-32</NUMEX>
Executive Order No. 12866
The interim rule is considered a "significant regulatory action"
under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX> and was reviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Information</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Affairs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> approved the interim rule as complying

with the requirements of the order based on the information
supplied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>, including a planned regulatory action document
describing the reason for the rule and an assessment of the costs
and budgetary impact of the interim rule.
Executive Order No. 12612
The interim rule has been reviewed under Executive Order No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12612</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism</ENAMEX>), and it has been determined that there are
insufficient federalism implications to warrant to the preparation
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism Assessment</ENAMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12988
The interim rule was reviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EOIR</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
Order No. 12988 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Justice Reform</ENAMEX>), sections 3(a) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
and found to meet the standards for drafting and clarity set forth
in the order.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-32</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> 20548


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">276475.2</NUMEX>
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable David McIntosh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on National</ENAMEX>
Economic Growth, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Resources</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Affairs Committee on Government Reform</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oversight</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
Dear Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>:
This is in reply to your inquiry regarding our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28, 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Review</ENAMEX> Act report on a major rule
concerning the inspection and expedited removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> issued by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration Review of the Department of Justice</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-32</NUMEX>).
Your inquiry seeks clarification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>' compliance with the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay in the effective date of a major rule from the latter
of the date of publication or receipt in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> required by
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5 of the United States Code</ENAMEX>.
As was pointed out in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 28, 1997</TIMEX>, report, while the rule
was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 6, 1997</TIMEX>, and was
received in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 14, 1997</TIMEX>, the rule
stated that it was effective on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1, 1997</TIMEX>. However, because
none of the statutory exceptions apply to toll the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay in
the effectiveness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> rule, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) required
that it take effect no earlier than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 13, 1997</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> stated that it found "good cause" to make the rule
effective on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1, 1997</TIMEX>, because of the statutory deadline
imposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Responsibility Act</ENAMEX> (IIRIRA) of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. But the good cause exception
to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay provision found at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 808</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) only
applies if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> finds with good cause "that notice and public
procedure thereon are impracticable, unnecessary, or contrary to
the public interest." Thus it is not available when notice and
comment procedures have been used. (Our report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financing Administration Medicare</ENAMEX> Program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Major</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-275549</ENAMEX>,
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275552</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 9, 1996</TIMEX>, discusses the good cause exception at
length.) Here, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> published a notice of proposed rulemaking on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3, 1997</TIMEX>, and received comments for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX>, and therefore
the good cause exception was not properly invoked. Moreover, as
discussed in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Program Major Rule Report</ENAMEX> referred to
above, the mere existence of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX> statutory deadline
established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIRIRA</ENAMEX>, which was enacted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 30, 1996</TIMEX>,
did not provide a basis for failing to comply with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay
provision.
We trust this answers your inquiry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Orrin G. Hatch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Patrick J. Leahy</ENAMEX>
Ranking Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Henry J. Hyde</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on the Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John Conyers, Jr.</ENAMEX>
Ranking Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>



