



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-277149
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Richard G. Lugar Chairman The Honorable Tom Harkin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forestry United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honorable Bob Smith</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Charles W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stenholm Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Agriculture House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodity Credit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Quality Incentives Program</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodity Credit Corporation</ENAMEX> (CCC), entitled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Quality Incentives Program</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0578-AA19</ENAMEX>). We
received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29, 1997</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22, 1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28258</NUMEX>.
Although this rule was promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodity Credit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that funds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Quality</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incentives Program</ENAMEX>), it was filed with us by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Resources</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Service</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> administer
the program).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Quality Incentives Program</ENAMEX> (EQIP) is a new
conservation program, reflecting the functions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> previous
programs--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agricultural Conservation Program</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Plains</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Program</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Quality Incentives Program</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado River Basin Salinity Control Program</ENAMEX>. Those programs were
repealed as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 4, 1996</TIMEX>. However, an interim program was
instituted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between April 4 and October 4, 1996</TIMEX>, to maintain a basic
program until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EQIP</ENAMEX> could begin. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3839aa-8</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-50</NUMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Resources Conservation Service</ENAMEX>, this
single, voluntary program will provide flexible technical,
financial, and educational assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranchers</ENAMEX> who
face serious threats to soil, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and related natural resources
on agricultural and other lands, including grazing lands, wetlands,
forest lands, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife habitats</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that,
except for ignoring the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay in the effective date of a
major rule required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Regulatory Enforcement</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fairness Act of 1996</ENAMEX> (SBREFA), the CCC complied with the applicable
requirements.
The preamble to the final rule states that the rule is effective
on the date of publication in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22, 1997</TIMEX>,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX> has determined that it is impracticable, unnecessary,
and contrary to the public interest to delay the effective date of
the rule. The immediate effective date, according to the preamble,
will permit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX> to offer the public timely, reliable
information about funding for conservation practices as early as
possible before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the start of the spring 1997</TIMEX> planting season
because it may influence planting decisions. Failure to provide the
information in a timely manner may mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> delay in the
conservation benefits. Finally, it stated that the expiration on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 4, 1996</TIMEX>, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> former conservation programs and the end
of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">180-day</TIMEX> authority to administer an interim conservation
program on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 4, 1996</TIMEX>, mean there is no program to provide
technical, financial, and educational assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranchers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBREFA</ENAMEX> provides that where an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for "good cause" finds that
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> and public procedures are impracticable, unnecessary, or
contrary to the public interest, the delay provisions of section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">801</NUMEX> do not apply. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 808</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>). Here, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX> did not make such a
finding but published the proposed rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 11, 1996</TIMEX>, in
accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Administrative Procedure Act</ENAMEX>. It received and
considered comments on the proposed rule. As discussed in our
report on a major rule issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Financing</ENAMEX>
Administration concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-275549</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-275552</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 9</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), the "good cause" exception to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay provision
found at <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 808</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) is not available when notice and comment
procedures have been used.
Moreover, we note that an effective date of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22, 1997</TIMEX>, is in
all probability too late to influence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> planting decisions.
Also, the fact that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> former programs expired over a year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> and the temporary authority expired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8 months</TIMEX> previously seems
to make a further delay of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX> of small consequence.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-50</NUMEX>
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Wannisky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate General Counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>, at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-5207</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work
relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Resources</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Service</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-5138</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul W. Johnson Chief</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Resources</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Service Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-50</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX> (a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ISSUED BY THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE, COMMODITY CREDIT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CORPORATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ENVIRONMENTAL QUALITY INCENTIVES</ENAMEX> PROGRAM"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIN</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0578-AA19</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) determined
that this was an "economically significant regulatory action" under
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order 12866</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Resources Conservation Service</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRCS</ENAMEX>) conducted an economic analysis of the potential impacts
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with this program. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRCS</ENAMEX> submitted that analysis to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29, 1997</TIMEX>, along with a copy of its
final rule.
The analysis estimates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Quality Incentives</ENAMEX>
Program (EQIP) will have a beneficial impact on the adoption of
conservation practices and, when installed or applied to technical
standards, will increase net farm income. The analysis also
estimates that society will benefit from the program in terms of
longterm productivity, maintenance of the resource base, non-point
source pollution damage reductions, and wildlife enhancements. NRCS
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EQIP</ENAMEX> is a voluntary program, it will not
impose any obligations or burdens on agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> who
choose not to participate. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NRCS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that the program was
authorized at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> for the period FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> through FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>,
with annual amounts of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> after the initial interim year
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130 million</NUMEX>.
In the analysis the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> discusses the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> alternatives
considered in implementing the program--i.e., targeting all the
funds to priority areas, targeting the majority of the funds to
priority areas, and targeting the majority of the funds to
non-priority areas. The analysis discusses the beneficial effects
and the adverse effects of each alternative and concludes that the
second alternative offered the greatest environmental return for
the federal dollars spent, provided program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> the greatest flexibility in program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>,
gave effective conservation coverage across the land, and involved
a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-50</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">603-605</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607 and 609</NUMEX>
The preamble to the final rule (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28258</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX> is not applicable to this rule
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodity Credit Corporation</ENAMEX> (CCC), which funds this
program and has issued this rule, is not required by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> 553
or any other provision of law to publish a notice of proposed
rulemaking with respect to the subject matter of this rule.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
According to the preamble, the rule does not compel the
expenditure of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more by any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, local, or tribal
government or the private sector and, therefore, a statement under
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 202 of the Unfunded Mandates Act of 1995</ENAMEX> is not
required.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX>, this rule is not covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 553</ENAMEX> of the
Administrative Procedure Act because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX> is not required to publish
a notice of proposed rulemaking by that section or any other
provision of law.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CCC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that no substantive changes have been made in this
final rule which affect the recordkeeping requirements and
estimated burdens previously reviewed and approved under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> number <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0560-0174</TIMEX>.
Executive Order l2866
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> determined that this rule was an economically significant
regulatory action under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12866</ENAMEX> because it could
result in an annual effect on the economy of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more.
Pursuant to the order, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRCS</ENAMEX> conducted an economic analysis, as
discussed above. The NRCS economic analysis is discussed in the
preamble to the final rule (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28258</NUMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRCS</ENAMEX> provided a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> copy of the analysis to us when it filed its copy of the final
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29, 1997</TIMEX>.
Executive Order 12998
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> reviewed this rule under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Executive Order 12998</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Reform</ENAMEX>, and determined that the provisions of the final
rule are not retroactive and that they
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-50</NUMEX>
preempt state and local laws to the extent such laws are
inconsistent with this rule. Before any legal action is brought
against this rule in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, the administrative appeal
rights set forth at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R.</ENAMEX> parts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 and 614</NUMEX> must be
exhausted.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Crop Insurance Reform</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reorganization Act of 1994</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">103</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">354</NUMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> classified this rule as a major
rule pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 304</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Crop Insurance Reform</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reorganization Act of 1994</ENAMEX> since it
had an annual economic impact on the economy of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> and it also affected human health and safety or the
environment. Because of this classification, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRCS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, in
cooperation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture's Office of Risk Assessment</ENAMEX> and Cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benefit Analysis</ENAMEX>, prepared an environmental risk assessment for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EQIP</ENAMEX>. The major conclusion of this assessment is that agricultural
production activities, in the absence of conservation techniques
and practices, can have serious environmental impacts. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX> concluded that the best solutions to address risks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">environmentally</ENAMEX> stressed resources are conservation measures
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> in concerted, concentrated efforts in priority areas, with
smaller scale efforts going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> outside priority areas.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seq</ENAMEX>.
In compliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Environmental Policy</ENAMEX> Act of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, as amended, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRCS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> developed an environmental assessment
of this rule to determine if implementation would have a
significant impact on the human environment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRCS</ENAMEX> concluded that it
would not and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRCS</ENAMEX> issued a finding of no significant
impact on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20, 1997</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRCS</ENAMEX> provided us with a complete copy of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Assessment</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Finding of No Significant</ENAMEX>
Impact.
Statutory authorization for the rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CCC</ENAMEX> cites as authority for this rule <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">714b and 714c</TIMEX>;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3839aa-3839aa-8</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-50</NUMEX>



