



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-279798
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 29, 1998</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John H. Chafee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Max Baucus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honorable John W. Warner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable William M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Committee on Printing Congress</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Emission</ENAMEX>
Standards for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hazardous Air Pollutants for Source Category: Pulp</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper Production</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Effluent Limitations Guidelines</ENAMEX>, Pretreatment
Standards, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Source Performance Standards</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp, Paper</ENAMEX>, and
Paperboard Category
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Emission Standards</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazardous Air Pollutants</ENAMEX> for Source Category: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp and Paper</ENAMEX>
Production<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">; Effluent Limitations Guidelines</ENAMEX>, Pretreatment
Standards, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Source Performance Standards</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp, Paper</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paperboard Category"</ENAMEX> (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2040-AB53</ENAMEX>). We received the rule on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14, 1998</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 15, 1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18504</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-45</NUMEX>
The final rule contains new effluent limitations guidelines and
standards under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Water Act</ENAMEX> for a portion of the pulp,
paper, and paperboard industry, and national emission standards for
hazardous air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> as amended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
for the pulp and paper production source category. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> is also
promulgating best management practices under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Water Act</ENAMEX>
for a portion of the pulp, paper, and paperboard industry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guerrero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>,
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerrero</ENAMEX> can be reached at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6111</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas E. Kelly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMISSION STANDARDS FOR HAZARDOUS AIR POLLUTANTS FOR SOURCE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CATEGORY</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PULP</ENAMEX> AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPER PRODUCTION; EFFLUENT LIMITATIONS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUIDELINES</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRETREATMENT STANDARDS, AND NEW SOURCE PERFORMANCE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STANDARDS</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PULP</ENAMEX>, PAPER, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AND PAPERBOARD CATEGORY</ENAMEX>" (RIN:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2040-AB53</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> performed an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Analysis</ENAMEX> of the final rule, including
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act and Clean Water Act</ENAMEX> portions of the rule, and the
analysis is summarized in the preamble to the final rule. Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> received a copy of the entire analysis as required by the
Congressional Review <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.
The analysis shows that the combined costs of the air and water
portions of the rule to be a capital cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.393 billion</NUMEX>, with
operating and maintenance costs of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$211 million</NUMEX> and post- and
pre-tax annualized costs of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$229 million and $351 million</NUMEX>,
respectively.
While the analysis states that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> is confident of the cost
figures included in the analysis, an estimation of the benefits is
more difficult because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s inability to quantitatively
evaluate all human and ecosystem benefits and to assign monetary
values to these benefits for a comparison in a standard
cost-benefit framework. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> was only able to monetize
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> air pollutants affected by the rule.
The analysis also discusses in qualitative terms the benefits of
the rule regarding human health, including the health effects for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subsistence fishermen</ENAMEX> and reduction of projected
non-cancer effects and improvements in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and wildlife
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">habitat</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603-605, 607</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has certified that the final rule will not have a
significant impact on a substantial number of small entities
because, using the size standard of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 750</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> would be considered small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. The cost of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Water Act</ENAMEX> portion of the rule for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> only
exceeded <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of revenues for one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and in no
case did it exceed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-45</NUMEX>
estimates that the impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> maximum
achievable control technology portion of the rule in combination
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Water Act</ENAMEX> portion is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> owned by one
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> may close as a result of the combined
impact.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has determined that the final rule, while not imposing a
federal mandate that will result in the expenditure of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>
or more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any one year</TIMEX>, will impose such a mandate on the private
sector. Therefore, in compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 202</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unfunded</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> prepared a written statement, including a
cost-benefit analysis, assessing the impact of the rule, which is
summarized in the preamble to the final rule. A complete copy of
the statement was furnished to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic</ENAMEX>
Analysis.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> determined that the rule will not significantly or
uniquely affect any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, local or tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
consulted with state and local air and water pollution control
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> primarily regarding implementation issues.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 205 of the Act</ENAMEX> requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to identify and
consider a reasonable number of regulatory alternatives and to
adopt the least costly, most cost-effective, or least burdensome
alternative that achieves the objectives of the rule. The preamble
discusses the alternatives considered and why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> believes that the
alternative selected is the least costly and least burdensome
consistent with the requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Water Act</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The final rule was issued pursuant to the notice and comment
procedures contained in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 17, 1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
published a notice of proposed rulemaking on the integrated air and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">water</ENAMEX> rules in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66078</NUMEX>. On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 10, 1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> held a public hearing so interested parties
could present their views on the proposed rule. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8, 1996</TIMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> of proposed rulemaking was published concerning the air
portions of the rule. All during this process, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> issued many
notices of data availability and held other meetings with numerous
industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and other interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.
In the preamble to the final rule, there is extensive discussion
of the comments submitted and the actions and changes to the
proposed rule that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> made as a result of its consideration of the
comments.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-45</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule contains collections of information which are
subject to approval by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>)
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>.
The preamble to the final rule contains the required information
regarding the collections, including the legal basis and reason for
the collections, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, and an estimate of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> estimates that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 490</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> that
are affected by the air emission rules and must submit an initial
applicability notification. Of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">490</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, an estimated
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">155</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> would be required to perform additional information
collection. This results in an estimated burden of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">320 hours</TIMEX> over
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 years</TIMEX> after promulgation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 3-year</TIMEX> cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29,600</NUMEX>
per respondent.
The collections have been sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for approval and the
requirement is not effective until approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> and a control
number is issued.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The final rule was issued pursuant to the authority of sections
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">301, 304, 306, 307, 308, 402</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">501</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Water Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1311, 1314, 1316, 1317, 1318, 1342</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1361</TIMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sections 112, 114</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">301</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7412</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7414</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7601</TIMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
The final rule was determined to be an "economically
significant" regulatory action by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX>. It was reviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> and approved as meeting the
requirements of the Order.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-45</NUMEX>



