



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">279588</NUMEX>; B-279589
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 3, 1998</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Alfonse M. D'Amato Chairman The Honorable Paul S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarbanes Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Banking, Housing</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Affairs United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open-End Management Investment Companies and New Disclosure</ENAMEX>
Option for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open-End Management Investment Companies</ENAMEX>; Final
Rules
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on major rules promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Registration Form Used by</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open-End Management Investment Companies</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registration Form</ENAMEX> rule)
and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Disclosure Option</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open-End Management Investment</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Disclosure Option</ENAMEX> rule) (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-AE46</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-AH03</TIMEX>). We received the rules on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 16, 1998</TIMEX>. They were
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as final rules on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23, 1998</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13916 and 13968</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registration</ENAMEX> Form final rule amends Form <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-1A which is used
by mutual funds to register under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Investment Company Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX> and to offer their shares under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Securities Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>.
The final rule is intended to improve fund prospectus disclosure
and to promote more effective communication of information about
funds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> by focusing the disclosure on essential
information. This will assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in deciding whether to
invest. Disclosure about technical, legal, and operational matters
that are common to all funds is minimized.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New Disclosure Option</ENAMEX> final rule permits a mutual fund to
offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> a new disclosure document called a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aprofile</ENAMEX>,"
which summarizes key information
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-40</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a fund's investment strategies, risks, performance, and
fees in a concise, standardized format. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> have the option
of purchasing the fund's shares after reviewing the profile or
after requesting and reviewing the fund's prospectus. An investor
deciding to purchase shares based on the information in a profile
will receive a prospectus with confirmation of the purchase.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rules. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas McCool</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Institutions and Markets</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCool</ENAMEX> can be
reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-8678</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Jonathan G. Katz</ENAMEX>
"REGISTRATION FORM USED BY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEN-END MANAGEMENT INVESTMENT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">COMPANIES</ENAMEX>" AND "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEW DISCLOSURE OPTION FOR OPEN-END MANAGEMENT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INVESTMENT COMPANIES; FINAL RULES</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-AE46</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-AH03</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> conducted a cost-benefit analysis for both final rules
as required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 2</ENAMEX>(c) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Investment Company Act</ENAMEX>. The act
requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> to consider whether its rulemaking will promote
efficiency, competition, and capital formation.
The analysis for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registration Form</ENAMEX> rule notes that while it
is difficult to quantify costs and benefits, the total annual cost
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175 million</NUMEX> for preparing, filing, and updating the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Form N-1A</ENAMEX> is not expected to rise significantly because new
information is not required. The benefits of the new rule include
more wellinformed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who may invest more of their resources
and allocate their investments carefully, which in turn would tend
to promote competition among the funds.
The analysis for the New Disclosure Option rule also notes the
difficulty of quantifying the costs and benefits of the rule. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> has estimated that the annual cost to the industry of preparing
and filing updated profiles would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $5.6 million</NUMEX>,
which may be offset by restructured advertising expenditures and
lower printing and distribution costs. One benefit is better
meeting the diverse information needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in evaluating
funds, which has become more difficult as the number of funds has
grown.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603-605, 607</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>
An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> and a Final
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> were prepared for both rules and
were summarized in the preambles to the proposed and final rules,
respectively. The complete analyses were furnished to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>.
The analyses contain the information required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
Flexibility Act.
The Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registration Form</ENAMEX> rule notes that of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 2,700</NUMEX> registered open-end management investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 620</NUMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-40</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX> are funds which meet the definition of small entities
with net assets of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> or less at the end of the most
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>. The analysis concludes that the final rule will
not impose any additional burdens on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> because most of
the changes in the rule do not require the development of new
information. The rule will primarily require a reformatting of the
current information, which may take longer the initial time it is
performed but will possibly result in less time in the future for
preparing the new format. While it considered several alternatives
to reduce to the burden on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> found that
separate treatment for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> would not be consistent with
the protection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>.
Concerning the New Disclosure Option rule, the Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX>
notes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately one-third</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">620</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> could
choose to use the new profile or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">207</NUMEX> funds. The analysis finds that
the new rule would not be significantly burdensome for small
entities because use of the profile is optional and that the
information contained in the profile is now typically contained a
fund's prospectus. As above, while several alternatives were
considered, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> found that it was unnecessary or inappropriate
to adopt any of them because of the need for investor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> is not subject to
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
Both final rules were issued using the notice and comment
procedures contained in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> 553.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registration Form</ENAMEX> rule was published as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of Proposed
Rulemaking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10, 1997</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10898</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX> comments
were received in response to the notice. The New Disclosure Option
rule was published as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> on the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10943</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">256</NUMEX> comments were received.
The preambles to both final rules respond to the issues raised
by the comments and discuss any action taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> in
response.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rules both contain information collections which are
subject to review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>)
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-40</NUMEX>
The preambles to the proposed rules contained the required
information regarding the reasons for the collections, the parties
affected, and the estimated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> has approved both rules' collections and has issued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>
No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-0307</TIMEX> for the collection under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registration Form</ENAMEX> rule
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3235-0488</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New Disclosure Option</ENAMEX> final
rule.
Statutory authorization for the rule
Both final rules were issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> pursuant to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 7, 8, 10</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>(a) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Securities Act</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">77e</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77g</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77h</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77j</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77s</TIMEX>(a)) and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 22</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Investment Company Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§
80a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80a-22</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80a-24</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80a-29</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80a-37</ENAMEX>).
Executive Order No. 12866
The rule, promulgated by an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, is
not subject to the review requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX> Order No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-40</NUMEX>



