



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-279224
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 23, 1998</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable William V. Roth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Finance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Bill Archer Chairman The Honorable Charles B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rangel Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Ways and Means House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financing Administration</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid Programs; Salary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Equivalency Guidelines for Physical Therapy, Respiratory Therapy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Speech Language Pathology</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occupational Therapy Services</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Financing Administration</ENAMEX>,
entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid Programs</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salary Equivalency</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guidelines for Physical Therapy, Respiratory Therapy, Speech</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language Pathology</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occupational Therapy Services</ENAMEX>" (RIN:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0938-AG70</TIMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 10, 1998</TIMEX>. It was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 30</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5106</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-30</NUMEX>
The final rule revises the salary equivalency guidelines for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> payments for the reasonable costs of physical therapy and
respiratory therapy services furnished under arrangements by an
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>. Also, the rule contains new salary equivalency
guidelines for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> payments for the reasonable costs of speech
language pathology and occupational therapy services furnished
under arrangements by an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>. The guidelines do not
apply to inpatient hospital services and hospice services and will
be used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> fiscal intermediaries to determine the maximum
allowable costs of the therapy services.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that HCFA
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Financing</ENAMEX>
Administration, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Scanlon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Financing</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scanlon</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7114</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Donna E. Shalala</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FINANCING ADMINISTRATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDICARE AND MEDICAID PROGRAMS</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SALARY EQUIVALENCY GUIDELINES FOR PHYSICAL THERAPY, RESPIRATORY</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THERAPY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SPEECH LANGUAGE PATHOLOGY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AND OCCUPATIONAL THERAPY</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERVICES</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0938-AG70</TIMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> has concluded that the final rule will result in an
estimated savings of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$170 million</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> Part A and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$90</ENAMEX>
million for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> Part B to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Trust Funds</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The preamble to the final rule discusses the
anticipated effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX>,
and therapist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in qualitative terms rather than
quantitative terms because of the difficulty of predicting what
revenue enhancement practices may be used in the future.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act, 5 U.S.C. Â§Â§ 603-605, 607</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>


The preambles of the proposed and final rules contain a combined
regulatory impact analysis with an Initial and Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>, respectively.
The analyses comply with the informational requirements by
discussing the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> subject to the final rule and
alternatives that were considered. The analyses use both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quantifiable</ENAMEX> (percentage increases or decreases in costs) and
general descriptions of the effects of the rule on the small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> considers all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX> to be small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
that the final rule will not have a significant impact on the
operations of a substantial number of rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, as required
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1302</TIMEX>(b)).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-30</NUMEX>
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>, the final rule will not impose a federal
intergovernmental or private sector mandate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or
more, as defined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The final rule was issued using the notice and comment
procedures found at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> published a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of
Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rulemaking</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 28, 1997</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14851</NUMEX>) and
requested comments on the proposed changes in methodology to
establish the salary equivalency guidelines.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">409</NUMEX> comments in the response to the notice. In the
preamble to the final rule HCFA summarizes the comments received
and its responses to the comments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The information collections contained in the final rule are
currently included in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> cost report information
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">collections</ENAMEX>, which have already been approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) pursuant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction</ENAMEX>
Act.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The final rule is issued pursuant to authority contained in
sections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1102, 1861</TIMEX>(v)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(A), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1302</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1395x</TIMEX>(v)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(A), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1395hh</ENAMEX>).
Executive Order No. 12866
The final rule was determined to be an "economically
significant" regulatory action by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and was reviewed under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX>. It was
approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 23, 1998</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-30</NUMEX>



