



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-279684
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17, 1998</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable James M. Jeffords Chairman The Honorable Edward M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Labor and Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources and Services Administration</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Organ Procurement</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transplantation Network</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Resources and Services</ENAMEX>
Administration, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Organ Procurement and Transplantation</ENAMEX>
Network" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0906-AA32</ENAMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 26, 1998</TIMEX>.
It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16296</NUMEX>.
The final rule establishes performance goals to be achieved by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Organ Procurement</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transplantation Network</ENAMEX> to improve the
effectiveness and equity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>'s transplantation
system.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>' compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-41</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Resources and Services Administration</ENAMEX>, is Bernice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinhardt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Services Quality and Public Health</ENAMEX>
Issues. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinhardt</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7119</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Donna E. Shalala</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESOURCES AND SERVICES ADMINISTRATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ORGAN PROCUREMENT</ENAMEX>
AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANSPLANTATION NETWORK</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0906-AA32</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> performed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact Analysis</ENAMEX> which is included in
the preamble to the final rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> recognizes in its analysis the difficulty of quantifying the
costs and the benefits of the rule. There is a discussion of the
current costs of transplantation and the analysis concludes that
the final rule will not substantially raise the costs.
Regarding benefits, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> discusses the use of the value of a
statistical life as a quantifying benefit and the fact that, in the
area of transplantation, the usefulness of such a measure is
reduced because of the older average age of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and the
substantial risk of either the graft or the patient not surviving.
Another benefit of the rule is the public oversight and
accountability of the organ transplant system, which will preserve
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> and confidence. Also, a system of patient-oriented
information of transplant performance will allow easier comparison
of transplant center performance and the use of performance goals
will create equity in the system.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603-605, 607</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> has certified that the final rule will not
have a significant impact on a substantial number of small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>.
However, because of concern over the effects of changes in
allocation policies on smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>
considered, as an alternative, the possibility of imposing quality
standards on transplant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, a voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> was prepared and is included in the rule's
preamble.
The major portion of the analysis discusses the alternatives
considered and the reasons why required volume or performance
standards for transplant programs and imposing specific allocation
standards focusing on geographic equity were rejected in favor of
the performance standards adopted.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-41</NUMEX>
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The final rule, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>, does not impose a federal
intergovernmental or private sector mandate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or
more, as defined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The final rule with comment period was promulgated using the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> and comment procedures in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> published a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> of proposed rulemaking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 8, 1994</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46482</NUMEX>). In a notice published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 13, 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> extended
the comment period on the proposed rule and announced a public
hearing to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 10-12, 1996</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> testified at the public hearing and
that it received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">541</NUMEX> documents containing comments pertaining to
the hearing, in addition to the 121 comment letters it received
from the proposed rule notice. In the preamble to the final rule,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> discusses these comments and addresses some misconceptions
certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commenters</ENAMEX> had regarding the role and relationship of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule contains information collections which are
subject to approval by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>)
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>. Certain of the collections have
been approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> and were issued control number <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0915-0184</TIMEX>.
The preamble describes the information being collected, the need
for the information, a description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, and the
estimated annual burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. The total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> for
all collections, both approved and pending approval, are estimated
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">43,692 hours</TIMEX>.
Written comments on the unapproved collections are requested and
no one need respond to such collections until approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>'s approval will be announced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX>.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The final rule was promulgated under the authority contained in
sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">215 and 371</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">376</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health</ENAMEX> Service Act (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">216</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">273-274d</ENAMEX>) and
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-41</NUMEX>
sections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1102, 1106, 1138</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1302, 1306</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1320b-8</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1395ii</ENAMEX>).
Executive Order No. 12866
The final rule was determined to be an "economically
significant" regulatory action under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12866</ENAMEX> and
was reviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> as complying
with the requirements of the order.
Executive Order No. 12612
The final rule contains a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism Assessment</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
Order No. 12612 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federalism</ENAMEX>) and concludes that the preemption
requirement of the final rule is necessary for the national organ
sharing system to be effective across state lines.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-41</NUMEX>



