



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-278773
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 16, 1997</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John McCain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Ernest F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Non-U.S.</ENAMEX>-Licensed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satellites Providing Domestic and International Service</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Non-U.S.-Licensed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satellites Providing Domestic and International Service</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>" (IB Docket No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-111</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC Docket</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93-23</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-399</NUMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 3, 1997</TIMEX>. It was published
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 4, 1997</TIMEX>. 62
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64167</NUMEX>.
The final rule adopts a new standard for foreign participation
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> satellite services market consistent with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' obligation under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization Agreement on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Telecommunications</ENAMEX> Services (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agreement</ENAMEX>). The procedures will
provide opportunities for foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> to deliver satellite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> here, and the liberalized market conditions resulting from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Agreement</ENAMEX> will allow
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to enter previously closed markets.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-18</NUMEX>
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-2834</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter W. Herrick</ENAMEX> AMD-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Performance Evaluation</ENAMEX> and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NON-U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LICENSED SATELLITES PROVIDING DOMESTIC AND INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERVICE</ENAMEX> IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITED STATES</ENAMEX>" (IB Docket No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96-111</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC Docket</ENAMEX> No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93-23</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-399</NUMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>, in its report to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>, states that it was not
required to prepare and did not prepare a cost-benefit analysis of
the final rule.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act, 5 U.S.C. Â§Â§ 603-605, 607</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> prepared both an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>
and a Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>, which appeared in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preambles</ENAMEX> to the proposed rule and the final rule,
respectively.
The analyses describe the reason for the rule and the legal
basis for it. They also include descriptions of the number of small
entities affected by the rule; discussions of the recordkeeping,
reporting, and other compliance requirements; and the steps taken
to minimize the burdens on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
In the Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> finds that
there will be no economic impact on small businesses. No additional
burdens are being imposed on foreign-licensed systems, large or
small, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> will apply the same rules that have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> licensed systems.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
As an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> is not subject to
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The final rule was promulgated using the notice and comment
procedures contained in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> published a Notice
of Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rulemaking</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-18</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24, 1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32398</NUMEX>. Following
the conclusion of negotiations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Agreement</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> revised
its proposed rule and published a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Further Notice</ENAMEX> of Proposed
Rulemaking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29, 1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40494</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> received
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> comments from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
overseas, which were considered in the issuance of the final
rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule contains a modification of a previously approved
information collection requirement under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction</ENAMEX>
Act.
The preamble to the final rule sets forth the information
required by the act, including the need and use of the information,
the estimated number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, and the annual burden hours
imposed.
The information will be used to evaluate the legal, technical,
and financial ability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> requesting authority to
operate. It is estimated that there will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,310</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> and
the burden hours vary from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 to 24 hours</TIMEX> per response depending on
the type of authorization requested. The total cost of compliance
with the information collection is estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.
No information will be collected and no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> need respond until
the collections are approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX>
and a control number is issued. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> will publish a notice in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> when such approval is granted.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The final rule is issued pursuant to the authority contained in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sections 1, 2, 4</ENAMEX>(i), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(r), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">308, 309</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">310</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Act of 1934</ENAMEX>, as amended, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">151, 152, 154</ENAMEX>(i), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>(r), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">308, 309</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">310</NUMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
The rule, promulgated by an independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, is
not subject to the review requirements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX> Order No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12866</NUMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-18</NUMEX>



