



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-279325
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11, 1998</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Richard G. Lugar Chairman The Honorable Tom Harkin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forestry United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable William F. Goodling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. Clay Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Education</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workforce House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Consumer Service</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Child</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adult Care Food Program</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Improved Targeting of Day Care</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Reimbursements</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Consumer Service</ENAMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child and Adult</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Food Program</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Improved Targeting of Day Care Home</ENAMEX>
Reimbursements" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0584-AC42</TIMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 1998</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 24, 1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9087</TIMEX>.
The final rule amends the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child and Adult Care Food Program</ENAMEX>
regulations governing reimbursement for meals served in family day
care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> by incorporating changes resulting from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>'s
review of comments it received on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 7, 1997</TIMEX>, interim rule<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>
The changes in the final rule involve the appropriate use of school
and census data for making tier I day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> determinations;
documentation requirements for tier I classifications; tier II day
care home options
1This interim rule was the subject of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>'s major rule
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Consumer Services</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Child</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adult Care Food Program</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Improved Targeting of Day Care</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Reimbursements</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-15</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-275874</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 22, 1997</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-32</NUMEX>
for reimbursement, including use of child care vouchers;
calculating claiming percentages/blended rates using attendance and
enrollment lists; and procedures for verifying household
applications of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> enrolled in day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>'s compliance with
the procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through
(iv) of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Consumer Service</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Agriculture Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> can
be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-5138</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Shirley R. Watkins</ENAMEX> Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Secretary Food,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nutrition</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Services Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-32</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ISSUED BY THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FOOD</ENAMEX> AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONSUMER SERVICE</ENAMEX>,
ENTITLED "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHILD AND ADULT CARE FOOD PROGRAM</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMPROVED TARGETING OF</ENAMEX>
DAY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARE HOME REIMBURSEMENTS</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0584-AC42</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> conducted a final economic impact analysis based
on new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child and Adult Care Food Program</ENAMEX> (CACFP) data, a recently
completed study of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CACFP</ENAMEX>, and comments received in connection
with the analysis performed for the interim rule.
The final analysis found that, based on the above, the expected
total federal savings for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 6 years</TIMEX> covering fiscal years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997-2002</TIMEX> will decline from the predicted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.2 billion</NUMEX> in the
interim analysis to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 billion</NUMEX>.
The effects of the final rule are that non-low-income providers
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tier II</ENAMEX>) and non-low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in tier II day
care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> will bear most of the costs resulting from the
government's savings. Non-low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> served by tier I
day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> will be unaffected by tiering. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> finds
it is possible that some low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in tier
II day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> may bear some of the costs, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> may offset
them by opting to increase child care subsidies.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603-605, 607</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> prepared an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Initial Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Analysis in connection with the interim rule (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">889,</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 7, 1997</TIMEX>), which we found in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> report complied
with the requirements of the act.
In the preamble to the final rule, the Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> is discussed and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> has found that
the final rule will have a significant economic impact on a
substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. The small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> are
composed of tier II day care home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> who will experience a
large decrease in reimbursement rates for meals served.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-32</NUMEX>
The analysis discusses the comments received in response to the
initial analysis and the actions taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> in
response. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> points out that due to the programmatic
changes mandated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Responsibility and Work</ENAMEX>
Opportunity <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reconciliation Act of 1996</ENAMEX>, there were no significant
alternatives available that would both accomplish the objectives of
the act and minimize any significant economic impact on the small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The final rule does not impose a federal mandate, as defined by
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title II of the act</ENAMEX>, on either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, local, or tribal governments
or the private sector of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any one year</TIMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
This final rule follows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>'s publication of an
interim rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 7, 1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">889</NUMEX>. The interim rule
was issued without use of the notice and comment procedures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Consumer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> had determined it was impracticable to obtain public
comments because of the statutory deadline imposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Law</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">104-193</ENAMEX>.
The final rule has been issued after considering the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">713</NUMEX>
comments which were received in response to the interim rule. The
preamble to the final rule discusses the response of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>
to the comments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule contains information collection requirements
which have been changed from the requirements of the interim rule
information collections. The preamble to the final rule discusses
these changes and the reasons they were made and the changes in the
estimated annual burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.
Based on new data being considered involving the numbers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National School Lunch Program State Agencies</ENAMEX>, sponsoring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> of family day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, and the annual frequency of
sponsoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>' recordkeeping requirements, the burden
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> are reduced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23,813</NUMEX> reporting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,208</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">recordkeeping hours</TIMEX> are added. In addition, the collection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elementary school</ENAMEX> attendance area information will result in an
additional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39,752</NUMEX> burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.
The revised information collections have been forwarded to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) for review and will not
require compliance until approved.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-32</NUMEX>
Statutory authorization for the rule
The final rule was issued pursuant to the authority of sections
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">708</NUMEX>(e)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Responsibility and Work</ENAMEX>
Opportunity <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reconciliation Act of 1996, Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 104-193</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 22</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
Executive Order No. 12866
The final rule has been determined to be an "economically
significant" regulatory action by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and was reviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> in accordance with the order.
Executive Order No. 12988 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Justice Reform</ENAMEX>)
The final rule has been reviewed under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order No. 12988</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> states that the rule is intended to have
preemptive effect with respect to any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> or local laws,
regulations or policies which conflict with its provisions, or
which would otherwise impede its full implementation. Also, the
final rule is not intended to have any retroactive effect and
administrative procedures must be exhausted prior to any judicial
challenge to the provisions of the rule.
Executive Order No. 12372 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intergovernmental Cooperation</ENAMEX>)
The preamble to the final rule notes that the rule has been
reviewed in accordance with the provisions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX> Order No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12372</NUMEX> and the interim rule had discussed the numerous meetings held
with state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and national sponsoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and the
attendance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Consumer Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> at conferences
held on the subject to discuss the rule.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-32</NUMEX>



