



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-279823
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 29, 1998</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable John H. Chafee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Max Baucus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emission Standards</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Locomotives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locomotive Engines</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emission Standards for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Locomotives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Locomotive Engines"</ENAMEX> (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2060-AD33</TIMEX>). We received
the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 26, 1998</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16, 1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18978</NUMEX>.
The final rule contains emission standards and associated
regulatory requirements for the control of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">locomotives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">locomotive</ENAMEX> engines as required by section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">213</NUMEX>
(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>. The standards will take effect in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2000</TIMEX> and will ultimately result, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, in a more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>-percent reduction in oxides of nitrogen from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">locomotives</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> complied with the applicable requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-46</NUMEX>
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guerrero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>,
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerrero</ENAMEX> can be reached at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6111</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas E. Kelly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STANDARDS FOR</ENAMEX> LOCOMOTIVES AND <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LOCOMOTIVE ENGINES"</ENAMEX> (RIN:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2060-AD33</TIMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> performed a cost-benefit analysis which is summarized in the
preamble to the final rule. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> received a copy of the full
analysis.
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 41-year</TIMEX> life of the program, the time necessary to
ensure a complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> turnover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> estimates that the total
costs will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.273 billion</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.331 billion</NUMEX> at net present
value.
This will result in a total benefit in the reduction of oxides
of nitrogen of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 20 million tons</NUMEX> and reductions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275,000</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">metric tons</NUMEX> of particulate matter and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400,000 metric tons</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hydrocarbons</ENAMEX>. An analysis for oxides of nitrogen reveals a cost
effectiveness of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$163</NUMEX> per ton or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$66</NUMEX> per ton <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at</TIMEX> net present
value.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603-605, 607</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has certified that the final rule
will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number
of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> types of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> which could
potentially be impacted by the rule: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> involved
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">locomotive aftermarket</ENAMEX> parts production and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">locomotive</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">remanufacturing</ENAMEX> and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has determined that
the impacts would be minimal or nonexistent because, among other
reasons, the phase-in of the remanufacturing requirements combined
with the compliance flexibility given to small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> during
the initial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of the program will allow them to make the
transition into the new marketplace for certified remanufactures
without hardship. Also, small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX> are exempt from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tier</ENAMEX> 0
remanufacturing requirements for their existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleets</ENAMEX> and the
railroad inuse test program included in the rule only applies to
Class I freight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX>, thus exempting all small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX> from
the requirement.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> states that it tailored the rule to minimize or eliminate
the effects on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-46</NUMEX>
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, the final rule does not impose an
intergovernmental mandate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more in any one year
because the rule does not impose an enforceable duty on any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
local, or tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. However, the final rule does impose a
mandate that may result in the expenditure of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more
in any <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> on the private sector.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> utilized the cost and benefit analysis it performed pursuant
to Executive Order No. 12866 and the discussion of alternatives it
considered to satisfy the requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unfunded Mandates</ENAMEX>
Reform Act, as permitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 202</ENAMEX>(c) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> also
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that the analysis shows that it chose the alternative which
represented the least costly, most cost effective approach to
achieving the air quality goals of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The final rule was issued using the notice and comment
procedures in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 11, 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> published a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> of proposed rulemaking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6365</TIMEX>). In addition to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> written comments received in response
to the notice of proposed rulemaking, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> held a public hearing in
Romulus, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15, 1997</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> responds to the comments in
the preamble to the final rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule contains collections of information which are
subject to review and approval by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has submitted
the required documentation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> and no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> need respond to any
collection of information until the collection is approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>
and a control number is issued.
The preamble to the final rule contains the required information
regarding the collection, including the reason and need for the
information, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, and an estimate of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> burden hours which will be imposed.
The information being collected will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to certify
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">locomotives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">locomotive</ENAMEX> engines will be in compliance with the
applicable emission standards. It is estimated that it will average
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">494 hours</TIMEX> per the expected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">126</NUMEX> responses from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> at an
annualized capital/startup cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 million</NUMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-46</NUMEX>
Statutory authorization for the rule
The final rule was promulgated under the authority of sections
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">114, 203, 204, 205, 206, 207, 208, 209, 213, 215, 216</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">301</NUMEX>(a)
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> as amended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7417, 7522</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7523, 7524, 7525, 7541, 7542, 7543, 7547, 7549, 7550</TIMEX>, and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7601</TIMEX>(a)).
Executive Order No. 12866
The final rule was determined to be an "economically
significant" regulatory action under the Order. It was reviewed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> and was approved as complying
with the requirements of the Order on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 17, 1997</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-46</NUMEX>



