



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-279750
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24, 1998</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable William V. Roth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Finance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Bill Archer Chairman The Honorable Charles B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rangel Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Ways and Means House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financing Administration</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Program; Schedule of</ENAMEX>
Per-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beneficiary Limitations</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Health Agency</ENAMEX> Costs for Cost
Reporting Periods
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Financing Administration</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>), entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Medicare Program; Schedule of Per-Beneficiary</ENAMEX>
Limitations on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Health Agency</ENAMEX> Costs for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cost Reporting Periods</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIN</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0938-AI84</TIMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 9, 1998</TIMEX>. It was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15718</NUMEX>.
The final rule, in accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 4602</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balanced</ENAMEX>
Budget <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1997</ENAMEX>, sets forth a new schedule of limitations on
home health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> costs that may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-44</NUMEX>
paid under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program for cost reporting periods
beginning on or after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1, 1997</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that HCFA
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Financing</ENAMEX>
Administration, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Scanlon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Financing</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems Issues</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scanlon</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7114</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Donna E. Shalala</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FINANCING ADMINISTRATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDICARE PROGRAM; SCHEDULE OF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PER-BENEFICIARY LIMITATIONS ON HOME HEALTH AGENCY COSTS FOR COST</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REPORTING PERIODS</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0938-AI84</TIMEX>)



(i)
Cost-benefit analysis

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> has assessed the impact of the final rule and finds that
it will decrease payments to home health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.06 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1998</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.14 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)
Agency actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act, 5 U.S.C. Â§Â§ 603-605, 607</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>


In the preamble to the final rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> discusses, in the form
of a combined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory Impact Analysis and Regulatory Flexibility</ENAMEX>
Analysis, the effect of the final rule on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. The small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> include most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, and health care
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, either by virtue of their non-profit status or by having
revenues of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HCFA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that it is clear that the rule will have a
significant impact on a substantial number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> since
the aggregate per-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> limitation will reduce payments by
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 9 percent</NUMEX>.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that it has examined the options for lessening
the burden on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, since the statute does not allow for
any exceptions to the aggregate per-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> limitation based on
the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>, no regulatory relief can be provided for
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HCFA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that the final rule will not impose a federal
intergovernmental or private sector mandate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or
more, as defined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-44</NUMEX>
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
This rule was issued as a final rule with comment period because
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> and comment were impracticable. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 553</NUMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Balanced Budget Act of 1997</ENAMEX>, enacted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 5, 1997</TIMEX>, required the
per-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> limitations be established by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1, 1998</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>,
among other calculations, had to perform a special data collection
from its fiscal intermediaries to obtain cost report data and
generate an unduplicated census count from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Claims</ENAMEX>
History <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Analytical File</ENAMEX>.
For the same reason regarding the statutorily mandated effective
date, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-day</TIMEX> delay in the effective date of a rule required by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 553</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) was also waived.
Since there was neither a proposed rule nor the receipt of
public comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> has properly invoked the exception found at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 808</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay in the effective date of a
major rule normally required under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Review</ENAMEX> Act
subtitle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Regulatory Enforcement</ENAMEX> Fairness Act
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> notes in the preamble that the final rule does not have any
collections of information that would be subject to review by the
Act.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The final rule was promulgated pursuant to the authority in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 1861</ENAMEX>(v)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§
1395x(v)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>)) and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 4207 of Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. 101508</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â</ENAMEX>§
1395x (note)).
Executive Order No. 12866
The final rule was determined to be an "economically
significant" regulatory action by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and was approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> as complying with the requirements
of the Order on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 26, 1998</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-44</NUMEX>



