



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-278931
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 23, 1998</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable James M. Jeffords Chairman The Honorable Edward M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Labor and Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable William F. Goodling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. Clay Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Education</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workforce House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Labor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occupational Safety and Health</ENAMEX>
Administration: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Respiratory Protection</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Respiratory Protection</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1218-AA05</ENAMEX>). We received the
rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 5, 1998</TIMEX>. It was published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>
as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 8, 1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1152</TIMEX>.
The final rule adopts respiratory protection standards applying
to general industry, construction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipyard</ENAMEX>, longshoring, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marine</ENAMEX> terminal workplaces. The rule requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to
establish and maintain a respiratory protection program and
includes requirements for program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>; worksite-specific
procedures; respirator selection; employee training; fit testing;
medical evaluation; respirator use; cleaning, maintenance, and
repair; and other provisions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX>
complied with the applicable requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-24</NUMEX>
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlotta Joyner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education and Employment Issues</ENAMEX>. Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joyner</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7014</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Charles N. Jeffress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Secretary</ENAMEX> of
Labor
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA Department of Labor</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-24</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
ISSUED BY THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEPARTMENT OF LABOR, OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY AND</ENAMEX> HEALTH
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADMINISTRATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESPIRATORY PROTECTION</ENAMEX>" (RIN:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1218-AA05</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> conducted an economic analysis of the costs and benefits of
the final respiratory protection rule.
The analysis shows that the incremental costs to the industry as
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a whole</TIMEX> are estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$111 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. The costs of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fit testing, estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$67 million</NUMEX>, and annual
training, estimated to cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35.9 million</NUMEX>, comprise <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of
the total costs.
The benefits of the final rule are expected to be an exposure
reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent to 43 percent</NUMEX>, with a best estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
percent. Such a reduction is estimated to prevent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">289 to 1,187</NUMEX>
inhalation injuries/illnesses per year and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">554 to 8,095</NUMEX> chronic
respiratory illnesses per year, with a best estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,046</NUMEX>
injuries and illnesses prevented per year. This reduction is
estimated to save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18.8 to $218 million</NUMEX> per year, with a best
estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$93.9 million</NUMEX> per year. Finally, the analysis estimates
aversion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">203 to 835</NUMEX> cancer deaths and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125 to 845</NUMEX> deaths related
to cardiovascular disease <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, with a best estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">932</NUMEX>
lives saved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603-605, 607</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> has certified to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX> that the
final rule will not have a significant impact on a substantial
number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. No small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> in any industry would
need to increase its prices by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than .05 percent</NUMEX> to compensate
for the costs of compliance with the final rule.
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
The final rule will impose a private sector mandate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. There is no intergovernmental mandate because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX>
standards do not apply to state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, except in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that have voluntarily elected to adopt an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA State</ENAMEX>
Plan.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-24</NUMEX>
In accordance with the act, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX>, either in the preamble or in
the Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Analysis</ENAMEX> submitted to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>, gives the
statutory authority for the action; a summary of the costs and
benefits, in both qualitative and quantitative terms; and a
discussion of the regulatory alternatives which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX>
considered.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The final rule was issued using the notice and comment
procedures contained at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">553</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> published an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14, 1982</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20803</NUMEX>)
which resulted in comments from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 15, 1994</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> published a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58884</NUMEX>), and a public hearing was held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 6, 1995</TIMEX>. The record
was reopened on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 7, 1995</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56127</NUMEX>) requesting
additional comments on a later <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX>-ordered study concerning
assigned protection factors.
The entire record includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> exhibits, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> individual items,
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,300</NUMEX> transcript pages, all of which were considered in the
final rulemaking.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule contains information collection requirements
which are subject to review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>). The preamble to the final rule contains the information
required by the act, including the need for and use of the proposed
collection, a description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, and an estimate of
the burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and costs associated with the collections.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> has estimated that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> there will be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,300,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> incurring total burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,926,558</NUMEX>, or
an average burden per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6.87 hours</TIMEX>, at a cost of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180,787,295</NUMEX>.
The information collections do not have to be complied with
until approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> and control numbers are issued.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The final rule was issued pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 6</TIMEX>(b), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>(c),
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occupational Safety and Health</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">653</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">655</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">657</NUMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 107</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contract Work</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safety Standards Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 333</NUMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 41</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longshore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harbor Worker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Compensation Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 941</NUMEX>);
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>'s Order Nos. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-71</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8754</TIMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8-76</NUMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25059</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9-83</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35736</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-90</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9033</TIMEX>), or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6-96</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX>), as applicable.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-24</NUMEX>
Executive Order No. 12866
The final rule was determined to be an "economically
significant" regulatory action under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Order</ENAMEX> and was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information and Regulatory Affairs</ENAMEX> (OIRA).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIRA</ENAMEX> approved the final rule as complying with the order on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 7, 1997</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-24</NUMEX>



