



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
B-282318
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1, 1999</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable James M. Jeffords Chairman The Honorable Edward M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Health</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pensions United States Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Thomas J. Bliley, Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Honorable John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dingell Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Commerce House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
Administration<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Over-the-Counter Human Drugs; Labeling</ENAMEX>
Requirements
Pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(A) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title 5, United States Code</ENAMEX>,
this is our report on a major rule promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>),
entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Over-the-Counter Human Drugs; Labeling Requirements</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIN</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0910-AA79</ENAMEX>). We received the rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19, 1999</TIMEX>. It was
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> as a final rule on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13254</NUMEX>.
The final rule establishes a standardized format and
standardized content requirements for the labeling of
over-the-counter drug products.
The final rule has an announced effective date of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, which is less than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay in a major rule's
effective date required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Regulatory</ENAMEX>
Enforcement Fairness <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1996</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5 U.S.C Â§ 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
gives no reason in the rule's preamble as to why the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay
provision was not met. While the rule has varying compliance dates
that are much later than the announced effective date of the rule
(some previously approved products covered by the rule have several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to become compliant with the labeling requirement), we do
note
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-36</NUMEX>
that products which have drug marketing applications approved on
or after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16, 1999</TIMEX>, must comply upon approval.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is our assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s compliance with the
procedural steps required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 801</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i) through (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
of title <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with respect to the rule. Our review indicates that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, with the exception of the failure to allow the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> delay,
complied with the applicable requirements.
If you have any questions about this report, please contact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James W. Vickers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant General Counsel</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-8210</TIMEX>. The
official responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluation work relating to the
Administration, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Scanlon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Financing</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health</ENAMEX> Issues. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scanlon</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-7114</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert P. Murphy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>
Enclosure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie White</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Secretariat Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-36</NUMEX>
ENCLOSURE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX> UNDER <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§ 801</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(i)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>) OF A MAJOR RULE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRUG ADMINISTRATION ENTITLED</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OVER-THE-COUNTER HUMAN DRUGS</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LABELING REQUIREMENTS</ENAMEX>" (RIN: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0910-AA79</ENAMEX>)
(i) Cost-benefit analysis
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> performed a cost-benefit analysis of the final rule. The
analysis estimates that the one-time costs of the rule to be about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$58 million</NUMEX> with annual recurring costs of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $11.5 million</NUMEX>.
The health benefits could not be quantified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
believes the benefits to be substantial. If the rule prevents 5
percent of the hospitalizations associated with the unintended
consequences of self-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>, the economic savings could be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$39</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> in direct benefits and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> from
indirect benefits. In addition, the rule is expected to produce
more efficient consumer search activities which could lead to time
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 million to $38 million</NUMEX> per year. Based on the
above, the total benefits of the rule range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110.5 million</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$129.6 million</NUMEX> per year.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulatory Flexibility Act</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603-605, 607</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609</NUMEX>
The preamble to the final rule contains the Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexibility Analysis</ENAMEX> conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>.
Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>'s size designation for
this industry of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 750</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>
percent of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in the industry would be considered small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> finds that the one-time cost of compliance for each product,
estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600</NUMEX>, should be manageable for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> even
if they manufacture <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 to 20</NUMEX> products that require relabeling at a
cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000 to $12,000</NUMEX>.
The analysis also discusses the alternatives considered such as
different compliance dates and the reasons for the alternative
selected.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-36</NUMEX>
(iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> actions relevant to sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1532-1535</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has found that the final rule will not impose a mandate on
either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, local, or tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> or the private sector in
any <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> or more.
(iv) Other relevant information or requirements under acts and
executive orders
Administrative Procedure <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â§</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">551 et seq.</TIMEX>
The final rule was issued using the notice and comment
procedures found at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. Â§</ENAMEX> 553.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 27, 1997</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> published a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> of Proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9024</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1,800</NUMEX> comments and discusses the comments and the
changes it made to the proposed rule in the preamble to the final
rule.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3501-3520</TIMEX>
The final rule contains information collections which are
subject to review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act</ENAMEX>.
The preamble to the final rule contains the information required
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, including a description of the collection, the reason
for the collection, and an estimate of the annual burden hours
imposed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> estimates that the total burden <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> will be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120,578</NUMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">51,336 hours</TIMEX> being a one-time burden. The burden hours
are not higher because, with the varied compliance dates for the
labeling, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> will be able to change the labels as
part of the usual and customary business practice of redesigning
the labels and therefore no additional burden is incurred.
Statutory authorization for the rule
The final rule was issued pursuant to the authority of the
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health Service</ENAMEX>
Act as codified at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">321, 331, 351, 352, 353, 355, 358,</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">360, 360b</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">360gg-360ss</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">371, 374, 379e</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Â§Â</ENAMEX>§ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">216, 241,</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">262</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">264</NUMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-36</NUMEX>
Executive Order No. 12866
The final rule was reviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and determined to be an economically significant regulatory
action and approved as complying with the order.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/OGC</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-36</NUMEX>



